<movie id="2" title="1492 Conquest of Paradise">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANCHEZ punctuates each word carefully.</context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty would wish to know the true facts concerning the island of Hispanola, our first settlement in the New World, and the activities there of your servant, Christopher Columbus, Admiral of the Ocean Sea, Governor of that Island. You will remember with what hopes and promises he beguiled us -- the truth is that he now presides over a state of chaos, degradation and madness beyond imagining.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PRIEST nods.</context>
      <utterance>From the beginning, Columbus proved himself incapable of managing the affairs of the island. He appointed his brothers to important positions, at once injuring the pride and dignity of the nobles who had gone with him. He promised to build a city, the City of Isabel, named after Your Majesty. What he actually built was nothing but a collection of huts, and that in the wrong place, for all of it was easily swept away by rain and mud. Is that not so, Brother Buyl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER BUYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Your Honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ISABEL lowers her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>He promised gold. Not finding the easy quantities he promised, Columbus commanded each Indian to pay an annual tribute. Most being unable to, they were barbarously punished, against the express wish of Your Christian Majesties...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ISABEL looks over at BROTHER BUYL.</context>
      <utterance>Since provocation and injustice never ceases, many of the Indians have fled to the forests, or have begun to slay the Christians.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could it be so?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER BUYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there is worse. From the beginning, he forced the nobles to undergo physical labor, treating them equally with the Indians, all of them reduced to slavery. When the nobleman Adrian de Moxica protested against such treatment...  ... he was executed.  Is that not true also, Brother Buyl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER BUYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Your Honor. It is all true. All of it. I saw it with my own eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>He has lost control. His great arrogance has led him into depravity. He encourages our soldiers to marry the native women. He promised a paradise, but he has made a hell full of all its horrors.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the man I knew, Treasurer Sanchez?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Your Majesty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Rain is falling into the room over documents spread on a table. COLUMBUS stands up and moves to the table. Some of the walls have been blackened with smoke and flames. A lizard scuttles into the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>Of all the words my Father wrote and there were many, I remember these the most. "Nothing that results from human progress is achieved with unanimous consent..."</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS stares down at the documents, moving them away from the rain drips. He stares out by the window, and we see: A devastated landscape. Flooded roads, half-destroyed huts, broken trees... A dog picks its way through the mud.</context>
      <utterance>"And those who are enlightened before the others are condemned to purse that light in spite of others..."</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a time when the New World didn't exist...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A TEN-YEAR-OLD BOY and a strongly built man in his middle thirties, are riding a mule. The MAN'S weather-beaten face frames unusually bright eyes. On the screen these words: ANDALUSIA, 1491 COLUMBUS AND HIS SON are following a windthrashed path at the top of the hill. COLUMBUS hums a song, and FERNANDO looks up at him in adoration.</context>
      <utterance>... The sun set in the west on an ocean where no man had dared to venture. And beyond that, infinity... Pulling back, we discover:</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>FERNANDO laughs. He then starts to hum along with his</context>
      <utterance>Once I asked my Father where he wanted to go. And he replied: "I want to travel all over the seas. I want to get behind the weather..."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rushes over, full of joy, to kiss his BROTHER -- an adolescent dressed in the novice-robe, with a solemn, delicate face. DIEGO'S response is constrained.</context>
      <utterance>Diego!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DIEGO smiles a little, and kisses FERNANDO -- who is immediately distracted by a procession of hooded MONKS, hurrying to the refectory, as a bell begins to chime. The MONKS all turn to greet ANTONIO DE MARCHENA, a white- haired, elderly man -- and a monk cosmographer. MARCHENA'S gesture is broad and elegant as he opens his arms to greet COLUMBUS. He pats FERNANDO'S head and turns to DIEGO.</context>
      <utterance>Diego! Aren't you going to kiss your brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Diego, take Fernando to the dining hall. He must be hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both CHILDREN leave under the arched roof. COLUMBUS and MARCHENA begin to walk across the cloister.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Diego is a bright boy -- a pleasure to teach -- but so serious... Brothers should be raised together, Colon. Even brothers from different mothers...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCHENA laughs at the compliment.</context>
      <utterance>Father, I am doing what I think is the best for him. And he has the teacher I would have chosen for myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have crossed the cloister. MARCHENA pushes open a door.</context>
      <utterance>Just be careful you don't lose him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Almost casually, he hands COLUMBUS a letter.</context>
      <utterance>I have something for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS stops dead in his tracks. Almost frantically he tears open the letter, hardly able to believe his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You will be heard at the University of Salamanca...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God... That's in a week!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what it says.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you manage it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With some difficulty. I had to promise them you were not a total fool. MARCHENA pushes open a second door, hidden behind a wooden panel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you wish to sail west?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans forward, and points to the map spread out on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>To open a new route to Asia. At the moment there are only two ways of reaching it...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His finger traces the journey, from west to east.</context>
      <utterance>By sea, sailing around the African Continent -- the journey takes a year...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are CLOSE now on the map, as we watch his finger tracing a line between Europe and the Far East.</context>
      <utterance>Or by land...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We notice that the outline of the European continent is familiar. But we also notice that, in that great expanse of ocean, the whole American continent is missing.</context>
      <utterance>... But the Turks have closed this route to all Christians. Trading with the Orient has become arduous, if not dangerous.  There is a third way...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON MARCHENA'S FACE, touched by the mystery.</context>
      <utterance>By sailing West across the Ocean Sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you be so certain? The Ocean is said to be infinite.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ignorance! I believe the Indies are no more than 750 leagues west of the Canary Islands.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you be so certain?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The calculations of Toscanelli Marin de Tyr, Esdras...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Esdras is a Jew.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCHENA throws his quill in the air in frustration. He glances at the hourglass:</context>
      <utterance>So was Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two minutes... and already you're a dead man. Don't let passion overwhelm you, Colon.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try to remember that, Marchena...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father Marchena!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Passion is something one cannot control!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get so carried away when you are being contradicted!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been contradicted all my life... Eternity!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only God knows the meaning of such words, my son.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS walks over to him, squats down so their eyes meet. He looks at his SON for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Diego.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncomfortable with the proposition, DIEGO cannot find an answer.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to come and stay with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do whatever makes you happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS reaches out -- and touches his shoulder. He climbs up behind FERNANDO, who waves back to his BROTHER as they ride off.</context>
      <utterance>I am happy, Father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before COLUMBUS can stop him, FERNANDO has slipped off the mule and into the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Father!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the BOY has been swallowed into the mass of people. COLUMBUS tries to follow him. Flames leap into the night sky with a terrible crackling, lighting up the square with a lurid glow. Prayers are being chanted somewhere. FERNANDO has elbowed his way to the front of the crowd. A PRIEST brandishes a crucifix in front of the face of a MAN bound to a post. The heretic wears the "sambenito", a robe made of coarse fabric on which his sins have been crudely illustrated -- we see cabalistic signs, indicating that the man is Jewish. THE MAN'S eyes are mad with fear. But he refuses to kiss the crucifix, as a sign of his repentance. FERNANDO is transfixed by the scene, but still doesn't realize what is happening. He is too close to the platform to see what is in the flames of the other pyres.</context>
      <utterance>Fernando!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to his son, takes the BOY'S hand, and drags him away from the scene. But FERNANDO looks back. The distance now allows him to see inside the flames. A HALF-CHARRED FIGURE -- THE MAN'S face is distorted in a silent scream... The neck snaps like burning wood, and the head falls on one shoulder. Then the whole body collapses into the fire.</context>
      <utterance>Fernando!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEATRIX nods. He goes to the stone butt and pours water on his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Executions. In the square.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEATRIX puts the candle on the table. Her face lights up with a smile. He walks to her, and kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>They've agreed to see me in a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could be gone for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't given you much of a life.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... that's true. I have a child by a man who won't marry me! Who's always leaving...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we going to argue?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh and kiss.</context>
      <utterance>I'd love to argue with you sometimes. But you're never here!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps I was never meant to live with a woman...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I find that hard to believe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say Asia can be found by sailing west?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, your Eminence. The voyage should not take more than six or seven weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately, Don Colon, that is precisely where our opinions differ...  Are you familiar with the work of Aristotle? Erathostene? Ptolemeus?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am, Your Eminence</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans back, satisfied, and pauses for effect.</context>
      <utterance>Then you cannot ignore that according to their calculations, the circumference of the Earth is approximately...  22,000 leagues or more. Which makes the ocean... uncrossable.</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A ripple of mirthless laughter.</context>
      <utterance>But you may have found new evidence proving that these men of knowledge are totally mistaken!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Excellencies are aware of the statements of Marin de Tyr?</utterance>
   <speaker>HERNANDO DE TALAVERA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A murmur of protest spreads among the members of the Commission. But Columbus is determined to press his theories.</context>
      <utterance>Then you are also aware that his theories contradict Ptolemeus... De Tyr believes the Ocean to be only 750 leagues...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indignant and amused murmurs. DIEGO DE DEZA raises his voice to quiet the assembly.</context>
      <utterance>The Florentine Toscanelli and the French Cardinal Pierre d'Ailly both think that Marin de Tyr is accurate in his calculations. And therefore, that the ocean can be crossed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEGO DE DEZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, let us suppose Marin de Tyr is right...  Are we here to examine this proposal or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEGO DE DEZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In your opinion, how long would the voyage be?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The murmur increases.</context>
      <utterance>Seven weeks. Six, during the summer months.</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MAN of simple bearing, that COLUMBUS identifies as being a seaman, interrupts.</context>
      <utterance>Marin de Tyr is wrong -- and has been corrected many times over the centuries by the finest geographers. Your voyage, Don Colon, would take a year!</utterance>
   <speaker>VICUNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would the crew survive without being able to land for fresh water? Water is undrinkable after six weeks! You'd never be able to turn back!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We wouldn't have to turn back! We would find land at this point!</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senor Colon, an experienced captain such as yourself will understand our concern with the crew. I am not willing to have on my conscience the loss of men who would have relied upon our judgment.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instantly, the protests stop.</context>
      <utterance>Excellency, you are right.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses, and starts walking in front of the experts, as a lawyer before a grand jury.</context>
      <utterance>I am a seaman, not a scholar... But as a simple man craving for knowledge, I have read all the work of these renowned geographers and discovered that none of them could agree on the exact width of this ocean...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The experts listen. CLOSE ON SANCHEZ'S FACE, impressed by the boldness.</context>
      <utterance>Therefore, as a modest man, I wonder: who is right?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks and stops before TALAVERA, and catches the look of SANCHEZ, sitting just behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Who is right? This question remains unanswered.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Eminence, there is only one way to settle the matter. And that is to make the journey.  I am ready to risk my life to prove it possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your life, and that of others!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they agree to follow me, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Conscious of a friendlier voice, COLUMBUS sees the Treasurer SANCHEZ, an imposing man in his fifties.</context>
      <utterance>Suppose you cross this ocean. Suppose you reach Asia. What would Spain do there?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trade, Your Excellency. According to Marco Polo, the Kingdom of China is one of the richest of the world. Even the meanest buildings are roofed with gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gold?</context>
      <utterance>Is that all that interests you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE MONK smiles thinly.</context>
      <utterance>No. The Portuguese have already discovered black-skinned people. I, too, will find other populations -- and bring them to the word of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christopher -- Christo Ferens -- the Bearer of the Cross!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another small rill of laughter.</context>
      <utterance>And Colon -- the one who populates!</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If God intended our proximity to Asia, do you believe he would have waited for you to show it to the world?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hum of interest. CLOSE ON SANCHEZ -- watching COLUMBUS intently, a hint of an admiring smile on his lips.</context>
      <utterance>Did He not choose a carpenter's son to reveal Himself to the world?</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>So you consider yourself the chosen one?</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you realize your words could be considered heretical?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Asia can be found to the west -- and I will prove it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANCHEZ bows slightly.</context>
      <utterance>The Treasurer of Spain honors us with his presence.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The State has some reason to be interested in this man's proposition, Your Eminence...</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Judgment is ours!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANCHEZ helps himself to some grapes, looks round at the other members of the committee, who pretend not to be listening.</context>
      <utterance>Naturally. But I would really deplore the loss of such a potential opportunity for Spain for a... dispute over a point of geography.</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is a mercenary! Did he not already try to convince the King of Portugal of his absurd notions?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AROJAZ understands the hint, and stops smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Indeed. The world is full of mercenaries -- and states often make use of them, when it benefits them.  My only concern is the welfare and prosperity of Spain.</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANCHEZ reaches for a decanter of sherry.</context>
      <utterance>You would use your influence to assist this... intriguer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers the decanter to AROJAZ, who automatically lifts his glass. But instead, SANCHEZ pulls back the decanter, pours himself a drink, and replaces it on the table, leaving AROJAZ staring at his own empty glass.</context>
      <utterance>You know, Your Eminence, the fascinating thing about power, is that what can be given so effortlessly...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he drinks with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>... can so easily be taken away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head, puts the letter down. COLUMBUS looks appalled; devastated.</context>
      <utterance>... and therefore nothing could justify the participation of Your Highnesses in the venture that relies upon such feeble assumptions, and which any man of knowledge would take to be impractical... if not impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He paces about the book-lined room.</context>
      <utterance>They didn't listen. They didn't want to listen!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You must wait.</context>
      <utterance>You mustn't give way to despair.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! I've waited seven years already! How much longer do you want me to wait?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If God intends you to go, then you will go.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCHENA is shocked.</context>
      <utterance>Damn God!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colon!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seizes a beautiful book from MARCHENA'S desk.</context>
      <utterance>Damn all of you! You all set up theories based on what? You never leave the safety of your studies! Go out! Find out what the world is about and then tell me something I can listen to!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurls the book across the room. MARCHENA is horrified.</context>
      <utterance>These don't mean anything! They're full of assumptions! Out of the heads of old men who've never been past the end of their gardens!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS seizes more books from the shelves, just sweeping them to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>No...! My books...!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of them! Just lies!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCHENA tries to stop him. In his fury, COLUMBUS accidentally knocks the poor old MAN to the ground. His cries bring three MONKS rushing into the room. As COLUMBUS continues to rage and scatter books everywhere, they try to stop him, struggling with this big, powerful man -- to almost comical effect. Finally, a short, muscular MONK delivers a quick punch that sends COLUMBUS crashing to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Colon! Don't!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sssshhhh...! One can't speak to a man doing penance.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause -- and then FERNANDO lies face down on the floor beside his FATHER, and stretches out his arms in the same way. DIEGO is left looking on, unable to bring himself to join them.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. That's the point, Fernando.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS turns, to see a small, stocky MAN approaching: a middle-class gentleman. He nods.</context>
      <utterance>Senor Colon?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs. COLUMBUS smiles, but doesn't say anything. PINZON is clearly a little surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, thank God! I've been looking all over Seville for you! Never expected to find a sailor in a monastery, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS glances around cautiously, and walks a little way down the cloister, away from the other MONK, gesturing for PINZON to follow him. PINZON is yet more surprised by this strange behavior.</context>
      <utterance>Name's Pinzon, by the way. Martin Alonzo Pinzon. I'm a ship owner from Palos...</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS shakes his head. PINZON stares at him, perplexed.</context>
      <utterance>Is he a spy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS shakes his head again.</context>
      <utterance>What is it? Are you a Trappist?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS nods vigorously.</context>
      <utterance>Vow of silence...? Penance?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off his hat, wiping his forehead with a silk cloth.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus! Just my luck!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS nods.</context>
      <utterance>Listen. I'll do the talking for both of us. You just nod. Agreed? Just as I do with the wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS gives him a glance like one throws a question in the air.</context>
      <utterance>I know that the Commission turned you down, right? What do you expect? You're a foreigner... But I want to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS looks at him, and bursts out laughing. The other MONK looks round severely. COLUMBUS ducks behind a map, PINZON following him. PINZON lowers his voice.</context>
      <utterance>You wonder why I believe in you? Hey, I am a seaman. And we don't like to be told where to go, and where not to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS shakes his head, but looks increasingly interested by what he's hearing.</context>
      <utterance>I don't look like it, but I have friends at the Court. The Treasurer of Aragon, for example. He finances me. His name's Santangel. Ever heard of him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS nods.</context>
      <utterance>He can get you an audience with the Queen! You know why...? She owes him money. That's how it is. You -- me -- the Queen -- the world and his mistress -- agreed?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS looks around, catches the disapproving face of the MONK, crosses himself, then speaks:</context>
      <utterance>So. What do you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where can I meet this man?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS turns and sees an elegant Lord in his fifties, examining the maps.</context>
      <utterance>Immediately.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SANTANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The THREE HORSEMEN pass a procession of grateful PENITENTS, who are crawling on their knees, chanting psalms and flagellating themselves. At the head of the procession, HOODED PRIESTS carry a statue of the Virgin Mary swathed in silk and lace. The gates of the Alhambra Palace are in sight.</context>
      <utterance>These people built Granada... Centuries ago! It is a great victory over the Moors, Don Colon -- and yet what a tragedy it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this a good time to meet her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bells are pealing triumphantly. The noise is tumultuous. They ride towards the magnificent palace.</context>
      <utterance>It couldn't be better. Victors can't say no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches the window, stopping close to her. ISABEL scrutinizes him quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Rise...! Come forward!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should not even be listening to you, since my council said no. But Santangel tells me you are a man of honor and sincerity... And Sanchez, that you are not a fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ISABEL smiles, enjoying the lack of obsequiousness.</context>
      <utterance>No more than the woman who said she would take Granada from the Moors.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ocean is uncrossable?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did they say about Granada before today?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ISABEL smiles again.</context>
      <utterance>That she was impregnable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cannot ignore the verdict of my council.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A direct challenge. She doesn't know what to make of this man.</context>
      <utterance>Surely you can do anything you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This little hint of vulnerability subtly reverses their positions for a moment. Now we sense COLUMBUS scrutinizing her.</context>
      <utterance>How little you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I speak freely?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You show no inclination to speak otherwise!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what I see. I see someone who doesn't accept the world as it is. Who's not afraid. I see a women who thinks... "What if?"...</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A slight pause.</context>
      <utterance>A woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bursts out laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me... but you're the only Queen I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Then we are equal... since you are the only sailor I know!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you, Senor Colon?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Once again taken off guard, ISABEL flushes, and turns away slightly to hide it.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty seven, Your Majesty... And you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty eight...</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS bows and goes to leave. As the DUENA opens the door for him, he turns back.</context>
      <utterance>You will be informed of our decision.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he goes out, leaving her stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I thought you were younger than me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ADMINISTRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ADMINISTRATOR looks up. He is reading the contract that COLUMBUS has proposed. SANCHEZ, his mouth full, gestures for him to continue.</context>
      <utterance>... and he demands... he DEMANDS to be made a Knight, with the right to bear the Golden Spurs! He will receive the title of Don Cristobal Colon -- which will be extended to his descendants for ever more...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMINISTRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ADMINISTRATOR looks up again.</context>
      <utterance>He will be named Great Admiral of the Ocean Sea. Viceroy of the West Indies... Governor of all islands or lands discovered or as will be discovered with his help...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMINISTRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANCHEZ gestures for the document. Wipes his mouth. Continues reading, calmly:</context>
      <utterance>The highest titles of nobility, Your Excellency! To an immigrant sheltered by monks!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, hands the document back.</context>
      <utterance>Furthermore he will receive one eight of all wealth or monies, precious gems, pearls, metals, spices and other lucrative sources conquered within the boundaries of his admiralty...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very underdone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMINISTRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Underdone! It's monstrous, Excellency!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he carries on eating.</context>
      <utterance>No, the pheasant. It's almost raw.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Believe me, he WILL!</context>
      <utterance>You worry too much, Carvajal... The man will have to lower his demands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS tightens his fists, tries to remain calm.</context>
      <utterance>We have considered your -- demands very carefully, Senor Colon... Your expectations are... excessive, in every way.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANCHEZ holds up a document.</context>
      <utterance>If I am right, my requests are fair!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers the document to COLUMBUS, who takes it, scans it quickly, shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>We have prepared our own contract...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The eyes behind the screen -- the mouth, forming a little smile.</context>
      <utterance>NO...! I have waited too long, fought too hard. Now you expect me to take all the risks while you take the profit! No... I will not be your servant!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remind you, Senor Colon, that you are in no position to bargain with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not bargaining!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS leans over the table, faces him.</context>
      <utterance>Then you are too ambitious.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And were you never ambitious, Excellency? Or is ambition only a virtue among the nobles, a fault for the rest of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS smiles.</context>
      <utterance>If you won't accept our proposal, we'll simply find someone who will.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns, strides towards the door. We hear a WOMAN'S muffled laughter. As COLUMBUS goes out, ISABEL appears through a secret door. SANCHEZ bows. ISABEL goes over to the window and looks out.</context>
      <utterance>If you can do that, Excellency -- I'll become a monk!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were right, Don Sanchez... His demands could never be granted.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns, questioningly, towards him.</context>
      <utterance>Never, Your Majesty. Although...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Although one may always renegotiate a contract. Especially signed by Royal Hands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Into a monk...</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It would be a pity, wouldn't it?  Call him back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. But he seems to be unable to share her happiness.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses to him quickly, placing her hand gently on his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>If I ever come back, I swear I will...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not asking you to swear to anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to wait for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>That's something you can't decide.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Turning, COLUMBUS finds his son beside him.</context>
      <utterance>You can't go there!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO points at the monsters. He pulls the boy to him.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a pen, and draws a smile on one of the terrible monsters, transforming it at once. FERNANDO laughs immediately.</context>
      <utterance>There aren't any monsters, Fernando. The only monsters are in here...  Watch!</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to go with you!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There'll be a time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO pulls the chain with the St. Christopher medal from under COLUMBUS' shirt.</context>
      <utterance>You promise?  Do you swear on St. Christopher...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you swear on all the Holy Saints in heaven?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he hugs his SON tightly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... Yes, I do... On all of them!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Nomine Patris et Filius, et Spiritus Sancti.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCHENA recognizes COLUMBUS' voice.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, Father. For I have sinned.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am listening, my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, I have betrayed my family. I betrayed my men. And I betrayed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lied. The journey will be longer than I said.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>I am not sure... It could be twice the distance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May God forgive you...! You must tell them! You must tell your men!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I tell them, they won't follow me. You know that I am right, Father. You trust me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And if you don't I will.</context>
      <utterance>My son, my son...  Your certitudes are sometimes frightening...  Christopher, you must speak to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long silence.</context>
      <utterance>You are bound by an oath, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believed in you...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>Give me absolution.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Devastated, MARCHENA reluctantly makes the sign of the cross.</context>
      <utterance>Give me absolution, Father!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO nods, tears in his eyes. Then COLUMBUS embraces BEATRIX tightly. She whispers into his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Be good to your mother, Fernando. Do you promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But COLUMBUS and DIEGO are unable to find words, and instead they clumsily hug. Someone taps COLUMBUS' shoulder. He turns around to see SANTANGEL. Wordlessly, they hug.</context>
      <utterance>Speak to Diego.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DIEGO catches it. Opening his hand he looks at the medallion. Then looks up at his FATHER, elated. THE SANTA MARIA is now two meters from the QUAY. SANTANGEL is now opposite COLUMBUS.</context>
      <utterance>Diego! Here!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take care of my investment, wherever you're going!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to tell you Santangel. I don't know where on earth I am going! They both laugh. A FISHERMAN, standing in his shrimp-boat lets his hand slide gently along the gigantic hull. He stares up at the SAILORS leaning on the rail.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vaya con Dios!  They wave back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Due west, Captain Mendez. And may God be with us...</utterance>
   <speaker>MENDEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MENDEZ doesn't move, continuing to observe COLUMBUS.</context>
      <utterance>God be with us admiral.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MENDEZ is hesitant. He nervously clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>What is it Mendez? Speak!</utterance>
   <speaker>MENDEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... It's the men, Sir. They wonder how you know our position. We've lost sight from land days ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do you think Mendez?</utterance>
   <speaker>MENDEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I surely know what a quadrant is! But I've never seen it used at night before.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MENDEZ hesitates, then motions to COLUMBUS. The SAILORS are watching, and some approach to hear the conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Come over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, find the North Star. Do you have it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MENDEZ tries again.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move! A mistake of one degree and we'll be off 6,000 leagues!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you read?</utterance>
   <speaker>MENDEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MENDEZ turns to COLUMBUS.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALONSO does not seem convinced.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. The twenty eighth parallel. And we'll follow it until we reach land.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know land is on the twenty eighth parallel?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others laugh. The BOY, ashamed, tries to ignore them. ALONSO'S hand accidentally touches a brass fitting; he reacts like he was burnt.</context>
      <utterance>Chicken-ass face!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sucks his blistered fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never seen heat like this! Not even in Las Minas!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The water's going putrid in the barrels.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SHIP'S BOY glances round at them.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be drinking your own piss... For the glory of Spain... and Admiral Colon...! Bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you listening to, chicken ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, leave him alone. He's doing no harm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BOY turns away, dropping the bucket back into the sea.</context>
      <utterance>With a face like that?  I don't want you looking at me. You hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the devil's child...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BOY throws more water over the deck. A SAILOR takes his guitar, and starts singing an improvised song.</context>
      <utterance>We'll all go crazy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh. The BOY, hearing this, climbs to the crow's-nest like a monkey.</context>
      <utterance>Culo de galina es el hijo del demonio...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should have seen land.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can't be that near.</context>
      <utterance>We left three weeks ago, Alonso.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COOK starts laughing. They turn to him.</context>
      <utterance>Can't be that far, I say. Also, I don't like the smell of the sea around here. Smells like a cunt. Bad sign...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MENDEZ has sensed the danger of this lack of respect. He approaches them.</context>
      <utterance>And why does this one take to the sea? Nobody knows. Never says a word...</utterance>
   <speaker>MENDEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They split in silence.</context>
      <utterance>To your post! At once!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHIP'S BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE HOUR-GLASS runs out. COLUMBUS converts the mark into a daily average for distance and speed.</context>
      <utterance>Mark. Twenty nine, Sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE SHIP'S BOY cups his hands to his mouth to shout.</context>
      <utterance>Six hundred and twenty nine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHIP'S BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AN OFFICER turns to PINZON to repeat the message.</context>
      <utterance>Six hundred and twenty nine!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PINZON does not seem too pleased.</context>
      <utterance>Six hundred and twenty nine, Sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE OFFICER examines his own calculations.</context>
      <utterance>I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes back to his cabin.</context>
      <utterance>I think I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MENDEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Continue rowing!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALONSO defiantly stares at MENDEZ. He then starts to beat a rhythm on the hull with his fist, followed by the others. In the two other boats, the MEN begin to follow suit, beating a rhythm of protest on the hulls. MENDEZ looks up to COLUMBUS, in panic. ON BOARD PINZON'S SHIP, an OFFICER cups his hands to his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>To where?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Pinzon requests permission to board.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Granted.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lied! You cheated! We're way past 750 leagues!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six days ago, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be mad...!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to keep the hopes of these men alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on the verge of a mutiny, Colon!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I don't know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're lost!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The land is there. I know it!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know anything! Listen Colon, these are my ships, right? So I'm telling you we're turning back!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You know that!</context>
      <utterance>And then what? Half of the water has gone, the rest is nearly putrid!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Maria! I should have never listened to you!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never did. You did all the talking for both of us, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bloody...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pinzon, Pinzon... All we can do now is go forward! Think about that!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell that to them!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS moves to the door. As an afterthought, he takes his scarlet-embroidered jacket from a hook.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. Let the men decide.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up and down the line, finishing on ALONSO. They stare at one another.</context>
      <utterance>Who gave you the order to come on board?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the MEN murmur their agreement.</context>
      <utterance>God doesn't want us to cross the ocean...! This voyage is cursed!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cursed?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALONSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALONSO glances towards the SHIP'S BOY, with his hair lip. The BOY lowers his eyes. COLUMBUS moves towards him, pulls him forward, stands him in front of ALONSO.</context>
      <utterance>We set sail for greed. God has abandoned us. The voyage is cursed. There are signs...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the men laugh at this statement. ALONSO is ill at ease. COLUMBUS pauses, looks around at all the MEN.</context>
      <utterance>This boy has the voice of an angel. What comes out of his mouth is blessed, Alonso. What comes out of your is evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MEN are listening. We sense a subtle change of mood...</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me! Every man is afraid who does something for the first time. But those who overcome their fears, will find their rewards. I do not know if it is God's will that we cross this ocean -- but I am certain it is the devil who puts fears into our hearts...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS points at the SHIP'S BOY.</context>
      <utterance>This jacket to the first man who sights land! I want a man up that mast day and night.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SHIP'S BOY rushes up the mast. As he climbs, the mainsail starts to fill with wind. The deck begins to move under their feet. This movement under their feet seems to imperceptibly erase the fears and the angers.</context>
      <utterance>You start first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MENDEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRIES from the other ships, as the sails snap taut, filling with wind. MEN rush to their posts. PINZON stares at COLUMBUS, shaking his head in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Alonso! Jaime! Don't let this wind escape us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS walks away to his cabin, then turning back to</context>
      <utterance>You lucky bastard...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MENDEZ grimaces, and opens one eye.</context>
      <utterance>Mendez! Mendez!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Land...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swallows. Tears have sprung to his eyes. He is so moved he cannot continue. Coming to his rescue -- THE SHIP'S BOY starts to roll the drum. He then stops.</context>
      <utterance>By the... by the Grace of... God...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the name of their Gracious Majesties of Castille and Aragon, and by all the powers vested in me, I claim this island and name it San Salvador. The MEN cheer as the flags are rammed into the sand, flapping in the wind. COLUMBUS starts to walk towards the jungle, and in silence the rest follow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MENDEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several of them raise their weapons to their shoulders, pointing them into the jungle. From COLUMBUS' POV we slowly scan the face of the thick jungle ahead. For a moment we don't see anything -- and then, with a shock, we see the first INDIAN. Naked, painted like an idol, carrying a hunting lance. As if they had materialized from nowhere: the rest of the HUNTING PARTY, with their bows and spears. Silent. Watchful. They stare back at us. The SPANIARDS nervously finger their weapons. COLUMBUS slowly lifts his hand into the air: a clear signal not to fire. Then, removing his sword, he drops it on the ground, and starts to walk forward, fixing his gaze upon the first INDIAN he saw.</context>
      <utterance>Arquebuses!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS ignores him, even though some of the INDIANS have raised their weapons. He stops in the no-man's land between them. The INDIANS don't move -- but something excites them. The SHIP'S BOY, wearing COLUMBUS' embroidered jacket and the drum, has followed COLUMBUS and now stands close to him. He is the cause of their interest. COLUMBUS puts his arm around the BOY, and this gesture of affection seems to put the INDIANS at their ease. They start talking and pointing. They come forward slowly, start to tentatively touch the BOY'S jacket. Then, now laughing, they touch COLUMBUS, pulling at his beard. COLUMBUS laughs too. Sensing their innocence, the rest of the MEN lower their weapons. Some of them laugh. An apparition: a beautiful young INDIAN GIRL, totally naked, walks out of the jungle. She is pregnant and holds a child. We begin to hear Indian music, played on a flute.</context>
      <utterance>Colon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The INDIANS says the word in his own language, laughing. We see that some of the other INDIANS also have small gold ornaments. PINZON repeats the INDIAN word for gold. The INDIAN removes the ornament from his nose, gives it to PINZON, who indicates that he wants to have it. The INDIAN nods -- but points to PINZON'S dagger, indicating that he wants it in return. PINZON shakes his head, stops the INDIAN from taking it.</context>
      <utterance>Gold...! Gold!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PINZON looks at him, about to argue -- but COLUMBUS insists. PINZON takes out the dagger and offers it to the</context>
      <utterance>Give it to him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OLD INDIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE OLD MAN nods, points into the distance, chatters away to UTAPAN.</context>
      <utterance>Cuba! Cuba!</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say not here! Cuba!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? A tribe? An island?</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Island. Far.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALONSO is quiet and silent. His eyes are looking around at his companions. UTAPAN shakes his head. There is nothing he can do. ALONSO is now leaning back, supported by one of his friends. He has grabbed the forearm of a SAILOR. His look is already far away. His companion shouts at UTAPAN.</context>
      <utterance>Help him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do something! Help him!</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALONSO starts convulsing. HIS FRIENDS hold him, desperate in their helplessness. Others simply move away, horrified. One of them cries.</context>
      <utterance>He dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UTAPAN stops obediently, and rushes back to COLUMBUS with comical energy. On their way back, they find one SOLDIER sitting, leaning against a tree. He has removed his helmet. His hair sticking to his forehead. As COLUMBUS and UTAPAN walk back, they find another SAILOR, then another, then the whole group gathered around PINZON. Ashen, he burns with fever. He attempts a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Utapan! Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS looks around him -- what he sees: exhausted men and jungle, as far as one can see.</context>
      <utterance>Well... You'll have to continue without me...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PINZON grins.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's enough. What would you say to a drop of Jerez, Pinzon?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh as the OFFICER helps PINZON to his feet. PINZON walks a few yards into the jungle -- starts to urinate. It is red. Suddenly dizzy, he reels and collapses.</context>
      <utterance>And a nice slice of Santa Fe lamb! I'd sell my soul for it.  Help me up. I've got to piss, gold.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come! You speak first!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell the Chief we thank him.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief knows.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UTAPAN translates.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him his country is very beautiful. Tell him we are leaving men here -- to build a fort.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UTAPAN translates. The CHIEF GUARIONEX asks a simple question.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him we will return very soon. Many of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief says -- how many?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thousands.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS doesn't seem to understand the question. For the first time he seems to be caught short.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To bring the word of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief says -- he has a God.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and also to bring medicine.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief says...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UTAPAN translates.</context>
      <utterance>He has medicine.  Tell him we admire his people.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the CHIEF gets up, awards COLUMBUS with a smile, and walks out of the hut, the ELDERS following, leaving COLUMBUS alone.</context>
      <utterance>Chief says he knows you like his...  Women...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a beginning...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MEN start to scramble below decks.</context>
      <utterance>Get below! All of you! Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ship rolls again. COLUMBUS and MENDEZ crawl towards the mast. Another gigantic wave crashes over them, tons of water falling like cement. They reach the mast. The wood groans.</context>
      <utterance>Stay with me!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MENDEZ nods... COLUMBUS grabs some rope. The ship rises into the air again, crashes down, the deck disappearing beneath them for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>We may have to cut it!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MENDEZ seems to hesitate. COLUMBUS screams at him again.</context>
      <utterance>Now go!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another huge wave washes over COLUMBUS. He emerges, almost suffocated. The storm rages, its eerie light making it seem at times like bright daylight. But as the lightning flashes, COLUMBUS begins to count:</context>
      <utterance>I said -- below deck, Mendez! MENDEZ crawls away.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's an enormous thunderclap on "four" -- it indicates how close they are to the eye of the storm. The ship keels over again, dropping down and down, seeming never to rise... COLUMBUS lifts his head to the heavens, screams out:</context>
      <utterance>One... two... three... four...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if in answer, another flash of lightning that illuminates the sky and the sea. COLUMBUS starts counting again.</context>
      <utterance>Damn you!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another terrible clap of thunder on "five" -- COLUMBUS starts laughing, knowing the storm is moving on. Then, in the strange light, something seems to move through the air towards him; it looks like some kind of projectile, a craft, with a trail of vapor. COLUMBUS stares up at it... amazed. We start to hear the "Te Deum", majestic and heavenly.</context>
      <utterance>One... two... three... four... five...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't be easy to get rid of your prophet now, Don Sanchez.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the contrary, Your Eminence. It seems to me the man is preparing his own cross.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the cigar back to MOXICA. With a casual air, MOXICA himself inhales deeply -- almost chokes to death. He gulps down a glass of wine... much to the amusement of the others.</context>
      <utterance>You must not inhale, but simply allow the palate to enjoy the flavor of the Tobacco...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you say this is an Indian vice? By God! I don't see any kind of pleasure that would make this a sin.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Indians have no such word, Don Moxica.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do they have such thoughts?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ISABEL blushes slightly.</context>
      <utterance>They come and go as naked as the day God created them...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And...</context>
      <utterance>They don't see sin in their nakedness. They live according to nature, in a never ending summer. The islands are covered with trees, filled with blossoms and fruits.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ISABEL opens the casket, revealing the gleam of gold inside. She takes out some of the little golden ornaments... a bracelet and then the mask. She holds it, somehow moved by its crude beauty. ISABEL raises the mask to her face, looking across at</context>
      <utterance>These are gifts for Your Majesty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We discover the SWORD MASTER is fencing with COLUMBUS. A dozen duellists are practicing in the magnificent rotunda, surrounded with a two-tiered colonnade. Out of breath, COLUMBUS stops the exercise, and removes his protective canvas padding. He bows at his teacher, who salutes him in return. COLUMBUS walks to a tressel laden with food and beverages. SANCHEZ, in a fencing outfit and boots, is having a glass of wine. Upon seeing COLUMBUS approaching, he hands him a glass.</context>
      <utterance>Si! Si! Muy bien! Excellente!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You defend yourself admirably...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANCHEZ laughs and raises his glass.</context>
      <utterance>... for a commoner?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drink. A short, somewhat ugly man, with some kind of imposing energy, approach them.</context>
      <utterance>To your second expedition.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOBADILLA bows.</context>
      <utterance>Don Colon -- Don Alonso de Bobadilla. A man who knows our laws.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBADILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand that you will soon be appointing Governors for the islands? Is it not so?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, Don Bobadilla -- those positions have already been taken.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBADILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I ask by whom?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANCHEZ looks at him in surprise. BOBADILLA reddens.</context>
      <utterance>Bartolome and Giacomo Colon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBADILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOBADILLA glances at SANCHEZ.</context>
      <utterance>I trust they are men of quality.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we do have a lack of notaries. You should contact my administration.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don Bobadilla is already a judge, my Dear Don Cristobal.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A grin disfigures the face of BOBADILLA.</context>
      <utterance>Good! We are also in need of judges. Except there are no thieves!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBADILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see I was mistaken. Don Colon has no need for my services... And he walks off. SANCHEZ fills his mouth with a slice of ham.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem to have a special talent for making friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...? Do I have so many already?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To rise so high, in so short a time, is a dangerous occupation.  A little hypocrisy goes a long way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BARTOLOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might have given us a choice!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIACOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bartolome is stronger, more capable than I will ever be...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need both of you. What are you afraid of? We are living what we always dreamt of.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIACOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I never shared those dreams with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS looks at them with such pained surprise...</context>
      <utterance>Are you saying you refuse to help?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTOLOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bastard... you always had your own way...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door to a terrace.</context>
      <utterance>Let me show you something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fighting their way through, the BOTHERS press their way, reaching the other side of the gallery. We get glimpses of the incredible activity down below. ADMINISTRATORS, MILITARIES, MERCHANTS are busy around tressels covered with documents, plans, maps... preparing the second expedition. COLUMBUS puts his arms around them.</context>
      <utterance>Of course... Of course... We'll see to it... Yes... Thank you... Soon... Soon...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now -- you tell me. Who can I trust?  We're brothers! We must be a House. A bloodline! In this country one can't exist alone! I need you...! Both of you! He walks then to the balustrade. The cries from the courtyard down below subside... some of the applicants begin to look up, aware of his presence.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Where is the Admiral? Has anyone seen the Admiral?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over the balcony. In the middle of the overcrowded courtyard, the SOLDIER who was shouting is brandishing a document.</context>
      <utterance>He is here! What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Admiral! The horses have arrived.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ASSISTANT raises his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I saw them! Who did we hire today?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty blacksmiths, twenty eight halberdiers, twenty carpenters, a hundred farmers, twenty miners... and Doctor Chanca, the royal surgeon.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whole courtyard bursts out laughing.</context>
      <utterance>The royal surgeon? Then we can count on royal health!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEATRIX smiles, nods. They walk on.</context>
      <utterance>He's growing up!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beatrix, I want to ask you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't usually ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEATRIX stops in her tracks, looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>I can arrange for the Queen to take Fernando and Diego into her service.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEATRIX nods, but bites her lip, and looks back at</context>
      <utterance>It is a great honor. We could not hope for anything better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS looks around in dismay. A YOUNG NOBLEMAN, HERNANDO DE GUEVARA, takes out his sword.</context>
      <utterance>Is this your new world, Don Colon?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUEVARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Other SPANIARDS join in, repeating this last word.</context>
      <utterance>These animals should be shown what savagery can be!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOBLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No mercy before God!</context>
      <utterance>Three heads for every life taken.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUEVARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No mercy! Let's find them.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Everyone looks at COLUMBUS.</context>
      <utterance>No Guevara. There will be no revenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We lost cousins, friends. We will wash this in blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are all listening.</context>
      <utterance>If you want to keep your head on your shoulders, you'll do as I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks among them.</context>
      <utterance>Moxica, I lost friends too... Thirty nine brave men who trusted me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Who will you kill? Which tribe?</context>
      <utterance>You want a war? Fine. We are a thousand. They outnumber us by ten!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't need to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We came here to stay! To build! Not to start a crusade. In this forest, there is enough danger to sweep us away in days! So we will be brave and swallow our grief. And in the name of those who died, we will accomplish what we came for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly, they begin to appear, one after the other -- materializing from the jungle. Shy and scared. They stare at this "Centaur" (the HORSE and the HORSEMAN seem to be one -- a God). To impress them even more, MOXICA makes the beast move sideways and backwards, rearing, its front hoofs pawing the air. THE INDIANS retreat in terror, except for one, who stands his ground, brandishing his lance. UTAPAN encourages the YOUNG WARRIOR to approach the centaur. He places his hand onto the shoulder of the animal. The muscles shudder. THE INDIAN jumps back comically, accompanied by the rest of the tribe. Without warning, MOXICA climbs down from the saddle. More INDIANS step back in fear and absolute astonishment. Now more have ventured from the jungle. The bravest of them approach MOXICA, daring to touch him, and the horse, retreating then touching until they fill the compound. At this moment, COLUMBUS and his SOLDIERS appear all around them, pointing their muskets, and their crossbows. A moment of tension. COLUMBUS walks forward, towards the CHIEF (GUARIONEX) we meet before.</context>
      <utterance>They here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CHIEF answers.</context>
      <utterance>Ask the Chief what happened to my men?</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>came by sea... took them away...</context>
      <utterance>Another tribe made war on them...</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER BUYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God have mercy on their souls...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. The SPANIARDS shifting, eager for blood.</context>
      <utterance>The monkey is lying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UTAPAN looks anxiously at COLUMBUS.</context>
      <utterance>We should kill them, Don Colon.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UTAPAN translates. The CHIEF listens in silence.</context>
      <utterance>No...! you'll do it my way.  Tell the Chief we will not harm his people, even though we have the power to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will work with his people. We want peace. Ask the Chief if he understands?</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He understands.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask him if he will help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MOXICA looks down at the sodden, dirty figure.</context>
      <utterance>Don Moxica -- we need your horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't raise the wheel without it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. COLUMBUS wipes some mud from his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>My horse doesn't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don Moxica -- we all have to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to turn away; COLUMBUS grabs hold of the reins.</context>
      <utterance>You did not hear me, Don Colon. Not my horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. MOXICA stares down at an equally determined COLUMBUS. Then, in front of everyone, MOXICA has to dismount, and suffer the disgrace of it.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, Don Moxica. But it was your horse I was talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS leads the horse away.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Don Moxica.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. We see the smoke and flames from a fire. Four or five INDIANS are squatting on the earth nearby, cooking for them, talking quietly in their own language. MOXICA calls out something in their language, and a naked YOUNG INDIAN GIRL comes out of the house, bringing more wine. GUEVARA stares at her lasciviously. MOXICA, letting his hand casually brush against her flank, smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>To the Governor of the Mosquitoes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns the GIRL round so that GUEVARA can admire her properly. GUEVARA nods. MOXICA lets the GIRL go with a peremptory order, and she disappears back inside. GUEVARA suddenly stands up -- unsteadily -- and sweeping his arm round in a broad gesture, says ironically:</context>
      <utterance>Do you want her?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUEVARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the new world, my friend! To the new world!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GIACOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nima's a good cook!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTOLOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeing GIACOMO'S sudden blush and discomfort, as NIMA smiles at him, the other BROTHERS laugh. To cover his embarrassment, GIACOMO returns to the topic of the food.</context>
      <utterance>She's more than that!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIACOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he sees BARTOLOME stifling a laugh, GIACOMO pauses.</context>
      <utterance>Eat! I'll tell you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIACOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS eats a mouthful, glances at BARTOLOME.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to know what I'm eating.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look of horror crosses GIACOMO'S face; he wretches slightly, puts down his fork, and gulps down some wine. The BROTHERS laugh again.</context>
      <utterance>Iguana.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What wrong with it? The Indians eat it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIACOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not an Indian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTOLOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wishes he were back in the seminary. Priests always eat well.  And they have very good cellars.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIACOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing grows here! Everything rots in the ground. The wheat and vines wither before we can harvest them.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly this time, GIACOMO goes back to his dinner.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to learn to live like the Indians.  Eat your Iguana!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much gold have we found?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTOLOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not enough to justify a single shipment.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps it doesn't exist anywhere but in my imagination.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTOLOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin to hear the sound of a flute -- a melancholy sound. COLUMBUS looks out over the jungle, and kills a mosquito by slapping his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Then let's hope not...  What will happen if we can't find enough gold?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'm Governor of the Mosquitoes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BROTHER BUYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of disease is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR CHANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It seems almost as if we have exchanged diseases with the Indians. They die of our most common cold, and we of their plague.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER BUYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God forgive us!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems to be caused by intimacy with the native women, Your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will he survive?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ISABEL looks around at SANCHEZ, appalled.</context>
      <utterance>No, Your Majesty. They go mad -- then they die. There is nothing we can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every ship returns with a cargo of sick and dying. But with no gold! The new world proves expensive, Your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANCHEZ bows in acknowledgement. But ISABEL, despite her words, looks distressed.</context>
      <utterance>We weren't expecting immediate profits, were we? We must have faith. We must give time for time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSLATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says he has not found any!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again the INDIAN pleads and gesticulates. MOXICA hits him across the face with the thonged crop. The INDIAN tries to run away -- but is held by a SPANISH SOLDIER.</context>
      <utterance>He's lying!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The frightened INDIAN is brought back to the table. One of the CLERKS slips away.</context>
      <utterance>Bring him here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him to put his hands on the table. Like this!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The terrified TRANSLATOR speaks to the INDIANS.</context>
      <utterance>Tell them I want them to watch this!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't Moxica! You can't...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In one act of brutality, you have created chaos. Tribes who were fighting each other are now joining forces against us! All that because of your criminal savagery!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Savagery is what monkeys understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Have you anything to say?</context>
      <utterance>You'll be held in detention, deprived of your privileges and possessions. Until you are returned to Spain where you will be judged.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strolls to the GUARDS at the back of the room.</context>
      <utterance>You will regret this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BARTOLOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BARTOLOME turns to UTAPAN.</context>
      <utterance>Moxica is right. Our ways don't work!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTOLOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UTAPAN looks distraught -- this is the first time he is being asked to do something against his own people. He looks up at COLUMBUS for help in confusion.</context>
      <utterance>Can you find them?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to find them, Utapan. Look what they did!</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS is caught short.</context>
      <utterance>You did the same to your God!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UTAPAN nods. He walks and takes an arrow. He examines it.</context>
      <utterance>We have to stop this war.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UTAPAN nods, uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know them?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes another step backwards, as COLUMBUS moves towards him.</context>
      <utterance>You know what they will say in Spain about my death -- don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOXICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, and steps back into space.</context>
      <utterance>You are nothing! You bastards will never inherit your titles. We are everything. We are immortal!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BROTHER BUYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish to go back with them, Don Colon. I have no desire to remain in this godless place.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BROTHER BUYL looks at him, almost with astonishment.</context>
      <utterance>You may do as you please, Brother Buyl -- though your departure will not help me to make it more Godly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER BUYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You treat Christians equally with heathen savages. You execute members of the nobility. And what do you offer in return?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A new world, Brother Buyl.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER BUYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody wants one...! Only you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BROTHERS do not answer.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps hope only exists in the journey. When it begins, everything is still possible -- every expectation; every dream...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not how I imagined it to be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UTAPAN is still and silent. A strange and mysterious figure now.</context>
      <utterance>Utapan!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Utapan, won't you speak to me? You used to know how to speak to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTAPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UTAPAN is gone.</context>
      <utterance>You never learned how to speak my language.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... But there is worse. He ordered the execution of five members of the nobility...</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this true, Brother Buyl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER BUYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. ISABEL seems to struggle inwardly with her emotions. SANCHEZ waits, expressionless, but on the point of victory.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Your Majesty. It is all true. I saw it with my own eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, what do you suggest, Don Sanchez?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He must be replaced.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who would you think of, for such a task?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BOBADILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don Alonso de Bobadilla.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOBADILLA turns, gestures to one of the other MEN, who comes forward and gives him a roll of parchment, bearing the royal seal.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... I remember...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBADILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My letters of appointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Appointment to what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBADILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Viceroy of the West Indies.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOBADILLA smiles wickedly, happy to give COLUMBUS a low blow.</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations. Then I am free to search for the mainland.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBADILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you learn? The mainland was discovered. Weeks ago. By another Italian. I forgot his name.</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS pales. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Amerigo Vespucci, Excellency.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far from here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBADILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not a seaman. But I heard it is no more than a week at sea. I hope you are not too disappointed.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I be? The mainland has been found. Exactly as I said it would.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBADILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am afraid this is not the worst news.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unable to believe it, COLUMBUS slowly sits up.</context>
      <utterance>Father?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fernando...! My God...! He laughs, overcome with joy. Embraces DIEGO.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man! Diego, how did this happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are going to get you out of here.</context>
      <utterance>Santangel is going to see the Queen.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DIEGO and FERNANDO look at one another, then back at COLUMBUS, incredulously, seeing his filthy clothes, his eyes rimmed with dried mucus.</context>
      <utterance>Good! I have to go back!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a new excitement in COLUMBUS' voice. He walks over to the table. The candlelight illuminates maps, charts, drawings, figures...</context>
      <utterance>Go back?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to explore the mainland.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS laughs and DIEGO looks at them both in astonishment.</context>
      <utterance>This time with me!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO glances at DIEGO.</context>
      <utterance>In your present state it is madness, Father!</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DIEGO is hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody is forcing you to come with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>I can't go anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DIEGO seems saddened by his brother's attitude. Once again DIEGO feels like the outsider. COLUMBUS hugs him.</context>
      <utterance>She's very beautiful! The Queen has very good taste. Diego is getting married.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am happy for you, Diego.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SANTANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ISABEL looks at him, then at SANCHEZ, MOVED BUT CLEARLY UNDECIDED. SANTANGEL presses his point.</context>
      <utterance>Granted his faults. Yes, a hundred times! But the man is still remarkable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All he asks is a chance to explore this... mainland.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It does not belong to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a way, it does, Don Sanchez.  I beg Your Majesty to receive him. To hear him... He will make no more demands. He has changed. He is penitent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Penitent...? He is suing us for breach of contract!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANTANGEL tries to stop himself laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS gets slowly to his feet -- but his eyes, as they meet hers, are as clear as before. ISABEL smiles with relief to see it. He looks back at her.</context>
      <utterance>Rise... Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles -- then again, tries to restrain it, and keeps her dignity.</context>
      <utterance>Now I do look older than you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS starts to interrupt; she stops him with a gesture.</context>
      <utterance>We have decided to allow you to undertake another voyage to the new world...</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But without your brothers. Nor are you to return to Santo Domingo or any of the other colonies. You may explore the continent.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is one thing I'd like to understand... Why do you want to go back, after all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She almost bursts out laughing -- only pauses, turns slightly, then goes out.</context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty -- some men are content to read about things. I must see them with my own eyes. I cannot be other than I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I should not tolerate his impertinence.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he is not afraid of me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I have to do is call the guards.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANCHEZ looks at him -- and doesn't call. COLUMBUS lets go of him.</context>
      <utterance>Call them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not afraid of you. You are nothing but a dreamer.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Surprised, SANCHEZ nevertheless turns, looks out.</context>
      <utterance>Look out of that window.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>spires...</context>
      <utterance>Roofs... towers, palaces...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANCHEZ turns round again to face him.</context>
      <utterance>All of them created by people like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS turns abruptly and walks away, vanishing down the echoing corridor.</context>
      <utterance>No matter how long you live, Sanchez, there's something that will never change between us. I did it! You didn't!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God... you're so beautiful! I can't believe no other man has ever taken you away from me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. They don't dare to touch. BEATRIX looks round the empty room.</context>
      <utterance>They tried... but I didn't let them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They took everything...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. There's a pause.</context>
      <utterance>Not everything... Do you think I care? I'm a free man again. Riches don't make a man rich, they only make him busier...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they throw themselves into each other's arms.</context>
      <utterance>God, how much I've missed you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SANTANGEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They laugh. With only a little embarrassment, BEATRIX gets off COLUMBUS' knee. SANTANGEL comes forward, and COLUMBUS embraces him like an old friend. BEATRIX goes to the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>One chair. One table. What more can a man expect, when he tries to sue the Crown?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>but as you see, I can't repay you.</context>
      <utterance>I owe you everything, Santangel...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS smiles. BEATRIX returns with a plate and glass for SANTANGEL.</context>
      <utterance>On the contrary. It is I who owe you everything. Through you, I have been an adventurer, an explorer! It's true I shall never see the new world... but it's here...  And here...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the wine BEATRIX offers, and raises his glass.</context>
      <utterance>What you are, Colon, is a sailor, a discoverer, a man of imagination... not a politician. You weren't meant to govern -- You cannot be all things to all men.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you could have compromised. It would have made your life easier...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh, and drink.</context>
      <utterance>But as least we haven't been bored, have we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SAILOR'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>West... southwest, Captain Mendez...</utterance>
   <speaker>MENDEZ</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS walks over to FERNANDO, who is leaning against the rail. He is smoking a cigar... as the smoke blows over FERNANDO'S face, FERNANDO wretches... It's clear he's feeling seasick, trying to control it. COLUMBUS leans against the rail next to him, staring out at the darkness. Then looks at his SON again. FERNANDO won't give in to the sickness, but COLUMBUS knows he'd feel better if he did.</context>
      <utterance>Steady as she goes...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you feeling, Fernando?</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS nods meditatively, puffs out some smoke. FERNANDO winces, gags slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Not bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>You know what I always used to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the thought of the pork fat, FERNANDO jerks his head over the side, and vomits copiously. COLUMBUS smiles, pats him on the back.</context>
      <utterance>Swallow a piece of pork fat on a string. It always worked.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>SAILORS and FERNANDO rush to the side of the ship, peering through the spray. FERNANDO wipes his eyes, and then he sees it: there in the distance, a speck of land. FERNANDO and his FATHER stand together, watching the low cloud formation sitting on the horizon.</context>
      <utterance>Tierra...! Tierra!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO looks excited. Discreetly, COLUMBUS watches his SON, enjoying his happiness.</context>
      <utterance>The mainland...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MENDEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's drawing an isthmus... He's saying we're on an isthmus.</utterance>
   <speaker>MENDEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO is still confused. The OLD INDIAN continues to sketch, talking quietly all the time. An INDIAN TRANSLATOR listens.</context>
      <utterance>We can't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me what he's saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSLATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says -- water on the other side.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TRANSLATOR asks. The OLD INDIAN shakes his head, laughs, points to the west, way beyond the other lakes, emphatically.</context>
      <utterance>Ask him if he means a lake. A big lake.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSLATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Above and below, much land.</context>
      <utterance>No. Says those are lakes. Water on other side big -- as wide as here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An ocean...? He's says it's an ocean?</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS is too stunned for a moment to explain. The INDIANS laugh. Then COLUMBUS takes the charcoal, and begins to draw on the map, for his son.</context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO stares west, then back at his FATHER. COLUMBUS looks very feverish, his face bathed with sweat.</context>
      <utterance>Here is Europe... and over here, the continent of Asia. But there's something in between! Another continent! We've found... another continent!</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There must be a passage to that other ocean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The remains of human beings.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at the remains, stunned. THE SOLDIER stops chewing. He drops the half-empty bowl he was still holding. He runs at the back door, rams his fingers deep in the back of his throat, and vomits.</context>
      <utterance>What is...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A HEADLESS HUMAN TRUNK spread open, like a sheep carcass. Disturbed flies rise in clouds.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Virgen Maria... Oh Madre de Dios...  But as he vomits and cries, he notices:</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Jesus, Mary, and all the Saints...)</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Maria, y todos los Santos...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, with sudden anger.</context>
      <utterance>I... I have to see Mendez.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks a few steps, lurches, and has to lean against the rail. He raises his hand to his eyes, grimacing in pain, as if they were burning. FERNANDO scrambles to his feet and rushes to him. COLUMBUS' eyes are already fixed somewhere -- fever is eating him up.</context>
      <utterance>Your brother was right. I should have never taken you with me. I'll never forgive myself. Never!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO turns around for help.</context>
      <utterance>Will you ever forgive me?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Mendez!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>continent is now well-established... We see a large amphitheater, filled with PEOPLE attending a lecture of "Nova Geographica" -- the new geography. AROJAZ stands in front of the assembly. Facing him, enthroned, is KING FERDINAND, surrounded by COURTIERS, including SANCHEZ. We slowly move across the arena, passing attentive faces.</context>
      <utterance>The sunset route to the new</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We continue to rise up the tiers of seats...</context>
      <utterance>... West by south west for 750 leagues to Santo Domingo. From there, west north west, leaving San Juan to the north, reaching the island of Hispanola on the northern cape of San Raphael... Then onto the mainland, at the Cape called Gracias a Dios...</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On a highest tier, we stop on the face of CHRISTOPHER COLUMBUS, listening impassively.</context>
      <utterance>Spain -- by Your Majesty's grace -- has confirmed for all humanity the existence of an unknown continent... Tierra Incognita...</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON COLUMBUS' eyes.</context>
      <utterance>... This continent was first discovered by a sailor commissioned by your Majesty...</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On COLUMBUS.</context>
      <utterance>His name... Amerigo Vespucci...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass close enough to touch COLUMBUS. But he does not see them.</context>
      <utterance>My God...! I thought he was dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can see for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>AROJAZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a tragedy... what a waste of a life...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AROJAZ looks at SANCHEZ in surprise -- then cranes his neck round, and looks back at COLUMBUS -- now a FACE IN</context>
      <utterance>A waste...? Let me tell you something, Arojaz. If your name, or mine, is ever remembered -- it will only be because of his.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose we're both old men now.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. COLUMBUS sits down. Bees drone lazily in the sunlight.</context>
      <utterance>You'll always be older than me, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCHENA nods his head.</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever forgiven me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCHENA looks at his plants, sighs contentedly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I forgave you a long time ago. You see, I was proud of you. You were like a willful child. You wouldn't accept what others told you. You had to find things out for yourself, hurting yourself -- and others -- in the process.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS nods.</context>
      <utterance>Do you remember when you said that people talk about the world, but never leave their gardens.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses, looks across at COLUMBUS, smiles again gently. MARCHENA, tiring, leans back in his chair, and looks up towards the sun.</context>
      <utterance>More than ever I wonder what it is we do achieve by leaving our gardens... The world changes -- and yet it seems the same. We find new worlds, but fill them with the same people...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to disagree.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you would.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New worlds create new people.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? So you are a new man?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCHENA starts laughing.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I have the impression that I didn't change that much. I still can't accept the world as it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both laugh.</context>
      <utterance>God bless you, and those like you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you stay with us a little?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles. She looks at him smiling, intrigued.</context>
      <utterance>I am busy inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, now? Tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO looks up at them above his letters, amused and slightly embarrassed. COLUMBUS looks at him with a fake air of reproach.</context>
      <utterance>I can't keep my eyes off you. I would like to catch up with all the moments I didn't spend with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you listening to?</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not listening, Father. But I can't help hearing. FERNANDO opens a letter and reads it quickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS smiles and nods -- all this seems to be of very little importance to him now.</context>
      <utterance>It's Diego... He is at the Court, with Santangel... He says they hope to get your privileges restored... And maybe the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO continues to read.</context>
      <utterance>But how is he? And Dona Maria?</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens one of them, glances at it.</context>
      <utterance>Fine, it seems. Diego is thinking of starting a pearl trade, in Santo Domingo... He says he received many letters for you. Some of your men, mostly.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS' eyes brighten with joy.</context>
      <utterance>This one is from Mendez!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He asks when he can come to visit you. He left his address.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FERNANDO laughs -- then, suddenly serious.</context>
      <utterance>He never had one... except aboard my ships!</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to tell me everything you remember, Father. From the beginning. Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?  God... I wouldn't know where to start... and yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLUMBUS sighs, and leans back on his chair. His eyes are fixed somewhere, searching. Then, almost in a murmur.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me the first thing that comes to your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLUMBUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the page. FERNANDO writes: ... I REMEMBER... A drop of ink falls from the quill onto the page and the words. FERNANDO is waiting.</context>
      <utterance>I remember...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
