<movie id="11" title="Adaptation">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RUSSELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laroche is asleep at the wheel.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crazy White Man is now Drowsy White Man. They share a stoned laugh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing still. Tony clears his throat into the radio.</context>
      <utterance>We got a Seminole, or Seminoles, in the swamp. I'm on Janes Scenic Drive just east of Logging Road Twelve. I repeat, Indians in the swamp. Tony waits for a response. Nothing. TONY  Indians in the swamp.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you want me to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response. Tony glowers, gets out of the truck, watches the vehicles through binoculars. Nothing. He straightens his cap. Mosquitoes land on his neck, his nose, his lips.</context>
      <utterance>Barry, Indians do not go on swamp walks. If there are Indians in the swamp, they are in there for a reason.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm old. I'm bald. I'm repulsive.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think you're just great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerie absently rubs her nose. Kaufman self-consciously rubs his nose in response.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerie rubs her nose again. Kaufman pulls at his nostril. A rivulet of sweat slides down his forehead. Valerie watches it. Kaufman sees her watching it. She sees him seeing her watching it. She looks at her salad. He quickly swabs.</context>
      <utterance>And we're thrilled you're interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thanks, wow. That's nice to hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a really unique voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thanks. That's... I appreciate that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very talented. Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Thank you. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman's brow is dripping again. He smiles, embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>So --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort of hot in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First, I think it's a great book.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman nods, flips through the book, stalling. There's a smiling author photo of Susan Orlean on the inside back cover.</context>
      <utterance>Laroche is a fun character, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Orlean makes orchids so fascinating. Plus her musings on Florida, orchid poaching. Indians. Great, sprawling New Yorker stuff. I'd want to remain true to that, let the movie exist rather than be artificially plot driven.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, great, great. I guess I'm not exactly sure what that means.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well... I'm not sure exactly yet either. So... y'know, it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Okay. Great. So, um, what --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just, I don't want to compromise by making it a Hollywood product. An orchid heist movie. Or changing the orchids into poppies and turning it into a movie about drug running. Y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, of course. We agree. Definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman is sweating like crazy now. Valerie is quiet for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Or cramming in sex, or car chases, or guns. Or characters learning profound life lessons. Or characters growing or characters changing or characters learning to like each other or characters overcoming obstacles to succeed in the end. Y'know? Movie shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, we thought maybe Susan Orlean and Laroche could fall in love during the course of --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So anyway I just wanted to stop by to congratulate you on your promotion.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thanks again. It's all so stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's great. Your photo in the trades and everything. Pretty cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway. Yeah. So what's up with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm considering jobs. Mostly crap. There's one you might like, about flowers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flowers? Really? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want me to do an adaptation of a book called The Orchid Thief.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman is thrilled; he's scored. Margaret pulls a copy of The Orchid Thief from her bookshelf. MARGARET (cont'd) See, see, see! I'm not lying to you!</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! You're kidding? I read that! I loved that book!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I loved the book.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Charlie, orchids are the most amazing flowers. So complex. Margaret plops onto the couch next to Kaufman.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. They're really great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should take this job. Doesn't it sound exciting, to immerse yourself in a real subject and learn everything about it? Blake wrote about seeing heaven in a wild flower. And after you learn all this stuff, you can teach me!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'd be fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, they're such beautiful flowers. And so sexy. Y'know?  Did you know that orchid means --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Testicle. I just read that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Indians ignore him. They trudge. Laroche spots something else, a dull green root wrapped around a tree. He stops, circles the tree. His eyes widen in reverent awe. LAROCHE (cont'd) Polyrrhiza Lindenii. A ghost. The Indians come around. Laroche stares at a single beautiful, glowing white flower hanging from the tree. He tenderly caresses the petals. Then, business-like: LAROCHE (cont'd) Cut it down, Russell. Russell pulls out a hacksaw, begins sawing through the tree.</context>
      <utterance>Pseudemys floridana. Did you fellas know you fellas believe the world rests on the back of a turtle? Not you fellas specifically. Although, maybe you fellas specifically. That I can't speak to.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...plus I love the idea of learning all about orchids. I really admire those guys who know everything about ants or fungus or whatever. I'd like to be more like that. See, I tend to write self- involved, self-loathing... even masturbatory stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's wonderful, by the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. That's nice to hear. But I need to challenge myself as a writer. I've arrived at an age where I want to think about the world in a different way.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adapting someone else's work is certainly an opportunity to think differently.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods sweetly. The boy returns to his search. He stops at a small turtle in an aquarium. BOY (cont'd) I want this then.</context>
      <utterance>Any one at all, ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A wonderful choice! And spiritually significant! Did you know that Native Americans believe the whole world rests on the back of a turtle?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool! I can't wait to tell the guys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman, pleased, clicks glasses. He takes a breath.</context>
      <utterance>To a fucking awesome assignment, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm going to an orchid show Sunday? For research? Maybe you'll come?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. I think David, this guy I'm seeing, would enjoy it, too. He's a real naturalist. Okay if he comes along?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, of course. Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to meet you anyway. All I do is tell him how great you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thanks. That's nice to hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll like him. He's so honest and smart. It's rare to find someone in this town who thinks about things other than this fucking business, y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That's great. He sounds great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like the other day we were in bed discussing Hegel. Hegel! In bed! It was fucking amazing. Have you read much?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, a long time ago. A bit. Y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman begins the laborious task of getting through his plate of food. He can no longer look up at Margaret.</context>
      <utterance>Well, anyway, David and I were discussing his Philosophy of History and I was... The entrees arrive. MARGARET  ... struck by his notion that history is a human construct...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... that nature doesn't exist historically, but rather cyclically.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that Injun round-up going, Tony?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rustling near the parked cars. Tony tenses. Laroche steps from the swamp with the Indians, who haul the pillowcases. TONY (cont'd) We got poachers. (into the radio, pleased) We got fuckin' poachers, Barry. Ha! Tony jumps into the truck and turns it around.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, Barry, you fuckin'...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SUBTITLE: RIO HACHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man lies face down near an unplucked orchid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Endres was shot dead in Rio Hacha.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning. May I ask what you gentlemen have in those pillowcases?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir, you absolutely may.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm asking then.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Okay then! Let's see...  Five kinds of bromeliad, one peperomia, nine orchid varieties. About a hundred and thirty plants all told, which my colleagues have removed from the swamp.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're aware that it's illegal to remove plants or animals from state owned land?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And don't forget these plants are all endangered, sir. Every one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Well, that's exactly the issue. This is a state preserve.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh, and my colleagues are all Seminole Indians. Did I mention that? You're familiar, I'm sure, with the State of Florida v. James E. Billie. Tony nods, even though he has no idea. LAROCHE (cont'd) So you know that even though Seminole Chief Billie killed a Florida panther, one of, what, forty in the entire world? Laroche looks to the Indians for confirmation. They give it. LAROCHE (cont'd) The state couldn't successfully prosecute him. Because he's an Indian and it's his right. As repugnant as you or I as white conservationists might find his actions.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir, it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche again looks to the Indians for confirmation.</context>
      <utterance>Not to mention the failed attempts on three separate occasions to prosecute Seminoles for poaching palm fronds, which, I believe, they use to thatch the roofs of their traditional chickee huts.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSSELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony looks at the Indians.</context>
      <utterance>He's right. That's exactly what we use them for. Chickee huts.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSSELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I don't... I can't let you fellas go yet. Just hold on while I...  Hey, Barry, can I get some help? Barry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>At the landing Kaufman comes upon Donald, his identical twin brother, on his back in pajama bottoms, opening a gift box.</context>
      <utterance>I am fat. I am repulsive. I cannot bear my own reflection.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you open your present from mom yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman nods vaguely, continues down the hall. Donald pulls a purple sweater from the box, calls after Kaufman. DONALD (cont'd) Hey, Charles, you'll be glad, I have a plan to get me out of your house pronto.</context>
      <utterance>My back.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A job is a plan. Is your plan a job?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna be a screenwriter! Like you! Kaufman doesn't respond, enters his bedroom. DONALD  I know you think this is just one of my get-rich-quick schemes. But I'm doing it right this time. I'm taking a seminar!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only five hundred bucks!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In theory I agree with you. But this one is highly regarded within the industry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald, now in the sweater, appears on all fours in the doorway. Kaufman puts the paper back under his pillow.</context>
      <utterance>Donald, don't say "industry."</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I forgot. Charles, this guy knows screenwriting. People from all over come to study his method. I'll pay you back, man. As soon as I sell --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me explain something to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody who says he's got "the answer" is going to attract desperate people. Be it in the world of religion --</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just need to lie down while you explain this to me. Sorry. I apologize.  Okay, go ahead. Sorry. Okay. Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no rules to follow, Donald, and anybody who says there are, is just --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not rules, principles. McKee writes: "A rule says, you must do it this way. A principle says, this works... and has through all remembered time."</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The script I'm starting, it's about flowers. No one's ever done a movie about flowers before. So, there're no guidelines, and that's good because --</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Flowers for Algernon?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not about flowers. And it's not a movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay, I never saw it. Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald stares at the ceiling, fuming. Kaufman waits. Getting no no response, he pulls out his Hegel book and reads:</context>
      <utterance>My point is, those teachers are dangerous if your goal is to do something new. And a writer should always have that goal. Writing is a journey into the unknown. It's not building a model airplane.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Kaufman's head is spinning. He puts the book down. Both brothers stare at the ceiling. Donald finally speaks</context>
      <utterance>Each being is, because posited, an op- posited, a conditional and conditioning, the Understanding completes these its limitations by positing the opposite...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McKee is a former Fulbright scholar. Are you a former Fulbright scholar, Charles?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turtles are of the order Testudine!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Testudine?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And they're found on every continent! Except Antarptica!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Antarctica. Every continent, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. The turtle shell has remained unchanged for two hundred million years! And there's all different kinds, Pelusio gabonensis, Phyrnops rufipes, Chitra indica, Dermochelys coriacea coriacea...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and what we have here, my friend, is ... thirteen Encyclia Cochleata... four Encyclia Tampensis --</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Encyclia what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coch-le-ata. Tem-pen-sis.  Okay, let's see, twenty-two Epidendrum Nocturnum. A very good haul. Two Catopsi Floribunda. Three Polyrrhiza Lindenii, the ghost orchid. What I really came for. These sweeties grow nowhere in the U.S. except in your swamp.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That true? Boy, you really know your plants, Mr. Laroche.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Kaufman, bored, looks over at Donald, whose cheeks are stuffed with food.</context>
      <utterance>The Orchidaceae is a large, ancient family of perennial plants with...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The most memorable, fascinating characters tend to have not only a conscious but an unconscious desire. Although these characters are unaware of their subconscious need...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should watch what you eat, Donald. Did you ever consider maybe you're a bit fat? Does it ever occur to you, you kind of represent me in the world? That people look at you and think, he's Charlie's twin, therefore that's what Charlie must look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the way, mom's paying for the seminar.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you even hear what I said?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Anyway. I pitched mom my screenplay --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, don't say "pitch."</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Anyway, she loved my... telling of my story to her. She said it's like "Silence of the Lambs" meets "Psycho."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, maybe you and mom could collaborate. I hear she's really good with structure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two glare at each other. They go back to their books.</context>
      <utterance>You think you're so superior, Charles. Well, I'm really gonna write this. And you'll see. And, and... you suck, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Florida is a landscape of transition...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do not proliferate characters; do not multiply locations. Rather than hopscotching through time, space, and people, discipline yourself to a reasonably contained cast and world...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally, Mr. Laroche, what is your experience in the area of horticulture?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I've been a professional horticulturist for twelve years. I've owned a plant nursery of my own which was destroyed by the hurricane. I'm a professional plant lecturer. I've given at least sixty lectures on the cultivation of plants. I'm a published author, both in magazine and book form. I have extensive experience with orchids, and the asexual micropropagation of orchids under aseptic cultures. This is laboratory work, not at all like your nursery work.  I'm probably the smartest person I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're very welcome.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens. Donald stands there for a moment in shadows.</context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you wanna hear my pitch, or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away. God damn it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman squints at his brother, sits up, waits.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know, I'm just trying to do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Kaufman groans, lies down, pulls the covers over his face.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, thanks a lot, man. Cool.  Okay, there's this serial killer, right --</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, wait. See, he's being hunted by a cop. And he's taunting the cop, right? Sending clues who his next victim is. He's already holding her hostage in his creepy basement. So the cop gets obsessed with figuring out her identity, and in the process he falls in love with her. Even though he's never even met her. She becomes, like, the unattainable, like the Holy Grail.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a little obvious, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald waits, proud. Kaufman pulls off the covers.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, but there's a twist. See, we find out the killer suffers from multiple personality disorder. Okay? See, he's really also the cop and the girl. All of them. It's all him! Isn't that crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, the only idea more overused than serial killers, is multiple personality. On top of that you explore the notion that cop and criminal are really two aspects of the same person. See every cop movie ever made for other examples of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom called it psychologically taut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other thing is, there's no way to write this. Did you consider that? I mean, how exactly would you show a character holding himself hostage?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trick photography?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald waits blankly. Kaufman gives up, gets out of bed, dresses. KAUFMAN (cont'd) I agree with mom. Very taut. Sybil meets.. I dunno, something very taut. Kaufman exits.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, that's not what I'm asking. What I'm asking is in the reality of this movie, if there's only one character, right?... Okay? How could you... What exactly would the scene... How...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna fucking crucify me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAXLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go into the Fakahatchee with a chainsaw. I swear to God.</utterance>
   <speaker>LERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buster waves a dismissive hand at Lerner, walks away. Vinson shrugs, stubs his cigarette, follows Buster. Lerner and Laroche stand there a moment. Lerner walks off. Laroche cracks his neck. A charmingly shy Orlean approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Buster, for crying out loud, I reminded her the Indians used to own Fakahatchee. Look, we'll deal with all this at trial.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean smiles, apologetic for the intrusion.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Laroche?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm familiar with the New Yorker. The New Yorker, yes, the New Yorker. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche scowls, smokes furiously, then, a test:</context>
      <utterance>Right. So I was interested in doing a piece about your situation down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean scribbles on her pad. Laroche twists his head to see that she's writing "Judge can screw herself." LAROCHE (cont'd) That for real would go in? Orlean nods. Laroche smiles his toothless smile at Orlean.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Put this in: I don't care what goes on here. I'm right, and I'll take this all the way to the Supreme Court. That judge can screw herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENSUOUS FEMALE NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Orchidaceae is a large, ancient family of perennial plants with one fertile stamen and a three petalled flower. In most orchid species, one petal is enlarged into a lip and is the most conspicuous part of the flower.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what looks good today?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um. Hi. Thank you. The key lime pie, please. A small slice. I'm watching my... And a coffee, please. Skim milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes blank.</context>
      <utterance>Orchids! I absolutely love orchids.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flinches at his response. A small awkward pause.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. They're really great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles warmly again and leaves. Kaufman is humiliated.</context>
      <utterance>So, I'll be right back with your pie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few days after the hearing, Laroche took me to an orchid show in Miami. She opens the passenger door. ORLEAN  Hi. Thanks for picking --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean nods, climbs in, and tries to rearrage some of the junk on the front seat so she'll have a place to sit. LAROCHE (cont'd) Sit on top of that. You won't hurt it. She situates herself on the seat. Laroche lurches off.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to know this van is a piece of shit. When I hit the jackpot, I'll buy myself an awesome car, maybe an Aurora.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The thing you gotta know is my whole life is looking for a goddamn profitable plant. And that's the ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the ghost orchid?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her and smiles. Orlean smiles back and indicates, with a small jerk of the head, that he might want to watch the road. He doesn't take the hint. LAROCHE (cont'd) The plan was, get the Indians to pull it from the swamp. I researched it. As long as I don't touch the plants, Florida can't touch us. Then I'd clone hundreds of them babies in my lab, sell 'em, and make the Seminoles a shitload of change.</context>
      <utterance>The sucker's rare. Collectors covet what is not available. I'm the only one in the world who knows how to cultivate it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want, Donald?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I just read about that Swamp Ape that supposedly lives in the swamp? Like bigfoot? You should put that in your script, like, killing people or something. That'd be very, very cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you in here now?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman stares at Donald, rubs his eyes, then:</context>
      <utterance>Nothing, I was just... Oh, one thing, I need a cool way to kill people. Don't worry! For my script! Ha ha!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, okay, killer's a literature professor who cuts off little chunks of his victims' bodies until they die. He'd be known in the tabloids as "The Deconstructionist."</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's kinda good. I like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I was kidding, Donald.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you mind if I use it, though?</context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay. Sorry. You got me! Heh-heh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy surveys the sad scene. His mother looks up, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>For certain is death for the born/And certain is birth for the dead/Therefore over the inevitable/Thou shouldst not grieve. Sweet, sweet Diane.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The boy beams with pride, then gets solemn.</context>
      <utterance>A slice of pie for my turtle expert?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, there's something I feel I have to do. I don't know how to do this, but I feel in my stomach that I have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you have to do, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Collect one of every turtle in the world.  It's a long list, ma. Cuora galbinifrons, Graptemys versa, Callagur borneoensis, all the Galapagos species, people think there's only one, but that's hardly the case. Cycloderma frenatum, Cuora pani...  I don't think my life is worth living if I can't do this. The boy and his mother look at each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we'd better get started, huh, baby? The boy nods his head solemnly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, that's some story. So how many turtles did you end up collecting?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I lost interest right after that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drive in silence. Orlean watches a flying heron.</context>
      <utterance>I dropped turtles when I fell in love with Ice Age fossils. Learned everything about them. Collected the shit out of 'em. Fossils were the only thing made any sense to me in this fucking world. Y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then fossils were over when I found lapidary, which I just adored.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now what is lap --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche fishes through junk as he drives.</context>
      <utterance>Ditched lapidary for resilvering old mirrors. Did that with my mom for a while. We had the largest collection of 19th Century Dutch mirrors on the planet. Perhaps you read about us. Mirror World October '88? I have a copy somewhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, did you ever miss the turtles? The only thing that made you ten year old life worth living?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you a story. I once fell deeply, profoundly in love with tropical fish. I had sixty goddamn fish tanks in my house. I'd skin-dive to find just the right ones. Anisotremus virginicus, Holacanthus ciliaris, Chaetodon capistratus. You name it. Then one day I say, fuck fish. I renounce fish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CONTINUED:</speaker>
      <mode>2</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>LAROCHE  I vow to never set foot in the ocean again, that's how much fuck fish. That was seventeen years ago and I have never since stuck so much as a toe into that ocean. And I love the ocean!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Done with fish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still obsessed with that girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Burger King girl? Dimples and sparkly eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>California Pizza Kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Red hair and nice? Likes orchids?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. She's really nice. I feel pretty certain she likes me maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do you think you'll talk to this one?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Some key lime pie for ya today?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, yeah! That sounds great! Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She winks at him. He's so in love.</context>
      <utterance>I'll pick you out an extra large piece. Preferred customer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. That's really sweet of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still reading about orchids, I hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am, in fact! Beautiful flowers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend of mine has a pretty little pink one, grows right on a tree branch.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what's called an epiphyte.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right! Boy, you know your stuff, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. I'm just learning. Epiphytes grow on trees, but they're not parasites. They get all their nourishment from the air and rain.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Awkward pause.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm impressed. That's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are more than thirty thousand kinds of orchids in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He beams. She smiles and turns to leave. Kaufman blurts:</context>
      <utterance>Wow, that's a lot, huh? Okay, then, so I'll be right back with a nice big slice of key lime pie for my orchid expert.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alice's smile slips away. Her warmth dissipates.</context>
      <utterance>But, so, anyway, I was also wondering... Alice turns back, still smiling. KAUFMAN  I'm going up to this orchid show on Saturday in Santa Barbara and I --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, um, well --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I apologize. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The other waitress brings his pie. He smiles a thank you.</context>
      <utterance>I am fat. I am old. I am repulsive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are more than thirty thousand known orchid species. One species looks like a German shepherd...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TEENAGED LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche sets up the tripod, focuses on the flower. His mother almost cries at the flower's beauty.</context>
      <utterance>Encyclia tempensis. The butterfly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"You will find something more in woods than in books. Trees and stones will teach you that which you can never learn from masters." Saint Bernard said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGED LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's pretty, ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Diane would've loved this flower, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGED LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe somehow she can see it. Y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... after this one how many, honey?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TEENAGED LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one hundred and seventeen more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you have to have a photo of every single type of orchid in Florida?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGED LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at him, rubs his neck.</context>
      <utterance>I have to, ma. You know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman glances down at his therapist's breasts. He does it fast and unintentionally. He quickly shifts back to her face. His therapist wraps her shawl around her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm successful, right? I mean, I could say to a woman, I'm a screenwriter and she'd look at me differently. I could get laid. But I want someone to like me. For me. Y'know? The way I like them. The way I'd do anything for that woman walking down the street. A million women walking down the street. I don't need to know what their jobs are. No one will ever love me like that. Like I love almost every woman I see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once you get the sickness, it takes over your life. I started out just photographing 'em. Now look at me.  It'll happen to you. You'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. I'm not prone to -- Laroche runs over to a flower.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angraecum sesquipedale! Beauty! God! Darwin wrote about this one. Charles Darwin? Evolution guy? Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who Darwin is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what proboscis means.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every one of these flowers has a specific relationship with the insect that pollinates it. There's an orchid that looks exactly like this particular insect. So the bug humps the flower and gets covered with its pollen. Thusly... Laroche mimes humping.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean looks around: people sniffing flowers, feeling petals, staring deep into nectaries. People jabber passionately, people buy plants, people carry boxes of purchased plants. Orlean looks deeply into various flowers, at a dizzying array of colors and shapes, but remains detached.</context>
      <utterance>That's called pseudo-copulation. These flowers are smart! You gotta fall in love with them. Once you learn anything about orchids, you'll devote your life to learning everything about them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He reads back what he's written.</context>
      <utterance>... then, after the entire history of life on the planet, in the last seconds of the montage, we see the whole of human history: tool-making, hunting, farming, war, lust, religion, self-consciousness. Yearning. Then, bam! cut to Susan Orlean writing a book about orchids. And the story begins. It's perfect! It's circular! It's everything!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The front door bursts open and Donald charges in.</context>
      <utterance>I'm an idiot. I'm fat. I hate my--</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McKee is a genius! And hilarious! He just comes up with these great jokes, and everyone laughs! But he's serious, too. You'd love him. He's all for originality, just like you! But he says, we have to realize we all write in a genre, so we must find originality within that genre. See, it turns out there hasn't been a new genre since Fellini invented the mockumentary!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and I share the same DNA. Is there anything more lonely than that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to do something tonight?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He loses his footing, falls two storeys, lands on his back.</context>
      <utterance>Asclepiadaceae. From thirty yards. Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche scarfs his pie. Orlean watches him.</context>
      <utterance>... I broke my back. Exactly how my dad did. Isn't that a psycho coincidence?  Y'know, the way I see it, we're a family of ailments and pain.  But, anyway, it was a godsend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laroche once spilled toxic pesticide into a cut on his hand. It resulted in permanent heart and liver damage. Most people would consider this a terrible accident. Laroche considered it a success...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CUSTOMER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, what is this? It's so beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Customer 2 enters with a creepy, dark flowered orchid.</context>
      <utterance>Catasetum tenebrosum. From Peru. It's neat 'cause its dimorphic, which means...</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Other customers gather around.</context>
      <utterance>Henry! Look at that Dracula vampira! It's gorgeous, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take me in to the Fakahatchee. Show me a ghost in bloom, and it's yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche picks up a ringing phone. Customer 3 continues to try and get his attention while he talks.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Laroche, would you be able to --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bromeliad Tree. Hey, Dora! Good, good. Well, sure, you gotta watch the temperature. Don't want an odontoglossum above seventy-five. Uh-huh, that should be fine. Yeah, damp it down. Oh, I'm doing well. She's fine, too. Sure...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't know why I thought I could --</context>
      <utterance>I don't know how to adapt this. I should've just stuck with my own stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry waves at a passing beauty. She waves back, keeps walking. Kaufman follows the girl's ass with his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>See her? I fucked her up the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman looks at Jerry. Will he accept help from an agent?</context>
      <utterance>Just kidding. Hey, maybe I can help. What's the problem, buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about flowers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman pulls out a folded newspaper clipping, reads:</context>
      <utterance>It's not only about flowers. It's got that crazy plant nut guy. He's funny, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(looking up defiantly)</context>
      <utterance>"There is not nearly enough of him to fill a book," blah blah blah, so Orlean "digresses in long passes" blah blah blah "no narrative really unites these passages." Blah blah blah blah blah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man. I'd fuck her up the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no story. The book has no story.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So make one up. The book's a jumping off point. No one in town can make up a crazy story like you. You're the king.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to do that this time. It's someone else's material. I have a responsibility... Anyway, I wanted to grow as a writer, do something profound and simple. Show people how amazing flowers are.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they amazing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I think they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, what I tell a lot of guys is pick another film and use it as a model. I always thought this one could be like Apocalypse Now. The journalist spends the whole movie searching for the crazy plant nut guy -- what's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John Laroche.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has to travel deep into the darkest swamps to find the mysterious "Laroche."</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to get me out of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie, at the end of the day, I think it would be a terrible career move.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>UNCLE JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nursery business good, Johnny?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're finally pulling out of this debt.</context>
      <utterance>Everything's good, Uncle Jim. This last year's been a dream, I'm telling you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche smiles back at his mother. A screech of tires and another car crashes head on into theirs. Laroche's face smacks against the steering wheel, his front teeth fly in all directions. His mother rockets forward smashing through the windshield. His uncle hits Laroche's wife in the head, jerking her forward and landing on top of her.</context>
      <utterance>Amen, honey. Praise Allah, Buddha, Vishnu. And all the rest of 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... see, Laroche researched it and found that Indians have the legal right to take endangered plants off state lands.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We gave them smallpox!</context>
      <utterance>What an amazing opening! So then it's a courtroom drama. A Few Good Men! And all those Indian rights issues are so complex. There are valid arguments on both sides. I mean we took their land!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, actually, there wasn't much of a trial. Florida got 'em on a technicality, about cutting down non- endangered trees. Even the Indians aren't allowed to do that. They all plead no contest. Laroche got fined five hundred bucks and banned from the Fakahatchee for six months.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, wow. So, like, then what happens?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing much. That's what I like. I mean, most people's lives don't include a lot of drama and I wanted to sort of be compelling without having to resort to big, um... Y'know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. I absolutely do.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman smiles, but she's somewhere else entirely.</context>
      <utterance>It's, like, Blake talked about seeing the world in a grain of sand and heaven in a wild flower. Y'know? Or like Hegel?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am a failure. I'm a poseur. I have no ideas. I wanted to do something great. There's no story. I'm fat. I'm repuls-- The phone rings.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie? It's Valerie.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hi. Hi. Hey! Hi!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to bug you. We were just talking about you, how excited we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it's coming along good?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, John? It's Susan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susie-Q!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I was thinking it'd be good for the article for me to go into the Fakahatchee to see a ghost. Would you take me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd love to, but, hey, I'm banned for the next six months. Goddamn crucified me. Get one of them monkey-suited rangers to take you. 'Course, they wouldn't be able to locate a ghost, if it climbed off a tree and shoved itself up their ass. Hey, put that in the article.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Travelling into the Fakahatchee, Donald, is a perfect metaphor for writing. I'm stepping into the confusion of the unknown. I'm taking the big risk here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald looks up from his work. He hasn't been listening.</context>
      <utterance>It's dark, dangerous, as dense as steel wool. I don't know if I'll come out alive, but if I do, I'll have something true to give the world. That's the difference between writing and aping some moron's "principles."</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Charles, I'm thinking of putting a song in. Y'know like when characters sing pop songs in their pajamas and dance around. I thought it might be a nice way to break the tension. So, try to think of a song about split personality...</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would have to want something very badly...</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He can't concentrate, closes the book and watches a stewardess tending to another passenger.</context>
      <utterance>... to go looking for it in the Fakahatchee Strand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SURVEYOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pond surrounded by bay and cypress swamp, impracticable. Full of monstrous alligators, counted fifty and stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever isn't wet in the Fakahatchee is blasted. The grass gets so dry that the friction from a car can set it on fire, and the burning grass can engulf the car in flames. A 1940's botanist noted:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's Kaufman standing there.</context>
      <utterance>Charlie?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Hi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the whole ecosystem is six thousand years old. Five to six thousand years old. About that. Five or six.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now the Fakahatchee is the largest of all the cyrpess strands, probably in the world. I don't know of any cypress strand bigger. It's about twenty miles long, or nineteen, nineteen to twenty, nineteen... and right here it's about five miles wide, four and a half, five. So, again, it's twenty miles long, three to five miles wide. And over here --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why isn't it wet? Orlean wrote about wading through black, corrosive water. She said it was the scariest experience of her life. And when I spoke to you on the phone, you said wear heavy boots, long pants and...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's usually water. We've been going through a bit of a drought. Say, have you seen that movie, Medicine Man? That's a good movie about protecting nature. It shows there could be something important in a rain forest we don't even know about, like a cure for cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not even hot. I was expecting it to be awful. Sun beating down, wading through water, looking out for snakes, wild hogs. I was thinking it would be dramatic. Alligators. Something!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman looks down and sees a plain-looking little lizard hanging on a tree. Mike Owen jots it down in his notebook. MIKE OWEN (cont'd) I try to keep a log of sightings.</context>
      <utterance>The alligators are over by the lakes. The temperature's a blessing for us. This time of year can get uncomfortably hot.  Green anole. Florida's most common.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman is desperate for something else. He blurts:</context>
      <utterance>What Laroche did was wrong. Those flowers belong to all of us, all 250 million of us -- 250? I think it's up to 270 now -- And belonging to all of us means they belong to none of us. Nobody has a right to take them. Not me, not you, not John Laroche, not...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Have you ever heard stories or --</context>
      <utterance>Listen, um, Susan Orlean wrote about a legendary creature called a Swamp Ape.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tourist garbage! I don't know why people need to invent silly creatures to make nature fascinating. Isn't nature amazing enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just asked because she mentioned it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That night I called Laroche.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't see anything but bare roots.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Kaufman is deeply moved. He hi-lites the passage, then looks at the smiling photo of Orlean. He finds himself lost in it.</context>
      <utterance>What I didn't say to him was that life seemed to be filled with things that were just like the ghost orchid -- wonderful to imagine and easy to fall in love with but a little fantastic and fleeting and out of reach.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, of course there are ghost orchids out there! I've stolen them!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Thanks very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're big fans.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Laroche is such a fun character.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, John's a character all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's funny and fresh. And sad in a way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thanks. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we were wondering, what's next?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, um, Random House wants me to expand it into a book. So I'll be doing that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And there'll be more of Laroche?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. More John, more orchids.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, we'd really like to option it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to make this into a movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laroche is such a fun character. So...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit I'm a fun character.  Who's gonna play me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to write it first. Someone's gotta write the screenplay. Most things never get made. It's premature to --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche swerves into a parking space in the nursery lot.</context>
      <utterance>I think I should play me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few young Indian guys are hauling bags of potting soil. They look at Laroche sourly. Laroche indicates the giant cartoon Indian on his T-shirt.</context>
      <utterance>I've got all the right qualities. While you write, I'll take an acting class.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wear this just to screw with 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BAXLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was trying to order some pink string beans from Argentina.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAXLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figure just because Project Ghost Orchid is dead, we're not closing shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAXLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, John --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get into plant multiplication. Buy little ones, turn 'em into big ones, sell 'em at a profit. Simple plant multiplication for the masses.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAXLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, we're thinking maybe now's a good time for you to take a few weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need a vacation, Buster.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAXLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a good time. Things are slow. Laroche stares at Buster. Buster stares back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, the guys on my crew here, all they do is smoke weed all day. I been meaning to talk to you about that. So if it's a question of productivity --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna fire me. Goddamn politics. Crazy White Man's bad publicity.  I can't believe I'm dealing with this!  Like I could give a damn. If they fire me, I'll sue. I already did some legal research on this when I was doing the other shit. They can't fire me. And I ain't going to quit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, it's Susan.  Orlean.  So, I was just wondering if you might be willing to talk some more.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context>Orlean rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, John, I'm trying to put together a book. Don't just abandon me down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean is silent, taps her fingers on the bedside table.</context>
      <utterance>I'm no longer interested in orchids. I'm pursuing other avenues. I apologize for any inconvenience this might cause you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche hangs up. Orlean sits there for a moment, flips through her list of orchid collector names.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for your time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>California.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY ON BENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? I'm moving to L.A. I just wrote a screenplay. I sent it to a lot of agents. But if they turn me down, I'll go there and market it myself. I used to be in marketing in New York, so I know exactly how to sell this thing.  Where's a nice place to live if you don't have a car?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kind of need a car. I guess West Hollywood would be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY ON BENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you recommend West Hollywood then.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not recommending it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY ON BENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old guy waits for a response. He gets none. GUY ON BENCH (cont'd) It's about a mob guy, but it's not your regular mob story. There's a twist. A cop tells this mob guy's wife that the mob guy's cheating on her. But the truth is, the cop's lying because he wants her for himself. See, they used to go together in high school. (waits for response, then:) You know anything about screenplays? Kaufman shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I moved down here for a change, and I wrote the screenplay. Just like that. It's a great idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CONTINUED:</speaker>
      <mode>2</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>GUY ON BENCH  Well, the object is to make people think you're going in one direction, then you twist it to keep 'em surprised. I came up with all these amazing twists out of nowhere. Well, not nowhere.  I'm a born again Christian.  You have faith?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY ON BENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't believe in anything? Kaufman shrugs. GUY ON BENCH  I don't know how you can look out at this beautiful ocean and not believe there's an intelligence that created it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY ON BENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you can't know until you experience it. That requires accepting Jesus Christ as your Lord and Savior. Believe me. Lookit, if I was to show you a bottle of clear liquid and told you it was vodka, how would you know if it really was or if it was water? There's only one way.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd smell it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY ON BENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You can't smell vodka. You'd have to taste it, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could be poison. I don't know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY ON BENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(resuming control)</context>
      <utterance>Look, let's go with the analogy I'm drawing here. It's not poison. Okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CONTINUED:</speaker>
      <mode>3</mode>
      <context>Right? That's my point.</context>
      <utterance>GUY ON BENCH  So you'd have to taste it to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY ON BENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all I'm saying.  So West Hollywood, huh? I think I'll make it out this year. Because how long can you look at an ocean, y'know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have failed. I have nothing to say. I am fat. I am not a writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kaufman, do you mind if I ask what type of work you do for Sony?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A song writer?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm a screenwriter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, wow! Good for you. You mind if I ask what your movie's about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response. Kaufman tries to make it interesting. KAUFMAN (cont'd) It's about this poacher who steals orchids out of a swamp.</context>
      <utterance>It's about flowers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard about that! Drug flowers, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Action-adventure is my favorite genre.</context>
      <utterance>I heard about that! That's great!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was Florida, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool! Hey, my script's going amazing! Right now I'm working out an Image System. Bob calls it an invaluable asset. Because of my multiple personality theme, I've chosen the motif of broken mirrors to show my protagonist's fragmented self. Bob teaches that an Image System greatly increases the complexity of an aesthetic emotion.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman disappears upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>You sound like you're in a cult.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(types, then:)</context>
      <utterance>No, it's just good writing technique.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other. Donald breaks the tension, smiles. DONALD (cont'd) 'Cause it's extremely helpful. (lies down on floor) Hey, any sign of that Swamp Ape?</context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't have done that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no Swamp Ape. It was invented for people who can't find the actual world fascinating. Y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay. I didn't know that. Sorry. Hey, I got a song! "Happy Together." I was worried about putting a song in a thriller, but Bob says, Casablanca, the greatest screenplay ever written, did exactly that. Mixed genres.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to go to bed, Donald. I haven't slept in a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald remains on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald snores happily off-screen. Kaufman switches on a lamp, pulls The Orchid Thief from his bag, flips through it. There are now many yellow hi-lited passages. He reads one.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are too many ideas and things and people, too many directions to go. I was starting to believe the reason it matters to care passionately about something is that it whittles the world down to a more manageable size.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman flips to the glowing, smiling author photo.</context>
      <utterance>Such sweet, sad insights. So true.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at the photo. Its smile broadens. It talks.</context>
      <utterance>And you're... I like looking at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN PHOTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The photo smiles warmly at him. Kaufman begins to jerk-off. He closes his eyes. Then: Kaufman and Orlean are in his bed together, making love. She smiles at him throughout. They finish. Then: Kaufman is alone in bed, heaving. He looks at the still smiling photo. It somehow seems sleepy now.</context>
      <utterance>I like looking at you, too. Charlie.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how to do this. I'm afraid I'll disappoint you. You've written a beautiful book. I can't sleep. I'm losing my hair. I'm fat and repulsive --</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN PHOTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhh. You're not. Whittle it down, focus on one thing in the story, find the thing you care passionately about and write about that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We see Susan Orlean, delicate, fragile, beautiful, haunted by loneliness, typing at her desk. She looks at the camera and talks to us: "John Laroche is a tall guy, skinny as a stick, pale-eyed, slouch- shouldered..." Donald enters in his underwear, pours coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem chipper.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm good. I have some new ideas.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool. Me too. I'm putting in a chase sequence now. The killer flees on horseback with the girl. The cop is after them on a motorcycle. It's like a battle between motors and horses.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're all still one person, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, hey, that's the big pay-off.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it sounds exciting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, man. Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean stops at a payphone and dials. It rings for a while.</context>
      <utterance>I suppose what I'd been doing in Florida was trying to understand how people found order and contentment and a sense of purpose in the universe by fixing their sighs on one single desire. Now I was also trying to understand how someone could end such intense desire without a trace.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, John, it's Susan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, how's everything going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great! I'm training myself on the internet. It's fascinating. I'm doing pornography. It's amazing how much these suckers will pay for photographs of chicks. And it doesn't matter if they're fat or ugly or what.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's great is what it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I've been meeting a lot of orchid people, going to shows, I thought you might want to hear about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I am officially no longer interested in orchids or the losers who are still interested in them. The end.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not like a marriage.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes tear up. She kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe what marriage could be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it ironic? You adapting my book? My three years in Florida meditating on my inability to experience passion resulted in my finding it with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman is immensely pleased. He smiles at Orlean's photo. KAUFMAN (cont'd) This is good. I'm finding you. The phone rings.</context>
      <utterance>... and in the final sequence Susan as a young girl swings alone in the backyard. From high in the air she sees her parents in separate rooms staring blankly in opposite directions. This symbolizes the profound scarring their waning passion has had on the girl's psyche, how she became afraid to ever really love something because it would go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yallo?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Charlie. It's Valerie. Just bugging you again. How's everything going?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I think really good now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. So I spoke to Susan yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Uh-huh, uh-huh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context>All color drains from Kaufman's face.</context>
      <utterance>And she said she'd love to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, well, y'know, for me it's distracting to... or confusing to discuss what I'm exploring in the screenplay at this point... before I finish... it. So...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fair. I'll let her know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell Susan I'd be very happy to meet her at a future date. As she sees fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Good enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And tell her how much I love her book. Say I think she's such a great writer. VALERIE  Will do. Just keep us posted, Charlie.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman hangs up and looks at the photo of Orlean. It's still smiling, but not at him. It's not glowing. Maybe it's even smirking. Kaufman paces frantically, holding his stomach. Donald's off-screen typing grows louder.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Nice talking to you. Okay then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He lies there for a moment, then his eyes light up.</context>
      <utterance>She thinks I'm repulsive.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Movie opens.: Charlie Kaufman, fat, old, bald, paces the room. His voice-over carpets the scene. "I am old. I am fat. I am bald. My toenails have turned strange. I am repulsive. How repulsive? I don't know for I suffer from a condition called Body Dysmorphic Disorder."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're getting antsy.</context>
      <utterance>... we need to talk about the orchid script. Valerie called yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I've got it on track now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. She said you sounded weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sometimes that takes a while to find.</context>
      <utterance>No Hollywood bullshit. Just raw truth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. What's the time frame here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's goddamned honest, Jerry. It's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hey, my friend sent me this fucked- up internet thing. It's a girl taking a shit, but a trout comes out. You got e- mail yet? I'll send it to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is more honest than anything anyone's ever done before in a movie, I'll tell you that. The only truth we can offer is the truth that's our own experience of the world. "The great poet, in writing himself, writes his time." T.S. Eliot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sounds good, buddy. But we do need to give Valerie a ballpark --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sick of their constant harassment!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been checking out the displays?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the Miami centennial, we're supposed to illustrate something about Florida history.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Now Laroche is part of Florida history. As a mannequin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean is moved by the quote.</context>
      <utterance>It's a world of words to the end of it./In which nothing solid is its solid self. You'll have to forgive me, I'm a reformed poetry professor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wallace Stevens.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, it's Susan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went to the Orchid Society Show a couple of days ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a display of you stealing the ghost orchids. You're famous.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not involved in that world now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, look, John, I still haven't seen a ghost. And I was wondering --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah. I'll take you in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Thank you so much! I just...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow. Pick me up at 5:30 am or it'll get too hot. I'll buy all the supplies we'll need.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Donald appears in the doorway with a script.</context>
      <utterance>Kaufman jerks off to the book jacket photo of Susan Orlean.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I finished. My script. I'm done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ourobouros.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what that means.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The snake is called Ourobouros.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. But it's cool for my killer to have this modus operandi. Because at the end when he forces the woman, who's really just him, to eat herself, he's also eating himself to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm insane. I'm Ourobouros.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's eating itself. I'm eating myself.</context>
      <utterance>I've written myself into my screenplay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. That's kinda weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's self-indulgent. It's narcissistic. It's solipsistic. It's pathetic. I'm pathetic. I'm fat and pathetic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you had a good reason, Charles. You're an artist.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The reason is I'm too timid to speak to the woman who wrote the book. Because I'm pathetic. Because I have no idea how to write. Because I can't make flowers fascinating. Because I suck.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, am I in the script, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's it. That's what I have to do.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to New York. I'll meet her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get mad at me for saying this, Charles, but Bob's got a seminar in New York this weekend. So if you're stuck -- Kaufman shoots Donald a look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are our supplies?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche pulls a new pack of cigarettes out of his pocket. Orlean turns off the ignition and stares at the steering wheel. Laroche shrugs. LAROCHE (cont'd) Look, don't worry about it. We'll get crap at the Indian trading post on Alligator Alley. Hey, want me to drive?</context>
      <utterance>Got everything I need right here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche continues walking and Orlean attempts to keep pace. He points at a tiny orchid on another tree.</context>
      <utterance>Cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clamshell orchid. You know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I found you two already. I'll show you every orchid you want today. I'll find you a fucking ghost if it kills me.  Rigid Epidendrum. That's an ugly-ass orchid. But I'm no snob. I'm interested in all orchids. Not just pretty ones.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A waitress brings a tuna sandwich and an ice tea to Orlean. KAUFMAN (V.O.) (cont'd) Likes tuna, drinks ice tea. Good character details. Good stuff! Orlean looks up from her magazine and smiles at the waitress.</context>
      <utterance>Reads Vanity Fair. Funny detail: New Yorker writer reads Vanity Fair. Use!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress nods and leaves. Kaufman scribbles.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Could I get some lemon please?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Likes lemon in tea and her voice is not at all what I imagined. Interesting!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche turns and scowls at her.</context>
      <utterance>Laroche, can I ask you a personal question?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not lost.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, y'know it's not really about collecting the thing, it's about --</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche looks down at it.</context>
      <utterance>The sundial isn't working.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean stares at the twig in the ground. She looks at Laroche. Laroche smiles sheepishly at Orlean. Rage and panic sweep across her face, her fists clench into balls. Her eyes become wild, some dark fantasy plays out in her brain. Laroche seems unaware. LAROCHE (cont'd) The thing about computers. The thing I like is that I'm immersed in it but it's not a living thing that's going to leave or die or something. I prefer having the minimum number of living things to worry about in my life. Orlean's anger softens. She looks sadly at Laroche.</context>
      <utterance>It is so working.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, John...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche points them in a direction and they walk.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, fuck the sundial. We'll just go straight and eventually we'll get there. They rise. LAROCHE  What I mean is we'll get somewhere. Out of here. I mean, logically, we have to get out as long as we walk straight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode>TELEPHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's Jerry. I woke you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode>TELEPHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going? Has it been helpful to talk to the writer? What's her name?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Susan Orlean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode>TELEPHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context>Valerie's breathing down my neck.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I mean, are you making headway?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't rush inspiration. Y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode>TELEPHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, fine. Um, the other reason I'm calling is to tell you Me, Myself, and I is just amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is Me, Myself, and I?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode>TELEPHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your brother's script. It's tight, inventive. A smart, edgy thriller. The best spec script I've read this year.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode>TELEPHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna sell it for a shitload. Two fucking talented guys in one family. Y'know, maybe you could bring Donald on to help you finish the orchid thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jerry, don't say that. I mean --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jerry, I gotta go. I have an appointment. I gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode>TELEPHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adios, buddy. Finish! Finish!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience laughs, except for Kaufman who looks pained.</context>
      <utterance>Years from now you'll be standing around a posh cocktail party congratulating yourself on how you spent an entire weekend locked in a room with an asshole, an opinionated arrogant asshole, for your art.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am pathetic. I am a loser. I am fat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McKee continues to talk but his voice goes under.</context>
      <utterance>So... what is the substance of writing? Nothing as trivial as words is at the heart of this great art, my friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I have sold out. I am worthless. I...</context>
      <utterance>I have failed. I am panicked. I am fat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman watches with disdain as people take notes.</context>
      <utterance>Literary talent is not enough. First, last, and always, the imperative is to tell a story.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone, except Kaufman, laughs giddily at McKee's joke. MCKEE (cont'd) Aristotle also said: A story must have a beginning, a middle, and an end. The students nod in appreciation at this profundity.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty three hundred years ago, Aristotle said, when storytelling goes bad in a society, the result is decadence.  Well, just look around you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is my weakness, my ultimate lack of conviction that brings me here with all these desperate idiots lapping up everything this bag of wind spouts. Easy answers. Rules to short-cut yourself to success. And here I am, because my jaunt into the abyss brought me nothing. Well, isn't that the risk one takes for attempting something new. I should leave here right now. I'll start over --  I need to face this project head on and --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman stops, looks up, startled. McKee seems to be looking at him.</context>
      <utterance>... and God help you if you use voice- over in your work, my friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman looks around at people scribbling in notebooks. "Any idiot..." writes the guy on one side of him. "Flaccid..." writes the guy on the other side. MCKEE (cont'd) Okay, one hour for lunch.</context>
      <utterance>God fucking help you! It's flaccid, sloppy writing. Any idiot can write voice-over narration to explain the thoughts of a character. You must present the internal conflicts of your character in image, in symbol. Film is a medium of movement and image.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talked about Crisis as the ultimate decision a character makes, but what if a writer is attempting to create a story where nothing much happens, where people don't change, they don't have any epiphanies. They struggle and are frustrated and nothing is resolved. More a reflection of the real world --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The real world? The real fucking world? First of all, if you write a screenplay without conflict or crisis, you'll bore your audience to tears. Secondly: Nothing happens in the real world? Are you out of your fucking mind? People are murdered every day! There's genocide and war and corruption! Every fucking day somewhere in the world somebody sacrifices his life to save someone else! Every fucking day someone somewhere makes a conscious decision to destroy someone else! People find love! People lose it, for Christ's sake! A child watches her mother beaten to death on the steps of a church! Someone goes hungry! Somebody else betrays his best friend for a woman! If you can't find that stuff in life, then you, my friend, don't know much about life! And why the fuck are you taking up my precious two hours with your movie? I don't have any use for it! I don't have any bloody use for it!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. McKee?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the guy you yelled at this morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need more.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was the one who thought things didn't happen in life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right, okay. Nice to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I make it a rule not to give private tutorials to my seminar students. It wouldn't be fair to the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McKee hesitates for a moment, then reaches out and puts his arm around Kaufman.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. McKee, please. My even standing here is very scary. I don't meet people well. I'm self-conscious and timid. But what you said this morning shook me to the bone. What you said was bigger than my screenwriting choices. It's about my choices as a human being. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could use a drink, my friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... We followed it like a beacon all the way to the road. Kaufman closes the book. There's a pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what happens?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the book. I wanted to present it simply, without big character arcs or sensationalizing the story. I wanted to show flowers as God's miracles. I wanted to show that Orlean never saw the blooming ghost orchid. It's about disappointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. That's not a movie. You must go back and put in the drama.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got pages of false starts and wrong approaches. I'm way past my deadline. I can't go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, the everpresent deadline. Yes, I was doing a Kojak once and... it was hell. McKee sips his beer, eyes Kaufman. MCKEE  Tell you a secret. The last act makes the film. You can have an uninvolving, tedious movie, but wow them at the end, and you've got a hit. Find an ending. Use what you've learned this weekend. Give them that and you'll be fine. Tears form in Kaufman's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McKee smiles. Kaufman hugs him. McKee recognizes his bulk.</context>
      <utterance>You promise?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've taken my course before?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's the one who got me to come.</context>
      <utterance>My brother did. My twin brother Donald.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twin screenwriters. Julius and Philip Epstein,who wrote Casablanca were twins.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mentioned that in class.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCKEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The finest screenplay ever written.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Kaufman is lost. He rubs his temples. He dials the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Climax. A revolution in values from positive to negative or negative to positive with or without irony -- a value swing at maximum charge that's absolute and irreversible.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great writers residence.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donald.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, how's the trip? Gettin' it on with that lady journalist? You dog you!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Listen, I'm calling to say congratulations on your script.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that cool? Jerry says he can make me, like, high-sixes against a mill-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great, Donald.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't any help.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, you let me stay in your place and your integrity inspired me to even try.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look, I've been thinking, maybe you'd be interested in hanging out with me in New York for a few days.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, yes! I'm flattered!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, like, what would you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Script kind of makes fun of me, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I was trying something. I --</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I don't mind. It's funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. So, what would you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're different talents.</context>
      <utterance>You and me are so different, Charles.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Just for fun. How would the great Donald end this script?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The great Donald.  Well, I mean... do you need the whole court case?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, it's what happened to Laroche. It's kind of important.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's boring. No offense. A courtroom scene should be dramatic. Stick the ruling in a line of dialogue, maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too much about orchids. Get rid of it. Pare that stuff down to a minimum. Frankly, I'd focus more on the relationship between the brothers. I think that's the gold here. No one cares about orchids.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The book's about orchids.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a problem. But don't let it ruin the movie. I mean, for example, use the orchids in a more dramatic way. Have some kind of bang-up, crazy action sequence in the swamp. Use the swamp better. It's a tremendous fictional world. A setting of great dramatic possibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's true. But --</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And put some twists in. Reveal some surprising thing about Laroche. God, what am I doing giving suggestions to you? I mean you're like a seasoned professional. You're an artist.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, you're the "mill-five" kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!  I love the Laroche porno web-site stuff. Is that real? Maybe make a bigger deal of that. I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's real. I haven't actually seen the site.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's sex, man! Incorporate it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hi, I was doing some research. I found Laroche's site and... I'm embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman passes Donald, glances at the grainy nude on the screen. He's stunned. It's Orlean smiling at him.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Donald.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman shows Donald Orlean's book jacket photo. DONALD (cont'd) Oh, wow. That's kind of a twist, huh?</context>
      <utterance>What? She's kinda cute. You don't like her? I dunno, I think she's okay. It's not like I'm marrying her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think this is maybe a good thing for the script. Go ask her about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna ask her about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to? I don't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't want you to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could easily pretend I'm you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was she wearing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Like a dress maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she look at me? At you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald turns and smiles across the room to Kaufman.</context>
      <utterance>Finally! Da-da-da-daaaaah! S. Orlean, TWA flight 651. Arriving Miami 10:20 tomorrow morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to do this, Donald.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll go together. It'll be good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so weird to actually see that van in real life.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you want to build the symbolic charge of the story's imagery from the particular to the universal. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, but when you're creating an image system, how do you know --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get a closer look. You wait here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I want to go. I should go. I mean, it should be me, right? I mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman gets out of the car. Donald gets in, peruses Kaufman's script. Kaufman walks past the house, trying to peer in windows. He sees nothing. He slinks around back.</context>
      <utterance>Go for it, bro. You the man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's movement in a window in the house. Kaufman ducks.</context>
      <utterance>Holy...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Kaufman crawls over to the house, lifts his face to the window. Orlean and Laroche are laughing, kissing, groping, and undressing each other. Kaufman is heartbroken but transfixed. Suddenly Laroche locks eyes with Kaufman.</context>
      <utterance>Darlin', I dunno what's come over you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche jumps up and runs naked to the back door.</context>
      <utterance>Don't stop, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Kaufman makes a mad dash around the side of the house. Laroche cuts him off, grabs him, drags him into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny! Where are you going?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman notices Laroche has a set of beautiful, white teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche shakes Orlean off his leg, kicks Kaufman in the gut.</context>
      <utterance>I just... nobody, I just --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm looking for the Johnson family.</context>
      <utterance>Um. I'm just. I was at the wrong house.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got your Johnson family right here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, come back to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell sent you? Rudy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Laroche kicks Kaufman in the head. His scalp bleeds. KAUFMAN (cont'd) I'm the screenwriter.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This registers with Laroche.</context>
      <utterance>I'm the guy adapting her book. Her book about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Fucking Christ.  Why the fuck were you in my backyard?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean is unforgiving.</context>
      <utterance>I was, um, trying... I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the bloody fat guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the fellow adapting your book for the movies, darling'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? I wanted to meet --  Oh. What does he know?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know anything. I swear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows about the greenhouse.  We can't have this appear on the silver screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't. I don't even under --</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean lies down. Laroche paces. Donald peers, unseen, into the back window.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny, I'm so tired now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He needs to be gotten rid of.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald's eyes widen. Laroche paces. Orlean watches Laroche, fascinated by his every muscle movement.</context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean snaps out of her muscle fixation, becomes fixated on his voice, his lips. LAROCHE (cont'd) Screenwriter doing research for movie about notorious orchid poacher was found drowned in the Fakahatchee after accidentally slipping and hitting his head on a rock. End of story. Is that credible from a journalistic standpoint?</context>
      <utterance>Small article in newspaper.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny, come lie on top of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Focus, darling'. Is this credible?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, oh... this screenwriter was killed doing research in Jamaica a few years ago.  Screenwriter, you have a car?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, um, no, I -- Laroche gets ready to kick him again. KAUFMAN  A rental, a rental.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We drive his car there, leave it on the side of the swamp. That works.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald disappears from the window.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I had a sense of you from your book.  I had a little crush on you, to tell the truth. You're different than I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't care what you two are you doing. Please don't kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, here's one of my lines.  "Isn't it ironic? You adapting my book? My three years in Florida meditating on my inability to experience passion resulted in my finding it with you."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was trying to do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drive in silence. Orlean reads more of the screenplay.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's kind of pathetic, dontcha think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's me! Here's me again!  "I wanted to know what it's like to care about something passionately." Orlean laughs derisively.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can laugh, but I didn't make that line up. That's a quote from your book.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know, Charlie-boy. Chill. I'm laughing at who I used to be. It's sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now you learned about passion.  From Weirdo Laroche. Bully for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't learn about passion. You can be passion. And it wasn't John who made me passion. It was orchids.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you didn't even like orchids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lied about what happened at the end of the book. On the way out of the swamp...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still don't get it. I mean, there it is. I can see it's pretty, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche pulls a saw from his bag and cuts the branch.</context>
      <utterance>You'll get it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it curious? An orchid made me passionate about orchids.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're throwing the truth away for a chemical confusion of your synapses --</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With this powder I am passionate about everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now how do we do this? Hit him in the head with a rock first? Keeping in mind we can only hit him once and only with as much force as would be created by him slipping and falling onto the rock. Laroche paces. Orlean finds a place to sit on a hammock. She unwraps a small square of paper and snorts something out of it. Kaufman shivers. Orlean's drugs kick in.</context>
      <utterance>This spot looks good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean trails off. Laroche talks to the spaced out Orlean.</context>
      <utterance>Holy Jesus. Holy... Hey, baby, hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we drown him, then hit him on the head? Uh-uh. A body bleeds different if the heart's stopped. These new forensic guys are very smart. We really have to know our corpses to stand a chance: rigor mortis, lividity, putrefecation, ocular changes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't write this kind of bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Laroche gets whacked in the back, flies forward into the water. Orlean looks up, spaced. She's confused by a second Kaufman standing there with a bag of potting soil. Donald grabs Kaufman and they run back toward the road. Laroche pulls himself from the water. LAROCHE (cont'd) Fuck!</context>
      <utterance>Don't get all huffy, I was simply --</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She staggers moonily toward Laroche. He pushes her away.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, let's, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now. We got to kill that guy. And now I guess that other guy as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohhh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For Christ's sake, why didn't you do something while we were in the car?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche's van pulls close to them and rams them from behind.</context>
      <utterance>My back had seized. I couldn't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It rams them again, this time sending them down into the swamp. The van stops. Donald tries to back the car onto the road; the wheels just spin. Laroche steps out of the van.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've gotta ditch this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a rental! It's a rental!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman and Donald climb from the car, make their way deep into the swamp. Laroche follows them in on foot, dragging Orlean, who is admiring all the plant life.</context>
      <utterance>Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's beautiful! What's that, Johnny? What's that one called? I just so want to fuck that flower, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche shoots at the brothers. Kaufman whines.</context>
      <utterance>Asclepias lanceolata. Red milkweed. Extremely fuckable. But we don't have time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, y'know... Charlie or something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Charlie! Listen, let's talk! This pie is big enough for four people!  Why are there two of him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman and Donald run through a colony of sawgrass. It slices them like razor blades. Kaufman yells in pain. Blood oozes through their shirts and pants.</context>
      <utterance>Identical twigs?  Did I say twigs? I meant twins.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cladium jamaicense, guys. Sawgrass. You want to watch out for that. That's some evil shit. Cut you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, Laroche!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman and Donald are stopped by a large body of water. Nowhere to go. Laroche and Orlean close in. The brothers run along the periphery of the lake. Donald stops.</context>
      <utterance>Just tryin' to be helpful. Walk with us and I'll be sure you avoid all the pitfalls. I know these swamps forwards and backwards. There's alligators and poisonous snakes, fellas. Wild hogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman stops, hears a distant galloping and squealing.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Do you hear something?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The brothers run in the opposite direction. The galloping gets louder. It's wild pigs. Donald spots an airboat on the shore. They jump onto it, search hysterically in the dark for bow to start it. The pigs get closer. Laroche and Orlean get closer. Donald finds a button, presses it, the engine starts. They pull away from the shore just as the pigs catch up. One pig leaps on board, squealing. Kaufman kicks at it as Donald attempts to steer the boat. A kick connects and the pig flies into the water.</context>
      <utterance>Donald, that sounds bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald gets the boat back on course. Laroche and Orlean have been left far behind. Donald slows the boat.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out, watch out, watch out!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Laroche's van comes tearing around a corner and speeds along the road at the water's edge. Orlean shoots at the boat from the van window. DONALD (cont'd) Hold on! Donald speeds up. The van keeps up, the shooting continues. Bullets whiz. Kaufman puts his head in his hands. A bullet hits the airboat's gas tank. It explodes in a ball of flame, illuminating the whole swamp. Kaufman and Donald are thrown, along with flaming pieces of debris. Donald treads water, looks all around for Kaufman. DONALD (cont'd) Charles?! Charles?! Where are you? Underwater. A dazed Kaufman tries to get his bearings. The murky lake bottom is lit a dim orange by the fire on the surface. An alligator appears. Kaufman panics, surfaces. On the surface, Donald spots Kaufman pop out of the water, then get jerked back down. Donald dives. Underwater. The alligator violently shakes Kaufman by the leg. Donald surfaces, comes back down with a broken propeller blade. He hacks the alligator's head off, grabs Kaufman, and brings him to the surface. Donald swims to shore with Kaufman in tow. Another shot is fired. It skims the water near Kaufman.</context>
      <utterance>I think we're okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck! Fuck, Donald, we're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're okay. How's your leg?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. How's your back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche and Orlean circle the lake in the van, shooting. Mike Owen, in pajamas, leaves his house, jumps in his truck and agitatedly drives toward the noise and flames. Donald makes it to shore. He climbs out and is helping Kaufman, when he gets hit by a bullet and falls.</context>
      <utterance>It's fine. My back is fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman sloshes to shore. His right leg is bloody and mangled. He lifts his brother's head onto his lap.</context>
      <utterance>Donald!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But don't let them get you, too.  You got a fucking awesome third act.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donald, this is an awful, bizarre thing to say and an awful time to say it, but I'm sorry I didn't get to know you better. I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really... You've been really nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald touches Kaufman's face. Kaufman looks at his brother. Donald's face glows radiantly in the fire light.</context>
      <utterance>See, it's just I thought I knew you already. I thought you were me. And I hated me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, don't do that anymore. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald dies. Kaufman screams heavenward. The van appears out of the bush, barreling for them. Kaufman rolls his brother out of the way, and limps off into a slough. The van follows, smashes into a tree, and comes to a halt.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Owen grabs his C.B., tries to radio for help. It's broken. He lifts Donald into the back of the truck and speeds off. Kaufman limps through the dark water. Laroche and Orlean follow the sound of his sloshing.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, that writer guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Water sounds so sparkly. Like lemon plastic jewels plopping onto a silver trampoline! Dontcha think?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darlin', please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Owen tears along the dirt road. Up ahead, Kaufman limps out of the swamp, into the truck's headlights. Owen is confused. He checks the back to see if Donald's body is still there and skids off the road into the swamp. Kaufman hurriedly limps over to the disabled truck. Owen climbs out.</context>
      <utterance>Can we fuck now, baby? Fuck like lemons?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta help me. You gotta help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They killed my brother.</context>
      <utterance>They're after me. They've got guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Owen finishes, his truck is flipped over. Donald's body flies into the water. There, staring Kaufman and Owen down, is a giant man-like beast. It's repulsive, covered in algae-matted fur. MIKE OWEN (cont'd) Holy shit.</context>
      <utterance>Who's got guns? What are you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CONTINUED:</speaker>
      <mode>5</mode>
      <context>It's real! I can't believe it, I never -- The creature grabs Owen and snaps his neck like a toothpick. Kaufman screams as he runs, watches over his shoulder. He runs right into the arms of Orlean.</context>
      <utterance>The two men turn and run. MIKE OWEN</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's the screenwriter!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman, Orlean, and Laroche look back. Nothing there.</context>
      <utterance>There's a thing back there! You don't want to be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche puts the gun to Kaufman's head. Kaufman tenses. Orlean studies Laroche's gun. Her nose is practically touching the barrel.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, I don't want to be here. I'm tired, let's get this over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love your gun, baby. Can we trade?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laroche reaches for Orlean's arm to pull her away. Suddenly the creature grabs Laroche, pulls him into the swamp. LAROCHE (cont'd) Susie! Susie! Orlean looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Stand back, sweetness.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd Johnny go?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAROCHE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Orlean, agitated and disoriented, fires repeatedly into the darkness. Something slumps forward in the water. Orlean steps cautiously over, keeping her gun on Kaufman. The creature is dead, so is Laroche.</context>
      <utterance>Susie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits next to Laroche and pets his head. Kaufman watches her. The sun is coming up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd just stare at your picture, and you looked so sweet. I read your words and I thought you were smart and maybe lost and lonely like me. And the way you wrote about Laroche. You said he was handsome even though he had no front teeth --</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Johnny. Johnny's teeth. Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman takes Orlean's chin in his hand and directs her gaze to him. She stares at him for a long while, then:</context>
      <utterance>I figured you could look at me and see something, even with all my flaws you could look at me and find something, you could maybe someday write a description of me that would be nicer than the one I write day in and day out in my head.  Would it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really so wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman lets go of her face and sits on a rock.</context>
      <utterance>So wonderful. I can see inside your soul. It glows with orange sadness. It's raining inside you. I want to run through your dripply dripples. It's so beautiful. I love you. I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean stands and walks toward Kaufman.</context>
      <utterance>It's the drugs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She paces, unfolds her little square of paper. ORLEAN (cont'd) I'm out. I'm fucking cleaned out. Kaufman watches her for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's me. It's the real me. Look at you. I just want to hold you and -- Oh, crap, it's wearing off. Crap!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORLEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orlean screams in anguish. Kaufman keeps walking. Orlean shakily aims the gun at his back. She shoots. Kaufman falls, gets up, keeps walking. She aims again through her tears. Suddenly she's pounced on by a bloody, soaking wet figure. Kaufman turns.</context>
      <utterance>I can't let you go, fatty. I can't let you make this public. Kaufman keeps walking. ORLEAN  You hear me? You pathetic, fat, bald... You don't even know how to write! You're not even... You're not leaving here!  I need a fix! Everything's so ugly!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman limps back. Donald and Orlean roll on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Donald!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gun fires. Orlean slumps over Donald. Kaufman arrives. Both Donald and Orlean are dead. Kaufman falls to his knees.</context>
      <utterance>My brother is not fat. He's not bald. My brother is a great writer! He was trying to do something important!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaufman cries a little. The cop waits sympathetically, then:</context>
      <utterance>That's Mike Owen. John Laroche. Susan Orlean. I don't know what that is. I think it might be a Swamp Ape. And that's Donald, my twin brother. He saved my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two really look alike.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yes, we do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I love McKee!  Oh, hi. Haven't seen you in a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Yeah, I've been away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you studying screenwriting?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm actually finishing one up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for you! Me too. God, it's so hard to get in, huh? Everyone and their brother is writing a screenplay.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Actually I'm writing this one for Sony Pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(beat)</context>
      <utterance>Really? Wow. Really? That's so cool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's tough. Let's see... about being yourself, maybe. It's about learning that if you can't love yourself, you can't really love anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's true. God, that's so true. It's such an important message, y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, my twin brother was murdered recently --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God! I'm sorry. That's so horrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forever. It was a wake up call.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Like part of me ripped away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry. You poor man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a pause. Alice just stares at him, in awe.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway, it helped put things in perspective. Life is a miracle. All life, from the flower to the human being. You. Me. And I want to show people that. For my brother. For everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, do you mind if I sit for a sec?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're working.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a stupid job, y'know. I'm Alice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alice smiles, sits. The two of them begin to talk.</context>
      <utterance>I like that name. Charlie. I've always really liked that name. Charlie.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
