<movie id="23" title="Amadeus">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A faint light illuminates the screen. Flickeringly, we see an eighteenth century balustrade and a flight of stone stairs. We are looking down into the wall of the staircase from the point of view of the landing. Up the stair is coming a branched candlestick held by Salieri's VALET. By his side is Salieri's COOK, bearing a large dish of sugared cakes and biscuits. Both men are desperately worried: the Valet is thin and middle-aged; the Cook, plump and Italian. It is very cold. They wear shawls over their night-dresses and clogs on their feet. They wheeze as they climb. The candles throw their shadows up onto the peeling walls of the house, which is evidently an old one and in bad decay. A cat scuttles swiftly between their bare legs, as they reach the salon door. The Valet tries the handle. It is locked. Behind it the voice goes on, rising in volume.</context>
      <utterance>Mozart! Mozart! Mozart. Forgive me! Forgive your assassin! Mozart!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Valet knocks gently on the door. The voice stops.</context>
      <utterance>Show some mercy! I beg you. I beg you! Show mercy to a guilty man!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Open the door, Signore! Please! Be good now! We've brought you something special. Something you're going to love.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice of Old Salieri continues again, further off now, and louder. We hear a noise as if a window is being opened.</context>
      <utterance>Signore Salieri! Open the door. Come now. Be good!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two servants look at each other in alarm. Then the Valet hands the candlestick to the Cook and takes a sugared cake from the dish, scrambling as quickly as he can back down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Mozart! Mozart! I confess it! Listen! I confess!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door of the house bursts open. The Valet hobbles out, holding the sugared cake. The wind catches at his shawl.</context>
      <utterance>Mozart! Mozart! I cannot bear it any longer! I confess! I confess what I did! I'm guilty! I killed you! Sir I confess! I killed you!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart, perdonami! Forgive your assassin! Pietˆ! Pietˆ! Forgive your assassin! Forgive me! Forgive! Forgive!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Old Salieri stares down at him. Some of the passersby have now stopped and are watching this spectacle.</context>
      <utterance>That's all right, Signore! He heard you! He forgave you! He wants you to go inside now and shut the window!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Old Salieri looks at him in contempt. Then he turns away back into the room, shutting the window with a bang. Through the glass, the old man stares down at the group of onlookers in the street. They stare back at him in confusion.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Signore! Look what I have for you! I can't give it to you from down here, can I?</utterance>
   <speaker>BYSTANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes a sign indicating 'crazy,' and goes back inside the house. The onlookers keep staring.</context>
      <utterance>No one, sir. He'll be all right. Poor man. He's a little unhappy, you know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cook, scared, shakes his head: no. The Valet again knocks on the door.</context>
      <utterance>Did he open?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He eats the sugared cake in his hand, elaborately and noisily.</context>
      <utterance>Here I am, Signore. Now open the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a thump from inside the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm - this is good! This is the most delicious thing I ever ate, believe me! Signore, you don't know what you're missing! Mmmm!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a terrible, throaty groaning.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's enough, Signore! Open!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down. From under the door we see a trickle of blood flowing. In horror, the two men stare at it. The dish of cakes falls from the Cook's hand and shatters. He sets the candlestick down on the floor. Both servants run at the door frantically - once, twice, three times - and the frail lock gives. The door flies open. Immediately, the stormy, frenzied opening of Mozart's Symphony No. 25 (the Little G Minor) begins. We see what the servants see.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't open this door, we're going to eat everything. There'll be nothing left for you. And I'm not going to bring you anything more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOCTOR GULDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop outside a door.</context>
      <utterance>He's going to live. It's much harder to cut your throat than most people imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR GULDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we are. Do you wish me to come in with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vogler nods and opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>No, Doctor. Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Old Salieri turns around to look at him. We see that his throat is bandaged expertly. He wears hospital garb, and over it the Civilian Medal and Chain with which we will later see the EMPEROR invest him.</context>
      <utterance>Herr Salieri?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Father Vogler. I am a Chaplain here. I thought you might like to talk to someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tried to take your life. You do remember that, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the sight of God that is a sin.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you understand that you have sinned? Gravely.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cannot leave alone a soul in pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know who I am? You never heard of me, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That makes no difference. All men are equal in God's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Offer me your confession. I can offer you God's forgiveness.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not seek forgiveness.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son, there is something dreadful on your soul. Unburden it to me. I'm here only for you. Please talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How well are you trained in music?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know a little. I studied it in my youth.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here in Vienna.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He propels his wheelchair to the forte-piano, and plays an unrecognizable melody.</context>
      <utterance>Then you must know this.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't say I do. What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plays another tune.</context>
      <utterance>I'm surprised you don't know. It was a very popular tune in its day. I wrote it. How about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plays it with growing enthusiasm.</context>
      <utterance>This one brought down the house when we played it first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I regret it is not too familiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slyly he plays the opening measure of Mozart's Eine Kleine Nachtmusik. The priest nods, smiling suddenly, and hums a little with the music.</context>
      <utterance>Can you recall no melody of mine? I was the most famous composer in Europe when you were still a boy. I wrote forty operas alone. What about this little thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I know that! That's charming! I didn't know you wrote that.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't. That was Mozart. Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart. You know who that is?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. The man you accuse yourself of killing.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah - you've heard that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All Vienna has heard that.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do they believe it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A very long pause. Salieri stares above the priest, seemingly lost in his own private world.</context>
      <utterance>Should I?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A further pause.</context>
      <utterance>For God's sake, my son, if you have anything to confess, do it now! Give yourself some peace!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>He was murdered, Father! Mozart! Cruelly murdered.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Old Salieri turns to him, a look of extreme innocence.</context>
      <utterance>Yes? Did you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was my idol! I can't remember a time when I didn't know his name! When I was only fourteen he was already famous. Even in Legnago - the tiniest town in Italy - I knew of him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The piece finishes. Leopold lowers the lid of the harpsichord and lifts up his little son to stand on it. Mozart removes the blindfold to show a pale little face with staring eyes. Both father and son bow. A Papal Chamberlain presents Leopold with a gold snuff box whilst the cardinals decorously applaud. Over this scene Old Salieri speaks.</context>
      <utterance>I admit I was jealous when I heard the tales they told about him. Not of the brilliant little prodigy himself, but of his father, who had taught him everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father did not care for music. He wanted me only to be a merchant, like himself. As anonymous as he was. When I told how I wished I could be like Mozart, he would say, Why? Do you want to be a trained monkey? Would you like me to drag you around Europe doing tricks like a circus freak? How could I tell him what music meant to me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The boy falls forward on his knees. So do his parents and the other members of the congregation. He stares up at Christ who stares back at him.</context>
      <utterance>Even then a spray of sounded notes could make me dizzy, almost to falling.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The music swells to a crescendo. The candles flare. We see the Christ through the flames looking at the boy benignly.</context>
      <utterance>Whilst my father prayed earnestly to God to protect commerce, I would offer up secretly the proudest prayer a boy could think of. Lord, make me a great composer! Let me celebrate your glory through music - and be celebrated myself! Make me famous through the world, dear God! Make me immortal! After I die let people speak my name forever with love for what I wrote! In return I vow I will give you my chastity - my industry, my deepest humility, every hour of my life. And I will help my fellow man all I can. Amen and amen!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do you know what happened? A miracle!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We see Salieri, age thirty-one, a neat, carefully turned-cut man in decent black clothes and clean white linen, walking through the crowd of guests. We follow him.</context>
      <utterance>One day he came to Vienna to play some of his music at the residence of his employer, the Prince-Archbishop of Salzburg. Eagerly I went there to seek him out. That night changed my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We see shots of assorted young men staring back at Salieri as he moves through the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>As I went through the salon, I played a game with myself. This man had written his first concerto at the age of four; his first symphony at seven; a full-scale opera at twelve. Did it show? Is talent like that written on the face?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Some of the men recognize Salieri and bow respectfully. Then suddenly a servant bearing a large tray of cakes and pastries stalks past. Instantly riveted by the sight of such delights, Salieri follows him out of the Grand Salon.</context>
      <utterance>Which one of them could he be?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart is not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're looking for him, Your Grace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her ankle. She screams. He pulls her out by her leg.</context>
      <utterance>Miaouw! Miaouw! Mouse-wouse? It's Puss-wuss, fangs-wangs. Paws-claws. Pounce-bounce!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They roll on the floor. He tickles her.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it. Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to drag her back under the table.</context>
      <utterance>I am! I am! I'm stopping it - slowly. You see! Look, I've stopped. Now we are going back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Back! Back! Listen - don't you know where you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are in the Residence of the Fartsbishop of Salzburg.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs delightedly, then addresses an imaginary Archbishop.</context>
      <utterance>Fartsbishop!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Grace, I've got something to tell you. I want to complain about this man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, tell him. Tell them all. They won't understand you anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because here everything goes backwards. People walk backwards, dance backwards, sing backwards, and talk backwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? People fart backwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think that's funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives a high pitched giggle.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I think it's brilliant. You've been doing it for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, ha, ha, ha.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sra-I'm-sick! Sra-I'm sick!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you are. You're very sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. Say it backwards, shit-wit. Sra-I'm-sick Say it backwards!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sra-I'm-sick. Sick - kiss I'm - my Kiss my! Sra-I'm-sick - Kiss my arse!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Em iram! Em iram!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not playing this game.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, this is serious. Say it backwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just say it - you'll see. It's very serious. Em iram! Em iram!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Iram - marry Em - marry me! No, no! You're a fiend. I'm not going to marry a fiend. A dirty fiend at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ui-vol-i-tub!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mood becomes suddenly softer. She kisses him. They embrace. Then he spoils it.</context>
      <utterance>Tub - but i-tub - but I vol - love but I love ui - You. I love you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tish-I'm tee. What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tish-I'm-tee.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eat</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shocked, she strikes at him. At the same moment the music starts in the salon next door. We hear the opening of the Serenade for Thirteen Wind Instruments, K.</context>
      <utterance>Eat my - ah!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaps up, disheveled and rumpled and runs out of the room. Salieri watches in amazement and disgust.</context>
      <utterance>My music! They've started! They've started without me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The music swells up and Salieri listens to it with eyes closed - amazed, transported - suddenly engulfed by the sound. Finally it fades down and away and changes into applause. Salieri opens his eyes. The audience is clearly delighted. Mozart bows to them, also delighted. Colloredo rises abruptly, and without looking at Mozart or applauding and leaves the Salon. Count Arco approaches the composer. Mozart turns to him, radiant.</context>
      <utterance>So that was he! That giggling, dirty- minded creature I'd just seen crawling on the floor. Mozart. The phenomenon whose legend had haunted my youth. Impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Follow me, please. The Archbishop would like a word.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows Arco out of the room, through a throng of admirers.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I think that went off remarkably well, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These Viennese certainly know good music when they hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His Grace is very angry with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They arrive at the door of Colloredo's private apartment.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arco opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>You are to come in here and ask his pardon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Grace.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Mozart. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why what, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I have to be humiliated in front of my guests by one of my own servants?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Humiliated?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The company watches this scene, deeply interested.</context>
      <utterance>How much provocation am I to endure from you? The more license I allow you, the more you take.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If His Grace is not satisfied with me, he can dismiss me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you to return immediately to Salzburg. Your father is waiting for you there patiently. I will speak to you further when I come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Your Grace! I mean with all humility, no. I would rather you dismissed me. It's obvious I don't satisfy.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He extends his hand to be kissed. Mozart does it with a furious grace, then leaves the room. As he opens the door we see:</context>
      <utterance>Then try harder, Mozart. I have no intention of dismissing you. You will remain in my service and learn your place. Go now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Suddenly the music snaps off. Mozart stands before him as he lays down the score.</context>
      <utterance>Extraordinary! On the page it looked nothing. The beginning simple, almost comic. Just a pulse - bassoons and basset horns - like a rusty squeezebox. Then suddenly - high above it - an oboe, a single note, hanging there unwavering, till a clarinet took over and sweetened it into a phrase of such delight! This was no composition by a performing monkey! This was a music I'd never heard. Filled with such longing, such unfulfillable longing, it had me trembling. It seemed to me that I was hearing a voice of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the score, bows, and struts briskly out of the room. Salieri stares uncomprehendingly after the jaunty little figure.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How good is he, this Mozart?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's remarkable, Majesty. I heard an extraordinary serious opera of his last month. Idomeneo, King of Crete.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That? A most tiresome piece. I heard it, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tiresome?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A young man trying to impress beyond his abilities. Too much spice. Too many notes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty, I thought it the most promising work I've heard in years.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-ha. Well then, we should make some effort to acquire him. We could use a good German composer in Vienna, surely?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agree, Majesty, but I'm afraid it's not possible. The young man is still in the pay of the Archbishop.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very small pay, I imagine. I'm sure he could be tempted with the right offer. Say, an opera in German for our National Theatre.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent, sire!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not German, I beg your Majesty! Italian is the proper language for opera. All educated people agree on that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-ha. What do you say, Chamberlain?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks defiantly at Orsini-Rosenberg.</context>
      <utterance>In my opinion, it is time we had a piece in our own language, sir. Plain German. For plain people.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-ha. Kapellmeister?</utterance>
   <speaker>BONNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty, I must agree with Herr Dirretore. Opera is an Italian art, solamente. German is - scusate - too bruta for singing, too rough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-ha. Court Composer, what do you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it is an interesting notion to keep Mozart in Vienna, Majesty. It should really infuriate the Archbishop beyond measure - if that is your Majesty's intention.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are cattivo, Court Composer.  I want to meet this young man. Chamberlain, arrange a pleasant welcome for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. There it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A servant admits LORL, a young lower-class girl, who appears carrying a basket in which is a box covered with a napkin. She has just come from the baker's shop.</context>
      <utterance>Si.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah! Here she comes. Fraulein Lorl, good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Greedily he unwraps the napkin and lifts the lid on the box.</context>
      <utterance>What have you got for me today? Let me see.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-ha! Siena macaroons - my favourites. Give my best thanks to the baker.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a biscuit and eats.</context>
      <utterance>I will, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Are you well today, Fraulein Lorl?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives a little curtsey, flattered and giggling and is shown out. Salieri turns back to his work, chewing. He plays through a complete line of the march. He smiles, pleased with the result.</context>
      <utterance>Bene! Bene!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He inclines his head to the Christ above the fireplace, and starts to play the whole march, including the phrase which pleased him.</context>
      <utterance>Grazie, Signore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Salesman puts the second wig on his head. Mozart pulls a face of doubt in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>And the other one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes it off and the other Salesman replaces it with the first wig on his head.</context>
      <utterance>And the other one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He giggles. The music stops.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, they're both so beautiful, I can't decide. Why don't I have two heads?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and comes into the salon, where another group awaits him. It consists of Von Strack, Orsini-Rosenberg, Bonno, Von Swieten and Salieri. The room contains several gilded chairs dotted about, and a forte-piano.</context>
      <utterance>Good, good, good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All bow and say, Good morning, Your Majesty!</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what do you have for me today?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty, Herr Mozart -</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, what about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-ha. Well. There it is. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He produces a paper.</context>
      <utterance>Majesty, I hope you won't think it improper, but I have written a little March of Welcome in his honour.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a charming idea. May I see?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a trifle, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I try it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Emperor goes to the instrument, sits and plays the first bars of it. Quite well.</context>
      <utterance>Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delightful, Court Composer. Would you permit me to play it as he comes in?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do me too much honour, Sire.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Majordomo bows and goes. The Emperor addresses himself to the march. He plays a wrong note.</context>
      <utterance>Let's have some fun.  Bring in Herr Mozart, please. But slowly, slowly. I need a minute to practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A-flat, Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-ha!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="61">
   <speaker>MAJORDOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart comes in eagerly. Immediately the march begins, played by His Majesty. All the courtiers stand, listening with admiration. Joseph plays well, but applies himself fiercely to the manuscript. Mozart, still bewildered, regards the scene, but does not seem to pay attention to the music itself. It finishes and all clap obsequiously.</context>
      <utterance>Herr Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bravo, Your Majesty!</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Emperor rises, pleased with himself. He snatches the manuscript off the stand and holds it in his hand for the rest of the scene.</context>
      <utterance>Well done, Sire!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He extends his hand. Mozart throws himself to his knees, and to Joseph's discomfort kisses the royal hand with fervour.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, gentlemen, a little less enthusiasm, I beg you. Ah, Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Embarrassed, Mozart bursts into a wild giggle. Joseph helps him out.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, please! It is not a holy relic.  You know we have met already? In this very room. Perhaps you won't remember it, you were only six years old.  He was giving the most brilliant little concert here. As he got off the stool, he slipped and fell. My sister Antoinette helped him up herself, and do you know what he did? Jumped straight into her arms and said, Will you marry me, yes or no?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Von Strack and Bonno nod.</context>
      <utterance>You know all these gentlemen, I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Baron Von Swieten.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a great admirer of yours, young man. Welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Director of our Opera. Count Orsini-Rosenberg.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orsini-Rosenberg nods without enthusiasm.</context>
      <utterance>Oh sir, yes! The honour is mine. Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And here is our illustrious Court Composer, Herr Salieri.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally! Such an immense joy. Diletto straordinario!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know your work well, Signore. Do you know I actually composed some variations on a melody of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mio caro Adone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A funny little tune, but it yielded some good things.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now he has returned the compliment. Herr Salieri composed that March of Welcome for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bows elaborately. Salieri inclines himself, dryly.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Oh, grazie, Signore! Sono commosso! E un onore per mo eccezionale. Compositore brilliante e famossissimo!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there it is. Now to business. Young man, we are going to commission an opera from you. What do you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did we vote in the end for German or Italian?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, actually, Sire, if you remember, we did finally incline to Italian.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did we?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think it was really decided, Director.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, German! German! Please let it be German.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why so?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I've already found the most wonderful libretto!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? Have I seen it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I - I don't think you have, Herr Director. Not yet. I mean, it's quite n - Of course, I'll show it to you immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you'd better.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what is it about? Tell us the story.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's actually quite amusing, Majesty. It's set - the whole thing is set in a - in a - He stops short with a little giggle.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a Pasha's Harem, Majesty. A Seraglio.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-ha.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean in Turkey?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why especially does it have to be in German?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He giggles again. Orsini-Rosenberg looks at him sourly.</context>
      <utterance>Well not especially. It can be in Turkish, if you really want. I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear fellow, the language is not finally the point. Do you really think that subject is quite appropriate for a national theatre?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? It's charming. I mean, I don't actually show concubines exposing their! their! It's not indecent!  It's highly moral, Majesty. It's full of proper German virtues. I swear it. Absolutely!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm glad to hear that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Sire, but what do you think these could be? Being a foreigner, I would love to learn.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cattivo again, Court Composer. Well, tell him, Mozart. Name us a German virtue.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love, Sire!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Italian faction - Orsini-Rosenberg and Bonno - laugh discreetly.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, love! Well of course in Italy we know nothing about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An embarrassed pause. Bonno giggles in nervous amusement.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't think you do. I mean watching Italian opera, all those male sopranos screeching. Stupid fat couples rolling their eyes about! That's not love - it's just rubbish.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Joseph is clearly pleased.</context>
      <utterance>Majesty, you choose the language. It will be my task to set it to the finest music ever offered a monarch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods - he has wanted this result all the time. He turns and makes for the door. All bow. Then he becomes aware of the manuscript in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there it is. Let it be German.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart does not take it.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, this is yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it, Sire, if you want to. It is already here in my head.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? On one hearing only?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>I think so, Sire, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart bows and hands the manuscript back to the Emperor. Then he goes to the forte-piano and seats himself. The others, except for Salieri, gather around the manuscript held by the King. Mozart plays the first half of the march with deadly accuracy.</context>
      <utterance>Show me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the courtiers look at Salieri.</context>
      <utterance>That really doesn't work, does it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plays another phrase.</context>
      <utterance>Did you try this? Wouldn't it be just a little more -?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plays another phrase. Gradually, he alters the music so that it turns into the celebrated march to be used later in The Marriage of Figaro, Non Piu Andrai. He plays it with increasing abandon and virtuosity. Salieri watches with a fixed smile on his face. The court watches, astonished. He finishes in great glory, takes his hands off the keys with a gesture of triumph - and grins.</context>
      <utterance>Or this - yes, this! Better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a knock at the door. He does not hear it, but sits on. Another knock, louder.</context>
      <utterance>Grazie, Signore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lorl comes in.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame Cavalieri is here for her lesson, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and enters:</context>
      <utterance>Bene.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maestro.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well? How do you like it? It's Turkish. My hairdresser tells me everything's going to be Turkish this year!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? What else did he tell you today? Give me some gossip.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I heard you met Herr Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? News travels fast in Vienna.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he's been commissioned to write an opera. Is it true?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a part for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well even if there is, I don't think you want to get involved with this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, do you know where it's set, my dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a harem.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A brothel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Turkish brothel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turkish? Oh, if it's Turkish, that's different. I want to be in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seats himself at the forte-piano.</context>
      <utterance>My dear, it will hardly enhance your reputation to be celebrated throughout Vienna as a singing prostitute for a Turk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well perhaps you could introduce us anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plays a chord. She sings a scale, expertly. He strikes another chord. She starts another scale, then breaks off.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might be disappointed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks and talent don't always go together, Katherina.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a few moments of this showy aria, with the composer and the singer staring at each other - he conducting elaborately for her benefit, and she following his beat with rapturous eyes - the music fades, and Salieri speaks over it.</context>
      <utterance>Since you are determined, Since you are determined, Calmly, with no ferment, Welcome - every pain and woe. Bind me then - compel me! Bind me then - compel me! Hurt me. Break me! Kill me! At last I shall be freed by death!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Music up again for the last 30 bars of the aria.</context>
      <utterance>There she was. I had no idea where they met - or how - yet there she stood on stage for all to see. Showing off like the greedy songbird she was. Ten minutes of ghastly scales and arpeggios, whizzing up and down like fireworks at a fairground.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before the orchestral coda ends, cut to:</context>
      <utterance>Be freed at last by death! Be freed at last by death! At last I shall be freed By! Death!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Understand, I was in love with the girl. Or at least in lust. I wasn't a saint. It took me the most tremendous effort to be faithful to my vow. I swear to you I never laid a finger on her. All the same, I couldn't bear to think of anyone else touching her - least of all the Creature.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bravo, Madame. You are an ornament to our stage.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And to you, Court Composer. Your pupil has done you great credit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let us pass, please! Let us pass at once! We're with the Emperor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLUNKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry, Madame. It is not permitted.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know who I am?  This is my daughter. I am Frau Weber. We are favoured guests!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLUNKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry, Madame, but I have my orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call Herr Mozart! You call Herr Mozart immediately! This is insupportable!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, Constanze. Just ignore this fellow.  Go ahead, dear!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLUNKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry, Madame, but no! I cannot let anyone pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Young man, I am no stranger to theatres. I'm no stranger to insolence!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart bows frantically: he is over-excited.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Herr Mozart! A good effort. Decidedly that. An excellent effort! You've shown us something quite new today.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is new, it is, isn't it, Sire?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, indeed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And German?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. Absolutely. German. Unquestionably!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So then you like it? You really like it, Your Majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I do. It's very good. Of course now and then - just now and then - it gets a touch elaborate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, Sire?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I mean occasionally it seems to have, how shall one say?  How shall one say, Director?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too many notes, Your Majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Very well put. Too many notes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. There are just as many notes, Majesty, as are required. Neither more nor less.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear fellow, there are in fact only so many notes the ear can hear in the course of an evening. I think I'm right in saying that, aren't I, Court Composer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! yes! er, on the whole, yes, Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this is absurd!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear, young man, don't take it too hard. Your work is ingenious. It's quality work. And there are simply too many notes, that's all. Cut a few and it will be perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. General embarrassment.</context>
      <utterance>Which few did you have in mind, Majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Into this uncomfortable scene bursts a sudden eruption of noise and Madame Weber floods onto the stage, followed by her daughters. All turn to look at this amazing spectacle.</context>
      <utterance>Well. There it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves toward Mozart with arms outstretched in an absurd theatrical gesture, then sees the Emperor. She stares at him, mesmerized, her mouth open, unable even to curtsey.</context>
      <utterance>Wolfi! Wolfi, my dear!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart moves forward quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty, this is Madame Weber. She is my landlady.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enchanted, Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Constanze curtsies. CU, of Cavalieri, astonished at the news. CU, of Salieri, watching her receive it.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Sire! such an honour! And, and, and these are my dear daughters. This is Constanze. She is the fiancee of Herr Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? How delightful. May I ask when you marry?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He giggles uncomfortably.</context>
      <utterance>Well - Well we haven't quite received my father's consent, Your Majesty. Not entirely. Not altogether.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but how old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-six.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, my advice is to marry this charming young lady and stay with us in Vienna.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cavalieri is glaring at Mozart. Mozart looks hastily away from her.</context>
      <utterance>You see? You see? I've told him that, Your Majesty, but he won't listen to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She attempts to kiss the royal hand, but faints instead. The Emperor contemplates her prone body and steps back a pace.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Your Majesty, you give such wonderful - such impeccable - such royal advice. I - I - May I?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods pleasantly to all and leaves the stage, with his Chamberlain. All bow. Cavalieri turns with a savage look at Mozart and leaves the stage the opposite way, to her dressing room, tossing her plumed head. Salieri watches. Mozart stays for a second, indecisive whether to follow the soprano or help Madame Weber.</context>
      <utterance>Well. There it is. Strack.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries away. The daughters gather around Madame Weber.</context>
      <utterance>Get some water!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Katherina! I'll tell you what I'm going to do. I'm going to write another aria for you. Something even more amazing for the second act. I have to get some water. Her mother is lying on the stage.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bother!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dashes off.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instead of being furious, Madame Weber smiles at them rapturously.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The activity continues to swirl around them.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, what an evening! What a wise man we have for an Emperor. Oh, my children!  Now I want you to write your father exactly what His Majesty said.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should really go home now, Frau Weber. Your carriage must be waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But aren't you taking us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to talk to the singers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME WEBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right; we'll wait for you. Just don't take all night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know? Had you heard?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The marriage!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what does it matter to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She catches him looking at her and tries to compose herself.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing! He can marry who he pleases. I don't give a damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was I? Tell me honestly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were sublime.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you think of the music?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Extremely clever.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart comes in unexpectedly.</context>
      <utterance>Meaning you didn't like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh - excuse me!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is her mother still lying on the floor?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, she's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seats herself at her mirror and removes her wig.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so relieved.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Mozart, my sincere congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you like it, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It really is the best music one can hear in Vienna today. Don't you agree?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she a good fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What??</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri looks astonished. There is a knock on the door.</context>
      <utterance>I assume she's the virtuoso in that department. There can't be any other reason you'd marry someone like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens. Constanze enters.</context>
      <utterance>Come in!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Wolfi. Mama is not feeling very well. Can we leave now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no, no. You can't take him away now. This is his night. Won't you introduce us, Wolfgang?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart hurries Constanze out of the door. Cavalieri looks after them as they go, her voice breaking and rising out of control.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse us, Fraulein. Good night, Signore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAVALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and collapses, crying with rage, into Salieri's arms. We focus on him.</context>
      <utterance>You really are full of surprises, aren't you? You are quite extraordinary, you little shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At that moment I knew beyond any doubt. He'd had her. The Creature had had my darling girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was incomprehensible. What was God up to? Here I was denying all my natural lust in order to deserve God's gift and there was Mozart indulging his in all directions - even though engaged to be married! - and no rebuke at all! Was it possible I was being tested? Was God expecting me to offer forgiveness in the face of every offense, no matter how painful? That was very possible. All the same, why him? Why use Mozart to teach me lessons in humility? My heart was filling up with such hatred for that little man. For the first time in my life I began to know really violent thoughts. I couldn't stop them.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you try?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every day. Sometimes for hours I would pray!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I won't have him back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he needs to be here in Salzburg, Your Grace. He needs me and he needs you. Your protection, your understanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hardly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh sir, yes! He's about to make the worst mistake of his life. Some little Viennese slut is trying to trick him into marriage. I know my son. He is too simple to see the trap - and there is no one there who really cares for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not surprised. Money seems to be more important to him than loyalty or friendship. He has sold himself to Vienna. Let Vienna look out for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir -</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your son is an unprincipled, spoiled, conceited brat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir, that's the truth. But don't blame him. The fault is mine. I was too indulgent with him. But not again. Never again, I promise! I implore you - let me bring him back here. I'll make him give his word to serve you faithfully.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how will you make him keep it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, sir, he's never disobeyed me in anything. Please, Your Grace, give him one more chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLOREDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have leave to try.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In deepest gratitude he kisses the Archbishop's hand. He motions Leopold to rise. We hear the first dark fortissimo chord which begins the Overture to Don Giovanni: the theme associated with the character of the Commendatore.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Your Grace - I thank Your Grace! I thank you!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The second fortissimo chord sounds.</context>
      <utterance>My dear son.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I write to you with urgent news. I am coming to Vienna. Take no further steps toward marriage until we meet. You are too gullible to see your own danger. As you honour the father who has devoted his entire life to yours, do as I bid, and await my coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera pulls back to see that he is in fact kneeling beside Constanze. A PRIEST faces them. Behind them are Madame Weber, Josefa and Sophie Weber, and a very few others. Among them, a merry looking lady in bright clothes: the BARONESS</context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And will you, Constanze Weber, take this man, Wolfgang to be your lawful husband?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The opening kyrie of the great Mass in C Minor is heard. Mozart and Constanze kiss. They are in tears. Madame Weber and her daughters look on approvingly. The music swells and continues under the following:</context>
      <utterance>I now pronounce you man and wife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Court Composer. This is my niece, the Princess Elizabeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of breath, the Princess nods nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Your Highness.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at Salieri.</context>
      <utterance>She has asked me to advise her on a suitable musical instructor. I think I've come up with an excellent idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Your Majesty, it would be such a tremendous honour!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri's face falls, almost imperceptibly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking about Herr Mozart. What is your view?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An interesting idea, Majesty. But -</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You already commissioned an opera from Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the result satisfies.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course. My concern is to protect you from any suspicion of favouritism.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-ha. Favouritism. But I so want Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure there is a way, Majesty. Some kind of a little contest. I could perhaps put together a small Committee, and I could see to it naturally that it will select according to Your Majesty's wishes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You please me, Court Composer. A very clever idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sire.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rides on. The groom releases her horse's head, and runs on after the Princess.</context>
      <utterance>Well. There it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this, Herr Chamberlain?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I have to submit samples of my work to some stupid committee? Just to teach a sixteen-year-old girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because His Majesty wishes it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the Emperor angry with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the contrary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why doesn't he simply appoint me to the post?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart, you are not the only composer in Vienna.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I'm the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little modesty would suit you better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is on this committee?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kapellmeister Bonno, Count Orsini- Rosenberg and Court Composer Salieri.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naturally, the Italians! Of course! Always the Italians!</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart -</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They hate my music. It terrifies them. The only sound Italians understand is banality. Tonic and dominant, tonic and dominant, from here to Resurrection!  Ba-ba! Ba-ba! Ba-ba! Ba-ba! Anything else is morbid.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart -</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show them one interesting modulation and they faint. Ohime! Morbidezza! Morbidezza! Italians are musical idiots and you want them to judge my music!</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, young man, the issue is simple. If you want this post, you must submit your stuff in the same way as all your colleagues.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must I? Well, I won't! I tell you straight: I will not!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're mad! You're really mad!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One royal pupil and the whole of Vienna will come flocking. We'd be set up for life!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll come anyway. They love me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they will not. I know how things work in this city.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes? You always know everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm not borrowing any more money from my mother, and that's that!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You borrowed money from your mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, don't do that again!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are we going to live, Wolfi? Do you want me to go into the streets and beg?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All they want to see is your work. What's wrong with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Just shut up! I don't need them.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glares at him, almost in tears.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't pride. It's sheer stupidity!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SERVANT enters.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir, there is a lady who insists on talking to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't say. But she says it's urgent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri goes into the salon.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, my dear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellency!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shyly, she unveils.</context>
      <utterance>Madame. How can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frau Mozart?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, Your Excellency. I've come on behalf of my hus band. I'm - I'm bringing some samples of his work so he can be considered for the royal appointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How charming. But why did he not come himself?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's terribly busy, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the portfolio and puts it on a table.</context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will look at them, of course, the moment I can. It will be an honour. Please give him my warmest.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would it be too much trouble, sir, to ask you to look at them now? While I wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I'm not at leisure this very moment. Just leave them with me. I assure you they will be quite safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I - I really cannot do that, Your Excellency. You see, he doesn't know I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My husband is a proud man, sir. He would be furious if he knew I'd come.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then he didn't send you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir. This is my own idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A short pause.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, we really need this job. We're desperate. My husband spends far more than he can ever earn. I don't mean he's lazy - he's not at all - he works all day long. It's just! he's not practical. Money simply slips through his fingers, it's really ridiculous, Your Excellency. I know you help musicians. You're famous for it. Give him just this one post. We'd be forever indebted!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He indicates a dish piled high with glazed chestnuts.</context>
      <utterance>Let me offer you some refreshment. Do you know what these are?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers her the dish. She takes one and puts it in her mouth. He watches carefully.</context>
      <utterance>Cappezzoli di Venere. Nipples of Venus. Roman chestnuts in brandied sugar. Won't you try one? They're quite surprising.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes one himself. We notice on his finger a heavy gold signet-ring.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! They're wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much, Your Excellency.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't keep calling me that. It puts me at such a distance. I was not born a Court Composer, you know. I'm from a small town, just like your husband. He smiles at her. She takes another chestnut.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you can't leave that music, and come back again? I have other things you might like.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very tempting, but it's impossible, I'm afraid. Wolfi would be frantic if he found those were missing. You see, they're all originals.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Originals?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. He puts out his hand and takes up the portfolio from the table. He opens it. He looks at the music. He is puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are originals?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. He doesn't make copies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vogler stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Astounding! It was actually beyond belief. These were first and only drafts of music yet they showed no corrections of any kind. Not one. Do you realize what that meant?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'd simply put down music already finished in his head. Page after page of it, as if he was just taking dictation. And music finished as no music is ever finished.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The music swells. What we now hear is an amazing collage of great passages from Mozart's music, ravishing to Salieri and to us. The Court Composer, oblivious to Constanze, who sits happily chewing chestnuts, her mouth covered in sugar, walks around and around his salon, reading the pages and dropping them on the floor when he is done with them. We see his agonized and wondering face: he shudders as if in a rough and tumbling sea; he experiences the point where beauty and great pain coalesce. More pages fall than he can read, scattering across the floor in a white cascade, as he circles the room. Finally, we hear the tremendous Qui Tollis from the Mass in C Minor. It seems to break over him like a wave and, unable to bear any more of it, he slams the portfolio shut. Instantly, the music breaks off, reverberating in his head. He stands shaking, staring wildly. Constanze gets up, perplexed.</context>
      <utterance>Displace one note and there would be diminishment. Displace one phrase, and the structure would fall. It was clear to me. That sound I had heard in the Archbishop's palace had been no accident. Here again was the very voice of God! I was staring through the cage of those meticulous ink- strokes at an absolute, inimitable beauty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Is it no good?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is miraculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another pause.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes. He's really proud of his work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri tries to recover himself.</context>
      <utterance>So, will you help him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow night I dine with the Emperor. One word from me and the post is his.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Overjoyed, she stops and kisses his hand. He raises her - and then clasps her to him clumsily. She pushes herself away.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some service deserves service in return. No?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at one another: Constanze in total disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't it obvious?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a post all Vienna seeks. If you want it for your husband, come tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But! I'm a married woman!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glares at her.</context>
      <utterance>Then don't. It's up to you. Not to be vague, that is the price.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rings a silver bell for a servant and abruptly leaves the roam. Constanze stares after him, horrified. The servant enters. Shocked and stunned, Constanze goes down an her knees and starts picking up the music from the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Father. Yes! So much for my vow of chastity. What did it matter? Good, patient, hard-working, chaste - what did it matter? Had goodness made me a good composer? I realized it absolutely then - that moment: goodness is nothing in the furnace of art. And I was nothing to God.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cannot say that!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? Was Mozart a good man?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God's ways are not yours. And you are not here to question Him. Offer him the salt of penitence. He will give you back the bread of eternal life. He is all merciful. That is all you need to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I ever wanted was to sing to Him. That's His doing, isn't it? He gave me that longing - then made me mute. Why? Tell me that. If He didn't want me to serve Him with music, why implant the desire, like a lust in my body, then deny me the talent? Go on, tell me! Speak for Him!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son, no one can speak for God.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? I thought you did so every day. So speak now. Answer me!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not claim to unravel the mysteries. I treasure them. As you should.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, yes, yes, yes, yes! Always the same stale answers!  There is no God of Mercy, Father. Just a God of torture.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evening came to that room. I sat there not knowing whether the girl would return or not. I prayed as I'd never prayed before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long, long silence. Salieri stares at the cross. Christ stares back at him impassively. Finally in this silence we hear a faint knocking at the door. Salieri stirs himself. A servant appears.</context>
      <utterance>Dear God, enter me now. Fill me with one piece of true music. One piece with your breath in it, so I know that you love me. Please. Just one. Show me one sign of your favour, and I will show mine to Mozart and his wife. I will get him the royal position, and if she comes, I'll receive her with all respect and send her home in joy. Enter me! Enter me! Please! Te imploro.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That lady is back, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Servant bows and leaves. We follow him through:</context>
      <utterance>Show her in. Then go to bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm here. My husband has gone to a concert. He didn't think I would enjoy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do apologize for this afternoon. I behaved like a silly girl. Where shall we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she talks, she extinguishes the candles in a pair of Venetian candelabra and subsequently other candles around the room.</context>
      <utterance>Should we stay here? It's a charming room. I love these candlesticks. Were they here earlier? I didn't notice them I suppose I was too nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and takes off her shawl.</context>
      <utterance>Wolfgang was given some candlesticks by King George in England, but they were only wood. Oh, excuse me. Let's not talk about him. What do you think of this? It's real lace. Brussels.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up the portfolio.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's much too good for every day. I keep saying to Wolfi, don't be so extravagant. Presents are lovely, but we can't afford them. It doesn't do any good. The more I tell him, the more he spends. Oh, excuse me! There I go again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him inquiringly, and drops the portfolio on the floor; pages of music pour out of it. Instantly we hear a massive chord, and the great Qui Tollis from the Mass in C Minor fills the room. To its grand and weighty sound, Constanze starts to undress, watched by the horrified Salieri. Between him and her, music is an active presence, hurting and baffling him. He opens his mouth in distress. The music pounds in his head. The candle flickers over her as she removes her clothes and prepares for his embrace. Suddenly he cries out.</context>
      <utterance>Do you still want to look at this? Or don't we need to bother anymore? I imagine we don't, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snatches up the bell and shakes it frantically, not stopping until the two servants we saw earlier appear at the door. The music stops abruptly. They stare at the appalled and frightened Constanze, who is desperately trying to cover her nakedness.</context>
      <utterance>Go! Go! Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Constanze hurls herself at him.</context>
      <utterance>Show this woman out!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seizes her wrists and thrusts her back. Then he leaves the room quickly, slamming the door behind him. Constanze turns and sees the two servants goggling at her in the room.</context>
      <utterance>You shit! You shit! You rotten shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wildly, she picks up the candelabrum and throws it at them. It shatters on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>What are you staring at?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Stanzi! Stanzi! Stanzi-Manzi!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sssh!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stanzi-Manzi-Banzi-Wanzi!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks unsteadily to the bedroom door and opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Sssh! Stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sssh! You're dishgrashful!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches the bed and sits on it. Immediately she starts crying again, desperately.</context>
      <utterance>Stanzi!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds her and she clings to him in a fierce embrace, crying a flood of tears.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? What is it? Stanzi!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it now. Stop it. I've brought some friends to meet you. They're next door waiting. Do we have anything to eat? They're all starving.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them to go away. I don't want to see anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them to go!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sssh. What is it? Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts crying again, throwing her arms around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>I love you! I love you!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you. Please stay with me. I'm frightened.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you understand me, Court Composer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty, I did. Believe me, it was a most agonizing. decision. But finally, I simply could not recommend Herr Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Sire, I made some inquiries in a routine way. I was curious to know why he had so few pupils. It is rather alarming.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a gesture Joseph dismisses the butler, who bows and leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty, I don't like to talk against a fellow musician.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to tell you, Mozart is not entirely to be trusted alone with young ladies.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact, one of my own pupils - a very young singer - told me she was - er - well!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Molested, Majesty. Twice, in the course of the same lesson.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-ha. Well. There it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri is plainly alarmed.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, there is a Herr Mozart waiting for you in the salon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he want?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't say, sir. I told him I didn't know when you would be back, but he insisted on waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He mounts the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Come with me. And stay in the room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herr Mozart, what brings you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Excellency, you requested some specimens of my work. Here they are. I don't have to tell you how much I need your help. I truly appreciate your looking at these. I have pressures on me - financial pressures. As you know, I'm a married man now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you are. How is your pretty wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is well. She is - well, actually, I'm about to become a father! She only told me last night. You are the first to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm flattered. And congratulations to you, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri looks at him in distress.</context>
      <utterance>So you see, this post is very important to me right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you come to me yesterday, Mozart? This is a most painful situation. Yesterday I could have helped you. Today, I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Here is the music. It's here. I am submitting it humbly. Isn't that what you wanted?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have just come from the palace. The post has been filled.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Filled? That's impossible! They haven't even seen my work. I need this post. Please, can't you help me? Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear Mozart, there is no one in the world I would rather help, but now it is too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whom did they choose?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herr Sommer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sommer? Herr Sommer? But the man's a fool! He's a total mediocrity.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no: he has yet to achieve mediocrity.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I can't lose this post, I simply can't! Excellency, please. Let's go to the palace, and you can explain to the Emperor that Herr Sommer is an awful choice. He could actually do musical harm to the Princess!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart chuckles delightedly. Salieri offers him a glass of white dessert and a spoon. Mozart takes it absently and goes on talking.</context>
      <utterance>An implausible idea. Between you and me, no one in the world could do musical harm to the Princess Elizabeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I must have pupils. Without pupils I can't manage.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't mean to tell me you are living in poverty?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I'm broke. I'm always broke. I don't know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has been said, my friend, that you are inclined to live somewhat above your means.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can anyone say that? We have no cook, no maid. We have no footman. Nothing at all!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is that possible? You give concerts, don't you? I hear they are quite successful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're stupendously successful. You can't get a seat. The only problem is none will hire me. They all want to hear me play, but they won't let me teach their daughters. As if I was some kind of fiend. I'm not a fiend!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, could you lend me some money till you have one? Then I'll teach her for free. That's a promise. Oh, I'm sorry. I'm being silly. Papa's right - I should put a padlock on my mouth. Seriously, is there any chance you could manage a loan? Only for six months, eight at most. After that I'll be the richest man in Vienna. I'll pay you back double. Anything. Name your terms. I'm not joking. I'm working on something that's going to explode like a bomb all over Europe!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, how exciting! Tell me more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd better not. It's a bit of a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come, come, Mozart; I'm interested. Truly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, it's a big secret. Oh, this is delicious! What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cream cheese mixed with granulated sugar and suffused with rum. Crema al Mascarpone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah. Italian?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me. We all have patriotic feelings of some kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two thousand, two hundred florins is all I need A hundred? Fifty?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What exactly are you working on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't say. Really</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you should become known in Vienna as a debtor, Mozart. However, I know a very distinguished gentleman I could recommend to you. And he has a daughter. Will that do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet! Quiet! Quiet! Down there, damn you.  Welcome to you. Pay no attention, they're impossible. Stop it, you willful things! Come this way. Just ignore them. They're perfectly harmless, just willful. I treat them just like my own children.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And which one of them do you want me to teach?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads Mozart through the throng of dogs into a salon furnished with comfortable middle-class taste.</context>
      <utterance>What? Ha-ha! That's funny - I like it. Which one, eh? You're a funny fellow.  Hannah! Come this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRAU SCHLUMBERG appears: an anxious woman in middle life.</context>
      <utterance>Hannah!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't be teaching this one either. She's my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Herr Mozart, my dear. The young man Herr Salieri recommended to teach our Gertrude. Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Upstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gertrude!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't be Herr Mozart!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, it's him. Who do you think it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard about you for ages! I thought you must be an old man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gertrude!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's such an honour for us to have you here, Herr Mozart. And for Gertrude.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People who know say the girl's got talent. You must judge for yourself. If you think she stinks, say so.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael, please! I'm sure you will find her most willing, Herr Mozart. She's really very excited. She's been preparing all morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GERTRUDE SCHLUMBERG appears in the doorway: an awkward girl of fifteen in her best dress, her hair primped and curled. She is exceedingly nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, now! Here she comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Fraulein Schlumberg.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gertrude giggles instead.</context>
      <utterance>Strudel, this is Herr Mozart. Say good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps a little refreshment first? A little coffee, or a little chocolate?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like a little wine, if you have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wine?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads the way into:</context>
      <utterance>Quite right. He's going to need it.  Klaus! A bottle of wine. Prestissimo! Now let's go to it. I've been waiting all day for this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now sit down all of you and behave. Zeman, Mandi, absolutely quiet!  Especially you, Dudelsachs - not one sound from you. The dogs settle at their feet. Husband and wife smile encouragingly at each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart gestures to the music bench. Reluctantly, the girl sits at the instrument. Mozart sits beside her.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, then. Up and at it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, please play me something. Just to give me an idea. Anything will do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERTRUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right, dear. Just go ahead, as if we weren't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERTRUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you are here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind, Strudel. It's part of music, getting used to an audience. Aren't I right, Herr Mozart?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes! on the whole. I suppose.  How long have you been playing, Fraulein?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just one year.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was your teacher?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was. But she quite outgrew the little I could show her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In response the wretched girl just stares down at the keyboard without playing a note. An awkward pause.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Madame.  Come on now - courage. Play me something you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Husband and wife look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps it would be better if we were left alone. I think we're both a little shy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. The girl sits unmoving. Schlumberg bellows:</context>
      <utterance>Nonsense. Strudel's not shy. She's just willful! You give into her now, you'll be sorry later. Strudel - play.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said play!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the girl rises. Mozart smiles at the parents. They smile nervously back. Mozart slides along the bench, raises his hands and preludes over the keys. Instantly a dog howls loudly. Startled, Mozart stops. Schlumberg leaps to his feet and goes over to the beagle.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps if I were to play a little first, it might encourage the Fraulein.  Why don't you let me try the instrument? All right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart resumes playing. This time it is a lively piece, perhaps the Presto Finale from the K. 450. The dog howls immediately.</context>
      <utterance>Stop that, Dudelsachs! Stop it at once!  Don't let him disturb you. He'll be all right. He's just a little willful too. Please, please - play. I beg you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart stops.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it! STOP!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amazed, Mozart starts to play the Rondo again. The dog howls louder.</context>
      <utterance>No, not you. I was talking to the dog. You keep playing. It's most important. He always howls when he hears music. We've got to break them of the habit. Play, please. Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart plays on. Suddenly the dog falls silent. Schlumberg smiles broadly.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. Now keep going, just keep going.  Now you stop that noise, Dudelsachs, you stop it this instant! This instant, do you hear me? Keep going, Herr Mozart, that's it. Go on, go on!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wife scurries to get a jar of biscuits. A servant brings in an open bottle of wine and a full glass on a tray. He puts it down beside Mozart as Schlumberg addresses the silent dog with deepest affection.</context>
      <utterance>Good, good, good! Very good dog! Very, very good Dudelsachs.  Quick, quick, dear, bring his biscuit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives the biscuit to the dog who swallows it greedily. Mozart stops playing and stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Now guess who's going to get a nice reward? Clever, clever Dudi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a miracle, Herr Mozart!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bows to them and leaves the room. They look after him in puzzled astonishment.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm a good teacher. The next time you wish me to instruct another of your dogs, please let me know. Goodbye, Fraulein, goodbye, Madame! goodbye, Sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a strange young man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. He is a little strange.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="51">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I not welcome?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, welcome! Welcome ten thousand times. Papa! my Papa!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart ducks away and fetches his father's bags from the landing.</context>
      <utterance>You're very thin. Does she not feed you, this wife of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feed? Well, of course she feeds me. She stuffs me like a goose all day long. She's the best cook in the world. I mean, since Mama. Just wait, you'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she not here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leopold looks about him at the mess in the room.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Stanzi? Stanzi!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you always live like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He carries the bag across the room and opens the door of the bedroom. Constanze lies in bed. She sits up, startled.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. Oh, I mean no - not exactly like this. I mean today - just today, Stanzi - I remember now. She had to go - yes! She had to help her mother. Yes, she's like that. Her mother's a very sweet woman, you'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Constanze, who looks ill and tired, stares at Leopold. Leopold stares back from the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! I didn't know you were home. Stanzi, this is my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the door again.</context>
      <utterance>We'll wait, we'll wait. Why don't you get up now, darling?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's very tired, poor creature. You know me: I'm a real pig. It's not so easy cleaning up after me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have a maid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh we could, if we wanted to, but Stanzi won't hear of it. She wants to do everything herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is your financial situation?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It couldn't be better.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what I hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? It's wonderful. Really, it's - it's marvelous! People love me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say you're in debt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who? Who says that? Now that's a malicious lie!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many pupils do you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pupils?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It's not important. I mean, I don't want pupils. They get in the way. I've got to have time for composition.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Composition doesn't pay. You know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up some pages of manuscript.</context>
      <utterance>This one will.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, let's not talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have secrets from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Constanze comes into the room. She is wearing a dressing gown and has made a perfunctory attempt to tidy her hair. We see that she is clearly pregnant.</context>
      <utterance>It's too dangerous, Papa. But they're going to love it. Ah, there she is!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Stanzi - look at her! Isn't she beautiful? Come on now, confess, Papa. Could you want a prettier girl for a daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it, Wolfi. I look dreadful. Welcome to our house, Herr Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not Herr Mozart. Call him Papa.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see that you're expecting.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When, may I ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In three months! Papa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that marvelous? We're delighted.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you mention it in your letters?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives a little giggle of embarrassment.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't I? I thought I did. I'm sure I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I offer you some tea, Herr Mozart?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tea? Who wants tea? Let's go out! This calls for a feast. You don't want tea, Papa. Let's go dancing. Papa loves parties, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wolfi!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? How can you be so boring? Tea!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wolfi, I think your father's tired. I'll cook us something here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. That'll be fine. Don't spend any money on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The jaunty tune of Ich Mochte Wohl Der Kaiser sein (K.539) sounds through all the following. This is an alternate song from Il Seraglio: a very extroverted tune for baritone and orchestra and a prominent part for bass drum. The vocal part should be arranged for trumpet.</context>
      <utterance>Why not? Oh, come, Papa! What better way could I spend it than on you? My kissable, missable, suddenly visible Papa!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People are delighted by the idea of this penalty. The children jump up and down with excitement. The three actresses immediately surround Leopold, reaching for his hat and mask and wig, whilst he tries to hold on to them. Mozart takes off Constanze's wig - an absurd affair with side-curls. Constanze laughingly surrenders it.</context>
      <utterance>No, no! You both lost. You both lost. You both have to forfeit. And the penalty is you must exchange your wigs.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite his protests an actress takes off his hat, to which the smiling mask is attached, to reveal his outraged face showing a very different expression underneath. Another actress snatches off his wig to reveal very sparse hair on the old man's head. The third actress takes Constanze's wig from Mozart and attempts to put it on his father's head.</context>
      <utterance>No, please! This is ridiculous! No, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, really!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Constanze echoes him with a touch of malice in her voice.</context>
      <utterance>This is just a game, Papa.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughingly, the bystanders take it up, especially the children.</context>
      <utterance>This is just a game, Papa!</utterance>
   <speaker>BYSTANDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Leopold glares furiously about him, the actress succeeds in getting Constanze's wig firmly onto his head. Everybody bursts into applause. Delightedly, Constanze puts on Leopold's wig, hat and mask: from the waist up she now looks like a weird parody of Leopold in the smiling grey mask, and he looks like a weird parody of her in the silly feminine wig. Schikaneder starts to play again, and the couples start to dance. Leopold angrily takes off Constanze's wig and leaves the circle; his partner, Constanze, is left alone. Seeing this, Mozart leaves his partner and catches his father entreatingly by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>This is just a game, Papa!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off his own wig and puts it on Leopold's uncovered head. The effect, if not as ridiculous, is still somewhat bizarre, since Wolfgang favours fairly elaborate wigs. He takes Constanze's wig from his father. As this happens, the music stops again. Mozart gently pushes his father down onto a nearby chair; the others scramble for the other chairs; and he is left as the Odd Man Out. He giggles. Schikaneder calls out to Leopold from the keyboard.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no, Papa, please! Don't spoil the fun. Come on. Here, take mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Applause.</context>
      <utterance>Herr Mozart, why don't you name your son's penalty?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Papa, name it. Name it. I'll do anything you say!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to come back with me to Salzburg, my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say? What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papa, the rule is you can only give penalties that can be performed in the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm tired of this game. Please play without me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the bystanders are watching.</context>
      <utterance>But my penalty. I've got to have a penalty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart runs over to the forte-piano, and Schikaneder surrenders his place at it.</context>
      <utterance>I've got a good one. I've got the perfect one for you. Come over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Applause.</context>
      <utterance>Now, I want you to play our tune - sitting backwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amused sounds of disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's really too easy. Any child can do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renewed applause at this wicked extra penalty. Mozart smiles at Schikaneder - it is the sort of challenge he loves. He defiantly puts on Constanze's wig and seats himself with his back to the keyboard. Before the astonished eyes of the company he proceeds to execute this absurdly difficult task. His right hand plays the bass part, his left hand the treble, and with this added difficulty he improvises a brilliant fugue on the subject of the tune to which they have been dancing. Attracted by this astonishing feat, the players draw nearer to the instrument. So does Salieri, cautiously, with some of the bystanders. Constanze watches him approach. Only Leopold sits by himself, sulking. The fugue ends amidst terrific clapping. The guests call out to Mozart.</context>
      <utterance>And a fugue in the manner of Sebastian Bach.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUESTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another! Do another! Someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a name. Who shall I do? Give me a name.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUESTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gluck! Haydn! Frederic Handel!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SMASH CUT: Salieri's masked face whips around and looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Salieri! Do Salieri!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For Salieri one has to face the right way around. Giggling, he turns around and sits at the keyboard. Then, watched by a highly amused group, he begins a wicked parody. He furrows his brow in mock concentration and closes his eyes. Then he begins to play the tune to which they danced, in the most obvious way imaginable, relying heavily on a totally and offensively unimaginative bass of tonic and dominant, endlessly repeated. The music is the very essence of banality. The bystanders rock with laughter. Mozart starts to giggle wildly. Through this excruciating scene, Salieri stares at Constanze, who suddenly turns her head and looks challengingly back at him. Mozart's parody reaches its coarse climax with him adding a fart noise instead of notes to end cadences. He builds this up, urged on in his clowning by everyone else, until suddenly he stops and cries out. The laughter cuts off. Mozart stands up, clutching his behind as if he has made a mess in his breeches. The momentary hush of alarm is followed by a howl of laughter. CU, Salieri staring in pain.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's hard. That's very hard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The music breaks off.</context>
      <utterance>Wolfi! Wolfgang!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a young girl to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does she want?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, ask her!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She won't talk to me. She says she has to speak to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, damn!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you Herr Mozart?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Lorl, sir. I'm a maidservant. I was asked to come here and offer my services to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll be paid for by a great admirer or yours who wishes to remain anon - anonymous.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? What admirer?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you that, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you saying that someone is paying you to be our maid and doesn't want us to know who he is?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart turns to his father.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I can live in or out just as you wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papa, is this your idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man emerges from his bedroom. His son looks at him delightedly.</context>
      <utterance>Mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you playing a trick on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never saw this girl in my life.  Is this a kind of joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all, sir. And I was told to wait for an answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Young woman, this won't do at all. My son can't possibly accept such an offer, no matter how generous, unless he knows who is behind it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I really can't tell you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is ridiculous? Wolfi has many admirers in Vienna. They love him here. People send us gifts all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you can't take her without reference. It's unheard of!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this is none of your business.  Whoever sent you is going to pay, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Constanze looks furiously at him, then at Lorl.</context>
      <utterance>So now we are going to let a perfect stranger into the house?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is we? Who is letting who?  Could you please wait outside?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lorl goes outside and closes the door. Constanze turns on Leopold.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, old man, you stay out of this. We spend a fortune on you, more than we can possibly afford, and all you do is criticize, morning to night. And then you think you can -</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stanzi!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's right he should hear. I'm sick to death of it. We can't do anything right for you, can we?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind. You won't have to do anything for me ever again. I'm leaving!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papa!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I'm not staying here to be a burden.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one calls you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She does. She says I sleep all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And so you do! The only time you come out is to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do you expect? Who wants to walk out into a mess like this every day?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, now I'm a bad housekeeper!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you are! The place is a pigsty all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Explosively she opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Do you hear him? Do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When can you start?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right away, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leads the maid into Leopold's room. Mozart steals back into his workroom and gently closes the door. Leopold is left alone.</context>
      <utterance>Good! Come in. You'll start with that room there.  It's filthy!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sorry! I'm sorry I spoke! I'm just a provincial from Salzburg. What do I know about smart Vienna? Parties all night, every night. Dancing and drinking like idiot children!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hand comes into frame offering a plate of sugared biscuits. On its finger we see the gold signet ring belonging to Salieri.</context>
      <utterance>They're out every night, sir. Till all hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do any pupils come to the house?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that I've seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how does he pay for all this? Does he work at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, sir, all day long. He never leaves the house until evening. He just sits there, writing and writing. He doesn't even eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? What is it he's writing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I wouldn't know that, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Confused, the girl hesitates. He hands her a pile of coins.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. You're a good girl. You're very kind to do this. Next time you're sure they'll be out of the house, let me know, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She accepts them, delighted.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you, sir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I've found out about the money, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens a drawer in a sideboard. Inside we see one gold snuff box: it is the one we saw Mozart being presented with as a child in the Vatican.</context>
      <utterance>Yes what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri turns to look around him.</context>
      <utterance>He kept seven snuff boxes in here. I could swear they were all gold. And now look there's only one left. And inside, sir, look - I counted them - tickets from the pawnshop. Six of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where does he work?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points across the room to the workroom. Salieri crosses and goes in alone.</context>
      <utterance>In there, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bravo, Mozart. Most charming. Yes, indeed. Clever man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Sire!</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well done, Mozart. Really quite fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees his wife and father standing by in the crowd. Leopold is signaling insistently.</context>
      <utterance>Baron!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty, may I ask you to do me the greatest favour?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I introduce my father? He is on a short visit here and returning very soon to Salzburg. He would so much like to kiss your hand. It would make his whole stay so memorable for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leopold comes forward eagerly and fawningly kisses the royal hand.</context>
      <utterance>Ah! By all means.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Constanze curtsies.</context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening.  We have met before, Herr Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, Your Majesty. Twenty years ago. No, twenty-two! twenty- three! And I remember word for word what you said to me. You said - you said -- He searches his memory.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bravo?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Yes, 'bravo,' of course 'bravo'! Everybody always says 'bravo' when Wolfi plays. Like the King of England. When we played for the King of England, he got up at the end and said, 'Bravo! Bravo! Bravo!' three times. Three bravo's. And the Pope four! Four bravo's from the Holy Father, and one 'bellissimo.' All the courtiers around are looking at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father -</utterance>
   <speaker>LEOPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hush! I'm talking to His Majesty. Your Majesty, I wish to express only one thing - that you who are the Father of us all, could teach our children the gratitude they owe to fathers. It is not for nothing that the Fifth Commandment tells us: 'Honour your Father and Mother, that your days may be long upon the earth.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-ha. Well. There it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've just learned something that might be of interest to you, Herr Director.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart is writing a new opera. An Italian opera.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Italian?</utterance>
   <speaker>BONNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aie!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's not all. He has chosen for his subject, Figaro. The Marriage of Figaro.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean that play?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's setting that play to music?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this Marriage of Figaro?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a French play, Kapellmeister. It has been banned by the Emperor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses himself, wide-eyed with alarm.</context>
      <utterance>Hah!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you absolutely sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen the manuscript.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know we banned this play, but frankly I can't remember why. Can you refresh my memory, Herr Director?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the same reason, Herr Chamberlain, that it was banned in France.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, yes. And that was?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the play makes a hero out of a valet. He outwits his noble master and exposes him as a lecher. Do you see the implications? This would be, in a grander situation, as if a Chamberlain were to expose an Emperor.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>LACKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all turn. Mozart approaches, rather apprehensively, and kisses Joseph's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Herr Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all sit, save Mozart. The room suddenly looks like a tribunal. Joseph is in a serious mood.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down, gentlemen, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart, are you aware I have declared the French play of Figaro unsuitable for our theatre?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Sire.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yet we hear you are making an opera from it. Is this true?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you this, Majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is not your place to ask questions. Is it true?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes, I admit it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you tell me why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Majesty, it is only a comedy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you think, Mozart, is scarcely the point. It is what His Majesty thinks that counts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Your Majesty -</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart, I am a tolerant man. I do not censor things lightly. When I do, I have good reason. Figaro is a bad play. It stirs up hatred between the classes. In France it has caused nothing but bitterness. My own dear sister Antoinette writes me that she is beginning to be frightened of her own people. I do not wish to see the same fears starting here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sire, I swear to Your Majesty, there's nothing like that in the story. I have taken out everything that could give offense. I hate politics.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others look at their king solemnly, all save Mozart.</context>
      <utterance>I think you are rather innocent, my friend. In these dangerous times I cannot afford to provoke our nobles or our people simply over a theatre piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Majesty, this is just a frolic. It's a piece about love.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, love again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's new, it's entirely new. It's so new, people will go mad for it. For example, I have a scene in the second act - it starts as a duet, just a man and wife quarreling. Suddenly the wife's scheming little maid comes in unexpectedly - a very funny situation. Duet turns into trio. Then the husband's equally screaming valet comes in. Trio turns into quartet. Then a stupid old gardener - quartet becomes quintet, and so on. On and on, sextet, septet, octet! How long do you think I can sustain that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess! Guess, Majesty. Imagine the longest time such a thing could last, then double it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, six or seven minutes! maybe eight!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty, sire! How about twenty? Twenty minutes of continuous music. No recitatives.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart -</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sire, only opera can do this. In a play, if more than one person speaks at the same time, it's just noise. No one can understand a word. But with music, with music you can have twenty individuals all talking at once, and it's not noise - it's a perfect harmony. Isn't that marvelous?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart, music is not the issue here. No one doubts your talent. It is your judgment of literature that's in question. Even with the politics taken out, this thing would still remain a vulgar farce. Why waste your spirit on such rubbish? Surely you can choose more elevated themes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elevated? What does that mean? Elevated! The only thing a man should elevate is - oh, excuse me. I'm sorry. I'm stupid. But I am fed up to the teeth with elevated things! Old dead legends! How can we go on forever writing about gods and legends?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because they do. They go on forever - at least what they represent. The eternal in us, not the ephemeral. Opera is here to ennoble us. You and me, just as much as His Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bello! Bello, Barone. Veramente.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, bello, bello, bello! Come on now, be honest. Wouldn't you all rather listen to your hairdressers than Hercules? Or Horatius? Or Orpheus? All those old bores! people so lofty they sound as if they shit marble!</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. All look at the Emperor.</context>
      <utterance>Govern your tongue, sir! How dare you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, Majesty. I'm a vulgar man. But I assure you, my music is not.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are passionate, Mozart! But you do not persuade.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sire, the whole opera is finished. Do you know how much work went into it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BONNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His Majesty has been more than patient, Signore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I persuade you if you won't let me show it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That will do, Herr Mozart!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just let me tell you how it begins.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON STRACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herr Mozart -</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A slight pause. Then Joseph nods.</context>
      <utterance>May I just do that, Majesty? Show you how it begins? Just that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart falls on his knees.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He giggles.</context>
      <utterance>Look! There's a servant, down on his knees. Do you know why? Not from any oppression. No, he's simply measuring a space. Do you know what for? His bed. His wedding bed to see if it will fit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Mozart is already rehearsing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Incredible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Emperor has given him permission.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Si, si! Veramente.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, gentlemen, so be it. In that case I think we should help Mozart all we can and do our best to protect him against the Emperor's anger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What anger?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About the ballet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ballet? What ballet?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me - didn't His Majesty specifically forbid ballet in his opera?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, absolutely. Is there a ballet in Figaro?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, in the third act.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart! Herr Mozart, may I have a word with you please. Right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He signals to the cast to break off.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly, Herr Director.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The company disperses, curious. The musicians look at Orsini- Rosenberg.</context>
      <utterance>Five minutes, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you not know that His Majesty has expressly forbidden ballet in his operas?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but this is not a ballet. This is a dance at Figaro's wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. A dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But surely the Emperor didn't mean to prohibit dancing when it's part of the story.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart hands him the score from which he is conducting.</context>
      <utterance>It is dangerous for you to interpret His Majesty's edicts. Give me your score, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rips out a page. Bonno watches in terror.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rips out three more.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing, Herr Director?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes on tearing the pages determinedly.</context>
      <utterance>Taking out what you should never have put in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart brushes past him straight towards Salieri, who rises to greet him. The little man is near hysterics.</context>
      <utterance>Herr Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs Salieri.</context>
      <utterance>Please! Please. I've no one else to turn to. Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wolfgang, what is it? Sta calmo, per favore. What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's unbelievable! The Director has actually ripped out a huge section of my music. Pages of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. They say I've got to re-write the opera, but it's perfect as it is. I can't rewrite what's perfect. Can't you talk to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why bother with Orsini-Rosenberg? He's obviously no friend of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I could kill him! I mean really kill him. I actually threw the entire opera on the fire, he made me so angry!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You burned the score?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no! My wife took it out in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How fortunate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not fair that a man like that has power over our work.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there are those who have power over him. I think I'll take this up with the Emperor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Excellency, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With all my heart, Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses Salieri's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you! Oh, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart giggles with relief and gratitude.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, no, Herr Mozart, please. It's not a holy relic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? I don't understand. Is it modern?</utterance>
   <speaker>BONNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty, the Herr Director, he has removed a balleto that would have occurred at this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart strains to hear what they are saying but cannot.</context>
      <utterance>It is your regulation, Sire. No ballet in your opera.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like this, Salieri?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is not a question of liking, Your Majesty. Your own law decrees it, I'm afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We do look at them. The spectacle on stage has now ground to a complete halt.</context>
      <utterance>Well, look at them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no! This is nonsense. Let me hear the scene with the music.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Sire -</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orsini-Rosenberg acknowledges his defeat.</context>
      <utterance>Oblige me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Orsini-Rosenberg rises and goes down to where Mozart sits anxiously with the musicians, watching his approach.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we see the scene with the music back, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks back deliriously at Salieri, trying to indicate his gratitude. Salieri acknowledges with a slight and subtle nod. Orsini-Rosenberg returns to his king.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, certainly. Certainly, Herr Director!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The singers scatter offstage to begin the scene again.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen, we're going from where we stopped. The Count: Anches so. Right away, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I hoped by that edict, Director, was simply to prevent hours of dancing like in French opera. There it is endless, as you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORSINI-ROSENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT BACK TO Mozart at the forte-piano, raising his hands. The musicians raise their bows. With a flourish the happy composer begins a reprise of the scene which had been cut out. The music of the march begins faintly; the celebrants of Figaro's wedding start to enter as the Count and the Countess sit in their chairs. In the theatre we see increasing pleasure on the Emperor's face, sullenness and defeat on the courtiers'. Then, suddenly, without interruption, on a crescendo repeat of the march, we</context>
      <utterance>Quite so, Majesty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine performances! Nine! That's all it's had - and withdrawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know; it's outrageous. Still, if the public doesn't like one's work one has to accept the fact gracefully.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what is it they don't like?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I can speak for the Emperor. You made too many demands on the royal ear. The poor man can't concentrate for more than an hour and you gave him four.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you think of it yourself? Did you like it at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's marvelous. Truly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the best opera yet written. I know it! Why didn't they come?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you overestimate our dear Viennese, my friend. Do you know you didn't even give them a good bang at the end of songs so they knew when to clap?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know. Perhaps you should give me some lessons in that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't presume. All the same, if it wouldn't be imposing, I would like you to see my new piece. It would be a tremendous honour for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, the honour would be all mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grazie, mio caro, Wolfgang!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bows too, giggling.</context>
      <utterance>Grazie, a lei, Signor Antonio!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sublime! Utterly sublime!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schikaneder laughs.</context>
      <utterance>That kind of music should be punishable by death.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOSEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri bows his head. Joseph places the chain around his neck. The crowd claps. Salieri makes to kiss his hand, but Joseph restrains him, and passes on. Cavalieri, smiling adoringly, gives him a deep curtsey, and he raises her up. The crowd all flock to Salieri with cries and words of approval. All want to shake his hand. They tug and pat him. But he has eyes for only one man - he looks about him, searching for him and then finds him. Mozart stands there. Eagerly Salieri moves to him.</context>
      <utterance>I believe that is the best opera yet written, my friends. Salieri, you are the brightest star in the musical firmament. You do honour to Vienna and to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mozart. It was good of you to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did my work please you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could it not, Excellency?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never knew that music like that was possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You flatter me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no! One hears such sounds and what can one say, but - Salieri!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door wide to admit Schikaneder and the girls.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Everybody's here! We've got guests. Good. I've brought some more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll have a little party. Come in. Come in. You know Herr Schikaneder?  This is! a very nice girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wolfi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my love?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These gentlemen are from Salzburg.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Salzburg. We were just talking about Salzburg.  If you've come from my friend the Fartsbishop, you've arrived at just the right moment. Because I've got good news for him. I'm done with Vienna. It's over, finished, done with! Done with! Done with!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wolfi! Your father is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The first loud chord of the Statue scene from Don Giovanni sounds. Mozart stares.</context>
      <utterance>Your father is dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure advances on the libertine. We see Mozart conducting, pale and deeply involved. Music fades down a little.</context>
      <utterance>Don Giovanni!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The music swells. We see Salieri standing alone in the back of a box, unseen, in semi-darkness. We also see that the theatre is only half full. Music fades down.</context>
      <utterance>So rose the dreadful ghost in his next and blackest opera. There on the stage stood the figure of a dead commander calling out 'Repent! Repent!'</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Music swells up again. We watch the scene on stage as the Commendatore addresses Giovanni. Then back to Salieri in the box. Music down again.</context>
      <utterance>And I knew - only I understood - that the horrifying apparition was Leopold, raised from the dead. Wolfgang had actually summoned up his own father to accuse his son before all the world. It was terrifying and wonderful to watch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EMMANUEL SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impresario de luxe</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESENTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Celebrated</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An Evening of</utterance>
   <speaker>PARODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Music! Mirth! Magic!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One more knock.</context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the pit a chromatic scale from the Overture to Don Giovanni turns into a anticipatory vamp. This grows more and more menacing until the whole flat representing the wall at the back falls down. An absurd pantomime horse gallops in. It has a ridiculous expression, and is manned by four men inside. Standing precariously on its back is a dwarf, wearing a miniature version of the armour and helmet worn by the Commendatore. He sings in a high, nasal voice:</context>
      <utterance>C-c-c-come in!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to keep his balance as he trots in, but fails. He falls off onto the stage. He beats at the horse, trying to get back on.</context>
      <utterance>Don Giovannnnnnnnnni!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bewildered, the horse looks about him, but cannot see his small rider who is below his level of sight.</context>
      <utterance>Down! Down!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The horse, amidst laughter from the audience, fails to locate him. Exasperated, the dwarf signals to someone in the wings. A tall man strides out carrying a see-saw; on his shoulders stands another man. The dwarf stands on the lowered end of the see-saw. There is a drum roll and the man above jumps down onto the raised end and the Commendatore is abruptly catapulted back onto the horse, only backwards so that he is facing away from Don Giovanni. The two men bow to the applauding audience, and retire off-stage. The Commendatore tries to extend his arms in the proper menacing attitude, and at the same time turn around to face Don Giovanni. This he finds difficult.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here! I'm here!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don Giovannnnnnnni!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the devil are you? What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've come to dinnnnnner!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dinner? How dare you? I am a nobleman. I only dine with people of my own height.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The horse takes a bow. The dwarf almost falls off again.</context>
      <utterance>Are you drunk? You invited me. And my horse. Here he is. Ottavio!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three girls rush to his aid and reach him just in time. They sing in the manner of the Tree Ladies later to be put into The Magic Flute.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Whoa! Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful!</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL THREE TOGETHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They grab him.</context>
      <utterance>Hold tight now!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone! Stop it! I'm a famous horseman.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives the ladies a radiant smile. The three ladies sing, as before, in close harmony.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm a famous horse!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's adorable!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adorable!</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An orchestral chord. The three ladies turn to Ottavio and sing to him.</context>
      <utterance>Adorable!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREE LADIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me your hoof, my darling, And I'll give you my heart! Take me to your stable, And never more we'll part!</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm shy and very bashful. I don't know what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREE LADIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ottavio neighs loudly, and runs at the girls.</context>
      <utterance>Don't hesitate a second. Just answer yes and neigh.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boos from the audience.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it. What are you doing? Remember who you are! You're a horse and they are whores.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He marches off stage.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. Women, women, women! I'm sick to death of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dash me! Bash me! Lash me! Flay me! Slay me! At last I will be freed by death!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behold!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="53">
   <speaker>THIRD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They throw them into the pot.</context>
      <utterance>Behold! She hiccups.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long does it take to cook a soprano?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWARVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five hours, five minutes, five seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't wait that long. I'm starving!</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schikaneder marches in as Figaro.</context>
      <utterance>So am I.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the pot, I have got a good dinner. Not a sausage or stew, but a singer. Not a sausage or stew but a singer. Is the treat that I'll eat for my meat!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CU, Mozart laughing delightedly with the audience.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shut up. I'm sick to death of that tune.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE THREE GIRLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me your hoof, my darling, and I'll give you my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the dwarves climb up the rim of the pot. As they climb, they all hum together the opening of Eine Kleine Nachtmusik.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. I'm sick of that one too.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soprano rises, dripping with water in the middle of the pot.</context>
      <utterance>And that one, too!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the dwarves beat her back down into the pot with their long wooden spoons.</context>
      <utterance>Oil me! Broil me! Boil me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soil me! Foil me! Spoil me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't eat her. Sopranos give me hiccups. I want some hay!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL THREE LADIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give him some hay, my darling, and I'll give you my heart!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The table is raised in the air by Leporello sitting under it on a bale of hay.</context>
      <utterance>Leporello! We want some hay - prestissimo! Leporello - where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behold!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behold!</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ottavio the horse gives a piercing neigh and runs down to the hay.</context>
      <utterance>Behold!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENDATORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leporello pries open the horse's mouth. Schikaneder pops the egg into it. A breathless pause as a drum roll builds the tension, up and up and up, and then suddenly out of the horse's rear-end flies a single white dove. Wild applause. It flies into the audience. Immediately all the cast start humming the lyrical finale from Figaro: Tutti Contenti. More and more doves fly out from the wings and fill the theatre. Everybody picks up the sausages and cakes and begins to eat. The end of the sketch is unexpectedly lyrical and magical, and then, suddenly, the tempo changes and the coarse strains of Ich Mochte wohl Der Kaiser take over and the whole company is dancing, frantically. A general dance as the curtain falls. It rises immediately. The audience - including Mozart - is delighted. They applaud vigorously. Schikaneder takes a bow amongst his troupe. Among much whistling and clapping, he finally jumps off the stage and strides through the audience toward the table where Mozart sits with his family. On stage, a troupe of bag pipers immediately appears to play an old German tune. Some of the audience joins in singing it.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Whoa, Ottavio! Whoa!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart is smiling; he has been amused. Constanze has been less amused and is looking apprehensive.</context>
      <utterance>Well, how do you like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonderful!  He liked the monkey, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, well, it's all good fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schikaneder sits at the table, and drinks from a bottle of wine.</context>
      <utterance>I liked the horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't he marvelous? He cost me a bundle, that horse, but he's worth it. I tell you, if you'd played Don Giovanni here it would have been a great success. I'm not joking. These people aren't fools. You could do something marvelous for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to try them someday. I'm not sure I'd be much good at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Course you would. You belong here, my boy, not the snobby Court. You could do anything you felt like here - the more fantastic the better! That's what people want, you know: fantasy. You do a big production, fill it with beautiful magic tricks and you'll be absolutely free to do anything you want. Of course, you'd have to put a fire in it, because I've got the best fire machine in the city and a big flood - I can do you the finest water effects you ever saw in your life. Oh, and a few trick animals. You'd have to use those.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Animals?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I tell you I picked up a snake in Dresden last week - twelve foot long - folds up to six inches, just like a paper fan. It's a miracle.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. You write a proper part for me with a couple of catchy songs, I'll guarantee you'll have a triumph- de-luxe. Mind you, it'll have to be in German.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>German!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course! What else do you think they speak here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, I love that. I'd want it to be in German. I haven't done anything in German since Seraglio.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So there you are. What do you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much will you pay him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah. Well. Ah,  I see you've got your manager with you. Well, Madame, how about half the receipts?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half the receipts! Stanzi!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talking about now. How much will you give him now? Down payment?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises in haste for his next number.</context>
      <utterance>Down payment? Who do you think I am? The Emperor? Whoops, I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He winks at Mozart and disappears toward the stage. Mozart looks after him, enchanted.</context>
      <utterance>Stay where you are. You're going to like this next one. We'll speak again. Triumph-de-luxe, my boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? Half the house!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When? We need money now. Either he pays now, or you don't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Stanzi.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't trust this man. And I didn't like what he did with your opera. It was common.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you liked it, didn't you? Monkey-flunki-punki.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half the house! You'll never see a penny. I want it here, in my hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stanzi-manzi, I'll put it in your hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He giggles like a child.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! I'll not let you put anything in my hand until I see some money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herr Mozart. What a surprise. What can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is my pupil still anxious to learn the art of music?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, your pupil is married and living in Mannheim, young man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Perhaps your dear wife might care to profit from my instruction?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this, Mozart? What's the matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. Since it appears nobody is eager to hire my services, could you favour me with a little money instead?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If a man cannot earn, he must borrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this is hardly the way to go about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>No doubt, sir. But I am endowed with talent, and you with money. If I offer mine, you should offer yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. I'll give it back, I promise. Please, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLUMBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CU, Mozart. His voice becomes mechanical.</context>
      <utterance>My answer is no, Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Please. Please. Please. Please. Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is embarrassing, you know. You introduced Mozart to some of my friends and he's begging from practically all of them. It has to stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agree, Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you think of anyone who might commission some work from him? I've done my best. I got him to arrange some Bach for my Sunday concerts. He got a fee - what I could afford. Can't you think of anyone who might do something for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Baron, no. I'm afraid Mozart is a lost cause. He has managed to alienate practically the whole of Vienna. He is constantly drunk. He never pays his debts. I can't think of one person to whom I dare recommend him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON SWIETEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How sad. It's tragic, isn't it? Such a talent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The opening measures of the Piano Concerto in D Minor steal in.</context>
      <utterance>Indeed. Just a moment - as a matter of fact I think I do know someone who could commission a work from him. A very appropriate person to do so. Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second chord sounds and fades. Mozart stares in panic.</context>
      <utterance>Herr Mozart?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have come to commission work from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What work?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Mass for the dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What dead? Who is dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man who deserved a Requiem Mass and never got one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am only a messenger. Do you accept? You will be paid well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri extends his hand. In it is a bag of money.</context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Almost against his will, Mozart takes the money.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty ducats. Another fifty when I have the Mass. Do you accept?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long will you give me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away. Mozart closes the front door. Instantly we hear the opening of the Requiem Mass (also in D Minor). Mozart turns and looks up at the portrait of his father on the wall. The portrait stares back. Constanze opens the door from the bedroom. She sees him staring up.</context>
      <utterance>Work fast. And be sure to tell no one what you do. You will see me again soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her with startled eyes. The music breaks off.</context>
      <utterance>Wolfi? Wolfi!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives a strange little giggle.</context>
      <utterance>I heard voices.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees the bag of money.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that? Oh!  Who gave you this? How much is it? Wolfi, who gave you this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not telling you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her. She stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>You'd think I was mad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vogler stares at him in horror.</context>
      <utterance>My plan was so simple, it terrified me. First I must get the Death Mass and then achieve the death.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His funeral - imagine it! The Cathedral, all Vienna sitting there. His coffin, Mozart's little coffin in the middle. And suddenly in that silence, music. A divine music bursts out over them all, a great Mass of Death: Requiem Mass for Wolfgang Mozart, composed by his devoted friend Antonio Salieri. What sublimity! What depth! What passion in the music! Salieri has been touched by God at last. And God, forced to listen. Powerless - powerless to stop it. I at the end, for once, laughing at Him. Do you understand? Do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his own hands and stares at them. The raging Dies Irae from Mozart's Requiem Mass bursts upon us.</context>
      <utterance>The only thing that worried me was the actual killing. How does one do that? How does one kill a man? It's one thing to dream about it. It's very different when you have to do it, with your own hands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her. The music breaks off. Silence. An enormous bang at the door startles him. Constanze moves to open it.</context>
      <utterance>Wolfi. Wolfi!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Don't answer it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart springs up. He is clearly terrified.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs out of he room, into his workroom, and shuts he door. Now a little scared herself, Constanze goes to he front door and opens it cautiously. Schikaneder stands there, floridly dressed as usual. Lorl is seen peeking out from the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him I'm not here. Tell him I'm working on it. Come back later.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I interrupting something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's our friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not in. But he's working on it. He said to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes her into the room.</context>
      <utterance>I hope so. I need it immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees he manuscript on the table, and goes to it eagerly.</context>
      <utterance>Is he happy with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a page without waiting for a reply.</context>
      <utterance>Is this it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart opens he workroom door. We see him as Schikaneder sees him: wild-eyed, extremely pale and strange.</context>
      <utterance>What the devil is this? Requiem Mass? Does he think I'm in the funeral business?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave that alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wolfi!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put it down!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put it down, I said! It's nothing for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! I'm sorry! I'm sorry! What have you got for me? Is it finished?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? The vaudeville, what'd you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He giggles triumphantly. Schikaneder stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Because there's nothing to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I asked you if we could start rehearsal next week and you said yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we can.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart, with a bright, rather demented smile presents his head to Schikaneder.</context>
      <utterance>So let me see it. Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He giggles. Schikaneder suddenly grabs his lapels.</context>
      <utterance>Here. It's all right here, in my noodle. The rest is just scribbling. Scribbling and bibbling. Bibbling and scribbling. Would you like a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you little clown, do you know how many people I've hired for you? Do you know how many people are waiting?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave him alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm paying these people. Do you realize that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's doing his best.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm paying people just to wait for you. It's ridiculous!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what's ridiculous? Your libretto, that's what's ridiculous. Only an idiot would ask Wolfi to work on that stuff!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes? And what's so intelligent about writing a Requiem?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Money! Money!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're mad! She's mad, Wolfi.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schikaneder suddenly takes Mozart by the arms, and speaks to him with intense appeal.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, and who are you? He's worked for Kings. For the Emperor.  Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Wolfi. Write it. Please. Just write it down. On paper. It's no good to anyone in your head. And fuck the Death Mass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now calm yourself. Calm. What's the matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving. I'm not working there anymore. I'm scared!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What has happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know what it's like. Herr Mozart frightens me. He drinks all day, then takes all that medicine and it makes him worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What medicine?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. He has pains.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, in his stomach. They bend him right over.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he working?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm frightened, sir. Really! When he speaks, he doesn't make any sense. You know he said he saw - he said he saw his father. And his father's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he working?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose so. He sits there all he time, doing some silly opera.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Opera? Opera!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't ask me to go back again. I'm frightened! I'm very, very frightened.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Overture to The Magic Flute begins grandly. To the music of the slow introduction, we see:</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure it's an opera?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have it yet. It's not finished. I'm sorry, but I need more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you neglecting my request?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and looks. Constanze has come into the living room. Nervously, Mozart indicates her.</context>
      <utterance>No, no! I promise you, I'll give you a wonderful piece - the best I ever can!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my wife, Stanzi. I've been sick, but I'm all right now. Aren't</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, sir. He's all right. And he's working on it very hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri contemplates them both.</context>
      <utterance>Give me two more weeks. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and goes down the stairs. Mozart shuts the door; he closes his eyes in fear.</context>
      <utterance>The sooner you finish, the better your reward. Work!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He will not look at her or reply.</context>
      <utterance>Wolfi, I think you really are going mad. You work like a slave for that idiot actor who won't give you a penny and here. This is not a ghost! This is a real man who puts down real money. Why on earth don't you finish it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me one reason I can understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't write it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>It's killing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly she starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>No, this is really awful. You're drunk, aren't you? Be honest - tell me - you've been drinking. And I'm so stupid I stay here and listen to you!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her tears flow. Mozart looks at her helplessly.</context>
      <utterance>It's not fair! I worry about you all the time. I try to help you all I can and you just drink and talk nonsense and - and frighten me! It's not fair!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go back to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the Rex Tremendai Majestatis from the Requiem and see on the wall the portrait of Leopold Mozart looking down. The camera pans slowly downward from it back to the table. Mozart is writing the music. He looks up and sees that Constanze is fast asleep in her chair. Mozart gets up quietly. He puts on his hat and cloak, takes a bottle of wine and tiptoes from the house. Without stopping, the music changes from the heavy Requiem to the light-hearted patter of the Papa-Papa duet from The Magic Flute.</context>
      <utterance>Please! Let me sit here. Let me stay here with you. I promise I won't say all word. I'll just be here, so you know no one's going to hurt you. Please, please! She sits down tearfully, staring at him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Papageno recoils.</context>
      <utterance>Go back!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAPAGENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merciful Gods! If only I knew by which door I came in.  Which was it? Was it this one? Come on, tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Papageno recoils.</context>
      <utterance>Go back!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAPAGENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the pit, Mozart indicates to the first violinist to take over as conductor. He slips from his place and goes stealthily backstage. We follow him. Over the scene we hear Papageno being addressed by the First Priest in stern tones.</context>
      <utterance>Now, I can't go forward and I can't go back. Oh, this is awful! He weeps extravagantly.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, thou hast deserved to wander forever in the darkest chasms of the earth. The gentle Gods have remitted thy punishment, but yet thou shalt never feel the Divine Content of the consecrated ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAPAGENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter. An enormous goblet of wine appears out of the earth. We follow Mozart into the wings. Actors and actresses stand around in fantastic costumes. We see a flying chariot and parts of a huge snake lying about. Also the scenery door of a temple with the word 'Wisdom' inscribed on the pediment. Mozart walks to where there stands a keyboard glockenspiel with several manuals, and a musician waiting to play it. Silently Mozart indicates that he wishes to play the instrument himself. On stage Schikaneder is being addressed haughtily by the First Priest.</context>
      <utterance>Oh well, I'm not alone in that. Just give me a decent glass of wine - that's divine content enough for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, hast thou no other desire on earth, but just to eat and drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAPAGENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter from the audience.</context>
      <utterance>Well!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAPAGENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at the audience and winks at them. They laugh. Now Papageno's aria (Ein Madchen oder Weibchen) begins. It is interpolated, as he pretends to play his magic bells, with the glockenspiel actually being played off-stage by Mozart. Schikaneder looks into the pit and does not see Mozart conducting. He looks into the wings and realizes the situation with amusement. He sings joyfully and the audience watches entranced.</context>
      <utterance>Well, actually I do have a rather weird feeling in my heart. Perhaps it's just indigestion. But you know, I really would like - I really do want - something even nicer than food and drink. Now what on earth could that be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A sweetheart or a pretty little wife is Papageno's wish. A willing, billing, lovey dovey Would be My most tasty little dish. Be my most tasty little dish! Be my most tasty little dish!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLEGRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then that would be eating and drinking I'd live like a Prince without thinking. The wisdom of old would be mine - A woman's much better than wine! Then that would be eating and drinking! The wisdom of old would be mine - A woman's much better than wine. She's much better than wine! She's much better than wine!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A sweetheart or a pretty little wife is Papageno's wish. A willing, billing, lovey dovey Would be My most tasty little dish.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLEGRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to net one birdie only And I will stop feeling so lonely. But if she won't fly to my aid, Then into a ghost I must fade. I need to net one birdie only But if she won't fly to my aid, Then into a ghost I must fade. To a ghost I must fade! To a ghost I must fade!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A sweetheart or a pretty little wife is Papageno's wish. A willing, billing, lovey dovey Would be My most tasty little dish.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLEGRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At certain moments we see the stage from Salieri's point of view: Schikaneder singing, then pretending to play; and then we see Mozart playing the glockenspiel with great flourishes in the wings. Then, suddenly, the actor mimes playing, and no sound comes. He mimes again, but still nothing comes. He looks offstage in anxiety; there is evidently some commotion. People are looking down on the floor. The song comes to a near-halt. Schikaneder stares. Then the comedian signals to the deputy conductor to pick up the song and finish it. At this moment Salieri gets up and hastily leaves his box.</context>
      <utterance>At present the girls only peck me. Their cruelty surely will wreck me. But one little beak in my own, And I'll up to heaven be flown! At present the girls only peck me. But one little beak in my own, And I'll up to heaven be flown. Up to heaven be flown! Up to heaven be flown!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The actors step back respectfully. He stoops and picks up the frail composer in his arms. Mozart is quite limp and Salieri has to fling his arms around his own neck. All this is watched nervously by Schikaneder on stage whilst performing his scene with Papagena as an ugly old woman.</context>
      <utterance>I have a carriage. Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>UGLY OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here I am, my angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAPAGENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Who the devil are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>UGLY OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've taken pity on you, my angel. I heard your wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAPAGENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audience laughter. The actress raises the little painted cloth with the ugly old face on it to show her own pretty young one to the audience. More laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well, thank you! How wonderful. Some people get all the luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>UGLY OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you've got to promise me faithfully you'll remain true to me forever. Then you'll see how tenderly your little birdie will love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAPAGENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>UGLY OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, promise then.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAPAGENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean - now?</utterance>
   <speaker>UGLY OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Of course now. Right away, before I get any older.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAPAGENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know! I mean you're a delicious, delightful, delectable little bird, but don't you think you might be just a little tough?</utterance>
   <speaker>UGLY OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm tender enough for you, my boy. I'm tender enough for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened? Is it over?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking you home. You're not well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to collapse again. Salieri helps him into the sedan. The door is shut. The chair sets off and Salieri strides beside it, through the mean street. A lantern with a candle swings from the chair.</context>
      <utterance>No, no. I have to get back. I have -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The porter leaves the room. Mozart stirs.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens his eyes and sees Salieri staring down at him. He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Papa! Papa!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He helps him to sit up and takes off his coat and his shoes and puts a coverlet around him.</context>
      <utterance>Come now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is your wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not here! She's not well, either. She went to the Spa.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean she's not coming back?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're so good to me. Truly. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He struggles to loosen his cravat. Salieri does it for him.</context>
      <utterance>I mean to come to my opera. You are the only colleague who did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would never miss anything that you had written. You must know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is only a vaudeville.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no. It is a sublime piece. The grandest operone. I tell you, you are the greatest composer known to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mean that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have bad fancies. I don't sleep well anymore. Then I drink too much, and think stupid things.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you ill?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doctor thinks I am. But -</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a violent knocking at the front door. Mozart starts and looks around wildly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm too young to be so sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall I answer it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No, it's him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man. He's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The knocking increases in loudness, terrifying Mozart.</context>
      <utterance>What man?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri moves to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him to go away. Tell him I'm still working on it. Don't let him in!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! Ask him if he'd give me some money now. Tell him if he would, that would help me finish it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finish what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>He knows. He knows!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herr Salieri.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am looking after him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he's sleeping now. Better not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he's all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. He's just exhausted. He became dizzy, that's all. We should let him rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, tell him we were here, won't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And say everything went wonderfully. A triumph-de-luxe - say that! Tell him the audience shouted his name a hundred times.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bene.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.  And congratulations to all of you. It was superb.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACTRESSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schikaneder produces a bag of money.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you! Thank you, Excellency!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHIKANEDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, by the way, give him this. This is his share. That should cheer him up, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, indeed. Goodnight to you all now. It was perfection - truly!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri pours the coins out of the bag onto the coverlet.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart looks at the coins astonished.</context>
      <utterance>He said to give you this. And if you finish the work by tomorrow night, he will pay you another hundred ducats.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another? But that's too soon! Tomorrow night? It's impossible! Did he say a hundred?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Can I - could I help you, in any way?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you? Actually, you could.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear friend, it would be my greatest pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you'd have to swear not to tell a soul. I'm not allowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's all here in my head. It's just ready to be set down. But when I'm dizzy like this my eyes won't focus. I can't write.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, let us try together. I'd regard it as such an honour. Tell me, what is this work?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Mass. A Mass for the Dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to go!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to go back to Vienna.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel wrong. I feel wrong being here.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="52">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did I stop?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The end of the Recordare - Statuens in parte dextra.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now the Confutatis. Confutatis Maledictis. When the wicked are confounded. Flammis acribus addictis. How would you translate that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Consigned to flames of woe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fire which never dies. Burning one forever?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strange!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his pen.</context>
      <utterance>Come. Let's begin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Confutatis Maledictis.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ended in F Major?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri writes the key signature.</context>
      <utterance>So now - A minor. Suddenly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri writes this, and continues now to write as swiftly and urgently as he can, at Mozart's dictation. He is obviously highly expert at doing this and hardly hesitates. His speed, however, can never be too fast for Mozart's impatient mind.</context>
      <utterance>Common time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Start with the voices. Basses first. Second beat of the first measure -</utterance>
   <speaker>A.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Con-fu-ta-tis.  Second measure, second beat.  Ma-le-dic-tis.  G-sharp, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Third measure, second beat starting on E.  Flam-mis a-cri-bus ad-dic-tis.  And fourth measure, fourth beat - D.  Ma-le-dic-tis, flam-mis a-cri-bus ad- dic-tis.  Do you have that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri sings back the first six measures of the bass line. After the first two measures a chorus of basses fades in on the soundtrack and engulfs his voice. They stop.</context>
      <utterance>Sing it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Now the tenors. Fourth beat of the first measure - C.  Con-fu-ta-tis.  Second measure, fourth beat on D.  Ma-le-dic-tis.  All right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice is lost on the last words, as tenors engulf it and take over the soundtrack, singing their whole line from the beginning, right to the end of the sixth measure where the basses stopped, but he goes on mouthing the sounds with them. Salieri writes feverishly. We see his pen jotting down the notes as quickly as possible: the ink flicks onto the page. The music stops again.</context>
      <utterance>Fourth measure, second beat - F.  Flam-mis a-cri-bus ad-dic-tis, flam- mis a-cri-bus ad-dic-tis.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now the orchestra. Second bassoon and bass trombone with the basses. Identical notes and rhythm.  The first bassoon and tenor trombone -</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart glares at him, irritated. His hands move impatiently. Salieri scribbles frantically.</context>
      <utterance>Please! Just one moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It couldn't be simpler.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First bassoon and tenor trombone - what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the tenors.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also identical?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He again hums the bass vocal line from the beginning, conducting. On the soundtrack, we hear the second bassoon and bass trombone play it with him and the first bassoon and tenor trombone come in on top, playing the tenor vocal line. We also hear the trumpets and timpani. The sound is bare and grim. It stops at the end of the sixth measure. Salieri stops writing.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. The instruments to go with the voices. Trumpets and timpani, tonic and dominant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's all?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sings the urgent first measure of the ostinato.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no. Now for the Fire.  Strings in unison - ostinato on all - like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sings the second measure of the ostinato.</context>
      <utterance>Second measure on B.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri sings the first two measures of the string ostinato.</context>
      <utterance>Show me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's wonderful!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is now sitting bolt upright, hushed and inspired.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes - go on. The Voca Me. Suddenly sotto voce. Write that down: sotto voce, pianissimo. Voca me cum benedictis. Call me among the blessed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C Major. Sopranos and altos in thirds. Altos on C. Sopranos above.  Vo-ca, vo-ca me, vo-ca me cum be-ne- dic-tis.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sopranos up to F on the second 'Voca'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and on 'dictis'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He writes feverishly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sings the violin figure under the Voca Me (Bars 7,8,9).</context>
      <utterance>And underneath, just violins - arpeggio.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sings the ostinato phrase twice.</context>
      <utterance>The descending scale in eighth notes, and then back suddenly to the fire again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's it. Do you have it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go fast!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The entire Confutatis bursts over the room, as Mozart snatches the manuscript pages from Salieri and reads from it, singing. Salieri sits looking on in wondering astonishment. The music continues right through the following scenes, to the end of the movement.</context>
      <utterance>Then let me hear it. All of it. The whole thing from the beginning - now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to rest a bit?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no. I'm not tired at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll stop for just a moment. Then we'll do the Lacrimosa.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can keep going, I assure you. Shall we try?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you stay with me while I sleep a little?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not leaving you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am so ashamed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOZART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mozart closes his eyes. Salieri stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>I was foolish. I thought you did not care for my work - or me. Forgive me. Forgive me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your husband is ill, ma'am. He took sick. I brought him home.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was at hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thank you very much. You can go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He needs me, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he doesn't. And I don't want you here. Just go, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He asked me to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She notices a movement from the bed. Mozart wakes. He sees Constanze and smiles with real joy. Forgetting Salieri, she goes to her husband.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm asking you -</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws herself on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Wolfi, I'm back. I'm still very angry with you, but I missed you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hugs her husband desperately. He stares at her with obvious relief, not able to speak. Suddenly she sees the manuscript in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'll never leave you again. If you'll just try a little harder to be nice to me. And I'll try to do better, too. We must. We must! This was just silly and stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at it and recognizes it.</context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes it from his weak hand. At the same moment Salieri reaches out his hand to take it and add it to the pile on the table. She stares at him, trying to understand - suspicious and frightened and at the same time unable to make a sound. Mozart makes a convulsive gesture to reclaim the pages. The coins brought by Salieri fall on the floor. Karl runs after them, laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no, not this. Not this, Wolfi! You're not to work on this ever again! I've decided.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not his handwriting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I was assisting him. He asked me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She extends her hand for the Requiem, as she stands up. Salieri hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>He's not going to work on this anymore. It is making him ill. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With extreme reluctance - it costs him agony to do it - Salieri hands over the score of the Requiem to her.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She marches with the manuscript over to a large chest in the room, opens it, throws the manuscript inside, shuts the lid, locks it and pockets the key. Involuntarily Salieri stretches out his arms for the lost manuscript.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But - but - but - She turns and faces him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I regret we have no servants to show you out, Herr Salieri. Respect my wish and go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other in mutual hatred. She turns to the bed. Mozart appears to have gone to sleep again.</context>
      <utterance>Madame, I will respect his. He asked me to stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTANZE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves to the bed. The child is playing with the coins on the floor. Faintly we hear the start of the Lacrimosa from the Requiem. Salieri watches as she touches her husband's hand. As the music grows, we realize that Mozart is dead. CU, Constanze staring wide-eyed in dawning apprehension. CU, Salieri also comprehending hat he has been cheated. The music rises. CU, The child on the floor, playing with the money.</context>
      <utterance>Wolfi?  Wolfi?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Why? Why? Why add to your misery by confessing to murder? You didn't kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you didn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I poisoned his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not his body.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What difference does that make?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son, why should you want all Vienna to believe you a murderer? Is that your penance? Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Father. From now on no one will be able to speak of Mozart without thinking of me. Whenever they say Mozart with love, they'll have to say Salieri with loathing. And that's my immortality - at last! Our names will be tied together for eternity - his in fame and mine in infamy. At least it's better than the total oblivion he'd planned for me, your merciful God!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my son, my poor son!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't pity me. Pity yourself. You serve a wicked God. He killed Mozart, not I. Took him, snatched him away, without pity. He destroyed His beloved rather than let a mediocrity like me get the smallest share in his glory. He doesn't care. Understand that. God cares nothing for the man He denies and nothing either for the man He uses. He broke Mozart in half when He'd finished with him, and threw him away. Like an old, worn out flute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tears off the Civilian Medal and Chain with which the Emperor invested him and has been wearing the whole time and throws it across the room.</context>
      <utterance>Why did He do it? Why didn't He kill me? I had no value. What was the use, keeping me alive for thirty-two years of torture? Thirty-two years of honours and awards.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens. An attendant comes in, cheerful and hearty.</context>
      <utterance>Being bowed to and saluted, called 'distinguished - distinguished Salieri' - by men incapable of distinguishing! Thirty-two years of meaningless fame to end up alone in my room, watching myself become extinct. My music growing fainter, all the time fainter, until no one plays it at all. And his growing louder, filling the world with wonder. And everyone who loves my sacred art crying, Mozart! Bless you, Mozart.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salieri ignores him and stares only at the priest, who stares back.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Professor! Time for the water closet. And then we've got your favourite breakfast for you - sugar-rolls.  He loves those. Fresh sugar-rolls.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SALIERI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He signs to the attendant, who wheels him in his chair out of the room. The priest stares after him.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Father. I'll speak for you. I speak for all mediocrities in the world. I am their champion. I am their patron saint. On their behalf I deny Him, your God of no mercy. Your God who tortures men with longings they can never fulfill. He may forgive me: I shall never forgive Him.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
