<movie id="30" title="American Psycho">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are the rules for a sweater vest? McDERMOTT What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Clarify. McDERMOTT Well, is it strictly informal-</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or can it be worn with a suit? McDERMOTT  Exactly</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you freebasing or what? That's not Robinson. McDERMOTT Who is it then?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Paul Owen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Van Patten returns.</context>
      <utterance>Some weasel from Kicker Peabody.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't have a good bathroom to do coke in. McDERMOTT Are you sure that's Paul Owen over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. McDufus, I am. McDERMOTT He's handling the Fisher account.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucky bastard. McDERMOTT Lucky Jew bastard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You spin a dreidel, McDermott, not a menorah. You spin a dreidel. McDERMOTT Oh my God. Bateman, do you want me to fry you up some fucking potato pancakes? Some latkes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Just cool it with the anti-Semitic remarks. McDERMOTT Oh I forgot. Bateman's dating someone from the</utterance>
   <speaker>ACLU.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Price leans over and pats Bateman on the back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>okay, I pick up this Vassar chick at Tunnel-hot number, big tits, great legs, this chick was a little hardbody-and so I buy her a couple of champagne kirs and she's in the city on spring break and she's practically blowing me in the Chandelier Room and so I take her back to my place-</context>
      <utterance>Oh God, I was there. I don't need to hear this story again. McDERMOTT But I never told you what happened afterwards. So</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh fuck you. I want a blowjob, Bate-man. I want a chick who's gonna let me-</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, wait. May I ask where Pamela is during all this? McDERMOTT</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is a Vassar girl. She's not from Queens. She would only-are you ready? (Dramatic pause) She would only give me a handjob, and get this...she kept her glove on. The men sit in shocked, horrified silence. ALL IN UNISON Never date a Vassar girl.</context>
      <utterance>She let you fuck her without a condom? McDERMOTT</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price and Bateman finally get a stall and rush in. Price is sweating.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, who knows? They don't know that. Prove it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman opens a tiny packet of coke.</context>
      <utterance>I'm shaking. You open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez. That's not a helluva lot, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's just the light.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman dips his Amex in the envelope and snorts.</context>
      <utterance>It's a fucking milligram of Sweet'n Low!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down. Let's do it anyway</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Raising his voice)</context>
      <utterance>I guess you're right...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GUY IN STALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, FUCK YOU!!  Sorry, dude. Steroids...Okay, let's do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both dig their platinum Amex cards into the envelope of white powder, shoveling it up their noses, then sticking their fingers in to catch the residue and rubbing it into their gums.</context>
      <utterance>That's the spirit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>twenty-six years old. I live in the American Garden Buildings on West Eighty-First Street, on the eleventh floor Tom Cruise lives in the penthouse. Bateman walks into his bathroom, urinates while trying to see his reflection in a poster for Les Miserables above his toilet.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Patrick Bateman. I am</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>balanced diet, in a rigorous exercise routine. In the morning, if my face is a little puffy, I'll put on an ice pack while doing my stomach crunches. I can do a thousand now. Bateman ties a plastic ice pack around his face. Bateman does his morning stretching exercises in the living room wearing the ice pack.</context>
      <utterance>I believe in taking care of myself, in a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>water-activated gel cleanser, then a honey-almond body scrub, and on the face an exfoliating gel scrub. Bateman stands in front of a massive marble sink applying a gel facial masque.</context>
      <utterance>After I remove the icepack, I use a deep pore-cleanser lotion. In the shower, I use a</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I leave on for ten minutes while I prepare the rest of my routine. Bateman opens the door of a mirrored cabinet, which is stocked with immaculate rows of skin care products. He begins selecting bottles jars and brushes, laying them in readiness on the marble counter.</context>
      <utterance>Then I apply an herb mint facial masque which</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>or no alcohol because alcohol dries your face out and makes you look older. Then moisturizer, then an anti-aging eye balm, followed by a final moisturizing "protective" lotion... Bateman stares into the mirror. The masque has dried, giving his face a strange distorted look as if it has been wrapped in plastic. He begins slowly peeling the gel masque off his face.</context>
      <utterance>I always use an after-shave lotion with little</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>kind of abstraction, hut there is no real me, only an entity, something illusory, and though I can hide my cold gaze and you can shake my hand and feel flesh gripping you and maybe you can even sense our lifestyles are probably comparable: I simply am not there.</context>
      <utterance>There is an idea of a Patrick Bateman, some</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>level. My self is fabricated, an aberration. My personality is sketchy and unformed, my heartlessness goes deep and is persistent. Fully dressed in Armani, Bateman stands in front of a full-length mirror in the middle of his vast bedroom, adjusting his cuff-links.</context>
      <utterance>It is hard for me to make sense on any given</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>He gives a last look at the mirror and likes what he sees. He gives his reflection a smile.</context>
      <utterance>My conscience, my pity, my hopes disappeared a long time ago, if they ever did exist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman walks past the desk of JEAN, his secretary, pulling his Walkman from around his neck. Jean is attractive, wholesome, earnest. She smiles shyly. She loves him.</context>
      <utterance>Morning, Hamilton. Nice tan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Late?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aerobics class. Sorry. Any messages?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After six.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean follows him into his office.</context>
      <utterance>Negative. Cancel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? And what should I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just...say...no.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean stands at his desk, waiting for instructions.</context>
      <utterance>Just say no?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, something. . romantic?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, silly. Forget it. I'll make them. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean exits. Bateman straightens some magazines in his office, lifts a painting off the wall and puts it back at a slightly different angle. He fiddles with some pencils in a beer stein. He puts on some MUSIC and flips through a Sports Illustrated. He buzzes Jean. She comes in a moment later with the Perrier and a file.</context>
      <utterance>You look nice today.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the Ransom file? Thanks. Don't wear that outfit again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ummm...what? I didn't hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said "Do not wear that outfit again." Wear a dress. A skirt or something. Jean stands there, then looks down at herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't like this, I take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, you're prettier than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone RINGS and Jean turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Patrick.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Jean leaves, Bateman clicks on the TV set in one corner of the room and starts watching Jeopardy!</context>
      <utterance>I'm not here. And high heels. I like high heels.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>want, a zydeco band. Or mariachi. Or reggae. Something ethnic to shock Daddy Oh, I can't decide...And lots of chocolate truffles. Godiva. And oysters on the halfshell. CLOSE-UP on Bateman, who is wearing a Walkman and staring out the window.</context>
      <utterance>I'd want a zydeco band, Patrick. That's what I'd</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Michael tape but Evelyn-my supposed fiance-keeps buzzing in my ear. Evelyn continues to make notes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to listen to the new George</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do...what.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get married. Have a wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evelyn?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, darling?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your Evian spiked?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No-I can't take the time off work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up to greet them, giving Evelyn a suspiciously long kiss.</context>
      <utterance>The menu's in braille.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drags her away, half giggling and protesting.</context>
      <utterance>I have to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pat, this is my cousin Vanden and her boyfriend Stash. He's an artist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me guess-you live in the East Village? Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>STASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COURTNEY RAWLINSON and LUIS CARRUTHERS arrive at the table. Courtney is blonde, classically beautiful and from precisely the same social background as Evelyn, but she is considerably more fragile and neurotic. Luis is half-English, half-Argentinean, slightly overweight (a rarity in this crowd), puppyish and eager to please. He wears the same type of designer clothes as Price and Bateman, but with foppish tendencies: velvet jackets, bow-ties, boldly patterned vests. They exchange air kisses. As soon as Luis turns his back, Bateman sneaks a kiss on Courtney's neck.</context>
      <utterance>SoHo.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stash and Vanden watch them in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>are having an affair. Timothy is the only interesting person I know. Courtney is almost perfect looking. She s usually operating on one or more psychiatric drugs. Tonight I believe it's Xanax. More disturbing than her drug use, though, is the fact that she's engaged to Luis Carruthers, the biggest dufus in the business. Courtney rouses herself from her drug haze.</context>
      <utterance>I am fairly sure that Timothy and Evelyn</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me. Stash...do you think SoHo is becoming to...commercial?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I read that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, who gives a rat's ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. That affects us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come on. Price. There are a lot more important problems than Sri Lanka to worry about. Sure our foreign policy is important, but there are more pressing problems at hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>down the nuclear arms race, stop terrorism and world hunger. But we can't ignore our social needs. either We have to stop people from abusing the welfare system. We have to provide food and shelter for the homeless and oppose racial discrimination and promote civil rights while also promoting equal rights for women but change the abortion laws to protect the right to life yet still somehow maintain women's freedom of choice. The table stares at Bateman uncomfortably.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we have to end apartheid for one. And slow</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>immigrants. We have to encourage a return to traditional moral values and curb graphic sex and violence on TV, in movies, in pop music, everywhere. Most importantly we have to promote general social concern and less materialism in young people. Price chokes on his drink. Everyone is silent and mystified.</context>
      <utterance>We also have to control the influx of illegal</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick, how thought-provoking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don t you just go for Price?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, Patrick. Why Price? Price?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's rich.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody's rich.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's good-looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody's good-looking, Patrick.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has a great body</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman unbuttons his shirt and makes advances to get Evelyn to have sex with him. She ignores him, watching the Home Shopping Channel with the remote in her hand. Finally, he straddles her, penis close to her face. She tries to look around him at the TV, then takes notice.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody has a great body now.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman flops back down beside her and stares at the television.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want to do with that, floss with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you using minoxidil?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm not. Why should I ?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your hairline looks like it's receding.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman looks suspicious for a moment and then, seeing his smile, smiles back.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman continues to speak to him in another language, grabbing at the sleeve of the jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, wait. You're not...shhh wait... you're not giving me valid reasons.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her husband has taken Bateman's horribly bloodstained sheets out of the bag and is staring at them.</context>
      <utterance>What are you trying to say to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bleach-ee? Are you trying to say bleach-ee? Bleach-ee. Oh my God. She keeps pointing to the jacket and talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't shut your fucking mouth I will kill you, are you understanding me? She talks faster.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...no wait, twenty minutes. I have a lunch meeting at Hubert's in twenty minutes with Ronald Harrison and I need those sheets cleaned by this afternoon. She keeps talking. BATEMAN Listen. I cannot understand you. Bateman starts laughing, slaps his hand down on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Now listen-I have a very important lunch meeting  at Hubert's in thirty minutes, and I need those</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is crazy. You're a fool. I can't cope with this. Bateman is on the verge of tears.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone enters the store behind him. It's VICTORIA, late-twenties, attractive but a little overweight, wearing a tailored business suit with white sneakers and sports socks.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid bitchee! Understand? Oh Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off her sunglasses.</context>
      <utterance>Patrick?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Patrick. I thought that was you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello  Awkward pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it ridiculous? Coming all the way up here, but you know. They really are the best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my, I see. What are those? Oh my.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, well...it s cranberry juice. Cranapple. VICTORiA  Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>like a Dove Bar. It's a Dove Bar...Hershey's Syrup?</context>
      <utterance>Well, I mean, um, it s really...Bosco. You know, like...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(He yanks the sheet out of the man's hand) I would really appreciate it. I'm really late. I have a lunch appointment at Hubert's in fifteen minutes. Bateman turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, if you could talk to them</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hubert's? Oh really? It moved uptown, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, oh boy, listen, I've got to go. Thank you, uh... Victoria?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we could have lunch one day next week? You know, I'm downtown near Wall Street quite often.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know, Victoria. I'm at work all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what about, oh, you know, maybe a Saturday?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next Saturday?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, can't, I'm afraid. Matinee of Les Miserables. Listen, I've really got to go. I'll-Oh...Christ...I'll call you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman glares at the woman behind the counter and rushes out the door. Victoria stares after him as we hear the sound of the bell on the closing door.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, what are you doing tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Oh, I'm...busy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it. I'm...</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On a lot of lithium?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waiting for Luis to call me. He said he'd call tonight. Oh don't be difficult, Patrick.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should come have dinner with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But-when?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I confused or were we talking about tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ummm . . yeah. Luis is calling me tonight. I need to be home for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pumpkin?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pumpkin you're dating an asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pumpkin you're dating the biggest dickweed in New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pumpkin, you're dating a tumbling, tumbling dickweed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Courtney? Dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking Dorsia.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dorsia's nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like it there, don't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Yeah. What time?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pick me up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is on hold for a long time, getting very tense.</context>
      <utterance>Dorsia. Please hold.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dorsia.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>relaxing, then to the Pottery Bam where I bought this silver muffin dish. (She starts to pass out)</context>
      <utterance>A facial at Elizabeth Arden, which was really</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Donald Trump's car?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, Patrick. Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>lithium. Or have a Diet Coke. Some caffeine might get you out of this slump.</context>
      <utterance>You know, Courtney, you should take some more</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Her voice trails as she descends back into a drug haze) The cab draws up outside a restaurant. The awning reads "Barcadia."</context>
      <utterance>I just want to have a child. Just...two... perfect...children...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>JB. Straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Champagne on the rocks. Oh-could I have that with a twist? She starts to sink back in her chair and Bateman leans over and pulls her back up.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Dorsia?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>soup with smoked duck and mashed squash. New York magazine called it a 'playful but mysterious little dish." You'll love it. And then...the red snapper with violets and pine nuts. I think that'll follow nicely.</context>
      <utterance>Courtney, you're going to have the peanut butter</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She falls asleep at the table.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm...thanks, Patrick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman gets on top of her, starts to fuck her.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to fuck me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luis is a despicable twit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Luis is a despicable twit. I hate him. He keeps fucking her.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not, is Luis a despicable twit. Is it a receptacle tip? Get off me.</context>
      <utterance>No, you idiot. I said "Is it a receptacle tip?"</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it a what?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm ignoring you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull out, goddamnit!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes him away from her.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want, Courtney?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a plain end. I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to sit up.</context>
      <utterance>Turn the light on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus. I'm going home.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns on the light.</context>
      <utterance>Patrick. Turn on the Light.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a plain end, see? So?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Courtney throws a pillow over her head and starts crying.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting out of here. Where's your lithium?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Christ, this really isn't worth it. And see, Courtney, it's there for what? Huh? Tell us.  Why is it pulled down half an inch? So it can catch the force of the ejaculate!</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I have a promotion coming to me. I don't want to get AIDS. Bateman grabs her head and makes her look at the condom.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not a turn-on for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucky, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a wonderful jacket. Let me guess, Valentino Couture?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks so soft.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their conversation fades down as we hear Bateman's thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>I've been great. And you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the Ransom account going, Marcus?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's...it's...all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? That's interesting.  Not great?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh well, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how's Cecilia? She's a great girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hey. Owen! Congratulations on the Fisher account.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes. I'm very lucky. McDermott and Price enter. McDERMOTT</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Baxter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Paul. Squash?</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about Friday?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that, a gram?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McDermott lifts it up and examines the lettering carefully. McDERMOTT Whoa. Very nice. Take a look. He hands it to Van Patten.</context>
      <utterance>New card. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Picked them up from the printers yesterday</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good coloring.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls a card out of his wallet and slaps it on the table.</context>
      <utterance>It is very cool, Bateman. But that's nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all lean forward to inspect it.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman clenches his fists beneath the table, trying to control his anxiety.</context>
      <utterance>That's really nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eggshell with Romalian type.  What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up his own card.</context>
      <utterance>But wait. You ain't seen nothin' yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raised lettering, pale nimbus white...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Homeless Man stares at Bateman, struggling to sit up.</context>
      <utterance>Hello. Pat Bateman.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Homeless Man nods and starts to cry. Bateman reaches into his pocket and pulls out a $I 0 bill, then changes his mind and holds out a $5 instead.</context>
      <utterance>You want some money?. Some...food?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Homeless Man nods, looks away, wipes his nose.</context>
      <utterance>Is this what you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cold out, too, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost my job...</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Insider trading? Just joking. No, really-were you drinking on the job? HOMELESS MAN I was fired. I was laid off.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Were you drinking? Is that why you lost it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, uh, that's too bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog starts to whimper.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so hungry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not...</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not what? Qualified for anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, what's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Al.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speak up. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Al.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You re so kind, mister. You're kind. You're a kind man. I can tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhhh...it's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please...I don know what to do. I'm so cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't...I can't find a shelter</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goddammit, Al-look at me and stop crying like some kind of faggot. Al...I'm sorry. Bateman carefully puts the money back in his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>You reek. You reek of...shit. Do you know that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOMELESS MAN'S POV as Bateman lunges at him with the knife. EXTREME WIDE SHOT of the street. Bateman's shadowed figure is hunched over the Homeless Man, stabbing him in the stomach. The dog barks wildly and Bateman stomps on it until it is silent. LOW ANGLE shot of Bateman as he throws a quarter on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know what a fucking loser ,you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman walks calmly into the empty caverns of Wall Street. Cars drift past, their headlights momentarily illuminating the body left twitching on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>There's a quarter. Go buy some gum.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>JB, straight. And a Dixie beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to hear-</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Double Absolut martini.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. Would you like to hear the specials?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waiter leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Not if you want to keep your spleen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, you're late.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Studying the menu; he's in a surprisingly good mood) Hmmm, I see they've omitted the pork loin with lime jello.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm a child of divorce. Give me a break</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a long disgruntled silence.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody goes there anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patrick I mean Marcus, what are you thinking? Why would Ivana be at Texarkana? Another pause.</context>
      <utterance>Is that Ivana Trump over there?  Jeez</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, wasn't Rothschild originally handling the Fisher account? How did you get it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, man. I'm gonna bail.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've got a preview of the Barneys catalogue and a bottle of Absolut waiting for us.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, you dumb son of a bitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like Huey Lewis and the News?</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their early work was a little too New Wave for my taste. But then Sports came out in 1983, I think they really came into their own, commercially and artistically. Bateman walks to his bathroom, taking a large ax out of the shower. He takes two Valium.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's been compared to ELvis Costello but I think Huey has a more bitter, cynical sense of humor. Owen is absent-mindedly leafing through the Barneys catalogue.</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Halberstam?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Owen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Owen.</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a raincoat?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman moves to the CD player. He takes a CD out of its case and slides it in the machine.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>accomplished album. I think I heir undisputed masterpiece is "HiP To Be Square," a song so catchy that most people probably don't listen to the lyrics. But they should because it's not just about the pleasures of conformity and the importance of trends. It's al~ a personal statement about the band itself. Bateman puts on "Hip To Be Square." BATEMAN crosses the room and picks up the ax. We follow BATEMAN from behind as he walks up to Owen, the ax raised over his head.</context>
      <utterance>In 1987 Huey released this, Fore!, their most</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Owen turns around, FROM OWEN'S POV we see Bateman swing the ax toward his face. Blood sprays onto the white raincoat. FROM BEHIND OWEN, we see BATEMAN as he yanks the ax out. Owen drops to the floor. His body falls out of the frame. We stay on his legs twitching mechanically. Blood pulses onto the newspaper-covered floor.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Paul?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman takes his raincoat off, still panting. He folds the coat carefully in half, bloody side in, and drapes it neatly over the back of a chair. He sits back on the white sofa and surveys the scene. He checks his Rolex and lights a cigar. OFFSCREEN, Paul Owen's last faint sighs are heard.</context>
      <utterance>Fucking bastard...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick? Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Luis. It's not me. You're mistaken.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>friend Patrick Bateman. Where are you going? We're going to Nell's. Gwendolyn's father's buying it. (Looking down at the body) Where did you get your overnight bag?</context>
      <utterance>This is Gwendolyn Ichiban. This is my very good</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cab stops. BATEMAN opens the door and manages to get Owen's body into the backseat. Bateman gets into the cab.</context>
      <utterance>Commes des Garcon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me please, Patrick.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus lives, Luis.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ye-es, Je-an?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick, a Mr. Donald KIMBALL is here to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Bateman stares out the window, then down at the drawing of a headless woman he's been doodling on the back cover of Sports Illustrated.</context>
      <utterance>Detective Donald KIMBALL?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him I'm at lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Patrick, I think he knows you're here. It's only ten-thirty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm sorry. I should've made an appointment.  Was that anything important?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh that? Just mulling over business problems. Examining opportunities...Exchanging rumors... Spreading gossip. They laugh politely.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm Donald KIMBALL</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Pat Bateman. Nice to meet you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what's the topic of discussion?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been hired by Meredith Powell to investigate the disappearance of Paul Owen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not with the FBI or anything, are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, I see...Yes. Paul's disappearance...Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it's nothing that official. I just have some basic questions. About Paul Owen. About yourself-</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perrier? San Pellegrino?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIMBALL takes out a small black notepad and the same gold Cross pen that Bateman and his friends all use. Bateman buzzes Jean.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you bring Mr...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kimball a bottle of San Pelle-</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman watches intently as KIMBALL writes something down in his notebook, then crosses something out. Jean enters and places the bottle of San Pellegrino and a Steuben etched glass on the table, shooting a concerned glance at Bateman. He glares at her. KIMBALL smiles and nods at Jean as she leaves.</context>
      <utterance>It's no problem</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what's the topic of discussion?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The disappearance of Paul Owen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think his family wants this kept quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Staring at the untouched bottle of San Pellegrino) Lime?</context>
      <utterance>Understandable.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, really. I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>You sure? I can always get you a lime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-six. I'll be twenty-seven in October.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you go to school?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvard. The Harvard Business School.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your address?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty-five West Eighty-First Street. The American Gardens Building.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice. Very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause as KIMBALL studies his notebook. Bateman closes his eyes, as if in pain.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me, but are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman reaches into his desk drawer and brings out a bottle of aspirin.</context>
      <utterance>You seem...nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimball takes out a pack of Marlboro's and lays it on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Nuprin? KIMBALL Uh...no, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad habit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I'm sorry. A pause, as Bateman stares at the cigarettes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you rather I not smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I guess it's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Patrick?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whisks in with a crystal ashtray as they sit in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Bring us an ashtray for Mr. KIMBALL, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can you tell me about Paul Owen?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He coughs, shakes two Nuprin into his hand and swallows them dry.</context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How well did you know him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Yale thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...Yale thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean...Yale thing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...there's nothing you can tell me about Paul Owen?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He led what I suppose was an orderly life. He... ate a balanced diet.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of man was he? Besides...  the information you've just given.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope I'm not being cross-examined here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you feel that way?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did Paul hang out?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang...out?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You know...hang out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had a yacht?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he just hung out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A slight pause.</context>
      <utterance>And where did he go to school?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you know this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to know if you know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes another note.</context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else you can tell me about Owen?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were both seven in 1969.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So was I.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any witnesses or fingerprints?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe he did, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His girlfriend doesn't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But...has anyone seen him in London?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know, and was into that whole Yale thing. A pause - the longest so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you consulted a psychic?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had his apartment been burglarized?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not yet. As I said, we're not sure. But... basically no one has seen or heard anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's so typical, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(He stares out the window, lost in thought) One day someone's walking around, going to work, alive, and then...</context>
      <utterance>It's just strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People just...disappear.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The earth just opens up and swallows people.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Eerie. Really eerie.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't the Four Seasons a little far uptown? I mean aren't you going to be late?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, no. There's one...down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman leads him to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh really? I didn't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIMBALL turns to face him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's very good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely, I'm 100% with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, and thanks for your, uh, time, Mr. Bateman. Bateman closes the door firmly on KIMBALL. He closes his eyes and leans against the door, sweating.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like that, slut? The person on the other end clearly hangs up. CLOSE-UP on his fingers dialing the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>boxer shorts by Ralph Lauren, a hundred-and-fifty-dollar white cotton T-shirt by Commes des Garcons. (He snorts like a pig) My Rolex cost- Another hang-up. He dials again.</context>
      <utterance>You want to know what I'm wearing? Sixty-dollar</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Bateman hangs up, frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>Dad, is that you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't seen you around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just haven't been looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman flips on the light inside the limo. He's wearing a tuxedo.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to see my apartment?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman is holding out a $100 bill, which Christie now notices, then takes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not supposed to.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to come to my apartment or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not supposed to.  But I can make an exception.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christie is still looking out behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Do you take American Express?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christie looks at him like he's crazy.</context>
      <utterance>Do you take American Express?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they drive uptown, Bateman dials the cell-phone. He reads off a credit card number.</context>
      <utterance>I'm joking. Come on, get in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause, in which Christie is luxuriating in the tub and Bateman is casually touching her breast.</context>
      <utterance>That's a very fine Chardonnay you're drinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christie reaches for a washcloth.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to clean your vagina.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christie shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>No. From behind. Get on your knees.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to watch. You have a very nice body. The doorman RINGS. Bateman answers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Send her up. Christie, get out and dry off, choose a robe-not the Bijan and come and meet me and our guest in the living room for drinks. Bateman answers the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite blonde, are you? More dirty blonde. I'm going to call you Sabrina. I'm Paul Owen. Bateman escorts her into the living room and brings her a glass of wine. Christie enters, sitting next to Sabrina on the couch, and Bateman sits across from them. There is a long silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two girls look at each other with uncomfortable smiles. Christie shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>So, don't you want to know what I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman is visibly irritated, recrosses his legs.</context>
      <utterance>No, not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another long pause. They shake their heads. Christie stands up and goes over to the CD collection.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I work on Wall Street. At Pierce n Pierce.  Have you heard of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a really nice place here...Paul. How much did you pay for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, that's none of your business, Christie, hut I can assure you it certainly wasn't cheap. Bateman leaves to refill his wine glass and Sabrina takes a pack of cigarettes out of her purse. Bateman returns, carrying a tray of chocolates.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks over to Christie.</context>
      <utterance>No, no smoking. Not in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christie stares at the plate and shakes her head. Sabrina takes one.</context>
      <utterance>Varda truffle?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman goes over to his CDs and scans his vast collection. He takes one out and examines it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to get drunk, but that's a very fine Chardonnay you're not drinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like Phil Collins? I've been a big Genesis fan ever since the release of their 1980 album, Duke. Before that I really didn't understand any of their work. It was too artsy, too intellectual. It was on Duke where Phil Collins' presence became more apparent. He puts aside the CD and takes out another one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>songwriting, this album hits a new peak of professionalism. Sabrina, why don't you dance a little? Sabrina dances awkwardly. Christie sits on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>In terms of lyrical craftsmanship and sheer</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>song, Phil Collins addresses the problem of abusive political authority. Bateman knots a silk scarf around Christie's neck - rather menacingly - then helps her into some suede gloves.</context>
      <utterance>Take the lyrics to "Land of Confusion." In this</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman gets up from his bed and goes over to his armoire. He opens the drawer in which are a nail gun, a coat hanger, a rusty butter knife and a half-smoked cigar. He turns around to see Christie and Sabrina both starting to get up and get dressed. He takes the coat hanger.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch the Rolex.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not through yet...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What an asshole. McDERMOTT Why is Laurie Kennedy dating Price? He's a fucking drug addict. No self-control.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Laurie Kennedy is a total hardbody. What do you think, Bateman?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why do you say it like that? Why does he say it like that?</context>
      <utterance>I know her. I knew her. McDERMOTT</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he dated her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you guess?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girls dig Bateman. He's CQ. You're total CQ, Bateman.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>babe. Don't even pretend you were interested for any other reason.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, guy, but...she's got a lousy personality. McDERMOTT So what? It's all looks. Laurie Kennedy is a</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they have a good personality, then something is very wrong. McDERMOTT If they have a good personality and they are not great looking-who fucking cares?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>little hardbody who will satisfy all sexual demands without being too slutty about things and who will essentially keep her dumb fucking mouth shut. McDERMOTT Listen, the only girls with good personalities who are smart or maybe funny or halfway intelligent or even talented-though God knows what the fuck that means-are ugly chicks.</context>
      <utterance>A good personality consists of a chick with a</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And this is because they have to make up for how fucking unattractive they are. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. McDERMOTT</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what Ed Gein said about women?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ed Gein? Maitre d' at Canal Bar?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, what about dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up from the table. As Bateman walks away, Van Patten grabs a waiter.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this tap water? I don't drink tap water Bring me an Evian or something, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strokes Bateman's hair.</context>
      <utterance>God, Patrick. Why here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman storms out of the men's room, bumping into a waiter and several customers and cursing. Noticing the maitre d' and another waiter conferring and looking at him strangely, Bateman straightens up and smiles and waves cheerfully at them. Carruthers walks up behind him.</context>
      <utterance>I want you. I want you...too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...is...it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've gotta...I've gotta...return some videotapes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRUTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman storms out of the restaurant.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you call me before Thanksgiving?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Courtney sighs and reaches for a bottle of pills on her nightstand, swallowing several. Bateman gets up and begins to dress, admiring himself in the mirror. Courtney watches the TV at low volume.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing tonight?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and...Luis?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were supposed to have dinner at Tad and Maura's, but-you know how Luis is...</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never knew you smoked.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman is making final adjustments to his tie.</context>
      <utterance>You never noticed.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen...Patrick. Can we talk?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that special?  Patrick?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Courtney?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Courtney picks up the black cat and starts petting its head. Bateman heads down the hallway to the front door.</context>
      <utterance>You too.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman gasps and recovers.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bateman?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detective Kendall...uh Campbell?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kimball.  Call me Don.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...you hang out here a lot?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, yes...I mean...whenever necessary. You know. Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>in for "formal questioning?" (He makes quotation marks in the air and laughs a not-so-relaxed laugh)</context>
      <utterance>How's the investigation going? Taken anyone</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rasta Man! The man stares at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man walks by, shaking his head. Bateman wanders into the next room, which is filled with a more familiar crowd: young men in designer suits, girls in black designer dresses. Across the room he spots McDermott and Price sitting with three models, all wearing black mini-dresses. Price and McDermott are having a whispered argument.</context>
      <utterance>I mean-Mon. We be jammin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman looks at the models. DAISY and CARON are staring into space, smoking. LIBBY is trying to work out how to unfold her napkin. Price signals to Bateman for help.</context>
      <utterance>I have to talk to these girls? They're models. McDERMOTT Someone has to get the Bolivian marching powder. You went last time. Stay here. McDermott waves gaily to the girls and disappears.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did Craig go?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not confused, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gorbachev's not downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you Iying?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask me a question.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A model? An actor?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Flattering, but no.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I m into, well, murders and executions mostly. DAISY  Do you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welt...it depends, why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving. I'm getting out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leaving what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman is confused, he thinks Price is referring to his drink.</context>
      <utterance>This.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't, I'll drink it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, Patrick. I'm leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where to? Are you going to go get a gram?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving! I...am...leaving!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me...merchant banking?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you dumb son of a bitch. I'm serious. I'm disappearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where to? Morgan Stanley? Rehab? What? Price looks away. McDermott and Daisy walk up to them. McDERMOTT Hey-don't worry, be happy. Price lifts his arms up as if greeting the crowd and is shouting something that can't be heard, then</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DAISY What is he doing?</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye! Fuckheads! He climbs over the railing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price leaps from the balcony. He disappears for a moment then resurfaces and runs off into the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Price! Come back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said...  He said you gave him bad vibes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's...that's too bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm dumb, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman nods without looking up.</context>
      <utterance>Doin' the crossword?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BATEMAN doesn't respond. We see that every space on the puzzle has been filled in with the words MEAT or BONE. Jean drops the folder on his desk and then walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Need help?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Patrick?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He erases one of the M's on the crossword puzzle.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to accompany me to dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is...if you're not doing anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no. I have no plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Well, isn't this a coincidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans back and pulls a Zagat's from the desk drawer.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, where should we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anywhere you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's not think about what I want. How about anywhere you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Patrick, I can't make this decision.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, come on. Anywhere you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I can't.  I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman stops looking through the Zagat's guide and smiles at her.</context>
      <utterance>What about...Dorsia?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soooo...Dorsia is where Jean wants to go...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know. No, we'll go anywhere you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dials the number.</context>
      <utterance>Dorsia is...fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dorsia, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, can you take two tonight, oh, let's say at nine o'clock? He checks his Rolex and winks at Jean.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are totally booked.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really? That's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said we are totally booked.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two at nine? Perfect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up the phone. He walks over to the coat rack. He glances over at Jean, who is still standing in front of the desk, confused.</context>
      <utterance>See you then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes? You're dressed...okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't give them a name.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>They know me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick, it's so...elegant. What a wonderful view. Bateman opens up the freezer where Daisy's head is cleady visible.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean? Sorbet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman walks in with a bottle of wine and a corkscrew in his hand and hands her the sorbet. Jean is eating the sorbet.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Patrick. I'd love some.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want a bite?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on a diet. But thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a boyfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you seeing anyone? I mean, seriously?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman opens up a cupboard where there are a lot of very Bateman opens a cupboard where there are a lot of neatly ordered weapons - an ax, a rifle, a chain saw, duct tape, twine and a nail gun.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe. I don't know Not really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Ted Bundy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>taping something. Bateman goes back to the cupboard for the nail gun.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Uh, tape. Duct tape. I...need it for...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...No! Put it in the carton.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From behind, we follow Bateman as he walks across the room and stands behind the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Make someone happy-have you ever wanted to?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>want to have a meaningful relationship with someone special.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for...I guess you could say I just</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points the nail gun at the back of Jean's head. The phone RINGS. Startled, Bateman hides the nail gun behind his back. The answering machine picks up. As Bateman listens he discreetly places the nail gun behind the couch. He sits down opposite Jean, enjoying her discomfort as she listens to the message.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmmm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Was that...Evelyn?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Are you still seeing her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I have no right to ask that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pause.</context>
      <utterance>Do you want me to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I don t think I can...control myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you stay, I think something bad will happen. I think I might hurt you.  You don't want to get hurt, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, I guess not. I don't want to get bruised. You're right, I should go. She gets up to leave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kimball-I've been wanting to talk with you, Come into my office. Jean, great jacket. Matsuda? Jean looks flustered. Kimball follows Bateman into his office.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I actually came to see Timothy Price, but he's taken a leave of absence.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, gone into rehab. Shame.  Is he a suspect?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you remember where you were on the night of Paul's disappearance?  Which was on the twentieth of December?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens his desk drawer and pretends to search through his diary.</context>
      <utterance>God...I guess...I was probably returning videotapes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a date with a girl named Veronica.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. That's not what I've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not the information I've received.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...I...Wait...What information have you received?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see...  That you were with-</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I could he wrong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, yes, I'd like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the night of Owen's disappearance, it would make my job a lot easier.</context>
      <utterance>And if you could try and pin down where you were</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimball is rifling through his briefcase. He pulls out a new shrink wrapped CD and holds it up.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. I'm with you on that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huey Lewis and the News. Great stuff. Heard it? I just bought it on my way here. Bateman stares at the CD - stunned, terrified.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>singers.</context>
      <utterance>Never. I mean...I don't really like...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a big music fan, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I like music. Just-they're-Huey's too... black sounding. For me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, to each his own. So-lunch, Thursday? I'll call your secretary about reservations.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHRISTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her a $500 bill.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just come in the limo and talk to me for a minute. The driver's here, you'll be safe. Christie gets in hesitantly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing like last time, promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours her a shot of vodka and makes her drink it.</context>
      <utterance>Alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you're looking great, how have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friend told me I should maybe even get a lawyer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows alongside her slowly in the limo, waving a huge wad of cash at her. She hesitates; he uses the money to lure her into the car. As she reluctantly gets into the limo, she reaches for the money. He snatches it away.</context>
      <utterance>Bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the money and puts it inside her shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Uh uh uh. Half now, half later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHRISTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is nicer than your other apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not that nice. Silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you two meet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's my...cousin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. Elizabeth looks at Bateman dubiously.</context>
      <utterance>She's from...France.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman hands her a cordless phone. She dials, and stares At Christie while she waits for someone to answer.</context>
      <utterance>Where's your phone? I've got to call Harley.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christie looks at Bateman and then back at Elizabeth.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you summer? Southampton?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, it's his machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, it's three in the morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell him you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman has poured her another glass of wine. She downs the whole glass, making a face.</context>
      <utterance>Why would I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harley? It's me. I need your services. Translate that anyway you'd like. I'm at-</context>
      <utterance>This tastes weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're at Paul Owen s.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul Owen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(She waves him away and continues into the reciever) Anyway, I'm at Paul Norman's and I'll try you later and if I don't see you at Canal Bar tomorrow night I'm going to sic my hairdresser on you. She hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>I want the number, idiot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick, you re a lunatic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Don't you find Christie attractive?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's not get lewd.  I'm in no mood to have a lewd conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. I think it would be a turn-on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christie shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Does he do this all the time?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christie looks at her wine and gingerly takes a sip.</context>
      <utterance>Christie, you're not drinking your wine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>called simply Whitney Houston had four number-one singles on it? Did you know that, Christie? Whitney's voice leaps across so many boundaries and is so versatile-though she's mainly a jazz singer-that it's hard to take in the album on a first listening.</context>
      <utterance>Did you know that Whitney Houston's debut LP</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>actually have a Whitney Houston CD? More than one? She giggles, rolling off the sofa onto the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You actually listen to Whitney Houston? You</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a firm commitment.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think, Evelyn, that we've...lost touch. Evelyn waves to a couple across the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk about what, Patrick? What is there to talk about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's over, Evelyn. It's all over</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>is no joke. I don't think we should see each other anymore.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fucking serious. It's fucking over. Us. This</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really serious, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about the past? Our past?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We never really shared one.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're inhuman.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm...in touch with humanity. Evelyn, I'm sorry.  You're just not terribly important to me. Evelyn begins to cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches desperately across the table and takes his hand. Bateman pulls his hand away.</context>
      <utterance>I know my behavior is...erratic sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, I can't believe this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But where?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rushes out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>I have to return some videotapes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The small mangy cat rubs against him. He picks it up and walks toward an ATM, holding the cat. He puts his card in the machine. The screen reads: FEED ME A STRAY CAT. Bateman begins to attempt to shove the kitten into the deposit slot with some difficulty. The kitten squeals. He takes a gun from out of his pocket and points it at the kitten. He doesn't notice the woman waiting behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Here kitty, kitty.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman wheels around and shoots her. She falls screaming to the floor. Responding to the gunshot, A POLICE CAR SIREN WAILS in the distance. Bateman breaks into a run. The police car screeches after him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! Stop that! What are you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No hash browns?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not in the mood, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But...everyone orders the hash browns here. I mean- it's-have you been here before?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Suit yourself, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, the night he disappeared? Any new thoughts on what you did?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not really sure. I had a shower...and some sorbet?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think maybe you've got your dates mixed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how? Where do you place Paul that night?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've questioned him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Marcus denied it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, does Marcus have an alibi?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He does? You're sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I checked it out. It's clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. KIMBALL Now where were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where was Marcus?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wasn't with Paul Owen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who was he with?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Mrs. Wolfe is up there right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Wolfe?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The real estate agent? You do have an appointment, don't you? Bateman steps out of the elevator and walks cautiously down the hallway. Owen's door is open. The apartment is freshly painted and has been immaculately redecorated in English country-house style: overstuffed sofas, lots of chintz. There are flowers everywhere, and a YOUNG YUPPIE COUPLE stands admiring the place talkingto the realtor, MRS. WOLFE. Bateman wanders down the hallway, looking for familiar signs. He stops at the closet where we last saw two dead girls hanging. He opens the door and the light switches on, but it is empty. Mrs. Wolfe approaches, smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WOLFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you my two o'clock?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Wolfe eyes him strangely, then looks down at the surgical mash clutched in his hand. Her expression changes.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WOLFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him impassively.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for...Paul Owen's...place.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't he live here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WOLFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WOLFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saw the ad in the Times?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Yes. I mean yes, I did. In the Times. But... doesn't Paul Owen still live here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WOLFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman is shaking as they continue to stare at each other.</context>
      <utterance>There was no ad in the Times.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WOLFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you should go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I think...I want to know what happened here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WOLFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make any trouble. Please. I suggest you go. Bateman backs away slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WOLFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Wolfe glares at him as he walks down the hall, rattled, and gets into the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>I won't...don't worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman looks up at him wild-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Kinsley.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy walks away, utterly unfazed. Bateman wanders down the street, banging his briefcase against walls, garbage cans, etc.</context>
      <utterance>See you at Fluties, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick Bateman's office.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean? Hello? Jean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick? Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Jean, I need help!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean-I'm not-</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Craig McDermott called. He wants to meet you and David Van Patten and Tim Price at Harry's for drinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, what did you say, you dumb bitch?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patrick? I can't hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are I doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you? Patrick, what's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think I'm gonna make it, Jean.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...to the office this afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just...say...no!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Patrick? Are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up. He throws the Walkman which is around his neck into a nearby trash can, and wipes his face with his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Stop sounding so Fucking sad! Jesus!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VAN PATTEN Le Cirque, Flamingo East, Oyster Bar, come on, faggots-just get a res.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going anywhere unless we have a reservation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep your shirt on. Maybe lose the suspenders. Bateman spots HAROLD CARNES at the bar, tenses.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches Carnes cautiously.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, gentlemen. Right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carnes is surprised, turns around, looks vaguely confused.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Carnes, they will not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carnes lights a cigarette, stalling. Then laughs.</context>
      <utterance>So, Harold, did you get my message?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a pretty long message, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What exactly do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carnes is distracted, waving at people.</context>
      <utterance>The message you left.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carnes? Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? Bateman is what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, if you'll excuse me, I really must...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. I really must he going.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carnes stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Why not, you stupid bastard?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you...didn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman returns back to his friends' table, in a daze. They are all looking at the television, where Ronald Reagan is giving a speech about Iran Contra. They are halfheartedly arguing about whether or not he's lying.</context>
      <utterance>Now, if you'll excuse me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman laughs at this. Price shoots him a look.</context>
      <utterance>Some guys are just born cool, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Bateman, what are YOU SO fucking zany about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just a happy camper. Rockin' and a-rollin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAN PATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you want another Perrier Timothy? Some seltzer water?</context>
      <utterance>Rehab's done wonders for you, pal. Working for UNICEF now? McDERMOTT</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh brother look-he presents himself as a harmless Old codger. But inside... Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SOUNDS OF THE BAR FADE AWAY and we hear Bateman's thoughts:</context>
      <utterance>But inside...</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But inside doesn't matter...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SOUNDS OF THE BAR RETURN.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside? Yes, inside? Believe it or not, Price we're actually listening to you.</context>
      <utterance>McDERMOTT</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bateman looks up and smiles at Price. Then shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Bateman? Come on, what do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The conversation breaks up as Van Patten takes out his phone.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
