<movie id="31" title="American Splendor">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce springs up, alarmed.</context>
      <utterance>Joyce... Joyce?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey just stands there for a moment saying nothing.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong, Harvey? What are you doing up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce rubs her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me the truth. Am I some guy who writes about himself in a comic book? Or am I just -- am I just a character in that book?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce just stares at him, unsure how to answer. Suddenly Harvey collapses. Joyce leaps from the bed, nervous, hysterical. She gets down on the floor and shakes him.</context>
      <utterance>If I die, will 'dat character keep goin'? Or will he just fade away...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Omigod, Harvey! Harvey, wake up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BOYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trick or treat!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lady drops a candy apple in each boy's container.</context>
      <utterance>Well, look at this! All the superheroes on the porch! Ain't that cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what about you young man?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other boys giggle. The kid flashes them a "kick yer ass" look.</context>
      <utterance>What about what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you supposed to be?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Harvey Pekar .</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey Pekar? That doesn't sound like a super hero to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pecker, Pecker...</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Housewife stares at him, confused.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't no super hero, lady. I'm just a kid from the neighborhood, alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frustrated, the kid throws his pillowcase down. He trudges off as the others watch in confusion.</context>
      <utterance>Ahh, forget this...</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is everybody so stoopid?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc, you gotta help me. My old lady's dumping me 'cause I can't talk. She says I'm a social embarrassment. Now that she's got her PhD, she's some hot shit academic star an' I'm nuthin' but a file clerk with nothin' ta say an' no voice ta say it. But me bein' a file clerk was fine when I wrote the damn check for her tuition --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points the tongue depressor at Harvey's mouth but he just keeps on going.</context>
      <utterance>Harvey, stop talking please, and open wide.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just don't get it... We were doin' okay for a while. Then we took that stupid belated honeymoon. I started losin' my voice on the plane. Can you believe that... On the plane, doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad timing, I guess. Now please say "Ah," Mr. Pekar.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Ahhh."  "Ahhh" ruined the trip. I got crazy, started to worry my voice would never come back. I mean, my wife didn't know me so long before we got hitched. What if she totally forgets what I'm like? Man, it's torture --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor shines a penlight into Harvey's mouth and looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises an eyebrow. Harvey catches this. Hypochondria overtakes him.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor removes the penlight.</context>
      <utterance>What? Is it bad, doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey jumps off the table.</context>
      <utterance>It's not good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cancer? First I got marital problems and now yer tellin' me I got throat cancer? Omigod...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Relieved, Harvey calms down. He nods, agreeing to be good.</context>
      <utterance>Harvey, calm down. It's not cancer. You have a nodule on your vocal chords. Probably from screaming and yelling too much. And if you don't stop talking and give it a rest, you're gonna lose your voice completely.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whew... Okay, okay. But fer how long?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few months.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Harvey's voice cracks under his effort to raise it. He sheepishly grabs his throat.</context>
      <utterance>Months!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Operate? Harvey gets nervous again. The Doctor throws him his clothing.</context>
      <utterance>See? More of that and you'll do permanent damage. Now go home, keep your mouth shut, and hopefully we won't have to operate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey barely looks up. He nods his head "yes" and keeps walking.</context>
      <utterance>Hi Harvey. You weren't in work today. Are you okay, Harvey?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey leaves Toby behind and turns the corner.</context>
      <utterance>I'm heading downtown to the White Castle. Wanna come, Harvey?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANISH WOMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already told you, I'm waiting for a call!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANISH WOMAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? Since when is this your private office?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANISH WOMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey stops in his tracks and stares at them, jealous of their ability to speak. CLOSE UP: SPANISH WOMAN 1's MOUTH</context>
      <utterance>Since you can kiss my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at 'em yakkin'. How do they do it? Out of the corner of her eye, WOMAN 2 notices Harvey eavesdropping.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Startled, Harvey moves on.</context>
      <utterance>Ay, what are you looking at? Maricone!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, BAM! Harvey is awakened from his reverie by a snowball. The kids laugh loudly. He wipes away the snow and walks on. A VOICE OVER interrupts the scene.</context>
      <utterance>They all make it seem so easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's our man walking home from the doctor's. He's got the weight of the world on him. And fer what, really? 'Cause his throat's a little screwy? Man, people in India are starvin' to death every day. His problems are nothin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey's voice breaks up.</context>
      <utterance>Ay... What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly what it looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whattya mean!! You mean yer dumpin' me?! Fer what?  Ah, shit! That last yell did it. Harvey grabs throat in pain, torn between his throat discomfort and trying to stop his wife from leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, your plebeian lifestyle isn't working for me anymore. Cleveland's not working for me anymore. I gotta get out of here before I kill myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gathers her bags and heads for the door. Harvey trails her, trying to reason. He opens his mouth, but nothing comes out.</context>
      <utterance>But --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A nurse pops her head in. Harvey hands her a file.</context>
      <utterance>Here's our man -- yeah alright, here's me -- or the guy playin' me, anyway, though he don't look nothin' like me, but whatever. So it's a few months later an' I'm workin' my flunky, file-clerk gig at the V.A. Hospital. My voice still ain't back yet. Things seem like they can't get any worse...</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't hear her, still stewing about LANA. He shoves the last files in the cart and pushes it away.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Harvey dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plebeian... where the hell did she get that shit?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MR. BOATS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Harvey turns around. Mr. Boats -- a portly, African-American maintenance worker wearing a bow-tie -- steps into Harvey's row. He has a tool box.</context>
      <utterance>Avoid the reeking herd! Shun the polluted flock! Live like that stoic bird, The eagle of the rock!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey resumes shelving.</context>
      <utterance>Huh? Oh. Hiya, Mr. Boats.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what that means, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Boats laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's from an Elinor Hoyt Wylie poem. It means stay away from the crowds of common ordinary people an' do yer own thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope, it means don't compromise yourself for women. Ain't gonna do you no good! Get away from 'em as soon as you can!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I ain't got no woman now. So I'm living like the stoic bird, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somehow this doesn't make Harvey feel any better about his life.</context>
      <utterance>The only way to live, son.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that fool over there. What's he wearing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh? That's an A.M.-F.M. radio he's listening to... They got 'em fixed up now like a pair of earmuffs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MMPH! Isn't that somethin! People have gone crazy. They'll buy any kinda junk! Probably listening to that loud rock stuff. Junk, junk, it's all junk!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Boats looks at him like he's crazy.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know. Rock music's got some good qualities. I mean it ain't jazz or nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, when you gonna bring me in some good records? Some Nat "King" Cole with Strings...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Boats stops and yells down the hall at Harvey.</context>
      <utterance>I don't got any of that, Mr. Boats...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey shakes his head as Mr. Boats finishes his diatribe. Mr. Boats turns into a room.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you got it... You're keepin' it at home, though! You won't turn loose the good stuff... You just sell the junk!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mona Lisa, Mona Lisa. Men have named you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>One of Harvey's pals -- MARTY -- pulls a record out of a box.</context>
      <utterance>In the early sixties I was with some buddies at a junk sale looking for some choice sides when I met this shy, retiring cat from Philadelphia named Bob Crumb. You know the guy; Fritz the Cat, Mr. Natural an' all -- they made a movie about him, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey jumps up from his search to check out the LP.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Harv. You dig Jay McShann. You gonna buy that or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Marty. It's got a lamination crack in it...  A quarter. Maybe I can get him down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are one cheap bastard Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A skinny guy with a big nose, glasses and a ratty trench coat taps Harvey on the shoulder. He is soft-spoken, a bit shy and very odd -- a young ROBERT CRUMB.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know I'm tight, man, but I live on a government wage.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You collect Jay McShann, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, man. How 'bout you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A greaser-type guy in a leather jacket, PAHLS, joins them.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah but most of my records are back in Philly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAHLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harv, meet my buddy Bob Crumb. He just moved to town. He's an artist at American Greeting Card Company.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAHLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should see his comics, Harv. They are outta sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? I'm into comics myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>HARVEY marches back and forth holding Crumb's illustrated comic novel. CRUMB sits on the floor nursing a beer and sorting through vintage comic books. Harvey's bursting with so much enthusiasm, it's almost aggressive.</context>
      <utterance>So Crumb showed me this comic book novel he was working on -- THE BIG YUM YUM BOOK. I'd never seen anything like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crumb ignores Harvey's praise.</context>
      <utterance>It's terrific, man! I really dig your work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This PETER WHEAT book is by Walt Kelly... It's pretty rare.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Can I get good bread for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey flops down in an overstuffed chair. Stuffing flies out. He sips his beer.</context>
      <utterance>Nah! Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen man, let's get back to your book. What are you gonna do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey flips through the book.</context>
      <utterance>I hadn't thought about it. It's just an exercise.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crumb is immune to Harvey's enthusiasm.</context>
      <utterance>It's more than an exercise. It's breaking ground, man. There's some wild shit in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're spitting on me, Harvey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey glances up at his portrait, completely unselfconscious.</context>
      <utterance>Check it out, man. Pretty scary.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey goes back to reading. Crumb back to sketching.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, ya don't know the half of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Crumb slowly evaporates from the room, leaving Harvey totally alone.</context>
      <utterance>Eventually people got hip to Crumb's art work and he started hangin' out with a Bohemian crowd. After a while, he got sick of greeting cards and moved away to San Francisco where he got the whole underground comic scene off the ground.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>HARVEY and R. CRUMB sit on a park bench together by a bus stop. A distraught Harvey whines while Crumb just sketches. Harvey's voice is still raspy.</context>
      <utterance>Once he came to visit when I was really feelin' bad. It was right around the time of my throat operation, an' right after my second wife left me. At first it was pretty weird. I mean, here my life was falling apart an' everything was going great for him. I was on my second divorce an' he was a big hit with the chicks. I was a nothin' file clerk and he was this famous cartoonist.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crumb may or may not be listening to Harvey. It's hard to tell.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno, man. On the one hand most women gettin' graduate degrees wouldn't give a guy like me the time a' day. An' she married me an' everything, so I gotta give her some kinda credit. But then she got so mean to me in the end. An' it ain't like I tried t'keep her captive or anything like that, y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' then on top of it I lost my voice for three months. I still sound like shit, but before I had nothin'. Man, talk about hell. I started forgettin' what I sound like, y'know? So I started writin' stuff down -- stories an' things, my points a' view, ideas. I even published a couple jazz record reviews. I guess that ended up bein' a good thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment, they both just sit there saying nothing to each other, each man in his own private universe. Finally Harvey looks over to Crumb.</context>
      <utterance>But don't think I buy into this "growth" crap. Everybody talks about how bad experiences can cause ya t'grow, an' all that cliched stuff. I've had enough bad experiences and growth to last me plenty.  Right now, I'd be glad to trade some growth for happiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crumb never looks up from his picture.</context>
      <utterance>So how long are ya stayin' in Cleveland?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno, man. I gotta go visit this chick in New York. And I'm really busy with the comic book stuff. It's good bread and all man but I'm getting fed up with the whole scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are ya talkin' about? Yer makin' a good living doin' yer art? Sheesh. How many guys get that lucky in their life, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I dunno.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know man, people are startin' to know the name "Crumb." When you croak you're gonna leave something behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, my ashes and some crappy doodles. It's not like I'm Blind Lemon Jefferson or Big Mama Thornton.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, man. It sure beats workin' a gig like mine -- being a nobody flunky and sellin' records on the side for a buck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey nods in agreement, mulling this over. He's not at all offended.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well that's true...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLD JEWISH LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, goily, dese glasses are six for $2.00 because I couldn't carry twelf... But I vanted twelf so today I'm buying six more... But you should only charge me $1.50 for dem... It's ok, you can esk de meneger. Harvey rolls his eyes and stamps his foot impatiently. He knows he's in trouble now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank! I need a price check.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARTOON HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Human Harvey seems oblivious to his cartoon replica. He impatiently leans on his cart, waiting and seething.</context>
      <utterance>Man, Old Jewish Ladies will argue forever with a cashier about anything. Get behind them in a line an' yer gonna wait forever!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTOON HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE LEFT HAND SIDE OF THE SCREEN... The MANAGER finally arrives. The Old Lady haggles with him, too.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, I'm a yid myself, an' the women in my family are like that... But I never got used to it... I may be cheap, but I got limits!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD JEWISH LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MEANWHILE ON THE RIGHT HAND SIDE... The Cartoon Harvey turns to address the Human Harvey, who actually looks him in the eyes. It now seems Human Harvey can actually hear his cartoon alter ego.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Let me 'splain von more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTOON HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wake up! You're whole life's gettin' eaten away by this kinda crap! What kind of existence is this? Is this all a workin' stiff like you can expect? Ya gonna suffer in silence fer the rest a' yer life?! Or ya gonna make a mark. Huh? Huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATTRESS GUY #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how smart is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTRESS GUY #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. I guess she's about average.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTRESS GUY #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drop the mattress in place. With the window framing these guys, the scene FREEZES, looking just like a comic book panel.</context>
      <utterance>Average? Hey, man. Average is dumb!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, ever since I read your stuff, man I've been thinking I could write comic book stories that were different from anything being done.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinkin', the guys who do animal comics and super-hero stuff are really limited 'cause they gotta try to appeal to kids. And underground comics like yours have been really subversive or opened things up politically. But there is still plenty more ta be done with 'em, too, y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pass me the ketchup?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crumb finally looks up from Harvey's work.</context>
      <utterance>I mean with pictures and words, it could be more of an art form. Like those French movies are. Or De Sica over in Italy, y'know?... So I tried writin' some things about real life. Stuff the everyman's gotta deal with.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Er, yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You turned yourself into a comic hero?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crumb reads more. Harvey waits anxiously. Finally Crumb starts to chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>Sorta, yeah. But no idealized shit. No phony bullshit. The real thing, y'know? Ordinary life is pretty complex stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are really good, Harv.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crumb shuffles through more.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Ya think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey is practically bursting.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. This is great stuff, man. I dig it. Can I take them home and illustrate them?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey's voice breaks like a kid in puberty. He clears his throat. And something miraculous happens... When Harvey opens his mouth to speak his LARYNGITIS IS GONE!</context>
      <utterance>Wow!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd do that for me, man? That'd be great! I can't draw a straight line!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's up with your voice, Harv? All of a sudden it sounds fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, man! I guess you cured me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WW II VET PATIENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hot off the presses, huh? We got a regular Hemingway here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DOCTOR 3 chimes in.</context>
      <utterance>No way, Jack, I don't go in for that macho crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know you could draw, Pekar.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TOBY, the supernerd from the bus stop, grabs the comic book off the table and peruses it.</context>
      <utterance>Nah! I don't draw. I just write the stories. A buddy of mine and some of his friends do the art work.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, am I in here? You promised I would be in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUDDENLY, MR. BOATS -- Harvey's philosophical co-worker -- pushes his way thorough the crowd. He snatches the comic out of Toby's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! Yeah! You're in there, alright? Jeez, Toby.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me see this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Boats, it's not polite to grab things. Next time --</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mr. Boats talks, the crowd starts to disperse.</context>
      <utterance>Son, you done good. Ya know, I was up in Toronto a few weeks back an' I saw the Red Chinese Ballet...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Boats hands the comic book back to Harvey and turns on his heels. Through the window he notices TWO VETS IN WHEELCHAIRS moving down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Now that was beautiful. The way those people were dancing together. Those Chinese work hard. I tell ya, they work hard -- Where is everybody goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BOATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey stands there, his moment of glory passed. But it's okay. He flips through his comic and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Where these sickly men rushin' off to? They ain't goin' nowhere for now. Maybe not for a long time. But damn if they ain't in a rush to get there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey rolls his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Hey look guys, here comes Captain America.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut it out. Man, I ain't nothin' yet compared to Bob Crumb.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUYS laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, listen to him. One lousy comic book and he wants to be Crumb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PAHLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Harvey, if ya wanna make comics for adults, ya oughtta put some dirty stuff in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey hangs with the guys but he doesn't engage. He seems to be observing them more than interacting with them.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you can write about Marty's sex life.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right Marty? I heard ya went out with Bonnie yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAHLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Howdja do? Wudja git offa her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guys all stare at him for a moment. Then they crack up.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, lousy. All's I got wuz armaround.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Toby comes in, decked out in plaid and stripes. He has an empty messenger bag.</context>
      <utterance>So -- to stave off desperation and feelings of uselessness -- I resigned myself to a menial existence. But hey, maybe the guy who's had a happy life feels worse just before he dies than th' guy who had a sad one. Or, maybe not. I dunno. Maybe I just needed a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey turns around. He seems down, depressed.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Harvey. Do you want these gourmet jelly beans? I gave up sweets for lent.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby watches Harvey eat a few.</context>
      <utterance>Huh? Sure, I'll take 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, watermelon. That's pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby heads down a file row and proceeds to take a few off the shelves, stuffing his bag. Harvey gets up and comes after him.</context>
      <utterance>I recommend the pina coladas. They are excellent and very authentic tasting.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Toby, can you eat lentils during lent?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. I don't see why not. You can't eat meat on certain days, but lentils should be acceptable anytime.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya think there's any connection between lentils and lent?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so but I'll ask Sister Mary Fred at church on Sunday.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sister Mary Fred, huh? Is she cute? Sounds kinda mannish but who am I to be picky.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, you're funny. She's a nun.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what? Maybe she became a nun because she couldn't get a guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, she became a nun because she had a higher calling.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Higher calling. That is such a crock of shit. I don't know why you waste your time prayin' anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby turns on his heels and walks off.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Harvey, I like the ritual. And I'm a very spiritual person. You know, you should try believing in something bigger than yourself. It might cheer you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey shrugs and digs deep into the jelly bean bag. He pulls out a fistful.</context>
      <utterance>What? Do I seem depressed, Toby? Toby doesn't respond.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GIRLS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>HARVEY surveys the donuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNTER GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Half in a daze, Harvey stares at the chick.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you're Harvey Pekar.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alice Quinn. From school. Harvey studies her face. Suddenly, it clicks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey pays and receives his items. They step back towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. College. We had a couple lit classes together.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey scratches his armpit.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to you? You just disappeared after one semester.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, man. I got good grades and all but there was this required math class. I can't do math, an' that required class hangin' over my head made me crazy. Eventually the pressure got to be too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This perks Harvey up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you're doing okay anyway. I heard all about your jazz reviews and your comics.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya did?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey stares at her wedding ring. His face drops.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, you're famous. Meanwhile I got my degree but I'm just a plain old wife and mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alice laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm not doing as great as ya think. My second wife divorced me and I work at a dead end job as a file clerk. Sometimes I hang out with the guys on the corner but most of the time I just stay home by myself and read.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're luckier than you think. My husband and kids make it impossible for me to cuddle up with a good book.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one of my favorites.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alice smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I hope it don't end like so many a' those naturalist novels... With someone getting crushed ta earth by forces he can't control.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits home with Harvey. He can't believe he's made such a connection with this woman. Alice stops in front of a beat-up station wagon.</context>
      <utterance>I think you'll be pleasantly surprised. It's certainly not a Hollywood happy ending, but it's pretty truthful. Which is rare these days...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice car. I don't have one yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I give ya a lift somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey looks down, a little sad.</context>
      <utterance>Nah. It's a nice day. I'll just walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we should have you over sometime for dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alice pecks Harvey on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, I'd be glad t'come. But if you really wanna do me a favor, introduce me to some a' your single girlfriends. I bet they're all smart like you. I'm no catch, though, so I'll take anything you can get me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets into the car.</context>
      <utterance>I'll work on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey watches as she drives off.</context>
      <utterance>Nice seeing ya Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I got home, I finished reading JENNIE GERHARDT. It was real good, way better than I expected. That Alice wuz right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>THE CAMERA TRAVELS AROUND THE ROOM TO FIND: Harvey again, now silhouetted in the door frame, still clutching the book and obsessed by his thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>Sure Lester -- the main character -- croaks in the end, but at least he's old and dies a natural dignified death.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>THE CAMERA TRAVELS AGAIN TO FIND Harvey sitting on a chair in the corner of his room. His head is bowed. His shoulders slump over, as if he's struggling with something weighty.</context>
      <utterance>I was more alone that weekend than any. All I did was think about JENNIE GERHARDT an' Alice Quinn an' all the decades of people I have known.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>THE CAMERA TRAVELS A FINAL TIME TO FIND: Harvey sprawled across his couch. But he's not asleep; he's still obsessing. The book lies on his chest like a lover. CLOSE UP of Harvey's troubled face. Beneath the pain, we see hope and determination.</context>
      <utterance>The more I thought, the more I felt like cryin'; Life seemed so sweet an' so sad an' so hard t'let go of in the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But hey, man. Every day's a brand new deal, right? Just keep on workin' and sump'n's bound ta turn up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to the new American Splendor?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We sold 'em, babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it! I put one aside for myself, next to the register. I didn't even get a chance to read it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce leans against the counter. She pushes up her glasses and looks really upset.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, sorry, Joyce. I didn't know you were such a Splendor fan. Next time take it home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce starts slamming things around the store. Finally Rand grabs his stuff.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'll call the publisher. But they take so damn long. Shit! Why does everything in my life have to be such a complicated disaster...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rand leaves. Joyce barely notices, still brewing.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm gonna hustle before the vibe in here gets any worse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Harvey scratches his head. He mutters to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Despite our steadily faltering business, my partner managed to sell the last copy of American Splendor 8 out from under me. I'm a big fan and I hate to wait for a new order. Is there any way I can get it from you direct? Sincerely, Joyce Brabner.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...man, she's got good lookin' handwritin'...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I think you an' I got a lot in common. How am I gonna get you to come visit me in Cleveland?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cleveland? You think that's a good idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLIP! He clips off a big one.</context>
      <utterance>It's a great idea. You should meet me, 'cause I'm a great guy. Despite the way my comics read, I got a lot of redeeming characteristics.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Where would I stay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With me. Don't worry, I'm not gonna put no moves on you or anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not worried about that...  Hold on, I just spilled chamomile tea all over my bathrobe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Joyce sighs and lies down. A variety of AMERICAN SPLENDORS are across her bed. Different interpretations of Harvey stare up at her.</context>
      <utterance>So what are ya worried about then?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the way all those different artists draw you, I don't quite know what to expect. I mean sometimes you look like a younger Brando, but then the way Crumb draws you -- like a hairy ape with all those stinky, wavy lines radiating off your body -- it's kind of scary.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Joyce smiles for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Those are motion lines. I'm an active guy. Anyway, just come out here an' I'll try to be anyone you want me ta be.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a dangerous offer. I'm a notorious reformer...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Joyce turns around. The flesh and blood HARVEY PEKAR stands before her -- not quite as bad as the Crumb version, not quite as good as the Dumm version, but still acceptable. She sighs with relief.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Are you Joyce?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She politely offers her hand. Harvey shakes it, but he looks overwhelmed, worried and pessimistic.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Harvey. We finally meet in person.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce lets go of his hand. She stares at him in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya. Look, before we get started with any of this, ya might as well know right off the bat. I had a vasectomy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somethin's wrong. Yer lookin' around everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I never imagined you eating in a place like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? I never been here. I thought you'd like it. But obviously ya don't, do ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey shakes his head, feeling more pessimistic.</context>
      <utterance>It's fine. What difference does it make?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. None, I guess.  They sure got a lot of meat on this menu.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a vegetarian?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce grabs a bread stick.</context>
      <utterance>Kinda. I mean ever since I got a pet cat, I couldn't eat animals anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey just stares at her.</context>
      <utterance>Hmm. I support and identify with groups like PETA, but unfortunately I'm a self-diagnosed anemic. Also, I have all these food allergies to vegetables that give me serious intestinal distress. I guess I have a lot of borderline health disorders that limit me politically when it comes to eating.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Yer a sick woman, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cheery waitress bounces over.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet. But I expect to be. Everyone in my family's got some kind of degenerative illness.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They slowly look up at her.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon! I'm your server Cindy! What can I bring you two today?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce puts down her bag.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I was gonna clean up, but why should I give you any false notions? The truth is I got a serious problem with cleanliness. I could wash a dish ten times and it'd still dirty. They even kicked me outta the Army 'cause I couldn't learn ta make a bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slumps down on the sofa as if she's been here a million times. She rubs her head. Harvey sits next to her.</context>
      <utterance>I've seen worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey just bounces back up and obeys.</context>
      <utterance>Harvey, go get me water and a few aspirin.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, ya got a headache?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey empties the aspirin bottle in his palm. For some reason, he's feeling more comfortable.</context>
      <utterance>No, but I want to avoid one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey arrives back with the aspirin. He hands it to Joyce.</context>
      <utterance>Well lemme tell ya Joyce, it sure is nice ta have company. I mean, despite all your problems, you seem like a great person. An' hey, sorry if my dating skills are kinda rusty, but I've just been through hell and back with women. I mean that last one turned out to be a real nasty bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce swallows the pill. Harvey sits down next to her.</context>
      <utterance>I had a nice time with you, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? You had a nice time?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make people repeat themselves. It's annoying.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're inches away from each other.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls him close. Harvey plants a kiss on her. They slowly separate. Joyce's eyes are closed. She likes him. He kisses her again. They start making out, moaning a bit. But before it gets heavy --</context>
      <utterance>C'mere...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce opens her eyes. She looks uneasy.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which door's the bathroom?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce puts the can down.</context>
      <utterance>Can I make ya something? How about some chamomile tea?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chamomile tea? What the hell's a guy like you doing with that? I thought you drink soda pop for breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Joyce turns her head to the door. She's truly surprised by what Harvey's just said. And very moved. She smiles to herself.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno. I noticed you drank a lot of it when we started talkin' on the phone. So I stocked up on herbal teas for your visit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce slowly opens the door. She leans against the door frame like she's just been through a war. She takes off her glasses and cleans them off with her shirt.</context>
      <utterance>The girl at the Food Co-op picked me out all kinds of herbal stuff. One of 'ems good for stomachaches. Grandma Bear's Tummy Mint, I think. Are you still there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, we better skip this whole courtship thing and just get married.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, am I glad I talked you into comin' up here. Any more time alone and I mighta lost it fer good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you don't have any problems with movin' to Cleveland?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. I find most American cities depressing in the same way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>An' yer okay with the vasectomy thing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ay Toby.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you can't have any of my White Castle hamburgers so please don't even ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I have a fry? Harvey reaches for a handful of Toby's fries.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey leans in, always amused by Toby. He steals another fry.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, but just a couple, Harvey. I'm not going to eat dinner until very late and this has got to hold me over.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whattya got, a church function?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm driving to Toledo to see a movie. Would you like to come?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah. I gotta fly to Delaware tonight. I'm gettin' married.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Why Delaware?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The chick I'm marryin' is from Wilmington. Plus, I gotta help her move her stuff here.  Why you drivin' ta Toledo to see a movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not playing at the Mapletown.  I didn't know you had a girlfriend, Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey opens the car door and slides in with Toby.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We met last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toby, what movie could possibly be worth drivin' 260 miles round trip for?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a new film called "Revenge of the Nerds." It's about a group of nerd college students who are being picked on all the time by the jocks, so they decide to take revenge. I already saw it once.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, ya really dig this movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it a lot, Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are these nerds like? How would you describe them?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby spills some catsup on his polyester button-down shirt. He stands up to get a napkin, revealing his flood pants.</context>
      <utterance>Hmm... Nerds are smart but they look and act differently than other people. Like nerds might wear polyester button- down shirts and flood pants where their ankles and their socks are showing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what yer sayin' is you identify with those nerds?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I consider myself a nerd. And this movie has uplifted me. There's this one scene where a nerd grabs the microphone during a pep rally and announces that he is a nerd and that he is proud of it and stands up for the rights of other nerds. Then, he asks the kids at the pep rally who think they are nerds to come forward... So nearly everyone in the place does. That's the way the movie ends.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the nerds won, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey grabs the rest of Toby's fries and opens the door to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. You got this movie an' I'm gettin' hitched. We both had a good month, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Harvey, how long are you going to be in Delaware because I'd really like to see this movie with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm only goin' for a week but then I'll have a wife, so I'll have to take her along. Is it a girl flick?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends on the girl. What kind of girl is your new bride? Is she a nerd?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby watches Harvey saunter off. He returns to his last hamburger.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, man. Maybe. She's into herbal teas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agree with Toby. I think it's a story of hope and tolerance.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey scrunches his face in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's about time that the people who get picked on get to be the heroes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce hits Harvey.</context>
      <utterance>It's an entertaining flick an' I can see why you like it Toby, but those people on the screen ain't even supposed to be you! They're college students whose parents live in big houses in the suburbs. They're gonna get degrees, get good jobs and stop being nerds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, what did I say about loud talking? Use your inside voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look Toby, the guys in that movie are not 28-year-old file clerks who live with their grandmothers in an ethnic ghetto.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough, Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce folds her arms in disapproval. Toby starts to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>They didn't get their computers like you did -- by trading in a bunch of box tops and $49.50 at the supermarket.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey looks at him, disappointed. He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>You're funny Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, Toby. Go to the movies and daydream, but "Revenge of the Nerds" ain't reality. It's just Hollywood bullshit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, maybe I was bein' so harsh on Toby onna count a' my own problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'see, I wasn't even married a month and my old lady was already showin' signs a' trouble. Granted, I tend ta get married fast 'cause I'll take any woman that'll have me, but this time I really met my match...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about these 78's, Harvey? Can't you sell them to one of those collectors?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce throws down the records in frustration. Harvey runs over to check if they're scratched.</context>
      <utterance>Are ya kidding? No way, man. I ain't getting rid of my 78's.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it then. I give up! How can I make more storage space, if you won't get rid of anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get rid of stuff. Just not my good stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's your good stuff. How am I supposed to live here, if there's no room for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw come on, baby. I'll make room for ya. You just have to give me time. I'm not so good at these kind of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A DOOR BUZZER rings. Harvey slams it to unlock the front.</context>
      <utterance>That's because you're obsessive compulsive Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon. I don't wanna hear that psychobabble crap!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A KNOCK ON THE DOOR interrupts their argument. Joyce storms away to answer it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care if you wanna hear it or not. You're the poster child for the DSM III. I'll have you know that I come from a very dysfunctional family. I can spot personality disorders a mile away...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce turns to Harvey and points to Toby.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Joyce. Is Harvey home?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This scene shrinks into a square up in the corner. The next few scenes (NEUROSIS MONTAGE) further divide up the full screen like a comic book.</context>
      <utterance>Borderline autistic!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Joyce, it's me. You're not gonna believe this but some LA producer called an' he wants to do a play about my life. Call me!  Joyce flips the page.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>END NEUROSIS MONTAGE (return to full screen)</context>
      <utterance>Delusions of grandeur.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STAGE ACTOR HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I think comics can be an art form. With pictures an' words, a guy can do pretty much anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE ACTOR JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The "Stage Actor Joyce" lunges over and plants a kiss on him.</context>
      <utterance>That's true, Harvey. But I didn't come all the way from Delaware to talk about comics ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He checks his watch. Joyce remains quiet and distant.</context>
      <utterance>I hate checkin' bags, man. It always takes forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey spots a bag that he thinks is his.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, look at the time. The bus is gonna leave soon and there won't be another one for an hour. That means I gotta shell out an extra thirty bucks for a cab.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Joyce mumbles something to Harvey.</context>
      <utterance>Hey wait, there's our --  Figures. That lucky Yuppie's gonna get on the bus in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know Harvey, vasectomies are reversible.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn Yuppies get everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heads turn.</context>
      <utterance>Are you listening to me? I said vasectomies are reversible.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More heads turn.</context>
      <utterance>What? Whattya talkin' about? I don't want kids. An' I came clean about my vasectomy the first time I set eyes on ya', right here in this airport.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know but things have changed. I think we can be a family.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Family?! What kinda family could we possibly be? I ain't no good with kids. I can barely take care of myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of the kid and you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce rolls over.</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell is that Ornette Coleman album, Joyce? I got a review due tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't touch it, Harvey. Would you let me sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce sits up. This time she means business.</context>
      <utterance>But it's one o'clock! How late can a person sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rolls over and covers her head with the pillow. Harvey just stands there staring at her.</context>
      <utterance>It happens to be Saturday you selfish sonofabitch! And don't you go telling me what to do. I'm the one who moved into your city, into your home, into your vasectomy and into your screwed- up life. The least you could do is allow me to live here my way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>HARVEY peruses the aisles. He pulls box upon box of herbal tea off the shelves.</context>
      <utterance>I tried everything but nothin' could get this woman outta bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean she wouldn't get a job, wouldn't go out, wouldn't make friends, nothin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A frustrated Harvey tries once more to cheer her up.</context>
      <utterance>Joyce diagnosed herself as "clinically depressed." I don't know what the hell she was goin' through but it was sure takin' it's toll on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can go out for dinner tonight. How 'bout catching a bite at Tommy's?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey throws his hands in the air and walks off.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he passes the answering machine, he notices it's blinking.</context>
      <utterance>I give up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Joyce, we got a message here. Why didn't you pick up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON ANSWERING MACHINE: A loud "beep," then ...</context>
      <utterance>Useless. He presses the play button.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, this is a message for Harvey Pekar. My name is Jonathan Greene and I'm a producer for LATE NIGHT WITH DAVID LETTERMAN. We'd like to talk to you about coming on the show to plug your comics. Please give me a call at 212-555-3333.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Joyce sits up. Harvey's finger hits the "Replay" button.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, this is a message for Harvey --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey tosses his shirt over to Joyce, who snatches it and starts cutting it with a scissor.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, c'mon. Who the hell cares?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, whattya doin?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She resumes her mysterious sewing project; she seems to be making some kind of doll.</context>
      <utterance>Merchandising.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey paces.</context>
      <utterance>People like this show?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nervous STAGE MANAGER wearing a headset peeks his head in.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gettin' hungry back here. They oughtta leave ya donuts or somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dave's ready for you now, Mr. Pekar.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you got anything ta eat? My stomach's growling.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey glances at the monitor just as Letterman announces his next guest.</context>
      <utterance>There's no time to eat now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. Where's the doll?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got it at the desk. Will you relax about that already?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Stage Manager physically pushes Harvey out of the Green Room. Joyce turns back to face the monitor.</context>
      <utterance>Guys, guys, we're in a hurry here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taken off guard, Letterman laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I'm ready for those Cleveland jokes. Go ahead...</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright settle down Harvey. Settle down.  Now let's explain to folks who may not be familiar with your work what it is you do here, exactly. You have comic books about you in your daily life in Cleveland.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And are they embellished at all or is it pretty much factual?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's all true, David. All true.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you also have a regular job in Cleveland working at a hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. Aiding the sick, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aiding the sick. Well that's certainly noble work.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now it seems to me Harvey that you have a very successful career here. This is being published by a major publishing company, Doubleday. Why do you maintain the day job?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now, Letterman cracks up.</context>
      <utterance>To make a living!  I don't make a living as a writer. I've been writing for many years, David. Maybe more years than you've been alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know that my youthful appearance belies, you know, my actual age. But, I've been around for a long time --</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN REGULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Letterman Regular takes a seat as he watches the monitor. He seems more intrigued than Joyce.</context>
      <utterance>I'm beginning to wonder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits a sore spot. Harvey goes from politely condescending to cantankerous in one second flat!</context>
      <utterance>But I have a feeling though, if you wanted to, you could probably get by on what you make selling your work. Because I know people are after you to write other things. You're publishing this anthology...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Letterman cracks up. The Audience laughs even harder.</context>
      <utterance>Who? What people? What people? What are you talking about? Where the hell do you get that stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Audience can't believe this guy's holding his own with Letterman.</context>
      <utterance>I'm no show biz phoney. I'm telling the truth. Come on, man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LETTERMAN REGULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least he's keeping up with Letterman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Joyce walks over to the monitor and looks for the channel. She hits a button, but it only changes the frame of the show.</context>
      <utterance>Pandering is more like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damnit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN REGULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to get some news. You know there's a big story about to break about the US selling arms to Iran and the Contras.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN REGULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a monitor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce gives up. She sinks back into her seat and pulls a book from her bag. The Letterman Regular stares at her like she's from Mars.</context>
      <utterance>Ugh. Just forget it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, I know you've got a job. I've got a job. We're both very lucky. We both have jobs.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Once again laughs and a big round of applause. Letterman pulls out Joyce's mysterious doll and props it up on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Then what's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've gotta go. Harvey I like you. I'm on your side. I enjoy the comic books. And here, quickly tell us about the little doll here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My wife made it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BACK TO JOYCE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She suddenly perks up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally something good.  Watch this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're made out of your old clothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do these go for?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-four bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-four dollars? Thirty-four dollars for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are ya cheap. You cheaper than me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you pay thirty-four dollars for that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No but I'm not asking it. My wife is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STAGE MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a natural.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN REGULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Stage Manager grabs the Regular.</context>
      <utterance>He is. Good stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A smiling HARVEY (the actor now) waltzes in straight from his command performance.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon. Your turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce taps her finger on Letterman's image on the monitor.</context>
      <utterance>Whad'ya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Megalomaniac.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Audience laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Harvey, you are the embodiment of the American dream...</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny thing is, somethin' about me and Letterman clicked for the viewers. He kept wantin' me back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HARVEY walks out with a box of donuts. He starts giving Letterman an earful right off the bat.</context>
      <utterance>It is my pleasure to welcome back our next guest, the lovable Harvey Pekar!</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here was this slick, ambitious guy with millions, winnin' over the country by makin' light of everything. And then there was me... A messy loser with no dough who takes everything too seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(laughter)</context>
      <utterance>Tell me Harvey, what do you do to get away from the pressure of being -- well, a file clerk?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead and laugh, folks. But he has more contempt for you than I do!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MTV DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ! Watch where you're going!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' yuppie or whatever kinda freak you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That day on the set with those MTV jerks, I had an epiphany. It seemed that real, salt of the earth people like Toby an' me were bein' coopted by these huge corporations. We were gettin' held up and ridiculed as losers in the system. What can I say, it was the 80's man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A YUPPIE in a jogging suit walks up to Harvey, interrupting Joyce in mid-sentence.</context>
      <utterance>Harvey, I've been reading about these kids who grew up in war zones... Palestinians, Israelis, El Salvadorians, Cambodians... These kids are amazing and they're --</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you're that guy from the Letterman show, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey's not smiling anymore. This guy's a jerk.</context>
      <utterance>That's so excellent. You and Stupid Pet Tricks are a riot.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Then why dontcha buy one of my comics, man. That's the only reason I go on that dumb show anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Yuppie rushes out.</context>
      <utterance>Right, sure. Later, Harvey Pekar!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, I want to do a political comic book about these kids. There's a conference in Jerusalem in a few weeks, and I can start by doing interviews there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa whoa, wait a second. Jerusalem? I can barely drag you off the futon to go to the Letterman show.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce hits a nerve.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know why? 'Cause I don't give a damn about the Letterman show. I want to work on something important to me. Something that matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People start to look over.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! You know I only go on the show for the extra bread!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey... you're yelling...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce doesn't dignify Harvey with an answer. She stares at him, her eyes well with hurt. He sighs, calming down. He looks around sheepishly.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe if you got yer lazy ass up and got a job, I could work on something that matters, too, huh?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, baby. I -- I'm sorry...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>They stop by the cab.</context>
      <utterance>I guess it was good ta finally see Joyce excited about somethin' of her own. Sure I was happy for her. But I was still upset for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is crazy. Can't ya just do somethin' here in Cleveland?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, you'll survive a few weeks alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss. Harvey grudgingly puts her bags in the car. He watches as the cab pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>Alright... Be careful. I love you, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was later that night when I first found the lump.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I care! Just gimme the chart already!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your problem today?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Miguel! I just don't wanna keep comin' back here for it, okay?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, that patient's due t'be admitted a week from now! Why do you always have to be picking fights with everybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Offended, Miguel storms off.</context>
      <utterance>How many times do we gotta go through the same bullshit. Just gimme the fuckin' chart!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see what the doctor says about this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LETTERMAN REGULAR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And there you have it, folks! Another enlightening episode of Stupid Pet Tricks!</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was startin' ta lose it. Between the lump, the loneliness -- I felt like everything wuz closin' in on me. And with Joyce over there savin' the world, I never felt more like a sell-out hack in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN REGULAR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Harvey clenches his fists.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know ladies and gentlemen, when Thoreau wrote that most men lead lives of quiet depression, he obviously had not met our first guest, who happens to lead a life of whining desperation...</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN REGULAR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Harvey's new t-shirt reads "ON STRIKE AGAINST NBC." He takes off for the stage, fists clenched, a soldier marching off to war.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome back, Harvey Pekar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Dave! You wanna know what my politics are? I'm a strident leftist, Dave.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could have guessed half of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You coulda guessed all of it, man! So why don't we talk about your parent company, G.E., huh? Let's talk about anti-trust violations and nuclear reactors!</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the P.A.'s walk back and forth in front of the monitor, we hear the Letterman / Pekar banter grow louder. Suddenly PRODUCTION ASSISTANT 2 stops and checks out the monitor.</context>
      <utterance>Joe, put more sodas in the fridge, there. And let's clean up the counters. That Pekar guy's a pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRODUCTION ASSISTANT #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa... you guys. Check this out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Toby's grandmother passes him a plate of cookies.</context>
      <utterance>You're a cop-out, Letterman. You're nothin' but a shill for G.E.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First of all, Harvey, what you are saying is not true. Second of all, this is not the place to say it. If you want to talk about this, go somewhere else, because you're not talking about it here!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Dave. I won't come back unless you beg me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not coming back at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I care --</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because we've given you many, many chances to talk about things that would be of general interest to people --</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mr. Boats shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>So what?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- And also to promote your little Mickey Mouse magazine. Your little weekly reader! But you've blown every chance you've got. You're a dork, Harvey!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dave, you're fulla shit! You're fulla shit!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you did it this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce puts the magazine down.</context>
      <utterance>Who cares. He wasn't helpin' my sales anyway.  Baby, don't go away anymore. I just can't take bein' alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you met those kids over there and saw what they go through, you wouldn't ask that of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if you go again I'm really gonna lose it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cuddles up close to him.</context>
      <utterance>It's not open for discussion, Harvey. I need this in my life right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to kiss him. He kisses her back. Her hands wander down. Suddenly she feels something strange.</context>
      <utterance>But I do appreciate the fact that you missed me so much. C'mere...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey looks at her and gulps.</context>
      <utterance>Harvey, what is that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DOCTOR #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...cat scan... diagnosis... MRI... cancer... cancer... cancer...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I have cancer? I don't feel sick at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a positive thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My cousin Norman died of lymphoma. He was twenty-nine. He was a brilliant oncologist.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey turns to Joyce.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it! You're not going to die, Harvey. You're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce stands up, determined.</context>
      <utterance>What's going to happen to you, baby? Who's gonna take care of you if I'm not around?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, look at me and focus. We are going to get through this. I understand illness. I know how to handle these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's you. I'm not strong enough. I don't know how ta be positive. I can't do it. I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite Joyce's passionate pitch, Harvey shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you can. And I'll tell you how. You'll make a comic book out of the whole thing. You'll document every little detail. And that way you'll remove yourself from the experience until it's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce folds her arm.</context>
      <utterance>I can't do that. I'm just not strong enough... I just wanna die.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. I'll do it without you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm Fred. You called me about the comic book?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right -- the artist. Come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce leans down and addresses the girl, who holds a toy horse.</context>
      <utterance>This is my daughter, Danielle. I had to bring her along. I hope you don't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Danielle. What's that you're holding?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's immediately obvious that Joyce is great with kids.</context>
      <utterance>A pony.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pony? What's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a girl. Clarissa.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all walk towards the table which is covered with papers.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I see. Well, I'm Joyce. Nice to meet both you and Clarissa.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry to hear about Harvey. Is he here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going to work until next week, when he starts the chemo. That's why I wanna get this project started now. Once he's stuck here, I know he'll take over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey tries the doorknob, but it's locked. He steps back on the lawn and looks around. Could he have dropped them? He retraces a few steps.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey yells up at the window.</context>
      <utterance>Damnit!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joyce, open the door! I lost my keys again! Joyce!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the door opens. Loud music pours out. But it's not Joyce, it's FRED, the artist.</context>
      <utterance>Joyce!! Open the fucking door!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey just stares at him. Fred opens the door to reveal: JOYCE and DANIELLE dancing together with the stereo blasting. They're having a ball.</context>
      <utterance>Fred?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here are some ideas we batted around.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheesh. Joyce doesn't know what she's doing. There's too many words in these frames. When are ya comin' back?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey looks away at Joyce and Danielle playing. They're oblivious to the world.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, she said something about next Tuesday, which is fine with me. Only thing is, I might have the kid again. My ex-wife's supposed to take her, but I don't have much faith in her showing up. She is in worse shape than me these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next week my treatment begins. Do me a favor. Bring the kid with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce springs up, alarmed.</context>
      <utterance>Joyce... Joyce?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey just stands there for a moment saying nothing.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong, Harvey? What are you doing up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me the truth. Am I some guy who writes about himself in a comic book? Or am I just -- just a character in that book?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce just stares at him, unsure how to answer. Finally Harvey collapses. Joyce leaps from the bed, nervous, hysterical. She gets down on the floor and shakes him.</context>
      <utterance>When I die, will 'dat character keep goin'? Or will he just fade away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Omigod, Harvey! Harvey, wake up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Harvey speaks, one-dimensional comic book images from his life pass over the screen once again. This time in front of him, behind him, everywhere. We dolly in towards him.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Harvey Pekar. It's an unusual name -- Harvey Pekar...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Images of Harvey's childhood float by, followed by his young adult years.</context>
      <utterance>1960 was the year I got my first apartment and my first telephone book. Imagine my surprise when I looked up my name and saw that, in addition to me, another Harvey Pekar was listed!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Harvey age in the images: he's hanging on the street corner with friends, collecting records, hanging with Crumb.</context>
      <utterance>I was listed as Harvey L. Pekar... My middle name is Lawrence... He was listed as Harvey Pekar -- no middle initial... Therefore, his was a purer listing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, in the seventies, I noticed that a third Harvey Pekar was listed in the phone book! This filled me with curiosity.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now, numerous images of Harvey's many years at the V.A. Hospital float by: Harvey filing, Harvey arguing with his boss, Harvey and Toby, etc.</context>
      <utterance>How could there be three people with such an unusual name in the world, let alone in one city?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The comic images fade out. Harvey is once again alone in the empty room.</context>
      <utterance>Then one day, a person I worked with expressed her sympathy to me concerning what she thought was the death of my father. She pointed out an obituary notice in the newspaper for a man named Harvey Pekar. One of his sons was named Harvey. These were the other Harvey Pekars.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We slowly move in on his face. Extremely close. As close as the camera can get.</context>
      <utterance>Six months later, Harvey Pekar Jr. died. Although I'd met neither man, I was filled with sadness. "What were they like," I thought. It seemed that our lives had been linked in some indefinable way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the story does not end there. For two years later another Harvey Pekar appeared in the directory. What kind of people are these? Where do they come from, what do they do? What's in a name?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce looks up. Harvey looks like he's trying to hide something.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Joyce.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it Harvey?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce stops what she's doing and gulps. She hangs on Harvey's every word.</context>
      <utterance>That was the doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears well in Harvey's eyes. Joyce breathes a sigh of relief and Danielle jumps up and runs over to Harvey. She hugs him.</context>
      <utterance>He said I'm all clear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya keep readin' 'em backward.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like reading them backward.  Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I keep tellin' ya, all of 'ems me, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look like a monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well wait'll ya see what you're gonna look like.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me??</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Yer part of the story too, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What story?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danielle makes a face.</context>
      <utterance>The story of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know I'm not as interesting as The Little Mermaid and all that magical crap...</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I want to write my own comic.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? What about?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know yet. But not about you. You have enough already.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know, you should write about things in your own life. Like school and... ponies... I don't know, girl stuff...</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have to hold my hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danielle looks up at Harvey like he's crazy.</context>
      <utterance>What, are you embarrassed a' me? I know, I'm embarrassing. I felt the same way about my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danielle drops his hand and rushes onto the bus with other kids. Harvey waves and watches as it pulls away. He turns and walks by himself down the busy Cleveland street -- -- a familiar image from the opening. He's still hunched over. He's still Harvey.</context>
      <utterance>No Harvey. You're just squeezing it too hard.  Joyce is right. You are obsessive compulsive.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, so I guess comics brought me a lot. But don't think this is some sunny, happy ending. Every day is still a major struggle. Joyce an' I fight like crazy, an' she barely works. The kid's got A.D.D. and is a real handful. My expenses have gone up so much that I'm writin' freelance 'round the clock, just to make my bills. My life is total chaos.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
