<movie id="37" title="Angel Eyes">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you hear me?  This one's conscious!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We are slipping away again. Sharon holds us with her eyes, and she grips our hand.</context>
      <utterance>Paramedics on the way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds on tight. We see that our hand, held in her own, is bloody.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Wait. Listen to me. Can you feel that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We watch our hand gripping hers, and as we hold on, the sights and sounds around us grow more clear.</context>
      <utterance>That's my hand. Hold it. Go on -- as hard as you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But our eyes unlock from Sharon's and DRIFT TO a patch of night sky. Her voice fades awawy. Our POV begins TO LIFT, MOVING TOWARD that sky, as the blue-black night begins to turn white. We GO INTO that white light and...</context>
      <utterance>It's over, and I've got you, and you're safe. You're safe now. You got that? Don't let go. Don't let me go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That car is older than they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'67 Chevy Impala.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I said.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Needs a servicing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robby nearly spits his coffee, laughing at what Sharon has said and trying not to choke. Sharon smiles, shaking her head.</context>
      <utterance>Don't we all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Robby smiles, Sharon looks ahead at the young couple who each have an arm around the other. She is stroking his neck. He is making gentle circles in her hair. Sharon watches this, and for a moment her eyes reveal a depth that may be loneliness, but she quickly pushes her thoughts away and hits the HORN, startling Robby and startling the people ahead who now disengage and drive on.</context>
      <utterance>Get it together, officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Pogo! Almost spilled my coffee again! You didn't like his hair, or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Robby's eyes have caught something on the monitor.</context>
      <utterance>I love Elvis hair. They were going two damn miles an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Robby secures that coffee cup, Sharon hits the SIREN and speeds around the car in front of them.</context>
      <utterance>Let's roll to this -- fight in progress.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Man trudges on, proud and suspicious, too.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know... since we're both walking the same way, I could take one of those bags for you. That way, I do some upper body work while I'm walking along. Helps my back. What d'you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Man glances at him, still not convinced, but he soon has to stop and rest. Catch stops, too. The old man looks at him, a bit embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Right now your mind's making pictures of me robbing your groceires, but, y'know, nine times out of ten, people do the right thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch nods, puts out his hand. The Old Man hesitates, then decides and lifts a bag, and Catch takes it.</context>
      <utterance>It's the dog food that makes it so heavy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch isn't kidding. He has that honesty. The Old Man nods and starts trudging again. As they walk on together, Catch reaches for that second bag. The man relents and lets him take it. They continue on, Catch carrying the bags and every now and then lifting them a bit for his upper body work.</context>
      <utterance>I guess it's worth it... for a good dog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon and Robby are both very good at their jobs, taking this Kid to their car while other cops contain the rest. A crowd watches -- mostly teens.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this bitch. Whoo! Benny, look at this!</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of his bystanders friends howl at that.</context>
      <utterance>You come in with me. Hey, bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He resists a bit, but they're getting him into the car.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to arrest me, you come into the back seat with me. Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. We'll have a good time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three Adam Five -- show us 1019 to the jail with one male prisoner.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take off your uniform. Take off my handcuffs, bitch, and come back here. I want one touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon is stone-faced through this.</context>
      <utterance>Give it a rest!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get him to the counter.</context>
      <utterance>That ain't the touch. That ain't the touch I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they remove the cuffs, the Kid makes a sudden move toward Sharon, reaching between her legs -- but she was not only ready for this, but hoping for it -- and the stoniness of her face cracks into fierce anger as she moves quickly and grabs the Kid by the hair, bringing his face into her upraised knee. He cries out and goes down on his knees, hurting and bleeding. The jailer rushes over to help, but Robby grabs the Kid's wrists.</context>
      <utterance>As I remove your cuffs, I want you to put your hands here. Spread your legs. More.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robby glances at Sharon -- a dark glance.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. Back off, John, we got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is straightforward, not rebellious.</context>
      <utterance>You trying to be a bad-ass, Pogue?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoner...</context>
      <utterance>I just dealt with the situation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SANDERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks away, and Sharon and Robby walk on to their car -- she is dark; he is glancing at her.</context>
      <utterance>And you don't see a pattern here?  I want you to keep yourself way inside the line instead of walking on it. All right? Are you taking notes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You broke his nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He grabbed me. End of story.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you were waiting for him. You were hoping. You were making long-range plans for his ass while he was mouthing off in the car -- and you're supposed to be above that shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you think I crossed the line, put it in the report.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the car, Sharon behind the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Pogo, stop the shit. What is it? You pissed off at me, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She STARTS the CAR and starts to back out, and he reaches over and turns OFF the IGNITION. She stares hotly at him -- but then, slowly, she softens, takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>Not you, Rob. You're a rare unthreatened male cop with a good marriage, and you like to eat where I eat -- so everything's code four.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come over for dinner tonight. I'll call Charlene. She'd like to see you. It's been awhile. We'll talk about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. But she'll invite friends, try and fix me up. She's always trying to fix me up so she doesn't have to worry about you and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She doesn't worry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both smile wryly, driving on.</context>
      <utterance>They all worry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anyway, I'm busy tonight.</context>
      <utterance>You don't need to fix me, Robby, or fix me up. I don't want some guy to heart and soul me and then walk away 'cause he can't stand the cop thing -- or worse: he wants cop stories every night 'cause it turns him on, and he has no idea who I am inside my head.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got some action, huh? Well, that's promising.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Hot and heavy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men, incredulous, stop the car and snap OFF the MUSIC in order to make sure they're hearing right. They stare death at Catch.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! You want to turn that volume down? What's your point?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They can hardly believe this.</context>
      <utterance>What's the point of blasting your music through the whole zip code? Don't you realize there are kids trying to sleep in these apartments -- old people, sick people?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch meets the man's look with his own unflinching, haunted eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You better watch your mouth, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch's look is not a macho challenge. It's something else -- beyond that, a man somehow without limits. One of the riders in the backseat taps the Driver's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Why? What're you gonna do? Kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Driver, never breaking his death stare, snaps on the DEAFENING MUSIC and then slowly rolls on, still glaring at Catch. Catch stands in the rain, watching them go.</context>
      <utterance>Guy's nuts. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CANDACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures, and she sees the keys and retrieves them, more friendly now.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. Your keys are in the...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANDACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While she is talking, Catch is staring deeply at the boy, who is shy. Catch almost speaks to the boy, wants to, goes halfway to a smile -- but the sight of the kid stirs that layer of darkness in Catch. He nods a good-bye to the mother and is about to go. She thinks about this, as he is turning, and pushes through her remaining caution to say...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you. Thanks a lot. God. I was trying to carry Tommy and all these bags. He was so tired. Of course, as soon as I put him down he had all this energy...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANDACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles and seems to want to stay, but he is already retreating. His contact goes only so far -- and no further.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know, we were just baking nectarine bars because the peaches weren't ripe. Ever had a nectarine bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with one more glance at the boy, he walks to his apartment, unlocks it and steps in.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Gotta be going.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MRS. VANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sherry!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mrs. Vander. You're looking good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. VANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is pulling a new blue dress out of a shopping bag.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you just wait. I splurged.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. VANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's just a little too long.</context>
      <utterance>It's for the church and the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. VANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, I cried over the invitation -- just imagine me in church.  It'll be so good to spend time with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MRS.   VANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know Dan and I renewed our vows last year. I bet that's where your mom got the idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their vows?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. VANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Vander realizes what's going on and stammers on, sympathetic and embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Your mom and dad -- the ceremony...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. VANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well... y'know, I just got that invitation a few... just now, so I'm sure you'll...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're both covering like mad, both realizing Sharon's been left out.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. We've had... there's been some problems with the mail in our building, so... I'll probably get it today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, I guess I'll see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. VANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon leaves -- Mrs. Vander staring after her, feeling bad. As Sharon walks away, we see her forced smile die, replaced by an old pain and darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, honey. I'll see you there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't see his truck, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches his shoulder as she says this, a friendly gesture, a reaching out. He doesn't respond, only shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>How you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kathy and the boy? Bet he's big now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Growin' fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has broken through a bit and they both smile a brief, wry smile.</context>
      <utterance>Is he looking more like you now -- or did he get lucky?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks about.</context>
      <utterance>He's got Kathy's looks and brains and my strong back. You should feel his grip.  You just passing by?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Larry's look stays on her, wondering what's on her mind.</context>
      <utterance>Place is coming along nice. The octagon window. Dad's signature.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Larry, I shouldn't have to hear it from Mrs. Vander -- about what's happening. He turns back to his work now as they speak, uncomfortable.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you really weren't going to tell me? Nobody was going to tell me? Mom and Dad renewing their vows, the church, the party. Mrs. Vander is all excited. She bought a new dress. It's blue.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're workin' on Dad. We think you should be there. We told him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom told him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We mentioned it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's holding out, hah?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to come?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my family. Jesus, Lar. It's over ten years, and he won't let go of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two were always head to head.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For good reason. Remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares, then...</context>
      <utterance>Let's just leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pissed, he throws his hammer down on the plywood, turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>You're still scared of him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think it's a good idea you coming around here in uniform. People see it, they think we're in trouble here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks away. He frowns, picks up his hammer, goes back to work.</context>
      <utterance>Nice seeing you, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she walks toward the oncoming van, which is parking now.</context>
      <utterance>Two more minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi! Look -- it's your Auntie Sharon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has a special affection for the boy -- who is subdued, but he smiles a small one for his aunt. She takes one of his hands and they shake in mock formality.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Champ, my God, look how big.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow! You hurt my hand with that grip. Whew.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon is staring at Kathy's badly bruised ear.</context>
      <utterance>We're bringing Larry his lunch. Hey, it's good to see you. It's been awhile. What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon pulls her eyes off the bruise to meet Kathy's look -- and connect.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I went boom into a low shelf -- chasing after him of course.  How're you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm semi-okay. I heard about the... ceremony and the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon smiles a bit, appreciating the support. She pats Kathy's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. I hope you'll be there.  Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy offers his little hand to shake again.</context>
      <utterance>Take it easy. You too, Champ.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smile and drive on and Sharon walks toward her car and Robby.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no. You're not breaking my fingers again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man runs on, and Sharon chases with Robby close behind her. Sharon speaks to her shoulder radio mike as she runs.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three-A-5, foot pursuit. Suspect fleeing south on Pico Place, young man, green jacket. No visible weapon...  Robby!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man has jumped a fence. Sharon follows.</context>
      <utterance>Right behind you!  Stop and lie down with your arms... shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Careful!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes over the fence, then Robby.</context>
      <utterance>I see him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Sharon, wide-eyed, is already pulling her weapon, but not in time. The man is aiming at her and about to fire when he is tackled by Catch. Catch and the man go sprawling, and the gun flies out of the man's hand, and Sharon is on him in an instant, pointing her gun at him...</context>
      <utterance>Gun!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch scrambles to his feet. Robby joins Sharon and puts his knee in the man's back and cuffs him, then glances at Catch. So does Sharon. But Catch starts to hurry off.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze! Right there!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two other cops (Ray Juliette and SANCHEZ) rush toward the suspect on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was armed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Citizen took him down.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon stares across the lot to where Catch has halted. More cops are converging. Ray Juliette and Sanchez move toward Catch, while a sergeant and others surround Sharon and the suspect. In between the crowd of cops, Catch and Sharon glance at each other, during...</context>
      <utterance>No shit!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... just saw it and... I saw the gun, so...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is shaken, speaks softly.</context>
      <utterance>You all right, Pogo?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances toward Catch. (She doesn't recognize him from the accident.) Their eyes meet briefly, but then their attention is pulled to the others. Sharon speaks to her sergeant.</context>
      <utterance>I was dead. Y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had me. I was dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray nods, handing the I.D. to Sanchez.</context>
      <utterance>I was just walking by. I live near here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant's going to want to talk to you, Mr. Lambert. We'll need a statement.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch glances at Sharon again, and he nods.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. That's just procedure. Look -- we appreciate what you did. No bullshit. Let us buy you a drink tonight, all right? You know where the Rib House is?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got you nectarines because the peaches are hard as rocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rolls away from the table in her motorized chair -- and as they speak across the house, she performs a ritual...</context>
      <utterance>Your jacket's all dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Elanora is moving about the living room, picking up framed photographs and turning them face down. We don't see what -- or who -- is in these photos. She is turning them all in a routine way, used to this.</context>
      <utterance>I tackled a guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you 'tackle' a guy?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had the ball. He was going for a touchdown.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you be serious?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What day is today?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wednesday.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are not smiling at their little jokes, but they have an ease with each other and the deep love of dear friends. He doesn't pause in his work, but we can see some nervousness in him as he says...</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Chu is now taking some of the groceries out of the bags to help.</context>
      <utterance>Met somebody today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? That's good. Ahh -- they had the broccolini today. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elanora is more interested and curious now, still helping with the groceries and being casual.</context>
      <utterance>A woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't tackle her, too, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, Catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a police officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch goes on working, a depth in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Are you in trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No trouble.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is still working, but his eyes are on his thoughts, his struggle.</context>
      <utterance>Well... that's a good thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elanora stares a moment. This has meaning for her.</context>
      <utterance>I saw her once a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't answer. He's nervous about this.</context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she watches him as he moves to the refrigerator and continues his work in silence.</context>
      <utterance>She looks the same.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... And Sanchez says proudly.</context>
      <utterance>Beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. My wife's got him in agility class.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray is handed the photo, and we see that they're talking about Sanchez's dog, the name "REX" printed on the photo.</context>
      <utterance>No shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Rex.' Rex is good. I wonder who the first person was to name a dog 'Fido,' and what the hell does it mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is some laughter. Ray is a smart-ass and a flirt.</context>
      <utterance>I like how you're always asking the big questions, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves some of the change on the table, sliding it toward Ray.</context>
      <utterance>I got a big question for you, Pogo -- but I can only ask it when we're alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here -- use this -- call your wife and ask her instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh and drink and Ray asks her...</context>
      <utterance>I happen to know Ray's wife is busy tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why doesn't your partner ever come out with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robby's a family man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a family man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More laughter. Sharon's eyes do a quick roam of the bar. Ray catches this.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but his family actually likes him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs this off like it's not important and starts to slide out of the booth.</context>
      <utterance>That Lambert -- I guess he's not showing either.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The head. Do you mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's just gonna freshen up her makeup.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves the booth with a wry frown.</context>
      <utterance>You're wearing makeup?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grins, leaving the laughter behind her.</context>
      <utterance>That reminds me, Ray. You still have that eye-liner you borrowed from me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLASHBACK - MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pointing the gun at her face today.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO SHARON</speaker>
      <mode>PRESENT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>in the mirror and see how shaken she still is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>We thought you wouldn't show. Why you sitting here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He half rises and gestures to the other chair. She glances back at her booth, then sits. She's nervous, too.</context>
      <utterance>I don't talk to a lot of people. Would you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts out her hand. He stares at that hand for just half a beat before taking it. They shake. The feel of her hand holding his evokes the memory of the accident, but he covers this.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't have a chance to thank you. I'm Sharon Pogue.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look familiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her way to cover nervousness is to be blunt, even tough.</context>
      <utterance>I guess I live on the beat you patrol.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you do that -- jump a man with a gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was going to shoot you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He could've shot you. You have a death wish? You a bungee jumper?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I didn't have time to think about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you think about it now?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figure... it was worth the risk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For someone you don't even know?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah -- and for what you do. I think cops are great. Out there, trying to keep it safe. You know? Tough job. Firemen are everybody's heroes. Kids wave at firemen. People should wave at cops. Did you ever think about how many people are walking around this town because you saved them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never thought about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... because you helped them or because you arrested somebody who would've hurt them or because you just... did your job?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I'm walking around this town because of you. Ever think about that? Maybe you should be a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has made her smile.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I look pretty dumb in a hat...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and I don't drive and, like I said, I don't talk to many people. Am I talking too much? I am. You go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. What d'you do? You employed around here? Oh, God. Sorry. Every time I try to talk to somebody, it comes out like an interrogation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you want to be ten years from now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody taught that to me. Kind of a shortcut. You ask somebody, what are your plans for tomorrow -- what're your dreams for ten years from now. It's supposed to get things started.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it work?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never tried it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Really. I just remembered it -- God is my witness.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she has made him smile, the first real smile we've seen from Catch. It's open and real and she is charmed by it.</context>
      <utterance>Not in here. It's mostly cops.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's a bit self-conscious, saying that, and just as she says it, the waitress arrives with shots and beers for both of them. Sharon looks up, questioning, and the waitress nods toward the booth. Catch and Sharon see the cops, staring, smiling, raising their glasses. There is a hint of teasing in their grins. And now Sharon is more self-conscious, and a bit tough again, taking her drink and turning back to Catch.</context>
      <utterance>You have a nice smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... what were we talking about? Oh, yeah, you were giving me some line about starting a conversation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The shortcut.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They clink glasses and drink. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'll play.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow I've got a night watch shift. If the weather clears, in the morning I'll go hiking. If it rains, I'll go to the gym -- and the laundromat. Ten years from now... I want to be living in some mountainous place.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tibet?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But now Ray Juliette is approaching the table.</context>
      <utterance>Could be Tibet. Could be Colorado. Your turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon drains her shot and stands.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Pogo -- don't keep him all to yourself. Come on over, Lambert, join the group. We'll buy you dinner, give you a medal for saving Pogo's ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm taking off.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I'm kind of tired, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch stands and turns to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. I'll... walk you to your car.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon frowns and waves to the booth of cops. Ray smiles and shakes hands with Catch as a good-bye.</context>
      <utterance>Least we could do. We don't like her very much -- but we don't want to lose her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a great neighborhood. Maybe I should walk you to your car.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk on, silent a moment. This doesn't come easy for her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have a car.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want a ride home?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thanks, but... I like to walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates, nervous about it, but then...</context>
      <utterance>It's starting to rain. Don't be a hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk to her car.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. If it's no trouble. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk side by side a moment. He shrugs. Then -- in his open way...</context>
      <utterance>Okay... ten years from now, what d'you want to be doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at him, taking this in, then fumbles a bit with her car keys, and he asks -- nervously again...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. This is pretty good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets a little defensive.</context>
      <utterance>Can you drive okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, looks at her dead-on a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not drunk. You think I'm drunk? I'm not. You'll know I'm drunk when I'm throwing up, and I never throw up, so don't worry about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only time I worry is when people tell me not to worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get in the car, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drive a while. She notices his anxiety. He grips the armrest when she speeds up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm on Lundy Street, just off Pico.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm good at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Streets are wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you one of those people who drive ten miles an hour in the rain? I hate that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at him, and he notices her glance.</context>
      <utterance>I never drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be alright.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, I can picture you in Colorado.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? What am I doing there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles in spite of herself, slows down.</context>
      <utterance>Driving around... pissed off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not pissed off at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she laughs. She drives, not to his building, but to her own street. She parks, takes a deep breath. This sounds a bit hard-bitten because she's using her toughness to cover.</context>
      <utterance>Give me some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She halts.</context>
      <utterance>Those guys in the bar are my friends -- sort of. We work together, we tell jokes and we bullshit, but I can't say to them...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She says this clipped and fast and even tougher:</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every time I close my eyes, I see that goddamn gun pointing at me and I don't know why I'm telling you unless it's because you were there and because I had three drinks, but I'm not ready to go inside and close my eyes and I don't want to go to your place and I don't want to keep driving around, so what the hell do we do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whew. I feel like we're boxing, and you've got me on the ropes.  We'll do whatever you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment, she shows her fear.</context>
      <utterance>What I want is to know how you happened to be walking by that parking lot at that minute. What if you hadn' t been there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare a while, then she opens her door.</context>
      <utterance>I guess we were supposed to meet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want -- you can come in for a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pours one for herself while he looks about. It's a stiff drink. Now that he's here, her I-don't-want-to- make-a-fool-of-myself alarm is on. She flops on the sofa, watches him.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit down or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's looking around at the clutter of her life -- the intimate details.</context>
      <utterance>I'm circling awhile.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not supposed to look around. I didn't have time to straighten up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... it's more real this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>It's rude.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that I'm in here, you seem mad about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not mad. You'll know when I'm mad. I don't usually let somebody in here, but here you are. That's all. Let's talk about something stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles in spite of herself.</context>
      <utterance>You first.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay -- one thing I don't believe is that 'supposed to' business. We were 'supposed to' meet. That sounds a little fringy to me, like something you might hear on public access TV. You believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some people say we each give off a particular odor -- that can only be detected by one other person's brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, we... smell each other? Who says that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea.  I'm more in the destiny school, we-met-in-another-life school. Do you believe that? Do you think when we die -- we come back in another form?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, steps close to her, takes the drink out of her hand, puts it to his lips and drinks it all down. He puts the glass on the table.</context>
      <utterance>You mean like a duck? No. I think dead is dead. I've been thinking about it all day -- and I don't want to think about it anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets a half smile, assessing him. Her look is direct, and the attraction is there. He feels it, too, and he deflects it, nodding toward a large photomural of snowcapped mountains.</context>
      <utterance>See? Now you're thinking about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me guess. Colorado.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rises and goes to a desk and takes the holstered gun off her ankle. She takes the cuffs off her belt, the mace from her jacket, the shield from her shirt pocket, puts them all in a desk drawer. She takes off her jacket and throws it over a chair. Disarmed, she turns to him. Her look is all wanting and pushing away, almost fierce in her struggle. He sees this.</context>
      <utterance>It's Austria, but I can't picture myself in Austria. I'm not good with languages, so I couldn't qualify for the departments over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for... coming up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that mean I'm going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You don't have to. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. You're here as a medic.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles in spite of herself -- again. He has gotten to her. She wants to fall into this guy, but she's pumping those brakes. They are standing close together.</context>
      <utterance>Is this the mad part?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe going is a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I come back some time?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't know what to say. The moment hangs. He leaves. Once he closes the door, the breath escapes her, and she shakes her head -- feeling like an idiot. She lost control. With a stranger.</context>
      <utterance>I better go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch is numb -- completely shut down there in the middle of the street. The Driver exits his car and comes toward him, raging.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell do you think you're doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch isn't even aware of him. The man gawks at this -- and now Catch walks off. It is raining. The streets are wet.</context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my car! What the hell were you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man shoves him.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I just...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw you! What did you take out of there?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man gets in his face, shaky...</context>
      <utterance>No, I rolled up the window. It's rain...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves Catch again, and Catch's desperate confusion explodes in a surprising reaction, grabbing the Man's jacket front in one hand and not punching him but quickly slap, slap, slapping him, saying...</context>
      <utterance>You take my phone?! Hah?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man is now speechless, frozen, terrified, as Catch's eyes hold him with a fierceness -- and a sadness.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Hey! Wake up! Wake up!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch lets him go, and immediately begins walking away, hunching into the rain, his expression dark and troubled. He gets five steps away and turns. The Man steps back -- but Catch only says...</context>
      <utterance>I helped you.  I helped you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he walks on. The Man watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises and hurriedly gets his purchases off the elevator so the woman and little boy can enter.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANDACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at her, a bit less subdued than before as he gets his things into the hall -- and he manages a special look for Tommy, a wink. He frees the elevator; they step inside. As the door starts to close, Catch's face "follows" the sliding door with a funny look for the boy. We hear Tommy laugh as the door closes. Catch carries his new possessions to his apartment.</context>
      <utterance>Shopping day?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's looking great, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a beat of awkward silence.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, honey. It's the best year ever for the impatiens. The very best.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks the same. Still smells like cigarettes. I thought he quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's down to six a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her Mother touches her hair, self-consciously. She can't help glancing at her daughter in all that gear -- bullet-proof vest under her shirt, radio, cuffs -- and that gun.</context>
      <utterance>Your hair looks nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon steps close to the mantel. There is a photo of her there, graduating from the police academy, a professional, not a family shot. She is surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Are you well?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I'm well. Is this always here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's always there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Larry tell you I came by where he's working? Is that why you called me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called because we want to invite you to our renewal of vows. It's three weeks from Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's 'we.' You said 'we' want to invite you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon takes that in, still looking about.</context>
      <utterance>The family.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you're renewing your vows?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's sort of... a fresh start.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>having the marriage blessed.</context>
      <utterance>No. Both of us. It's a way of...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her Mother sighs, sad for all the trouble between them.</context>
      <utterance>Wasn't it blessed before?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sherry... of course it was blessed. You just...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just what, Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon stares deeply at her.</context>
      <utterance>You just think about the bad, and you never remember the good. I wish you remembered the good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I wish I did, too.  Does he? Remember any good about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He just... still feels hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. He doesn't hate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurt? I hurt him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somebody doesn't forget that.</context>
      <utterance>Being arrested like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? How come you forgot what he did?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't as bad -- you always make it sound worse. And it hasn't been that way for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad it hasn't been that way. That means it worked, Mom. That was the point. That's why I did it. Christ. Why do I get punished for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, nobody's punishing you. We're inviting you. Will you come?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I'll come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't think you'd want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now her Mother shows a trace of fear. She says gently...</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't want any trouble... on that day. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They each get a small, sad smile.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, I'm your daughter. I don't want any trouble -- ever. I'll come to the ceremony. I won't come to argue, and I won't come in uniform.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's on the 23rd. Saint Monica's.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her Mother starts to leave the room.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like you to send me an invitation. Mrs. Vander said it's a beautiful invitation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll show you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom. I'd like to get one... in the mail... from my family. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon goes to the door, then stops and turns, letting her guard down all the way to say...</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Tell Dad... thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FULL SHOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As we INTERCUT the call:</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a machine?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have an answering machine?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you hang up please, and I'll call your machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up. He stares at the phone a moment, bewildered. He hangs up, and his PHONE RINGS. He lets it ring. His MACHINE comes on with no recording, only a</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up, sighs a heavy one.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. Maybe we can... have breakfast or something. I get up early and run in Ballard Park. There's a Denny's across from the park. Like eight or so. If you're there, you're there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she falls back on her bed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stumbles out of the bedroom to her door.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! Who?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally.</context>
      <utterance>I was just falling asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We made a date.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't a 'date.'</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives an exasperated moan and turns to stagger back to bed. He closes the door and follows.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, an 'appointment.' I keep my appointments.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called you. I called you at seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I waited there.</context>
      <utterance>I get up early. I walked there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads for the bed, passing a mirror, looking at her rumpled self and groaning at the sight. She climbs into bed and snuggles there and puts the sheet over her head. He is entering the bedroom. He carries a Denny's take- out bag.</context>
      <utterance>Check your messages.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need more sleep. Come back in a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lump under the sheet says...</context>
      <utterance>Come back? What makes you think I'd come back here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why are you here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has come out from under the sheet and is watching him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here to tell you that when you tell someone you're going to be somewhere then that someone rearranges his life and you should be more aware of that and a lot more considerate instead of just...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in the bag?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? None of your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you bring some coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you deserve coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else did you bring? Food?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You definitely don't deserve food. I've got coffee, sugar, sweetener, non-dairy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits up. He hands her the coffee. She sips, relishing the sip, then studies him.</context>
      <utterance>Just black. Black. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what kind of life did you rearrange in order to get to Denny's? You never said one word about yourself last night. What d'you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the difference?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the difference?! You're standing in my bedroom. That's the difference. Who are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody who keeps appointments.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Convinced -- she picks up one of the throw pillows from the bed and tosses it at him.</context>
      <utterance>You're ducking. Don't duck.  Oh, shit -- you're married, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't believe me? Give me back the coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him the coffee. He hits her with the pillow and hands her back the coffee. He has made her smile, but she continues, half teasing now.</context>
      <utterance>Give me the coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God. Oh, wait -- you're involved in some criminal activity, aren't you? Great -- That's all I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Catch Lambert. I don't work. I don't commit any crimes. I like being with you. We can start from here -- from now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. I'm... I let you in here. I'm not going to be some fool. I need the details.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I need to start from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's ridiculous. Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the way it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Your rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is conflicted -- but he won't relent. He walks to the door. She stares, waiting. But he never turns around. He walks out. She is mystified, exasperated. She hears her FRONT DOOR CLOSE. She puts the coffee on her bed table -- and finds herself staring at that damn rose. She suddenly gets up and begins to dress hurriedly -- with a plan.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Okay. Fine. I don't really want to know you anyway. Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks in and closes the door and starts looking around as he says...</context>
      <utterance>Can I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite his recent "decorating" the apartment is still nearly empty. No books, magazines, photographs, no clutter of life. She glances into the equally sterile kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sure. Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You live here? Nobody lives here. This place is some kind of front, a scam, a drop -- or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is what you told me about -- right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has made her look at herself, and take a breath.</context>
      <utterance>Your interrogation. Do I need a lawyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just don't want to be jerked around.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is silent, and she starts to leave. Moment of truth.</context>
      <utterance>Then tell me straight out. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it you're looking for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your life. I don't want any surprises.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is it. I sleep here. I walk around town. That's all of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Except for you -- the way I feel about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surprising. I thought it was impossible. I thought I was...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You thought you were what? Gay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead. In a way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm supposed to understand that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, looks at his empty place, his non-life, and back at him again.</context>
      <utterance>No. Did you ever wonder what 'scratch' meant, when people say, 'we'll start from scratch'? This is scratch. We can start from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks off the stare and heads for the door. He watches her go.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I just don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Chu registers surprise at this, but keeps it covered and casual.</context>
      <utterance>You know the cop -- the woman cop? She... visited me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? Where did she sit?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a chair now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He darkens a bit as he works.</context>
      <utterance>You're... seeing her?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has a lot of questions. She wants to know everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course she does. Everybody does.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could start from today. What's so wrong with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The can in Catch's hand bangs on the cupboard, and he stops, suddenly uptight.</context>
      <utterance>Tell her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Chu comes closer.</context>
      <utterance>Tell her what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's been almost two years.</context>
      <utterance>Tell her, Catch. Tell somebody.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nora...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His next warning is tough and absolute.</context>
      <utterance>Every time I tell somebody, it gets a little bit easier. I'm not saying it goes...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is silenced. The moment hangs. She rolls her chair to him, takes a box of cookies out of his hand, opens the box and eats one, defusing the moment.</context>
      <utterance>Nora!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to work again.</context>
      <utterance>She nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's tough.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She pretty?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's sort of pissed-off at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her a while.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter. We like it when men apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and hands him the box.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I yelled at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a cookie. See?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SANDERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sharon...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can see the computer screen now. Sharon is searching for any prior record of "Catch Lambert" -- arrests, convictions. She has several "Carl Lamberts" on the screen, even a "Casper," no Catch.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything bothering you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What'd I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon stops typing. She can find nothing. She clears the screen, sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I'm talking about your general attitude lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My attitude's fine. End of a long day. I'm tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Family matters getting to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Family?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your brother, Larry...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Larry?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits her hard.</context>
      <utterance>You know Nester -- on the Culver City P.D.? He went out on a violent domestic dispute yesterday. A neighbor called it in. It got a little ugly. No arrest -- a warning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry. Oh Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon is quiet a while, taking it in, shaken by it.</context>
      <utterance>Nester said it's not the first time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for telling me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, you're up early.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to catch you before you went to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were on late shifts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't sleep much. Can I come in?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Kath?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon nods, but then walks past him.</context>
      <utterance>She's busy with Larry Jr. right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he stays focused on the TV, some darkness, some unsayable worry in his eyes. She picks up a toy car, speaks softly.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Champ.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, they call this one a woody 'cause it has wood on the sides.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he looks at her with sad and bottomless eyes. She is hurting for him. Larry is now in the doorway. Sharon kisses the child's head and walks out, passing her brother.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you come by?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To see Kathy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make it worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It gets worse?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon moves closer. She reaches out, touches Kathy with a comforting touch as the woman turns her bruised face away.</context>
      <utterance>He's okay now. He's torn up about it. Don't make him mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When Larry and I were growing up, our mother said that all the time. 'Don't make your father mad.'  Has he hit Larry Jr. yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never would.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry is in the doorway now, angry.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Just you, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you think you're doing in my house, Shar? In my home. She walks out of the room and he follows her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see a pattern here, bro?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost my temper. Things got out of hand. It won't...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People always say that: 'I've got a temper.' Like it's an excuse.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes very close to him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't need a goddamn lecture.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to hit someone? Next time your 'temper' flares up, Lar, and you just have to hit somebody, you go home and hit your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You blame everything on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her shirt hard.</context>
      <utterance>I'm blaming you, you fucking coward.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes her into the wall.</context>
      <utterance>You don't come in here...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't come in here and call me names.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swings a slap at her. She blocks it and punches him hard in the face, and he crashes down on the floor. Kathy comes running, calling out...</context>
      <utterance>What do you call a man who uses his wife as a punching bag?  Coward.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't hurt her, Lar...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She unlocks and opens the door, stares at Catch, very vulnerable, on the very edge, her pain and fear over Larry just under the surface. Catch holds a box of cookies as an offering.</context>
      <utterance>It's you, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you just shut up? Just shut up and listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps back, allowing him in, and closes the door and turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to talk. I don't care if you have to play some game and pretend you're a... 'angel of mercy' or... whatever. I don't care, but I don't want to hear about it. All right? I don't want to hear anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees her pain and puts his arms around her, pushes through his fear and holds her -- and she lays her head on his chest. He embraces her fully, and the effect on him goes deep, to his core, where there is both pain and longing, but he holds on to her, even rocks her a bit. She sighs. In a moment...</context>
      <utterance>It's a bad night.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks her to the couch and has her sit, and then slowly, gently, he "disarms" her. He lifts her leg, takes the ankle holster and gun off, puts it on the table. He turns her, takes the cuffs off her belt from the middle of her back. He reaches into her pants pocket and removes the Mace. From her shirt pocket he takes her I.D. shield. He has her lie down on the couch now, their faces close, eyes locked. They linger...</context>
      <utterance>This is good... but I'm too tired to stand up anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to kiss me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's not sure what to do. He begins to look her over -- as if hunting, and she gets a soft smile. He starts slowly toward her ear -- but she shakes her head. Her shirt is out of her belt and her midriff bare, and he starts to move there, but checks her with a look. She shakes her head. He hunts. Her smile deepens a bit. He takes her hand and turns it over, going for the soft flesh on the underside of her forearm, and she closes her eyes. He kisses her there softly, and then again, and then he lavishes kisses from her wrist to the underside of her elbow as she sighs with pleasure and draws up her knees in a kind of sensual glow that is leading them to... No. He stops. She looks at him, a deep look, soft voice.</context>
      <utterance>Kiss me someplace I've never been kissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has a glimpse of his mystery, the old sorrow, the deep pain. He hugs her drawn-up knees, closing his eyes a moment. Then he sits on the couch, puts a pillow on his lap and raises her slightly, lays her head on the pillow. He strokes her hair, her scalp as she closes her eyes and sighs, slowly moving toward sleep. Our TRUMPET MUSIC slides in here, lush and dreamy as we linger a while, and then --</context>
      <utterance>Why do you stop? You always stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They look up to see a well-dressed man pausing in the middle of the crosswalk to face their car. He is in his forties, tall, with grey-blond hair. This is RICHARD PINDELLA. He has a small smile and wave for Catch. Sharon is curious, looking at Catch. Catch throws the man a dark look and then turns away, ignoring him, nervous, intense.</context>
      <utterance>Catch?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catch?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pindella is moving toward the car, Sharon watching him, wondering.</context>
      <utterance>Drive, will you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The light changes. Pindella hurries to the curb as the cars surge forward. Sharon drives slowly, checking the mirror to see Pindella stare after them -- then enter the office building on the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Drive!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She makes a turn, glancing at Catch.</context>
      <utterance>Will you get off this street?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But his dark look persists, and he doesn't answer. Then...</context>
      <utterance>What? You owe him money?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is nervous, being in the car -- and glad to leave it when she pulls over. She watches this, wondering.</context>
      <utterance>If you take a right and stop -- we can walk from here. I'd rather walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're in trouble...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're in trouble with him, maybe I can help.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates, then falls in beside him as he walks on. They walk along in silence, the neighborhood growing more seedy, tougher as they go. Catch is relaxing now, trying to push it all away. Sharon looks around her.</context>
      <utterance>Forget about him. Somebody I used to know. I don't want to know him anymore. That's all. Forget about it. Walk with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not a great place to walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it here. It's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I work here. It's not fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As someone approaches them, Catch makes eye contact and smiles a small, friendly smile-in-passing. He gets a brief smile in return. He and Sharon amble on. He does it again.</context>
      <utterance>Besides the shootings, break-ins, rapes, cart thefts? We've got a loose dog raiding garbage cans, knocking 'em over. Can't catch him. Got somebody blowing a trumpet between midnight and three. Can't find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods to another YOUNG MAN he's never met...</context>
      <utterance>You know everybody here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch and Sharon smile.</context>
      <utterance>Goin' uphill, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You try it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has misgivings. A young woman is bustling along. Sharon makes eye contact and presents a nervous smile and a nod -- but the woman looks at her sternly and bustles on.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. We need this. Everybody.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch smiles, Sharon frowns, but when an OLD MAN passes, she gives a small smile. The Man lights up.</context>
      <utterance>I feel like a jerk. I feel like a smiley face.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch looks at her. She tries to shrug it off, but can't quite hide her pleasure. Now Catch is pausing as a woman is walking her six-year-old daughter to their parked car. Catch makes eye contact with the girl and does a goofy wave that makes her smile. Sharon smiles, too. As the girl's MOTHER is unlocking the car, the girl shyly looks back at Catch for more fun. He does that quick finger trick -- trying to catch his own thumb, and the girl giggles But the Mother is impatient.</context>
      <utterance>Mornin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl gets in. The Mother is about to close the door. She frowns, mean-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl slides in further, and the Mother slams the door. The girl follows her mother with hurt eyes as she walks around to the driver's side. Catch has paused to watch this, his eyes gentle on the girl. The Mother is about to enter the car when she sees Catch staring.</context>
      <utterance>Move your arm!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you staring at?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She feels bad 'cause you yelled at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon is uncomfortable. Catch persists, never flinching at the woman's anger.</context>
      <utterance>What?! Who the hell do you think you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She just needs you to smile at her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's none of your business!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not smile at her? What's it cost?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch's anger is like flint in his eyes. It surprises Sharon. She's upset by this.</context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are you to talk to me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're so damn impatient.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get away from me!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're so busy being pissed off, and time is going by.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Woman gets into the car and slams the door.</context>
      <utterance>It's not her fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm calling the police!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Woman speeds her car away. Sharon gets in Catch's face.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm calling the police.  Hey -- police.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, Catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe she'll think about it now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had no right to do that. God! You think you know everything?! Who the hell are you, some expert on raising kids?! The neighborhood angel?! Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, I just... some people are walking around blind...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not your problem!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me what my problem is!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, fine -- you tell me what it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's not my problem. Maybe it's your problem. Maybe you're going around blind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blind to what?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blind to what's going on around you. Blind to what people need. We're supposed to take care of each other. We're supposed to keep each other safe. That's the way it should be -- if you're not going around blind, like that woman...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That stops him, the darkness rising. He looks about, trying to contain it.</context>
      <utterance>Or like me, right? What about you? How come you can see?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll... walk the rest of the way on my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call you later -- about the hiking.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and walks away. He is still angry, but sorry to see her go.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she keeps walking, and he watches her walk away. Then he walks on, upset, mad at himself, trying to pound through it, walking quickly. He is passing an alley, when he hears a CRASH. He looks in...</context>
      <utterance>Shar... wait. Hey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at the dog as he moves the picture.</context>
      <utterance>Do we go for... symmetry? Or... more off-center. Japanese.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog watches him.</context>
      <utterance>Are you into this? Bob?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare. She starts walking back into his darkening front yard, looking over her shoulder. She walks to a tree where the tire swing hangs, waits there. He goes back inside, but leaves the door open. In a moment he reappears, coming outside, closing the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go talk in the yard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has a Polaroid photo in his hand, holds it in front of her, dried blood and bad bruising on his face.</context>
      <utterance>You asked for it -- calling me a coward. You knew I'd swing. You think I look bad now? Look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts it in his pocket, and they stare a moment more.</context>
      <utterance>Nice, huh? Beautiful. The cops'll love this, right? Evidence. Don't you guys love evidence?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks away. She nods, speaks softly.</context>
      <utterance>You wanted me to swing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I hit you so hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're not sorry you hit me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Larry, what about Kathy's face?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their stare holds, but she is giving way.</context>
      <utterance>That's not your business! Nobody called you, right? She didn't ask for you to come here. This is my family. You don't get it, 'cause you've got no family. Nobody. So you try to run everybody else's life. Jesus Christ -- get your own life. That's the goddam problem. Get your own goddamn life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'm sorry I came here. I'm sorry I hit you. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is very hard for her.</context>
      <utterance>Okay what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go to my department, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the hell not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because the job's all I got.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, her voice smaller, almost a whisper.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I said, right? No life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes her wait, thinking it over.</context>
      <utterance>That's what you said.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a moment Sharon nods.</context>
      <utterance>And you won't come around here. You won't call. Ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes snap to his, surprised.</context>
      <utterance>And I don't want you to come to Mom and Dad's celebration...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After another moment, she nods again -- and he snatches the photo out of his shirt pocket and pushes it against her chest and walks away. The photo falls to the ground. Larry says without turning...</context>
      <utterance>Not the church. Not the party. Stay away. I don't want you around. I don't want to see you, Shar.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... and she snaps.</context>
      <utterance>Go get a life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words burst out of her, thick with tears, but she's not crying. Larry stops and turns.</context>
      <utterance>I got a life!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell would you know about my life?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches down, snatches the Polaroid photo off the ground, walks to her car, enters and slams the door as hard as it is possible to slam it.</context>
      <utterance>You know nothing about me, because you don't want to know. The family doesn't want to know me. Well, too bad. Sharon's got a life. Sharon's got a boyfriend. Sharon's going hiking in the morning with her boyfriend. She's not sitting alone miserable like you want. Too bad!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waits. He catches up.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Hey! Can you wait up a minute?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you walked all over the city.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she walks on.</context>
      <utterance>The city is flat. Okay? Can we stop here? Can we examine the view? Have a Milky Way? I've burned every calorie I ever had.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My favorite lunch spot is another half mile.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and walks on, and he follows, calling out.</context>
      <utterance>Up?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not one of those competitive guys, you know!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles again and takes a bite and stares off, and soon enough her dark thoughts come and cover her, and Catch notices.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks. I can't eat and have a heart attack at the same time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As soon as you get happy, you get sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay. Everything's code four.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something happened yesterday.</context>
      <utterance>Fine? This isn't fine. I know fine. This is something else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesterday -- you mean you want to hear about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kidding. Why? You never talk about yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps staring, waiting. She is chewing a sandwich, looking at him. Finally, she begins -- with no emotion.</context>
      <utterance>All my days are the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is staring at her. He takes her hands, holds them.</context>
      <utterance>Yesterday. Okay. Yesterday we rolled on a 415. Juliette and Sanchez had these four guys against a wall, but they were H.D.B. and definitely unco-op. It got pretty jumpy, but we got them in the car with a couple of bruises and Robby got a sprained wrist, so I did the rest of the shift with a rookie who lost it over a D.B. in Sunset Park, old woman who'd been dead maybe six, seven days, and I usually do all right but the smell got to me, and I can still smell her. Then we arrested a prostitute working out of her home, and I carried her little girl out to the social worker, and the kid was holding on real tight and making my shoulder wet and I wanted to punch her rock-head mother, and then shift ended and I had a nice visit with my brother Larry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. That would make anybody sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry you asked?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares a moment, then speaks with an irony he doesn't pick up on.</context>
      <utterance>No. No, you can always tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I feel better now. You feel better?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off his T-shirt and begins stripping off his shorts, his underwear!</context>
      <utterance>I feel fine. Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is surprised, smiling, as he plunges into the pond, her darkness dissipating.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dives under and surfaces again.</context>
      <utterance>Catch! There's no swimming here! And you can't be naked in a state park!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the day off, Pogo!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dives and surfaces once more. We STAY CLOSE ON him.</context>
      <utterance>What if a park ranger comes?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops because she isn't there. He looks about. Then suddenly he sees her, poised on a boulder right above him, in her underwear about to dive! He yelps and gets out of her way, and she dives off the rock in classic, near-professional form, a beautiful, sleek dive. She hits the water just right and surfaces, and they splash and swim and frolic and dunk each other in unabashed play.</context>
      <utterance>Take your badge off for once. Don't be such a damn Marine about everything. Just...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, staring, then slowly reaches her hands to his face, gently closes his eyes and is about to kiss him on the closed lids, but she changes her mind and instead puts her lips tenderly on each of the small scars on his face. Then she moves away. He opens his eyes. She walks to the shore, moves to her clothes and starts getting dried and dressed, giving him a soft look. Catch comes to the shore to dry himself, but as he dresses, Sharon glances at his body -- and the scarring on his chest and arms. He is troubled about this, avoiding her eyes. Then he makes a decision.</context>
      <utterance>Someplace I've never been kissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long time ago.</context>
      <utterance>They tell me I was in an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like a bad one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waits -- but he says no more. She continues to dress, sliding her shorts over her wet underwear -- but before she puts her shirt on, she turns her back to take off her wet bra. He glances at her. She looks over and catches him glancing. They both smile softly, ironically, as they finish dressing.</context>
      <utterance>I don't remember it. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We have to pack up.</context>
      <utterance>We should be thinking about lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So soon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of us have to work.  You ever work?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I worked.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch is held back, smiling a bit, but on thin ice here, dipping into his past.</context>
      <utterance>Catch -- Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you? Sit down. Been years. You been out of town?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack's smile clouds as memory kicks in.</context>
      <utterance>I've been around.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch, with a steady look, says...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, man, I'm really sorry about what happened. I never got a chance to say...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods a moment.</context>
      <utterance>We don't need to go there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. All right. So... what d'you want, a coffee?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want my old job back.  What d'you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been workin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I'm up to speed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not good with Randal anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch stares, nods.</context>
      <utterance>No, he's out of it, but Danny Coley's got something going. Wanna go see 'im?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finish your coffee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl nods, not trusting her voice.</context>
      <utterance>I have to check these jacket pockets. What's your name -- Allison?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to unsnap this, Allison. I'm checking your waistband. You got to Whitney School?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>St. Mark's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on, Pogo? You're not happy or anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at Robby's look.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's a mix, Robby. Life is shit, but I'm dating this great dead guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says before I came along, he thought he was dead. Sounds better when he says it --  Listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robby stops the unit, rolling the windows down. They hear the FARAWAY SOUND of...</context>
      <utterance>Shhh. Sh!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robby pulls over.</context>
      <utterance>The trumpet player.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exit the car and stand in the street, looking up, scanning the dark buildings -- but the sound is hard to track, a FAINT BALLAD on a skillful HORN.</context>
      <utterance>This time we got his ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got 'im?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at the full moon. In a moment, we hear the sound of ROARING CARS, their TIRES SCREECHING as they turn onto this street, one car speeding ahead to cut off the other and force it to stop. The two male drivers are screaming at each other. Robby shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Look at that moon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They run toward the drivers who are exiting their cars to confront each other. One big guy carries a baseball bat. Robby heads off one DRIVER while Sharon intercepts the</context>
      <utterance>Full moon, man. Hey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy's crazy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BAT-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This asshole side-swiped me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you McGuire?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAT-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark McGuire?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAT-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man hesitates, then moves toward his trunk.</context>
      <utterance>Then put that bat away. Put it in your trunk. Now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never touched his car.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAT-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man charges, bat in hand, and Sharon makes a flying tackle, bringing him down hard on the street -- and we immediately...</context>
      <utterance>You lying bastard!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow. Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That's good. Deeper.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How heavy was this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God. Tractor-trailer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins to moan as he digs out the pain. He is fighting against the erotic charge of this, trying to keep it medicinal, but he's got his hands all over her naked back, and she is moaning -- so he stops and takes a breath.</context>
      <utterance>Pickup. Ow. Ow! That's really good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches to the bed table and puts oil on his hands, noticing a card that stands open on the tabletop, a very pretty invitation.</context>
      <utterance>I better... More oil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get oil on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is this your parents?</context>
      <utterance>Renewal of vows -- that's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Just put it down. I'm not going.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't answer. He puts it down, comes back to the slow rubbing of her shoulders, her neck. In a moment...</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moans in pleasure as he rubs, trying to push all other thoughts away.</context>
      <utterance>If I go, my brother'll hurt me with the department. I got mad and knocked him down. All they need is a complaint. Just leave it alone and keep rubbing. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... he says you can't go?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All right?</context>
      <utterance>Can't you rub without talking?  It's been bad with my family a long time, so the hell with it anyway. If they don't want me there, I don't want to be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.  Bad how?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But we see her eyes turn inward toward the old pain and, for once, she shares it.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch works in silence a while, absorbing this, looking at Sharon with more tenderness than ever. In a moment...</context>
      <utterance>My father used to knock us around, all of us. But I'm the one who called the cops -- finally.  They say I turned against the family.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... they invited you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So forget it.</context>
      <utterance>You don't know anything about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I know about family.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah? What about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's... a door you don't close.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't close the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're closing it now. Right? Family invites you, you go. Family shows up, you welcome them in. That's family.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure. What if they don't deserve it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you forgive.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have all the answers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I just... It seems like a chance, doesn't it? A chance to make things right. I'd take it. Then you tried -- y'know? And it's up to them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That hits him, but he keeps rubbing her, gentle now, looking a little lost. He doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>You close with your family?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But as he works her back in silence, we see her facing her pain and thinking through it.</context>
      <utterance>See? So why should I listen to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises -- as if to go to the band with a request. She smiles, spent.</context>
      <utterance>What's your favorite song?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catch, I'm beat. So are they. I think they're finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She watches as he leaves her, walks to the bandstand. He talks to the leader who is the PIANO PLAYER.</context>
      <utterance>One more. It's a surprise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Danny.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode>PIANO PLAYER</mode>
      <context>Catch comes to the edge of the bandstand, grinning a bit at Sharon, at his surprise for her, nervously fingering the horn. He puts it to his lips.</context>
      <utterance>Gonna be good having you back, Catch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We WIDEN to see Ray and Sanchez in their police unit 20 feet away. Ray uses a small electronic bullhorn to say...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you in danger there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was talking to him, Pogo.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon laughs aloud and walks (with Catch in hand) to the police car, her joy overwhelming any embarrassment. She gestures behind them at the jazz club.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks, Ray. Everything's code four. Go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch notes the pride with which she says this.</context>
      <utterance>See that place? He's going to be playing there every weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah? What d'you play?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waves and walks off with Catch, arms around each other. The cops watch them go.</context>
      <utterance>It's music, Ray. You wouldn't like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like these?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy stares at him, then back at the toys in delight. Candace is walking toward them, and Catch turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>Well... They're for you. We can pretend it's your birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her look of surprise questions him.</context>
      <utterance>They're for me, Mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I've... kind of been saving them up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANDACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. She kneels close to her boy, the toys, pleased but not quite knowing what to say.</context>
      <utterance>For Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANDACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catch nods, grins at Tommy who is already at play with the figures.</context>
      <utterance>Well, thank you. Thanks a lot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CANDACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Tommy looks up. Catch is moving away with Bob, walking home. Tommy stands up, Candace calls out to stop Catch.</context>
      <utterance>Wow, Tommy -- Look at them all. Did you say thank you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANDACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Catch is walking away with that frozen, numb look, all shut down by his fear and his memory as Bob trots along beside him and the Biker comes after him and Tommy and Candace watch him go and Sharon hurries her steps to catch up. The Biker reaches Catch first.</context>
      <utterance>Goddammit -- I saw the kid. Jesus. I wasn't even close.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Catch won't turn to him, walking on -- and the man gets in front of him, raging.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute! Hey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pain and darkness build in Catch's eyes until he says in a quiet, choked voice, right into the Biker's face...</context>
      <utterance>Why the hell did you cause a wreck?! I told you -- I saw the kid, you idiot. I was...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man stops talking, looking at the dead certainty in Catch's eyes. He wants to say more, to save face, but Catch's look holds him like a fist. Sharon has stopped, frozen, watching. The Biker turns away and walks back to his downed bike as Catch moves on. Sharon can hardly believe all of this, following Catch again.</context>
      <utterance>One more word, and your life will change forever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes a moment for her voice to penetrate, then he quickly turns and sees her approaching.</context>
      <utterance>Catch! Catch!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he is tight, nearly frozen, everything held in.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right? Your elbow's bleeding. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks away from her, and this shakes her, and she catches up again.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he walks on, desperate, and she gets in his way, faces him.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you going? Catch -- you're scaring me. Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and walks off, heading for the street.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Catch, don't... Can't you talk to me?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to tell me why we're sitting outside this building again?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>40s. Grey-blond hair.</context>
      <utterance>Watching for somebody. Tall guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's personal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine -- what am I supposed to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She watches the building, studying the people who come and go.</context>
      <utterance>Chill.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She senses the silence on the other end and quiets a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Hi! How are you? Have you been out in this great afternoon? Brenda took me for a walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is quiet for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I've been... remembering.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catch... This is good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, there's good to remember.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catch?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up, staring at his thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's calm, gentle in the eyes. She stares a moment, trying to keep her emotions undercover.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... is there a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. Who am I speaking to?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes her time, afraid.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Dr. Pindella.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know a Catch Lambert?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Yes! Is he in trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at his watch, worried for Catch.</context>
      <utterance>I... need to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I have a patient in five minutes. But I can...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a psychiatrist.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Mr. Lambert...</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's dying inside -- but covering, lying, forcing her way into this.</context>
      <utterance>My relationship with Mr. Lambert is confidential.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's your patient. He's your patient we... know all this. This is police business. I'm officer Sharon Pogue -- L.A.P.D.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look... I want to help Mr. Lambert but I can't tell you anything that isn't public record.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In general. In general. He's your patient, and he...</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>nearly a year ago.</context>
      <utterance>He's not my patient. He walked away from treatment. That was...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did he walk away?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't discuss that, but if you know how to reach him, I would appreciate being able to talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can help by just telling me what's in the public record. It'll take me half a day to do a search. Can you tell me? Just... She is unable to play this out as a "cop," her emotions coming through. Pindella sees this. She sits on the edge of a chair and takes a breath, speaks more softly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares a moment, sympathetic -- and realizing...</context>
      <utterance>Can you please tell me what's in the record?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, nods.</context>
      <utterance>You were with him -- in the car. Your uniform threw me. Are you his friend?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes that in, leans back on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>More.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can tell you he was in an accident, hospitalized, referred to me as an outpatient...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What accident?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bus... a city bus hit his vehicle. That was a couple of years ago. It was... an awful thing. His family was in the van. His wife and child. His wife's parents...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something is pulling at her memory. Her vision turns inward, and she stops breathing for a moment -- remembering. She was there. And here we get a...</context>
      <utterance>A bus... and a van. Where? On... the freeway?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so. Yes. Near Santa Monica. On the freeway. He was severely injured but... thrown clear. The others were trapped in the van.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO SHARON</speaker>
      <mode>PRESENT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>still in shock, looks at Pindella again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Survivors? Only him? I... don't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pindella stares, then...</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I was there. I was there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a moment, absorbing this.</context>
      <utterance>His wife's mother survived, but... she was paralyzed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elanora Chu. She's still in town, I believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does he... still see her?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He used to. I don't know.  I'm glad to see... he has someone else who cares about him. I know he's running from this. He left all his friends, his home, his whole life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says... he doesn't remember the accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares.</context>
      <utterance>He lost a lot of memory. I tried to help him with that. He resisted. Walked away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Very subdued now, she asks...</context>
      <utterance>I think he remembers me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does he live?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINDELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him and nods.</context>
      <utterance>He received a large settlement from the city, but he...barely touches it. He was a professional musician.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he sits there, waiting, listening.</context>
      <utterance>Catch, it's me. Can you pick up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>About two o'clock. Okay?</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we... meet tomorrow? I'll be in Westwood. Can you meet me there? Westwood and Cole.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm okay now.</context>
      <utterance>It's hard to explain, but it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at her, wondering, walking along.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have to explain.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... why'd we meet here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk along in silence a moment.</context>
      <utterance>So you're the trumpet player who was waking people up -- on my beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>outside. On my roof.</context>
      <utterance>I used to practice late...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On your roof? That's why we couldn't find you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smile nervous smiles. She walks on, leading him somewhere. He looks about, beginning to show some agitation, but covering it.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't know it bothered anybody until you mentioned it. You arresting me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slows his steps, looking across the street and down half a block...</context>
      <utterance>You going to tell me where we're going?  That's okay. I mean... I'll go anywhere with you, Shar. Jaws of death. The mall on a Saturday. Just about any...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>You can trust me, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got you now. I'm holding on -- like before.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He suddenly pulls his hand out of hers, shocked, and it shakes her.</context>
      <utterance>Like I held you before. Like I did -- at the accident.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to shut down, to grow cold and numb and not hear this.</context>
      <utterance>What makes it so... unspeakable, Catch? What makes it like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away, closing his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Is it because you were driving?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her hand out for him again.</context>
      <utterance>I read the reports, and it wasn't your fault. It wasn't. Is it because you survived and they didn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does not take her hand, so she takes his and walks a few steps toward that building.</context>
      <utterance>Catch. Please. Hold on, and we'll go in there together...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls his hand away again, more violently, a layer of rage over his pain.</context>
      <utterance>You can talk to them. You can say goodbye or I love you or whatever...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is wrong! It's wrong! Why are you doing this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need your help! I don't need this. We don't need this -- we're fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is as if she's fighting for his life again -- and her own.</context>
      <utterance>We're not. We're not fine, Catch. Nothing is fine -- no matter how much you pretend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You pretend that nothing happened. You walk all over the city helping people, but you're dying inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not dying! I'm not pretending! I don't remember! I don't remember any of it. So leave me alone! What good does it do? It's gone! And I'm all right this way! Why do you have to change it? I'm all right. She points at the building across the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't even look at the place.</context>
      <utterance>Then walk in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walk in there, and I'll walk in with you. Walk in there and say it's real -- what happened is real. Your family died.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk about that! Don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right -- you talk about it! You tell me your family died and I say yes, I know, I'm sorry, and you say, I loved them... and I say, what an awful thing to lose a family...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn you, Shar. Damn you -- why won't you stop?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you can have a life!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why do we need to do that?!</context>
      <utterance>I have a life! We could have a life. We could get up and go to work and come home to each other and never, never talk about before. We don't need to do that!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it happened! Because it's the truth! I'm sorry. I'm so sorry it happened, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing happened! If we say it, then that's the truth, that can be the truth. Say it. Nothing happened. Say it, Shar.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catch -- take my hand. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her tears come, and she shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Say it! I'm asking you to say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I want it too much. I want everything with you. I want all of you -- not just the part that isn't hiding and running away...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you pushing so hard? Why does it have to be your way? Why does it have to be your truth? This is who I am! This is the way I am!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore. It doesn't have to be this way anymore because you're not alone -- because we're the family now. We can be the family...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like to push people, don't you? You just have to push and shove and make it right for you -- for you. You push everybody, Shar. You even pushed your family away, didn't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just... want to say...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You already said it. You said it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she turns and walks away. He watches her go, angry, scared and sorry for what he said. He takes a few steps after her, wanting to call out and to stop her. We see him almost call to her. He is coming apart, watching her, needing her so much, but unable to call out. He is shaky. He takes a glance at that building, then away. He stares after Sharon -- but she's out of sight now. He steels himself, then looks across the street again at that building. He is desperately afraid. He stares at the building a long while. He begins to cross the street. He makes fists to keep from shaking. He walks to the entrance.</context>
      <utterance>When you're ready, I'll be there for you. I just want to say that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pogo? Bring your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I think I'll turn vegetarian.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta have that meat to keep your strength up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a scattering of laughter -- almost by rote -- as Sharon enters her car without even the hint of a smile. Robby notices. She just punches up the CAD monitor, all business. Our TRUMPET MUSIC comes in, aching now, and takes us into...</context>
      <utterance>How come it's not working for you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts up a hand to brush all the words away. She can't talk about it. She pushes through it by doing the work.</context>
      <utterance>Pogo...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which store is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk on, but as Sharon reaches the sidewalk, a little child, three years old or so, toddles out the door of a shop. A SKATEBOARDER is rattling along, and Sharon makes a grab for the child, taking his arm gently...</context>
      <utterance>The little market there. They came through a back window last night. Mostly vandalism...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... and pulling him to safety as the Skateboarder passes by shouting...</context>
      <utterance>Whoa...</utterance>
   <speaker>SKATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now the WORRIED MOTHER is emerging from the shop...</context>
      <utterance>Sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>WORRIED MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up her boy, walks back into the shop. Sharon stands there -- as it all blooms inside of her, rocks her, really, this little act, evoking Catch, who he is, what he said and what he means to her. Robby is a few steps ahead, waiting for her, but she can't move yet, looking around her now at the people walking among the shops and cafes. She picks one. She catches the eyes. She gives a brief smile. The smile is answered, shyly, kindly, the person moves on.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, thank you. Billy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't move for a moment. Then she turns to Robby.</context>
      <utterance>Pogo?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something I have to do. I need an address and phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robby looks at her, then nods, giving her this.</context>
      <utterance>Elanora Chu.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk back to the car.</context>
      <utterance>Let's do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mrs. Chu emerges from the shadows of the portico, rolling her wheelchair toward Sharon. She has a smile for her -- but with some reserve.</context>
      <utterance>Pogo?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Sharon Pogue. I know all about the...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon nods, very held back. She gestures toward the wheelchair self-consciously.</context>
      <utterance>Elanora.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry for... what happened. I know about the accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told you?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I found out, and... I remembered. I was there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon stares a moment, begins with some of her tough cover in place, over her emotions.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess he comes here a lot -- to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He shops for me. Twice a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. And when he comes here -- he never mentions the past, never talks about the accident?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you... let him do that? All this time? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what he needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walking all over the city like...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like an angel. Yes. Sweet man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elanora is a bit defensive now.</context>
      <utterance>But... you let him get so lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I let him find his own way through it. Why did you come here, Sharon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because... I want to know how to help him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are helping him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He... he was paying me back, I guess, for the accident, for helping him. That's why he felt... so close to me. But...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But now he probably hates me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took him to the cemetery, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elanora's look darkens and she begins to shake her head in worry.</context>
      <utterance>The cemetery!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it might help him... come back, you know? But he wouldn't even go in. He screamed at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What made you take him there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the truth...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he won't even say it, or...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon is shaken by this, realizing, crumbling a bit as Mrs. Chu goes on.</context>
      <utterance>That's his way. That's his way through all this. He made a wall -- around that whole day, that night -- other things, too. He keeps them behind the wall -- his little boy, my daughter. He can't help it. The cemetery?! Do you know how hard it is for me to go to the cemetery? Can you imagine?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elanora takes a breath, acknowledging how upset she is.</context>
      <utterance>That's where it stares you in the face -- the loss. And it's too much sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>go by the cemetery.</context>
      <utterance>See? I'm still finding my way through it. And Catch -- it almost kills him to think about it or say it or drive a car or see the place where it happened or...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was trying to help him... come back to some kind of life. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon, battered by the truth of this, is totally exposed now, realizing, admitting.</context>
      <utterance>But he was coming back. Do you realize how much he changed in the past weeks? His apartment, his life, his music is coming back. He fell in love! He even got a job, Sharon -- for you. For the two of you. Isn't that coming back? Why do you have to rush? Everybody has to rush these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>when I'm scared.</context>
      <utterance>I was scared. I push so hard...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scared of what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elanora sighs, looking at her, and her anger drains away, studying Sharon's misery.</context>
      <utterance>Losing him. So I did. I lost him. He won't talk to me. I... I didn't know what I was doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head at Sharon's tears, her warmth showing now, liking this girl.</context>
      <utterance>You were finding your way. What else can we do? You think I'm always sure what to say to him, what not to say? I do what I think is right and hope he sees the love in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at you -- so worried now, so miserable. That's the love in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I... make it worse for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELANORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon stares, without much hope. She puts out her hand to touch Elanora's, to say goodbye. Elanora takes her hand and holds on a moment, staring into the girl, with strength. Sharon nods and walks off, dark and sad. Elanora watches her go.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I really don't. But I think he'll see the love in what you did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Larry grow tense and angry.</context>
      <utterance>She came.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry doesn't look at Sharon. The little boy, looking fine in a tiny suit and tie, and being bored, leans to look at his aunt. Sharon and Larry, Jr. trade a look. She winks, then settles back in her pew, watches.</context>
      <utterance>Don't say anything. Think of your parents.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fishes a piece of paper out of his pocket. His hand is shaking as he reads a number off the paper.</context>
      <utterance>Annie. Chet. I don't... want you to think I forgot about you. It's just that I... I couldn't find you.  I woke up, and you were gone. Everything was gone. It all just... disappeared. In one minute. I couldn't remember that minute. I lost it. It took me so long to find it. I think I found it all now. I used a calculator. I did. I figured it out. You know... we get about 1400 minutes a day and so I figured it out. I was 33 years old and three months and eight days, so it was... I've got it here...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the paper away.</context>
      <utterance>It was minute number 17 million eight hundred ten thousand, two hundred... or so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We --</context>
      <utterance>That's the one I lost. And... when I lost that minute, I guess I tried to lose it all, all the memories -- because they hurt. I tried, but... I couldn't do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>at the grave, struggling through this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Annie and Catch both glance back toward Chet, and we get present sound in this FLASHBACK scene as Catch and Annie both say, "What's the matter? Hm? Aww." And then Annie looks out the window and turns to Catch and -- we CUT TO Catch at the grave, his eyes filling.</context>
      <utterance>Chet... you weren't feeling so good, remember? It was your birthday, and you ate too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the FLASHBACK we see Annie turn to him again, and this time we hear her say, softly...</context>
      <utterance>And, Annie, you said... you said...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We GO TO Catch at the grave, fighting tears.</context>
      <utterance>Slow down in the rain, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back in the FLASHBACK, we see Annie reach around as Elanora hands Chet to her. Then we're BACK at the grave and INTERCUTTING so that we see Catch speaking through his tears and we also see this tender moment played out in the van.</context>
      <utterance>And I don't know if I slowed down. I don't know. I hope I did, but... I didn't always listen. I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... You put him on your lap, and he looked at me, and I made a face. Remember? I made you smile, Chet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PHOTOGRAPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of the milling crowd comes Sharon, taking a breath and braving it, walking up there, speaking quietly.</context>
      <utterance>All right. The whole family in this one. Just...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Photographer turns to her, wondering.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you want me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHOTOGRAPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! Oh, well, how about...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You both look so great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Father speaks to her, his voice not hard, but flat, not warm either. No smile.</context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to...</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You coming to the party?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, then turns to greet well-wishers. Sharon is left alone by the drifting away of the family, but one old couple greets her, the older woman (Mrs. Vander) wearing her new blue dress, her HUSBAND beaming beside her.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. VANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sherry! Look how nice you look.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big police officer now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharon moves off toward a side exit, trying to catch up with Larry and his family.</context>
      <utterance>Not so big.  Nice dress.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you have the guts to walk into a church after breaking your word?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to be here. It's a chance to make things right, and I'm taking it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why even talk go me? You got what you wanted. You laugh about it? You tell your cop friends how you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops herself, catching her rush toward the old anger. She goes calmer, deeper, even sad.</context>
      <utterance>You think I talk about it?! You think...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him something. It is the Polaroid photo. He looks at it, surprised. They lock eyes. She speaks softly.</context>
      <utterance>Here, Lar.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she walks off toward the parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>I was invited. I'm here. I'm going to the party. You do what you want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>anything today.</context>
      <utterance>Don't make him talk about...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, I was going to fix his tie. His tie is crooked. She sighs, pushing through her hurt to say...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a nice ceremony.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. We're running out of chicken, though. Nobody's eating the ham.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some joy is allowed to surface in her Mother's face.</context>
      <utterance>It's a great party, Mom. You look happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her Mother's look clouds a little, nervous again.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty-five years and still in love, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think that's wrong, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always... I feel like apologizing to you. But I love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she walks away. Sharon's eyes follow her, surprised and thoughtful. She watches her Mother approach her Father and straighten his crooked tie. Then Kathy is moving toward Sharon. Sharon turns to her and they both speak quietly -- at the same time.</context>
      <utterance>And then I feel like apologizing to him for loving you. I'm the one in the middle. I'm the only one in this family who knows how to forgive anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then they smile sad smiles. Kathy gestures to her face, the faded bruise.</context>
      <utterance>You look great.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smile wryly again.</context>
      <utterance>Tons of makeup. On Larry, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about that, but... I couldn't stand him doing that to you. I took it on...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare, and Sharon gives her a hug, Kathy returns it.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'm not your mother. If he tries it again, I'm gone. I'm out of there, me and Larry Junior. He knows that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't let me watch T.V.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look about the room.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well... let's pretend this is T.V. It's a show about a party.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That man... is really a super hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is too. And so is she. Look. See? Red tights under her dress... Oh-oh, that man gave her a drink with something in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman sips her drink, and the boy smiles, getting into it.</context>
      <utterance>With stuff to make her sleep. He's a bad guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She drank it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy is suddenly swooped up, lifted away by his father. Larry puts the boy down near the door.</context>
      <utterance>Watch. She'll fall down any minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, sport, you should go play outside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he turns to the crowd, smiling a smile without humor, speaking loudly.</context>
      <utterance>Stay away from my family.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is some nervous laughter, people watching them now. Sharon is angry and embarrassed, keeping her voice low.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, everybody, keep it down. Somebody might call the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once the cops leave, we can really party. The crowd around them is all staring now -- as he turns back to Sharon.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the hushed tension that follows, a GLASS falls and SHATTERS, and more people quiet down and stare. Sharon looks at her glaring brother, looks at her Mother nervously picking up the broken glass -- no support there. Angry and shaken, she turns to the door. She walks to the door, opens it, starts to leave, starts to close the door behind her, and she stops, take takes a breath, battling hard against the old patterns of hurt and anger. She looks at that nearly-closed door. She pushes it open and walks back in. We see a surprised and angry look from Larry, a worried look from her Mother -- but Sharon is moving through the crowd, searching until she sees her Father. She heads toward him. He sees her and walks into the kitchen, avoiding her. She follows him. We see Larry and his Mother exchange an anxious look -- and then move toward the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you give everybody a break -- and go home?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He acts as if he just noticed her.</context>
      <utterance>Don't walk away. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures toward his hearing aid.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He absently touches the device.</context>
      <utterance>Is it working? Do you need to check it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the kitchen door opens. We hear the party going on out there. Larry and Sharon's Mother enter, her Mother looking at her husband and back to her daughter, very frightened. Larry is raging in a near whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sharon, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to her dad.</context>
      <utterance>Please? Please what?! Will you stop protecting him? You were always protecting him! Don't talk to your father. Don't bother your father!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry advances on her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to bother you for one minute, Dad. Okay? Can you handle that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she turns on him in a fury that halts him.</context>
      <utterance>Just get the hell out...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns back to her father.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't about you, Larry -- or you, either, Mom. This is between me and my father, so leave us alone for one goddam minute!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about you, Dad. Do you want me to leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad... I'm asking. Am I welcome here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What d'you want?</context>
      <utterance>Jesus -- you're here, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you want me here? Do you love me, Dad? I want to know. The question's out, and she's totally exposed now -- and the silence that follows breaks her heart. She nods toward his hearing aid. Her voice is close to a whisper, thick with tears.</context>
      <utterance>I want to know!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you... need to... check that again?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't finish it.</context>
      <utterance>I feel like...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, Dad? You feel like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the blow and doesn't crumble, only her eyes show the depth of the pain. She speaks quietly, softly.</context>
      <utterance>I feel like I don't have a daughter anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they roll tape, people turn, gather, watch. Sharon speaks over a torrent of emotions.</context>
      <utterance>I'm next.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know... being in this house reminds me of something. I was about ten, I guess, and Larry and I were playing aliens -- remember, Lar? We're making a lot of noise, and Dad comes home from work tired and pissed off...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Shar. For what I said.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a moment, he gestures toward the Pogue house.</context>
      <utterance>Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't like me in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares a moment more, still together.</context>
      <utterance>Then they don't deserve you in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a nice thing to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can only look away, not wanting to cry.</context>
      <utterance>It's not a thing to say. It's the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him again. Her throat fills with tears, mouth is trembling a bit. She starts quietly, finally, with nothing held back -- but this is not anger as much as mourning.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you try so hard not to cry?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tears come, and she doesn't fight them, emptying the old, old wound, speaking through her weeping now. The first time we've seen her cry.</context>
      <utterance>It's not fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not fair. Things got better for them because of what I did. Things got better, and I'd still do it. I'd do it all over again. And it's not fair they shut me out. It's not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not fair. I was 19, and I didn't know what else to do. I didn't know how else to stop it. It's not fair I don't have a family anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his hands to her face, places a palm gently on each cheek, and she covers his hands with her own and closes her eyes. They remain that way awhile. In a moment he lightly kisses her forehead. There is a depth to his words...</context>
      <utterance>No. It's not, Shar. It's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens her eyes, staring deep into his. He has said it all -- as it is and as it will be. She smiles a bit through her tears and nods. He puts an arm around her shoulder and holds her tight against him as they walk to her car. She puts an arm around his waist. They reach the car, and she unlocks it, gets in behind the wheel as Catch gets into the passenger seat.</context>
      <utterance>We're the family, Pogo.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
