<movie id="40" title="Anonymous">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PROLOGUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He died at the age of 56, and was survived by his wife and two daughters who were, like Shakespeare's own father, irrefutably illiterate.</utterance>
   <speaker>2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 3</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PROLOGUE</speaker>
      <mode>O.C. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The actor who will play "Ben JONSON" (mid 30's) appears in the wings, bearded, ready to go on stage, holding a prop leather manuscript. Behind him a group of Elizabethan "soldiers" strap on their swords.</context>
      <utterance>His will famously left his second best bed to his widow. But it made no mention of a single book or manuscript.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROLOGUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The rain has intensified. "Prologue" turns and the camera starts to leave him and the TITLES END....</context>
      <utterance>Is it possible Shakespeare owned no books at his death because... he could not read? That he wrote no letters because he, like his father before him and his children after him, could not write?  Our Shakespeare is a cypher, a ghost; his biography made not by history... but by conjecture. His story not written with facts, but with... imagination.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROLOGUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So! Let me offer you a different story. A darker story... Of quills and swords. Of power and betrayal. Of a stage conquered, and a throne lost! A FLASH OF LIGHTNING, and for a moment only sheets of RAIN are visible. No stage, no "Prologue". Then, trough the rain, we see a form of a man... Ben Jonson... running. Then we make out the shapes of houses... a street. We're not on a stage anymore. We are:</utterance>
   <speaker>3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 4</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And several of the guards charge the door with their pikes, HITTING it hard.</context>
      <utterance>Break it down!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nothing. A beat, then--</context>
      <utterance>Out with you! Jonson! We'll smoke you out like a rat if we have to!  Jonson?! Jonson!!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The soldier hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Torch it.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The soldiers obey, lighting fire to the walls, the galleries, the columns as--</context>
      <utterance>Torch it! All of you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson nods.</context>
      <utterance>You are Benjamin Jonson, playwright? Son of William Jonson, glass-blower, son of James Jonson brick-layer?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And have you ever been arrested before, Mr. Jonson?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a writer, aren't I? Of course I've bloody well been--</utterance>
   <speaker>6</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And a guard BACKHANDS Jonson on the face full force-- hard enough to send Jonson and the chair to the ground. His nose starts to bleed. As the Guards pull him up, the Interrogator looks across the room-- there is someone else there, a FIGURE, watching, but cloaked in the darkness. Jonson notices the figure as well. We hear a voice from the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 7</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask him about the plays.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And SMACK! He's hit by the guards again. He SPITS out a tooth.</context>
      <utterance>Plays?  Which would you prefer, my lord? A pastoral? An historical? An historical-pastoral, or an hysterical historical pastoral--</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson stares at him a beat, and then looks into the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>We are not interested in your plays, Jonson. We are interested in the plays given to you by Edward de Vere, Earl of Oxford.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry my lord, but I am not sure I know whereof you speak. I have had the honor of meeting his lordship-- And SMACK--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The skin has broken on his forehead. The Interrogator leans into the bloody Jonson.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 8</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Jonson even has a chance to answer-- SMACK!</context>
      <utterance>Where are the plays?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonderful, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's certainly... big.</utterance>
   <speaker>8</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 9</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promise you, Edward, you've seen nothing like it before! Nothing!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bricklayers and whores watching Aristophones? You're quite right, Henry, not only have I never witnessed it, I'm not sure I care to.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford pauses at the entrance.</context>
      <utterance>You're an elitist, you know that, Edward?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Southampton grins and gives a few coins to an USHER, who escorts the two of them (the retainers stay outside) inside.</context>
      <utterance>There won't be puppets, will there?</utterance>
   <speaker>USHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lords...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come to the second floor, where a SELLING-MAID has a box of food and drink in front of her bosom-- much like a match-stick girl.</context>
      <utterance>The stage-craft is quite spectacular. Far more elaborate than anything I've seen at court. I've witnessed be- headings that god as my witness look as real as at the Tower, cannons fired in battle...</utterance>
   <speaker>SELLING-MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Southampton waves her off as they follow the usher up another flight of stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Ale? Mutton, mi' lord?</utterance>
   <speaker>9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 10</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and last week, they had some sort of a device to hoist cherubs into the air and fly over the entire audience!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as they ascend up more stairs, Oxford catches glimpses of the stage and performance through the rafters and over the heads of the attending audience.</context>
      <utterance>An ap mekhanes thes. Deus ex machina. Machine of the Gods.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford is becoming intrigued by the theater, almost despite himself.</context>
      <utterance>Whenever the Greeks wrote their heroes into a situation from which they couldn't write their way out--</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford continues up, two steps behind Southampton. They come to the third floor and enter the box seating area reserved for nobles, giving Oxford his first real look at the theater itself. Oxford looks around and sees-</context>
      <utterance>--Out came the ap mekhanes thes... As when Hippolytus is saved by Artemis, or Medea flown to Athens... Always good for an ap mekhanes thes was Euripides</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>10</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wears an enormous feather on his hat. Also on stage is an actor called John HEMINGE (late 40's), who plays "Sogliardo"</context>
      <utterance>pg. 11</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And whither were you riding now, signior?</utterance>
   <speaker>"FASTIDIOUS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who, I? What a silly jest's that! Whither should I ride but to the court?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience ROARS in laughter as Shakespeare looks below at a buxom young lady among the "groundlings". He smiles seductively. She smiles back.</context>
      <utterance>O, pardon me, sir, twenty places more; your hot-house, your pig-house, or your whore-house!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His second play, and almost a full house.  He's got a wit, does Jonson.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That might be so, but like a grain of wheat hid in a bushel of chaff: you shall seek all day ere you find it, and when you have it, it's not worth the search!</utterance>
   <speaker>11</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 12 The others smile as a WOMAN passes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ale! Ale!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marlowe-- spot me a few pence, will you? Henslowe still owes me for "Shoemaker's Holiday".</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be because no one saw "Shoemaker's Holiday".</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlowe gives the woman a few pennies as--</context>
      <utterance>Ale here!</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kit... Isn't that one of your unrequited loves in the box over there? Marlowe glances across the theater and spots Southampton siting next to Oxford.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nashe squints.</context>
      <utterance>But with whom? Tell me not he prefers the company of such old grey men as that!</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think-- yes, by the beard, that's the Earl of Oxford. Old Tom Hooker used to play for him. Had his own acting troupe for private Court performances and the like.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder if he needs any material?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly not any of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no-- that was years ago. Had a falling out with the Queen, I heard. He's more of a recluse than a patron these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>12</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 13</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare struts around as though he owned the place. The more he talks, the more the audience ROARS in laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Who, he, the noble there? Why, he's a gull, a fool, no salt in him i' the earth; man, he looks like a fresh salmon kept in a tub!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sleeps with a musk-cat every night, and walks all day hang'd in perfumed chains for penance.</utterance>
   <speaker>A GROUNDLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More groundlings laugh. Interestingly--</context>
      <utterance>Oi! So that's what I been smelling!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOBLEMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>in the box seats do not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>13</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 14</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is a good and empty puff, but he loves you well, signior. I wish you well with him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BACKSTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare returns backstage and takes a deep swig from his tankard. He's actually drunk, though his performance didn't show it at all. He spots Jonson, and grabs him.</context>
      <utterance>Later in the play...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Wonderful. I hope your next--</context>
      <utterance>Jonson! Wonderful dialogue!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENSLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Shakespeare turns to see a furious Philip HENSLOWE (50'S) heading his way.</context>
      <utterance>Will! Will Shakespeare!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>14</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 15</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience begins to BOO at the mention of Cecil.</context>
      <utterance>This play has been declared seditious and illegal by Lord William Cecil!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All are herewith ordered to disperse immediately!</utterance>
   <speaker>A GROUNDLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you disperse William Cecil's arse!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arrest that man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up. Oxford does not, seemingly interested in the real drama below as everyone hurries from the theater.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it all. Well! Off to Essex's then?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford turns to him, distracted, and nods.</context>
      <utterance>Edward?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seditious? Seditious?! It's a comedy for god's sake! There's nothing seditious about--</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oi, is that right, is it? And you know this because?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I wrote the bloody thing! And-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson is grabbed by guards.</context>
      <utterance>Arrest him as well!</utterance>
   <speaker>15</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 16</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson looks around-- the cell is filled with a dozen or so other prisoners.</context>
      <utterance>A pox on you!  And your carbuncled father!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People taxed to the point of starvation, Spain running the New World, open revolt in Ireland, Catholic plots everywhere you turn...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The court is inside, and slightly different from today's game: the back walls are playable, somewhat like racquet-ball. Oxford sits on a bench, watching. Essex SLAMS a shot, but it goes--</context>
      <utterance>...and how do the Cecils spend their time and energy? Shutting a theater! A theater, for god's sake? It's madness! No wonder the mob hates them so!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Essex looks furious, but holds his tongue. Southampton prepares to serve.</context>
      <utterance>Out!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, how many people were at that play?</utterance>
   <speaker>16</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 17 Southampton pauses before serving.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Southampton SERVES. Essex returns, and another heated rally begins.</context>
      <utterance>Hmm? I'm not sure, two thousand, maybe more.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how many performances are there of a play like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He HITS the ball again, and this time Essex misses it.</context>
      <utterance>Five or six I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the--!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So! Ten thousand souls. All listening to the writings of one man-- the ideas of one man. That's power, Robert. And if there is one thing the Cecils understand, it's power.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Southampton SERVES as Oxford smiles at Essex's naivet.</context>
      <utterance>And when did words ever win a kingdom? I think I'll keep my sword, thank you very much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave us.  Henry... Some of my men have... intercepted... some of William Cecil's recent correspondence with King James of Scotland...</utterance>
   <speaker>17</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Southampton pauses in clothing himself. This is serious.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 18</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecil's all but promising him the throne...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To James? Elizabeth would never agree to-</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth is old. Ill. Not of her old mind. Sometimes she doesn't even recognize me. And yet, still she refuses to name an heir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But a Scotsman? On the Tudor throne?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not in the Privy Council. Elizabeth does everything the Cecils wish of her. Everything!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WIDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Southampton stiffens at that last phrase.</context>
      <utterance>Think, Henry, if James owes Cecil his throne, Cecil will have more influence in the next reign than he does in this one. And after William Cecil, his hunch-backed son will take his place...  That is why we must do everything in our power to ensure that the right man succeeds her.  A man deserving of the Tudor crown.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ask you for the support of you and your men, Henry.... if it comes to a fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>18</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 19 Southampton looks at Essex hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Essex smiles at him warmly. They both HEAR something shuffle behind them. They turn, and see:</context>
      <utterance>You know you need not ask. I stand with you, as I always have.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHERE OXFORD WAS STANDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. He is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO SOUTHAMPTON AND ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They exchange a slightly worried look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Southampton just nods, distracted. Oxford reaches out to him, and touches his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Essex played rather poorly, didn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Southampton pauses, confused for an instant, then--</context>
      <utterance>Henry... The Cecils brook no rivals.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford nods.</context>
      <utterance>You heard?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They keep walking towards Southampton's men.</context>
      <utterance>Always concerned for me, aren't you Edward?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what would you have me do?</utterance>
   <speaker>19</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 20</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would have you deny him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The son of the Queen?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop. Southampton makes sure that his men are out of earshot.</context>
      <utterance>That is rumor only, Henry--</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rumor? My god, all you have to do is look at Essex to see the Queen's reflection. Everyone thinks he's her son, everyone! And I for one would rather bow to a Tudor, bastard though he may be, than a Scotsman!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I desire nothing more than to see the next king be the rightful king. But what Essex contemplates will surely lead to Civil War.  No. If this is to be done, it must be done carefully, skillfully.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then he feels instantly ashamed of having said that.</context>
      <utterance>As I heard it, Elizabeth exiled you from her presence for the last twenty years because of your "skill" at Court politics.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only have your interests in mind, Henry. For as you so rightly point out, my interests are already lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford nods, still worried, and Southampton heads for his horse.</context>
      <utterance>I know. Forgive me. You know how I feel about you. You have been a great friend to me ever since my father died. I promise you that I will do nothing rash without consulting you first.</utterance>
   <speaker>20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 21</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>elaborate gift?</context>
      <utterance>Henry! Will you do me one thing more? Deliver a gift for me? A rather...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir Robert.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lord of Southampton.  Have you seen Essex?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe he is still in the viewing chamber with her majesty...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>21</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 22</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FOOTMAN clears his throat and--</context>
      <utterance>With your father in London dealing with all the troubles in Ireland, who else should the Queen turn to but Essex? Robert Cecil looks annoyed, but holds his tongue as the SOUND of pikes HITTING the floor silences the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the grace of god, her majesty, Elizabeth, Queen of England, Wales and Ireland!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUBLE DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>wearing a large sparkling pearl-encrusted dress with a wide collar. She walks slowly and carefully, and has a slight tremor in her head and hands. She seems un-certain; like she's not sure she recognizes all the faces around her (Alzheimer's?). And she compensates for it by being all the more regal, all the more un-human. Essex is on her arm, dressed in a splendid jewel- encrusted doublet. Robert Cecil FROWNS at the sight of Essex on her arm. Essex ignores Cecil's glare, notices Southampton--</context>
      <utterance>open, and Elizabeth  enters. She is</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-- Majesty, I've been told my lord of Southampton has a gift for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A gift?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Southampton CLAPS his hands and a door across the room</context>
      <utterance>Yes, your grace, though not from me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>22</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth's rheumy eyes widen in complete delight, a smile of total jubilation crosses her face. Robert Cecil, on the other hand, looks horrified.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 23</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you this gift, my precious little man?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWARF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, my most majestic majesty. I am a free man. My gift is a play, majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dwarf bows his assent.</context>
      <utterance>A play?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plays are the work of the devil, born from a cesspool of plague, whoredom, thievery, fornication, and heresy. You may tell your master that her majesty--</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil turns to Essex, shocked.</context>
      <utterance>--Will gladly accept your gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course that is if you so desire, majesty.  The choice is her majesty's to make, not yours. Is that not so Sir Robert? Robert frowns as Elizabeth looks around, unsure of the political tides around her. Then--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comedy? Or tragedy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWARF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comedy, majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A comedy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>23</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 24</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By whom?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWARF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By... Anonymous, your majesty...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh, but I do so admire his verse... Elizabeth lets go of Essex, and offers her hand to the Dwarf, who smiles brightly.</context>
      <utterance>Anonymous...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And the Dwarf leads Elizabeth towards the door. Essex follows, and Southampton locks into step next to him. They exchange a knowing look as-- Robert Cecil steps in line far after the Queen, not happy with this turn of events as we hear--</context>
      <utterance>Lead us to this gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>"QUINCE"</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless thee, Bottom! Bless thee! Thou art translated!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>"BOTTOM"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chairs have been brought out and put in rows in the grass. Elizabeth is watching center front row (of course). She loves it, SQUEALING in delight like a young woman. Essex is next to her.</context>
      <utterance>I see their knavery: this is to make an ass of me; to fright me, if they could. But I will not stir from this place, do what they can.</utterance>
   <speaker>24</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 25</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>"BOTTOM"</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will walk up and down here, and I will sing, that they shall hear I am not afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACKSTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>observing the Queen's reaction. Somehow we feel that seeing her again after so many years stirs up some deep emotion in him.</context>
      <utterance>Oxford watches from behind a curtain, carefully</utterance>
   <speaker>"TITANIA"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What angel wakes me from my flow'ry bed?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>"PUCK"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Next to Young Elizabeth, JOHN DE VERE, Oxford's father, also watches, his face beaming with pride.</context>
      <utterance>If we shadows have offended, think but this, and all is mended, that you have but slumber'd here while these visions did appear...</utterance>
   <speaker>"PUCK"</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...And this weak and idle theme, No more yielding but a dream, gentles, do not reprehend; if you pardon, we will mend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>26</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 27</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lovely. Lovely!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Young Elizabeth and her senior Court, including William Cecil and John De Vere, have entered. Boy Oxford bows deeply.</context>
      <utterance>Ah! There he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father tells me you wrote this evening's play yourself. Boy Oxford glances at his father-- should he answer directly? His father NODS.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did indeed, your majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sport with me.  Compose something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now?</utterance>
   <speaker>27</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 28</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks. Then--</context>
      <utterance>On what subject, your grace?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truth...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, claps.</context>
      <utterance>For... Truth... is Truth... Though... never so old... and time cannot make that false, which once was true.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lord of Oxford. It seems you have added a poet to your family's long line of warriors.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam, I am as accomplished with the sword and the musket as I am with verse.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you indeed?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is my only desire to one day be your majesty's most trusted servant in matters both of war and state, if you will but have me.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, Lord Cecil, it seems we may very well have found your replacement.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We hope not too soon, majesty, we hope not too soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>28</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 29</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil stiffens in discomfort.</context>
      <utterance>And how liked you our young lord's play, William?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our Lord Cecil is our most religious of subjects, and no doubt thinks your little masque will deliver your soul straight into the arms of Lucifer himself. Don't you, William? The Boy Oxford looks at William Cecil, perplexed by such a thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil looks directly at John de Vere resulting in an uncomfortable silence. Elizabeth notices.</context>
      <utterance>That is God's decision, your majesty. Not mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boy Oxford smiles. He might very well be in love.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if plays are indeed such a sin, I pray I do not find my salvation until very late in life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The other prisoners make way as the guard approaches Jonson. The guard tosses a wax-sealed piece of parchment onto Jonson's lap.</context>
      <utterance>Jonson! Ben Jonson!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jonson looks at it, confused.</context>
      <utterance>You've been released.</utterance>
   <speaker>29</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 30</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got powerful friends, now, don't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesco just stares back.</context>
      <utterance>And who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Francesco is silent.</context>
      <utterance>And where are we going?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lord...</utterance>
   <speaker>30</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 31</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Tudor rose. The most beautiful of flowers, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks to me to have quite a number of thorns, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it does. So it does.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am told, my lord, that I owe my freedom to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson doesn't know who he is talking about.</context>
      <utterance>That is true. And it was quite hard to come by. One does not cross my father-in-law lightly.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford looks over to his wife who watches them suspiciously. He begins to walk away forcing Jonson and Francesco to follow.</context>
      <utterance>Lord William Cecil. I have the questionable distinction of being married to his only daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jonson suddenly looks worried and turns and looks back to Anne.</context>
      <utterance>It did, however, serve as helpful when I wrote to your jailers to release you in my father-in-law's name.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lord-- I'm sorry, does that mean my release is not officially sanctioned?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have come to an entrance to a GARDEN MAZE and Anne watches them as they disappear into the maze.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be an idiot Jonson, of course it wasn't.  But you are free, are you not?</utterance>
   <speaker>31</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 32</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I enjoyed your little comedy last week, Jonson. You have potential, great potential.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's politics did seem to have quite an effect on the Tower. My father-in-law's men felt it quite seditious.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Politics? My play had nothing to do with politics! It was just a simple comedy--</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they enter the center of the maze, Oxford turns to his servant.</context>
      <utterance>That showed your betters as fools who go through life barely managing to get food from plate to mouth, were it not for the cleverness of their servants.  All art is political, Jonson. Otherwise it would just be decoration. And all artists have something to say, otherwise... they'd make shoes. And you're not a cobbler, are you, Jonson?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Francesco steps forward and hands Jonson a leather bound manuscript. Jonson looks at it confused and opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Francesco.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A play, my lord?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One you shall stage Bankside.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stage?</utterance>
   <speaker>32</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 33</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name, my lord?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson tries not to be offended.</context>
      <utterance>I can't very well use my name, can I? I'm the seventeenth Earl of Oxford. The Lord Great Chamberlain of England, Viscount Bolebec, Lord Escales, Sandford and Badlesmere, etc, etc. No. I have a... reputation to protect. In my world, one does not write plays, Jonson. People like you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. My lord. You wrote an entire play, my lord. I know how difficult--</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a play, Jonson, I've written many. No doubt, many more than you yourself. A good number performed at Court years ago, others never seen by a living soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you want... me to apply my name to this play?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I mean you to put your name to all of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson pales. This is a disaster for him.</context>
      <utterance>Well don't look like I just gutted your pet dog, Jonson. I mean to make you the most popular-- and therefore the most monetarily successful-- playwright in all of London.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jonson looks down at the manuscript, reads a few lines.</context>
      <utterance>I wish you god speed and good morrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>33</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 34</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up, but Oxford is gone, having left the maze without so much as a good-bye.</context>
      <utterance>My lord-- I really--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But before he can follow, Francesco tosses a leather pouch of coins at his feet.</context>
      <utterance>My lord?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Francesco follows after his master as Jonson picks up the pouch, examining its contents. And then Jonson realizes he doesn't know how to get out of the maze. He chases after them.</context>
      <utterance>That is for your trouble, Signor Jonson. And your silence. If I hear you break that silence, then... not so good for Signor Jonson.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he's lost. He looks this way and that, then picks a path (the wrong one).</context>
      <utterance>Hello? My lord?! I--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil looks at him sharply. How did he know.</context>
      <utterance>So! I am gone for three days, and you somehow manage to let her spend all of them solely in the company of the Earl of Essex...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think because I was in London, I didn't know exactly what went on here in my absence.</utterance>
   <speaker>34</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 35</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is an Earl, father. I cannot deny him--</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His ambitions are becoming a nuisance.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not! You don't deny him anything. You find excuses. She is unwell, she is reading, she is seeing the Ambassador from Russia. For God's sake, use your imagination, Robert. Whatever will you do when I am gone?  We will have to deal with Essex soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil looks surprised for an instant that he knows about that as well.</context>
      <utterance>Now tell me about the play.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It-- it was an anonymous gift. Essex insisted it be performed, just to spite me in front of Court...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course he did.  But what was it about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About? Some nonsense about fairies and cherubs.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert looks surprised at his father who has stopped suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>...And dancing asses?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Edward...  Have you any idea what you have-- No, how could you...</utterance>
   <speaker>35</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 36 And he starts back up the stairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father... It was just a play...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do you know how long it took me to banish them from her presence? She adores them! Adores them! And Edward knows it.  Mark my words, Robert, he has done this for a purpose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Purpose? What purpose?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What purpose indeed?  But through your carelessness I must now deal not only with Essex, but Edward as well. For whether in shadow or in person, Edward has returned to Court! And with that he slams the door shut. Robert Cecil walks over to a nearby window. Visibly upset he starts to stare out of the window and remembers...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robert.</utterance>
   <speaker>36</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 37</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Finally Boy Robert Cecil turns and sees Young Oxford (now 17) entering the hallway with William Cecil and his wife and daughter, Young ANNE (15). In front of them, lined up, are several men whom we will learn are</context>
      <utterance>Robert! Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TUTORS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy Robert Cecil doesn't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry, my lord. But my son Robert prefers the company... of himself... Boy Robert Cecil watches as his father turns to his mother and sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Young Anne curtsies.</context>
      <utterance>May I present my wife, Lady Cecil, and my daughter, Anne.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry for your loss, my lord. The realm lost a great lord with your father's death. We hope you will be happy in our house--</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Everybody turns and sees the odd hunchback child has finally come over.</context>
      <utterance>Are you going to live here forever?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Only until I reach my maturity.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because the Queen has bade it so.  My lord, when we first met, you said you wished to become a great man of State. Both the Queen and I hope to make that so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>37</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 38</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To that end, I have the honor of introducing you to your tutors.  Seven to eight you shall be tutored in French by Mister Crane--</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Master Crane bows his head.</context>
      <utterance>Monsieur. Ca me fait plaisir de vous connaitre.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine to ten is Greek with Mister Simmons.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dalon, an d'ego, hoti mathamata ge esti ha trafo psychas.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Homer?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boy Robert frowns at the correction.</context>
      <utterance>No. Plato.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you know your uncle, Mister Golding, who has petitioned me to allow you to assist him in his translations of ancient Latin texts into English.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Continetne, ut spero, Ovidii Metamorphose? Mihi honori erit, patrue Mister Golding bows his head in appreciation.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil seems to have finished.</context>
      <utterance>Then cosmography with Doctor Richards. Two to three is geography and history, and four to five fencing.</utterance>
   <speaker>38</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 39</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And composition? Poetry?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a Puritan home, your grace. We believe such activities to be the worship of false idols, and therefore a sin before the eyes of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A sin? But surely there must be room for beauty and art in life, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not in this household.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were losing anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young Oxford picks up the sword, throws it to his tutor, who catches it.</context>
      <utterance>I was also winning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I am going to one day succeed my father at the Queen's side. Not you.</utterance>
   <speaker>39</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young Oxford motions to go, then picks up the black king, and tosses it to Boy Robert Cecil, who can't catch it because of his deformity. It CLANGS on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 40</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WRITING DESK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>where the parchments are scattered.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>parchment. It has poetry on it. His poetry. He goes through some other pages. And realizes other pages are missing. He becomes infuriated. He sees--</context>
      <utterance>goes to his desk, picks up one of the pieces of</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDER THE TAPESTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>40</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 41</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it any good?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How in blazes should I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Shakespeare is drawn back--</context>
      <utterance>You haven't even read it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BACKSTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--so Jonson can answer him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read a line or two-- I promised Henslowe I'd finish "Eastward Ho" by Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>And you say he's a nobleman?</utterance>
   <speaker>41</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 42</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jonson still doesn't answer, which is answer enough.</context>
      <utterance>Powerful? Rich??</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And Shakespeare goes back on stage.</context>
      <utterance>Ohhhh, you have to do it then, don't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you Will-- I came to London to become a great poet, to, to, be the conscience of our times, the soul of our age! To change the world, not to become someone else's--</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Change the world? With rhyme?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare laughs at him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, why not? Why can't a man change the world with words?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I can make you the most popular and the richest playwright in all of London."  Ballocks! I can do that myself, thank you very much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's actually not half bad...</utterance>
   <speaker>42</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 43 Jonson takes a swig of ale, then--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not half--?! You're an actor, what in God's name do you know about writing?! He's an amateur, Will, a complete and utter amateur. Last week gardening, this week playwrighting, next week hawking.  No. I won't do it. It would be an affront against the Muses...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well we musn't offend the muses, whatever we do.  How much money did you say he gave you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare smiles enigmatically.</context>
      <utterance>What, you think my name can be bought, if the number's great enough, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson frowns, confused as we--</context>
      <utterance>No, not at all... I think we should keep your good name quite intact, thank you very much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>King Philip of Spain sees the current Catholic revolt in Ireland as a weakness of ours. A weakness to be exploited....</utterance>
   <speaker>43</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 44 Elizabeth's wig is being glued into place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ireland?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are rumors of his sending financial aid, and even troops. We must act quickly.  We must replace the Lord Lieutenant of Ireland, and send additional troops immediately, majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil hesitates slightly, then--</context>
      <utterance>Replace? With whom?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would recommend the Earl of Essex, your majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Essex? To Ireland?  For how long?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as the present crisis warrants, majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not what William Cecil wanted to hear.</context>
      <utterance>Impossible. He cannot be spared. We feel his counsel is of greater import with each passing day.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only recommend we send your most able subjects where they are most needed, majesty.  Philip of Spain dreams still of taking your kingdom from you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>44</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 45</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of burning you at the stake as a heretic. Give him a foot-hold in Ireland, and--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Essex?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Essex's martial abilities are, in my opinion, the only antidote to the plague of Philip.  Though, Essex would not, unfortunately, be able to remain in the Privy Council if he is in Ireland...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three ladies-in-waiting approach with three different gown. Elizabeth studies them as:</context>
      <utterance>And who would you advise to replace him?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir Robert Cecil.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your son?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth points to one of the dresses, and waves the handmaidens away.</context>
      <utterance>He is my own advisor first, my son second, majesty. His counsel has been invaluable to me, and no doubt will be to you as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But William's flash of victory is dampened by--</context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, yes. We will send Essex to Ireland and place Robert on my Privy Council.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw a play this last weekend, William. It made me think of... days long past. Of memories... long past. Long past. I should like to see more of them... Has Edward been happy, William? With your daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>45</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil doesn't answer. Instead he thinks, remembers, as we hear his younger voice...</context>
      <utterance>pg. 46</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Murdered!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By your own hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was stealing my poems.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was doing my bidding!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. As soon as Robert informed me that you were disobeying my express--</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robert? Robert told-- William Cecil SLAMS his fists on a table.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not poems. Your soul!</context>
      <utterance>Enough! Thou shalt not worship false idols in my household! Your everlasting soul hangs in the balance.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil turns away in frustration as much as disgust.</context>
      <utterance>My poems are my soul!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have placed me in a grave position, Edward.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>46</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 47</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Young Oxford looks worried.</context>
      <utterance>I cannot have my reputation soiled by this regrettable lack of control on your part... No. I will not have it. We can claim self-defense, he drew sword first.  But... I wish something in return.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daughter is young, impressionable. She has feelings for you, Edward. It is to be expected, living in such close quarters...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir. For the last three years you have managed to seize much of my inheritance--</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold your tongue, Edward, before you make a claim you cannot retract! I have been legally reimbursed for your education and living expenses.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil studies Young Oxford's face.</context>
      <utterance>And now you suggest you be "reimbursed" the rest of my once considerable estates through your daughter's bed?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. This is how I suggest you keep your noble head from the executioner's block.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>47</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 48</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and in the fear of god, duly considering the causes for which matrimony was ordained. One was the procreation of children...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>appears triumphant. He looks beaming over to...</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...to be brought up in the fear and nurture of the Lord and praise of God. Secondly, it was ordained for a remedy against sin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>48</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 49</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Henry V" by... No one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlowe takes a swig of ale, and spots Jonson coming to join them.</context>
      <utterance>And why would any of you admit to trying to better me in a historical drama? Comedy, yes, tragedy, perhaps. But never will one of you best me in historicals.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jonson sits next to Marlowe.</context>
      <utterance>Or will we be seeing a most hysterical historical?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Before Jonson can answer--</context>
      <utterance>Hmm? Ben? Waiting to see how it's received before you lay claim??</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HORSE HOOVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as they POUND on cobblestone. We are:</utterance>
   <speaker>49</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 50</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>"HENRY V"</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He that shall see this day and live t'old age, will yearly on the vigil feast his neighbors, and say 'To- morrow is Saint Crispian.</utterance>
   <speaker>"HENRY V"</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The actor playing "Henry" kneels at the front of the stage. He speaks to the groundlings as though they are his troops.</context>
      <utterance>Then will he strip his sleeve and show his scars.</utterance>
   <speaker>50</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 51</utterance>
   <speaker>"HENRY V"</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And say 'These wounds I had on Crispin's day.' Old men forget: yet all shall be forgot, but he'll remember with advantages what feats he did that day. This story shall the good man teach his son.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GROUNDLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>become literally spellbound.</utterance>
   <speaker>"HENRY V"</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The entire audience stands and CHEERS madly.</context>
      <utterance>And Crispin Crispian shall ne'er go by, from this day to the ending of the world, but we in it shall be remembered; we few, we happy few, we band of brothers; for he to-day that sheds his blood with me shall be my brother; be he ne'er so vile, this day shall gentle his condition: and gentlemen in England now a-bed shall think themselves accursed they were not here, and hold their man-hoods cheap whiles any speaks that fought with us upon Saint Crispin's day!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>watches, with a pride he has never felt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>"SALISBURY"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My sovereign lord, bestow yourself with speed. The French are bravely in their battles set and will with all expedience charge on us.</utterance>
   <speaker>"HENRY V"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All things are ready, if our minds be so.</utterance>
   <speaker>"WESTMORELAND"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perish the man whose mind is backward now!</utterance>
   <speaker>51</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 52</utterance>
   <speaker>"HENRY V"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know your places: God be with you all!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford processes this.</context>
      <utterance>William Cecil's convinced the Queen that only Essex can save Ireland from the Revolt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We sail in an hour.</context>
      <utterance>I've pledged to go with him, Edward.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry--</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ask for your blessing, Edward.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't give it to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he is to be my king, then it is my sacred duty to be with him in battle.</utterance>
   <speaker>53</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford tries to understand Southampton, but then notices Shakespeare on stage. His mouth opens in shock, and he turns to look across the theater at--</context>
      <utterance>pg. 54</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And he exits.</context>
      <utterance>I am sorry to have disturbed your entertainment.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the younger man is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Henry-- Henry!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah... Thank you.</context>
      <utterance>I, I... It's been... I, I, want to... thank my actors, whose great acting brought... my words... to life due to their most finest acting.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An actor?!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An actor for god's sake?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lord, I thought that--</utterance>
   <speaker>54</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 55</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Jonson is a bit afraid.</context>
      <utterance>You presumed to think? On my behalf? Whatever made you believe you had that prerogative?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lord, your voice is completely different than mine. My, my, my characters are--</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson NODS.</context>
      <utterance>Voice? You have no voice! That's why I chose you!  You at least kept my name from him?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford studies him, believes him. Then he opens a cabinet. In it, manuscript after manuscript are stacked. Jonson looks behind him, stunned by the number. Oxford looks up and down the cabinet. He pulls one out, decides no, and puts it back, looking for just the right one... He pulls another out, then hands it to Jonson.</context>
      <utterance>And will continue to do so?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A romantic tragedy. In iambic pentameter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All, my lord? Is that possible?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it is!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>55</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She watches him go by and immediately realizes that she has seen him before. But she stays silent.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 56</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford holds up a finger to prevent her from speaking while he finishes writing a thought. It's a long thought. Anne is obviously annoyed, and interrupts him.</context>
      <utterance>Who was that man? I've seen him before.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Edward-- we must discuss our Bridget's dowry.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He remembers when he spies his daughter.</context>
      <utterance>Dowry?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She cannot go into marriage without a dowry that is becoming to the daughter of the Earl Oxford.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can give her Brooke House and a hundred pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hundred pounds? Father? Mother!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The matter over, Oxford goes back to his writing.</context>
      <utterance>That is all we have to give at the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford turns.</context>
      <utterance>Edward. Edward! Speak to me! Our family is in financial ruins, and, and you, you play the flute while Rome burns!</utterance>
   <speaker>56</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 57</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then he goes back to writing.</context>
      <utterance>Nero fiddled whilst Rome burned.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>For god's sake, who cares Edward? When your own daughter can't even have a suitable dowry?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford turns to her, full of emotion</context>
      <utterance>My god, you're writing again, aren't you? After you agreed-- after my father expressly forbade it!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He was so--</context>
      <utterance>Anne-- If you could have seen them-- the mob... They, they didn't just sit there like the reptilia of court, faces motionless, fangs momentarily retracted. No! They, they jumped on stage, they fought the French! A butcher-- he actually broke his arm!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anne storms over and grabs the parchment from under him, and begins RIPPING it up.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! Stop it at once!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He stares at her, almost uncomprehendingly. Then--</context>
      <utterance>Why!? Why must you write?! Why must you continue to humiliate this family?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The voices, Anne... The voices. I, I can't stop them... They, they come when I sleep, when I wake, when I sup, when I, I, I walk down a hall! The sweet longings of a maiden, the, the surging ambitions of a courtier, the foul designs of a murderer, the wretched pleas of his victims. Only- - only when I put their words-- their voices-- to parchment are they cast loose, freed... Only then is my mind... quieted... at peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>57</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 58 Anne steps back, frightened of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She stares at him, horrified.</context>
      <utterance>I... would go mad if I didn't write down the voices.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares back at her. A long beat</context>
      <utterance>Art thou possessed?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Two households, both alike in dignity, In fair Verona, where we lay our scene"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"From ancient grudge break to new mutiny, Where civil blood makes civil hands unclean."  Incredible!! The whole bloody thing in verse?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really not that difficult, if you try.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson gives him a sharp look, and pauses to pick some onions from a stand. Shakespeare notices a BUXOM BLONDE women selling apples at the next stand.</context>
      <utterance>And have you ever tried?</utterance>
   <speaker>58</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 59</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"But soft, what light through yonder window breaks? It is the east, and Juliet is the sun. Arise, fair sun, and kill the envious moon, Who is already sick and pale with grief, That thou her maid art far more fair than she." The Buxom Blonde smiles at Shakespeare seductively.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have little trouble parting the legs of barmaids after that performance!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson leaves the stall, and continues down the street. Shakespeare hesitates, then gives the girl a dazzling smile. She smiles back, then Shakespeare runs after Jonson.</context>
      <utterance>You can't play Romeo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? I won't let that oaf Spencer have another go at one of my roles. No-- only Will Shakespeare can pump the life into Romeo's veins.  And his cod piece!  Ben-- Ben! I'm an actor, every inch of me, down to my very toes... I want- - no, I need, crave-- to act. I can't just idle the day by with--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Writers don't have time to act.</context>
      <utterance>So bloody well act like a writer! And for God's sake, keep off the stage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>"ROMEO"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What lady's that, which doth enrich the hand of yonder knight?</utterance>
   <speaker>"SERVANT"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know not, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>"ROMEO"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The actor playing Romeo plays to the women in the audience. And</context>
      <utterance>O, she doth teach the torches to burn bright! It seems she hangs upon the cheek of night like a rich jewel in an Ethiop's ear; beauty too rich for use, for earth too dear!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>respond, eye lashes twittering.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth smiles.</context>
      <utterance>My lord of Oxford.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We liked your play tonight very much. Your young King Henry reminded us of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rash, yet brave. A boy-- and yet a man. Fair on the eyes, fairer to the ear...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Young Oxford dips his head slightly in acknowledgment.</context>
      <utterance>We are glad of your return from the continent. Two years is far too long to be without such excellent amusements.</utterance>
   <speaker>61</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 62</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Was that a come-on? Young Elizabeth decides to find out.</context>
      <utterance>If I had known my absence would cause your grace so much... longing, I would have returned much-- much-- sooner.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young Oxford glances over at--</context>
      <utterance>Your wife must be much pleased by your presence once more at her side...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as this sinks in.</context>
      <utterance>If she is, it is but a small comfort to me. I am returned only under my father-in-law's insistence.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecil had told me your match was one of love.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And so he would wish.  But how could one ever love the moon, after having first seen the sun? He stares intensely into her eyes. And she stares right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Bessie turns to William Cecil.</context>
      <utterance>Where is her majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>BESSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Ladies-in-waiting share knowing smiles.</context>
      <utterance>My lord. Her majesty went riding with the Earl of Oxford.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And which country did you like the most on your travels, my lord?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Italy, your grace.</utterance>
   <speaker>63</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 64</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why is that? The weather? The food?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises an eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>No their theater, which they call la Commedia dell'arte. And, of course, the women.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The women?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They do not wait to be taken...</context>
      <utterance>They were more... clear with their desires than our English ladies. When they want something, they take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>64</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 65</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Puck</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Puck?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's only teasing.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Puck!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, but Puck would never fight for you in the Netherlands...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But then she realizes he's serious, and the smile vanishes.</context>
      <utterance>The Netherlands?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes narrow as she studies his face.</context>
      <utterance>Well, why not? It's an open secret on the continent that you support the rebels against Spain-- and that you are commissioning Englishmen to help their cause. Spain's loss is England's gain, is it not?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this why you bedded me? For a commission?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands, wrapped in her sheets, furious at the thought of once more being used.</context>
      <utterance>No. No-- of course not-- I--</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me. Leave at once!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bess--</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How dare you! How dare you!! I command you to leave my presence.</utterance>
   <speaker>65</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she steps back, waiting for him to exit. Young Oxford stands... and starts to approach her... He's nude, his back to us. She steps back, a bit stunned by his impertinence. He steps towards her as--</context>
      <utterance>pg. 66</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bit stunned by his approach, she stumbles backwards on her sheets.</context>
      <utterance>O Mistress mine, where are you roaming? O stay and hear... your true-love's coming, That can--  --kiss both high and low...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But he's sexy... and naked. And spouting poetry. She stops retreating and allows his approach.</context>
      <utterance>Trip no further, pretty sweeting....</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A small smile escapes her lips.</context>
      <utterance>Journeys end in lovers' meeting-- Every wise man's son doth know.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He starts to kiss her neck. Cautiously at first. But she likes it.</context>
      <utterance>What is love? 'tis not hereafter; Present mirth hath present laughter; What's to come is still unsure:</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She responds to him, melting from both his words and touch. They start to kiss deeply, passionately... And-</context>
      <utterance>In delay there lies no plenty-- Then come kiss me, Sweet-and-twenty, Youth's a stuff will not endure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>my chambers...</context>
      <utterance>You will stay in England... And in...</utterance>
   <speaker>66</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flash of disappointment on Young Oxford's face about that last bit is tempered by Young Elizabeth's sheet falling to the floor. They begin to make love passionately once more.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 67</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could do it if I wanted to...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A play in iambic, in iambic pen...in- bic-pentameter. It's not that hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think you so? Have you ever tried?</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not. But I could if I wanted...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't all in verse.</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare enters and makes a bee line for them.</context>
      <utterance>Ha! See! Even easier!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Shakespeare goes over to the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Henslowe wants "Romeo" to run a fortnight.  A fortnight! Innkeeper! A round for everybody! Inkeeper!!  Billy!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>67</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 68</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fortnight?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The maids love the romantic tragedies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Precisely why I avoid them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, well. No worries. A one-trick pony. He'll never be able to do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>"TWELFTH NIGHT"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Viola and Sebastian are reunited...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>68</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 69</utterance>
   <speaker>A PLAYBILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare's Hamlet". Shakespeare's name is now above the title. We HEAR the audience howl with LAUGHTER as--</context>
      <utterance>in front of the theater announcing "William</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>"POLINOUS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth absent mindedly starts to scratch her chest, irritated by some sort of itch, but still focused on the play.</context>
      <utterance>....Costly thy habit as thy purse can buy, but not expressed in fancy, rich, nor gaudy, for the apparel oft proclaims the man. This above all, to thine own self be true.</utterance>
   <speaker>"GERTRUDE"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What wilt thou do? Thou wilt not murder me? Help, ho!</utterance>
   <speaker>69</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 70</utterance>
   <speaker>"POLONIUS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Hamlet" draws his sword.</context>
      <utterance>What ho, help!</utterance>
   <speaker>"HAMLET"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Hamlet" stabs "Polonius" through the curtain.</context>
      <utterance>How now? A rat? Dead, for a ducat, dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>"POLONIUS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Polonius" emerges from behind the curtain, covered in pig's blood, and dies an anguished death. There is stunned silence in the audience. And then one lone Groundling CLAPS, then another, then the whole audience.</context>
      <utterance>O, I am slain.</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUNDLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a day too soon for old Cecil!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>"GERTRUDE"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O me, what hast thou done?</utterance>
   <speaker>"HAMLET"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nay, I know not. Is it the King?</utterance>
   <speaker>"HAMLET"</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thou wretched, rash, intruding fool, farewell! I took thee for thy better: take thy fortune; Thou find'st to be too busy is some danger. Leave wringing of your hands: peace! sit you down, And let me wring your heart; for so I shall, If it be made of penetrable stuff, If damned custom have not brass'd it so That it is proof and bulwark against sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>70</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth can't take the itching anymore. She RIPS open her bodice and violently scratches some sort of rash on her chest.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 71</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you certain of this?  William Cecil was murdered?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pole reads more from the parchment.</context>
      <utterance>Not literally, of course. He was a character, a fictional character. But the metaphor was clear for anyone to see. And see, they did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Pole continues to read.</context>
      <utterance>Will you shut it down?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brings out a pouch of coins, and tosses it across the table.</context>
      <utterance>That is not for me to decide...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Marlowe takes the pouch of money.</context>
      <utterance>Your service to his lordship is once again greatly appreciated.</utterance>
   <speaker>72</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 73</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He butchered you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not only in front of Court! But the entire City as well! We must arrest this Shakespeare and-</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil slowly-- and shakily-- bends down from his chair as--</context>
      <utterance>No, Robert, think. If he is really as popular as you say, we would only anger the mob. No. We must strike at Edward directly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we cannot maintain our authority if the mob thinks us laughing stocks--</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil looks hurt by his father's anger.</context>
      <utterance>Our authority comes from Elizabeth and from God! Elizabeth! Elizabeth is the key to all.</utterance>
   <speaker>73</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 74</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil looks surprised.</context>
      <utterance>From King James of Scotland.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>James knows of the Queen's affection for Essex... and the rumors of his birth. He is justly concerned.  You will reply to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will reply to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am dying, Robert--  We both know this to be true. And I will not witness the next coronation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robert Cecil wheels his father in.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as this registers on Robert Cecil.</context>
      <utterance>Help me to my bed, my son.  If we are to secure your place at the side of the next king, you must get that king his throne, not I.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will write to James that I am gravely ill, but that all is in hand. Much of the Privy Council has already secretly agreed to his ascension to the English throne due to your tireless, but secret, entreaties on his behalf.  And then tell him Essex will not return from Ireland alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>74</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 75 Robert Cecil looks surprised.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>William Cecil has a coughing fit-- reaches for a glass vial of medicine at his bedside-- takes it.</context>
      <utterance>This is how kings are made, Robert. So it was with Elizabeth, and so it shall ever be. There were many rival claims to her throne, but none survived to make their claim. James must know that you will do the same for him, and he will reward you for it.  But we must do one thing more...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like Essex, Edward must be removed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil is slowly falling asleep...</context>
      <utterance>Edward?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He uses the tools at his disposal, as we use the tools at ours. But ours will win... as they always have.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-- I don't understand, father. What does Edward--</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Robert Cecil's surprised face we hear:</context>
      <utterance>Edward seeks what we seek. To choose the next King.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am with child...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>75</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 76</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young Elizabeth turns to Bessie.</context>
      <utterance>Are you certain?</utterance>
   <speaker>BESSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil thinks.</context>
      <utterance>Two cycles have passed, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil looks startled.</context>
      <utterance>I wish to marry him...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marry him, your grace? He is already married.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can do what I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a sharp look.</context>
      <utterance>Can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Young Elizabeth hears him, thinks on it, then begins pacing again.</context>
      <utterance>Most of the Catholic princes of Europe wish to topple you and end your Protestant reign... The only things that stop them are the channel, and the hope that they might marry you, and thereby achieve your realm through other means.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love him...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knows the answer to that.</context>
      <utterance>Would you risk your throne for him? Would you risk England for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must do as we have done before... You must go on Progress, somewhere isolated, accompanied by only those whom you most trust.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>76</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 77</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Young Elizabeth is uncertain.</context>
      <utterance>After the birth, I will find a suitable house for the child to be reared in.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Edward?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He must never know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you done?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am praying.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She won't see me! I've gone to her chambers three times, and she will not receive me. And now she's gone! William Cecil regards Young Oxford for a beat, then stands.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With this he leaves the chapel.</context>
      <utterance>She's on Progress.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil is silent.</context>
      <utterance>Where? Where did she go?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say to her? Tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>77</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 78</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has a point.</context>
      <utterance>The Queen does not ask for my advice about matters of the heart, Edward. If she had, she hardly would have chosen you for her pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Young Oxford looks up at him like a bucket of cold water has hit him. William Cecil stops. He looks at Oxford with a stern face.</context>
      <utterance>You must have known her eye would move elsewhere, Edward. It always has. You are neither the first, nor the last, of her lovers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Off Young Oxford's pained expression.</context>
      <utterance>Go back to my daughter, Edward. She will accept you with open arms, as she always has. Behave as your great title demands you behave. Tend to your estates, your investments.  And make me a grandson, an heir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jonson looks up. Marlowe sits, uninvited. Jonson looks annoyed at the interruption.</context>
      <utterance>It's difficult to write, isn't it? After watching something like "Hamlet"...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen you watch him. Will. During a performance. It eats at you... at your soul...</utterance>
   <speaker>78</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 79 Jonson stares at him, his answer obvious.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you think Will hasn't been arrested? You or I make the slightest joke about a nobleman of no consequence, and we find ourselves in a cell quicker than a fart spreads in the trade winds. Will-- he murders a caricature of old William Cecil himself, and still whores all the way to Westminster and back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson gets up and walks towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps they haven't noticed..</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson turns around.</context>
      <utterance>I made sure they did...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You informed on one of your own? To the Tower?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Watch who you judge, Ben, for as God is my witness, you may well find yourself doing the same before you meet your maker. We do what we have to, to survive, and survive well, in this life. All of us. And Will is definitely not one of us. You know he's illiterate, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? Oh, he can read well enough-- how else could he learn his lines? But the man never actually learned to form his letters.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you here, Kit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who did write it? You? No. You'd take credit for it. No...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>79</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 80</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jonson is getting nervous.</context>
      <utterance>It must be someone who wants their anonymity protected. Someone who might even pay to have it protected.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jonson looks up. Marlowe smiles, knowing he is closer to the truth.</context>
      <utterance>A nobleman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But which? You know, don't you, Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson stands and hurries out of the Tavern.</context>
      <utterance>You've had too much to drink, Kit. You're beginning to sound like one of your plays.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>for a price.</context>
      <utterance>Ben! Tell me. We can go to him together. Guarantee his anonymity...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You reported on me as well, didn't you, Kit? Last year. That's why I was arrested, wasn't it? Because you went to the Tower?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson studies Marlowe for a beat and then walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, Ben... I had nothing to do with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLOWE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But Jonson is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Ben-- I'll just go to Will! He'll tell me because he has so much more to lose than you. Fame. Fortune. And you'll profit nothing from it. Nothing!</utterance>
   <speaker>80</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 81</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the Rebels have stripped the northern borders... Then we must march south... and take Cahir Castle... The SERVANT stays in the background as he pours wine into various goblets. Southampton notices him-- the servant's hand shakes as he pours the wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Southampton notices the Servant's shaking hand slipping into a pocket as--</context>
      <utterance>My lord. `Tis a well-defended fortress. Two thousand men at least. We cannot--</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what would you have me do? Spend the entire spring encamped? I am sent to Ireland to end this infernal rebellion, not idle my days with--</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In an instant Southampton draws a silver engraved pistol and SHOOTS the servant! Everyone is shocked-- but then we see:</context>
      <utterance>Robert!</utterance>
   <speaker>81</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 82</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>had drawn his own, small wooden pistol.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>shares a look with Southampton.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bien. Faisons du travail... le Coup droit d'autorit?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mais oui, mon seigneur.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they once again begin to duel. But we quickly surmise something is amiss. Beaulieu is much more aggressive than he was before. Oxford realizes it, but is an expert swordsman, and defends himself well. And then Beaulieu aggressively moves forward, and STABS Oxford in the leg.</context>
      <utterance>Bien. En garde!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But Oxford has little chance to react, because Beaulieu continues his attack.</context>
      <utterance>Qu'est ce que vous faites?</utterance>
   <speaker>82</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 83</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>This has become an assassination attempt, not an exercise.</context>
      <utterance>Beaulieu? Beaulieu?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Signor? Signor?!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford checks his leg wound, and glances at the dead Beaulieu. He tries to wave off Franceso's aid, but to no avail as--</context>
      <utterance>Signor? Mio dio! Signor! What has happened--</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beaulieu-- he, he tried to kill me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>83</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 84</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's all that, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson peers over and sees:</context>
      <utterance>A body...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>is stunned.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must have been a cut-purse. Nowhere's bloody safe anymore, I'll tell you that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>BEAR BAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare suddenly sits next Jonson hardly notices.</context>
      <utterance>Sampson! Sired by the great Arthur himself! No dog's yet been bred that can take him down!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need more money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More--? You already make more than any playwright Bankside.</utterance>
   <speaker>84</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 85</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAR BAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But then here, good friends, I bring you a pack of dogs so fierce, so dangerous, that Medusa herself would shrink in fear!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to build my own theater, Ben, one that fits the scale of my work-- Jonson suddenly turns to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your work?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAR BAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a one has had a morsel of food in a week! Bred by the great John Sinclow!</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fourpence on three dogs!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They insist only a gentleman can own the land.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A shilling on four!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bribes are outrageous, but I found some one who will make me a coat-of-arms, and change the Stratford lists for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight shillings on six dogs! Eight shillings on six dogs!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take that bet!! Eight shillings on the bear, six dogs!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Done!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad bet, that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have to make do with what you've got. I won't be your beggar.</utterance>
   <speaker>85</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 86 Shakespeare gives him a look to kill.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't a request, Ben. I'll have more money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or what? You'll slit my throat like you did Kit's?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare shows no reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Release the dogs! Release the dogs!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know he went to see you last night, Will. And I know he was planning to expose you if you didn't agree to his terms.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shakespeare stares at Jonson.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're mad, Ben. Kit was my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the spectators BOO while others CHEER, and--</context>
      <utterance>Be careful, Will. You kill me off too, and you won't have any good plays to act in after this is all done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he gets up and leaves as the--</context>
      <utterance>I'll have my guineas, Ben. One way or another, I'll have my guineas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I am at your service, sir.</context>
      <utterance>So! You are the famous Shakespeare whose labors I have enjoyed so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>87</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare is uncomfortable. He wasn't expecting Oxford himself. Then he just goes for it.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 88</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lord-- I- I need more money.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>since this all began.</context>
      <utterance>My expenses have, ah, aggrandized...</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Aggrandized"?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if, if your lordship doesn't agree to an increase in my, ah, fee, I shall be forced to make certain... facts public.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you any idea to whom you are speaking?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford is silent. Francesco goes to physically eject Shakespeare from the room.</context>
      <utterance>I am addressing the writer of Hamlet... of Juliet and her Romeo. Am I not?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out. Get out! How dare you insult my master in--</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare looks at Francesco, then Oxford.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!  How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four hundred pounds. A year.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A year?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pay him.</utterance>
   <speaker>88</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 89 Francesco is shocked.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Shakespeare smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Pagalo!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me for speaking of things above my place or understanding, signor. But... Is this wise? They have already tried to kill you once.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesco stares at Oxford who is deep in thought. The sound of heated love making takes us to...</context>
      <utterance>Wisdom, Francesco, is a quality I have unfortunately never possessed...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BESSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Edward... You know she would be furious if she found out about this...</utterance>
   <speaker>89</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young Oxford doesn't answer. He is deep in thought.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 90</utterance>
   <speaker>BESSIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She still loves you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. She abandoned me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BESSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her quizzically.</context>
      <utterance>You don't know, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BESSIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Queen. She had your child.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>90</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 91</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But sometime soon after your return to Court.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is crushed.</context>
      <utterance>They-- they haven't been very discreet, majesty. I presume he wanted you to know. To... to hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Young Elizabeth freezes, stunned. Then--</context>
      <utterance>Majesty, there is more. The lady is pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now alone, Young Elizabeth lets her emotions out. She picks up a vase and THROWS it into a wall.</context>
      <utterance>Arrest them. Arrest them both! William Cecil bows and exits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young Oxford turns to William Cecil. The stare at each other for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Your whore gave birth last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>91</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 92</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A beat as Young Oxford thinks on all this.</context>
      <utterance>The Queen has decided to release you. It seems time does indeed heal all wounds.  These are her conditions for your release. One. You will not acknowledge the child. Two. You will never see the mother again. Three. You will avoid Court at all costs. Her majesty would prefer not to be reminded of you in any way ever again.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Banished...?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford reluctantly NODS. William Cecil goes to leave.</context>
      <utterance>No. You have the freedom of the kingdom. Just not of the Court.  Those are her terms. Here are mine. You will go back to my daughter. You will make some effort to make her happy and you will finally act according to your station in life, and accept the responsibilities of your great title.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil turns.</context>
      <utterance>My lord! I, too, have a condition.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>You tell me the name of the child.</context>
      <utterance>I will go back to your daughter if...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if the whore has even delivered the--</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecil's face goes to stone.</context>
      <utterance>No. The other one.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other one?  Who told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>92</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecil is obviously annoyed by this development.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 93</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William Cecil thinks.</context>
      <utterance>I will go back to your daughter. I will make you as many grandchildren as she can bare...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>William Cecil decides.</context>
      <utterance>Or I can remain here...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no record of his true birth, no trail that leads to you, or the... mother. His foster parents never knew the truth, and both are now dead...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make even a hint of this to the child, or anyone else, and this agreement is void, and I'll see your head on the block within a fortnight. And the boy's as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a boy...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young Oxford smiles at the boy.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Edward, the Earl of Oxford.</utterance>
   <speaker>93</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 94</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boy bows, a serious expression on his face.</context>
      <utterance>My lord...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They tell me one day you're to be an Earl as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shall be the Earl of Southampton.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well then, we shall be Earls together, shan't we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil is instantly concerned, but hides it well. They continue to walk.</context>
      <utterance>We wish to recall Essex from Ireland...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil bows his head as he walks.</context>
      <utterance>We feel a terrible void, now that your father is no longer at our side...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still walking, she turns to him sharply.</context>
      <utterance>A wise decision, your majesty. If nothing else, it will give him an opportunity to respond to all these rumors.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rumors?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, majesty, I thought you'd heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heard what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Essex is in negotiations with Philip of Spain...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peace is at hand. We know this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Majesty-- it is said that Essex has promised Phillip all of Catholic Ireland in return for...</utterance>
   <speaker>95</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 96</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In return for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have arrived at her carriage.</context>
      <utterance>Spain's support of Essex's claim to the throne of England...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is, as of yet, just rumor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring him to me, William. Bring him to me at once!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth stares at him for an instant, then gets into her carriage, unsure of herself.</context>
      <utterance>Robert, majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She ignores him, trying to collect herself. Robert Cecil turns to the driver, NODS, and the carriage takes off. As soon as it is away, Robert Cecil turns and some in the crowd of commoners begin to BOO at him.</context>
      <utterance>My father's death has been a great loss for us all...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>96</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 97</utterance>
   <speaker>MESSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands him a sealed envelope. Essex takes it, begins to read. Frowns, SLAMS the parchment down. He looks into the distance, trying to process what he's just read. Southampton picks up the parchment and begins reading.</context>
      <utterance>My lord...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can't believe this...</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, can't she?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Essex heads for the flap of the tent.</context>
      <utterance>It's Robert Cecil. He failed to kill you, now he tries to kill your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We leave with the tide!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare unravels the parchment. He puts it on the table with a flourish. It shows a coat-of-arms containing a spear and a falcon. The colors are numerous, and garish.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I've got it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Everyone is confused by it.</context>
      <utterance>The herald just finished it not an hour ago.  Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's quite... colorful.</utterance>
   <speaker>97</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 98</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in blazes is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson looks over at Shakespeare. Shakespeare locks eyes with him, but looks away, ashamed of something.</context>
      <utterance>My coat-of-arms! It cost a bloody fortune, but, by god, you can call me gentleman now!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Non sanz... Non...</context>
      <utterance>I can't quite make out the motto...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Non sanz droict".</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not without--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare doesn't want to discuss this with the others present.</context>
      <utterance>Right!? Not without right?  You went to him, didn't you? You lying knave-- you went to him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs Jonson's shoulder, but Jonson pushes him away.</context>
      <utterance>Ben. Ben! Let me buy you a--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare looks at the confused Nashe and Dekker nervously.</context>
      <utterance>What? You've already killed off one competitor. Now you want another dead as well?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you mean. Ben, we should really--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(to Nashe)</context>
      <utterance>I swore to him I wouldn't tell you his name. Swore it! Do you have any idea what he might do to me? Do you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>98</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 99</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not even a writer you know. He can't even--</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare grabs Jonson.</context>
      <utterance>Ben-- you've had too much to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare backs off. Jonson pulls out a piece of parchment from his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Unhand me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nashe and Dekker look at each other, slightly embarrassed. Jonson finds a quill deep in his pants. He thrusts it at Will, who ignores it.</context>
      <utterance>Here!  A quill! A quill!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Shakespeare stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Go on, Will. Write something for us. Now. Go on! Amaze us with your verse. Your wit! No? Try astounding us with the letter "E". Or an "I"-- it's just a straight line!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he exits.</context>
      <utterance>You haven't got any ink.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him, horrified to be seen in such a manner. The she regains her composure and--</context>
      <utterance>Majesty, I, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps back in horror-- not at her appearance, but what he has just done. The doors SLAM in front of him as we--</context>
      <utterance>Get out! Out!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins to absent-mindedly unbutton the top of her bodice.</context>
      <utterance>Who in God's name does he think he is? Abandoning his post without my leave!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming into our presence in such a manner, neither announced nor invited, half his army in my courtyard. He's gone mad... mad!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to him sharply, furious at the thought.</context>
      <utterance>No. Unfortunately for us, your majesty, he is quite sane. He simply believes he is your royal equal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Edward, Earl of Oxford.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Southampton comes towards him.</context>
      <utterance>Edward! Edward! Thank god you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth has revoked all of his royal licenses! She believes every lie Cecil tells about him.  Edward? What happened to your leg?</utterance>
   <speaker>101</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 102</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford continues towards the door. Southampton follows, his concern for Oxford's wound noticeable.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She won't accept my letters. I cannot get to her. Cecil plans to arrest me any day. I know it.  But that won't be as easy as he thinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fight him in London, and you only validate every rumor and lie Cecil has ever told about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what do you suggest I do? Let myself be arrested so I can be tried and executed for crimes I did not commit?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I will go to Elizabeth, myself, alone--</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How? Cecil won't let her see a letter without reading it first.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Essex looks confused, but Oxford ignores it.</context>
      <utterance>I won't send her a letter. I will send her a book.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She will call for me. And while I am with her, you will come-- not with an army, not with swords, but with her loyal subjects. The cobblers, the tinkers, the bricklayers of London.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>102</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 103</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Essex looks unsure.</context>
      <utterance>All, all calling for Robert Cecil's banishment from Court. Words, Robert, words, will prevail with her, not swords.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the mob? How will I--</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave that to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out, woman!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oi. `Oo's going to pay me then?</utterance>
   <speaker>103</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare gives a look to Oxford-- he certainly isn't going to pay for it. Oxford nods to Francesco, who gives the whore a few coins. She smiles, and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 104</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>You shall begin rehearsals immediately. But it is not to be performed until I tell you. And you may only have a day's notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford tosses a very large pouch of coins at him, and then begins to leave.</context>
      <utterance>That will be expensive-- keeping all the actors ready. Having the props made but not--</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, and congratulations. You've had an epic poem published today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renaissance MUSIC BEGINS as we--</context>
      <utterance>Published? You mean like in a book?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>104</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 105</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The printer nods his approval... The poem continues with:</context>
      <utterance>And on his neck her yoking arms she throws:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>A COVER OF "VENUS AND ADONIS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>that is held by a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY IN WAITING</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Fondling,' she saith, I'll be a park, and thou shalt be my deer; Feed where thou wilt, on mountain or in dale: We are:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LADY IN WAITING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Graze on my lips; and if those hills be dry, Stray lower, where the pleasant fountains lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>105</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 106</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND LADY IN WAITING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look up and see--</context>
      <utterance>Seeds spring from seeds, and beauty breedeth beauty; Thou wast begot; to beget is thy duty. By law of nature thou art bound to breed...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Repugnant. Wrinkled?</context>
      <utterance>You find me disgusting, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, you are the sun, majesty. The glory of--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil shuts his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Liar!</utterance>
   <speaker>106</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 107</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She doesn't have to say which one. Robert Cecil sees a copy of "Venus and Adonis" on a table. He NODS.</context>
      <utterance>Is it so hard to believe that once I was young? That I was... beautiful? Your father knew me as such...  You have read the book?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil knows to be silent. She looks out the window.</context>
      <utterance>He writes to me. To remind me of that beauty. That love. How I... took him. How I... adored him...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She smiles seductively, transported in time.</context>
      <utterance>Graze on my lips; and if those hills be dry, Stray lower, where the pleasant fountains lie...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>I've been foolish. Proud. Yes. Too proud. Gloriana... The Virgin Queen... A statue. Bloodless.  "Thou wast begot; to beget is thy duty. By law of nature thou art bound to breed, That thine may live when thou thyself art dead"...  Your father told you of the child?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth's eyes flare in anger for an instant, then she regains composure.</context>
      <utterance>Which one, your majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil nods.</context>
      <utterance>His. Mine. He still lives?</utterance>
   <speaker>107</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 108</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was well placed? A nobleman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... your majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am your Queen! Now who is my son!!?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seems surprised. Perhaps she was expecting Essex. But then she smiles, and NODS in approval.</context>
      <utterance>His grace, the Earl of... Southampton, your majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth goes into a rage.</context>
      <utterance>Majesty... You are not having doubts about James of Scotland succeeding you, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil is surprised by her fury. He bows his head as Elizabeth tries to collect herself.</context>
      <utterance>James?! He is the son of Mary! She plotted and schemed to steal the throne from under me! No son of hers will rule while a yet Tudor lives!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She says no more, the audience over. Robert Cecil hesitates, and then she glares at him... He bows and exits, the fury on his face plain. Elizabeth looks at her own reflection in the window...</context>
      <utterance>I will decide what is best for my kingdom! Not you! Not you!!  I have bid Edward to come to me on my return to London on Monday next. It is decided.</utterance>
   <speaker>108</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 109</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And so, in spite of death, I shall survive, In that, my likeness still is left alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>"GLOUCESTER"</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, that am curtail'd of this fair proportion, deformed, unfinish'd, sent before my time into this breathing world...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good part, that...</utterance>
   <speaker>109</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 110</utterance>
   <speaker>"GLOUCESTER"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and that so lamely and unfashionable that dogs bark at me as I halt by them.  Is this wise?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURBAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only the one performance. Go on!</utterance>
   <speaker>"GLOUCESTER"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And "Gloucester" heads backstage.</context>
      <utterance>I need a drink...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burbage. Wonderful theater. Wonderful! The best Bankside! But only one performance? Is it that bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURBAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hardly, it's Will's new play. Richard the Third. We've been hired to perform it free to the public.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Free?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURBAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson thinks a beat-- that's odd-- but then holds up his manuscript.</context>
      <utterance>Aye. Some anonymous nobleman paid for everything. God knows Will never would. Been rehearsing all week, just found out this morning, we go up next Monday.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My best so far. I guarantee more than one performance. Though I'll not pay for the tickets myself.  No need to.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURBAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Ben...</utterance>
   <speaker>110</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 111</utterance>
   <speaker>BURBAGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jonson is in shock.</context>
      <utterance>Will... He's part owner... I'm sorry Ben, but I had to agree no Jonson plays at the Globe... Ever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You doin' tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You askin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Managed to get two tickets to Shakespeare's latest. Cost me a fortune.</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSING MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the actors from the rehearsal enter, all jolly and excited. They head for the bar. They are: The ACTOR WHO PLAYED "GLOUCESTER", Spencer, Pope, Heminge, etc...</context>
      <utterance>Ballocks, did it! They're giving them away free.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best villain in the history of theater, Richard the Third. No doubt.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEMINGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Better than Mephistopheles?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No doubt! Your Marlowe-- god rest his soul-- is fine for your everyday scalawag, and your Jonson won't even try the hard drama. No, this is Shakespeare, for god's sake! The man knows drama. I tell you, not even the Greeks compare!  To Shakespeare! And villainy!</utterance>
   <speaker>111</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 112</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson gets up, furious, and exits, quite drunk. The actors don't even notice him.</context>
      <utterance>To Shakespeare! And villainy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't got all day, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... There is a-- there is a play to be performed... on Monday.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's many plays to be performed next Monday, isn't there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pole is confused. So?</context>
      <utterance>Yes, my lord, but this one is to be performed one performance, and one performance only. On Monday. All Bankside is talking of it.  The History of King Richard the Third. By William Shakespeare.</utterance>
   <speaker>112</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 113</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He kills his brother the king, and half the royal family to get the throne for himself--</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who Richard the Third was.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pole realizes this is significant.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Of course you do. But in William Shakespeare's version, he is played as a hunch-back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>113</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 114</utterance>
   <speaker>BURBAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And both men look out the curtains to the crowd outside. The theater is full to the last seat. The people are crammed together like sardines.</context>
      <utterance>We have to turn `em away by the hundreds! Look! Never seen anything quite like it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So! I heard the Earl of Essex paid for this whole performance! Man's never even been to the theater, and still he's heard of Will-- Dekker also joins them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Essex!? Impossible. My cousin's one of his men-at-arms. Hasn't been paid in weeks. They're all just sitting there, waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waiting? Waiting for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wants to have an audience with the Queen. As if Cecil would ever let Essex near her now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(takes a swig)</context>
      <utterance>By the mass, Cecil in favor, Essex out! Who can keep up with it all!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>114</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 115</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zounds, I tire of politics, politics, politics.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEKKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson gives Dekker a sharp look. What's going on here?</context>
      <utterance>Tired of politics are you? Seems you picked the wrong day to come to the theater, then...</utterance>
   <speaker>"GLOUCESTER"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now is the winter of our discontent made glorious summer by this son of York. Grim-visaged war hath smooth'd his wrinkled front....</utterance>
   <speaker>115</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hissing and booing has swelled so strong that the actor stops for a moment. But then he finds the courage again to continue. Jonson looks down at the Groundling's reaction, and spots--</context>
      <utterance>pg. 116</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>looks over to Oxford's box. It's empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>"GLOUCESTER"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and now instead of mounting barded steeds to fright the souls of fearful adversaries, he capers nimbly in a lady's chamber to the lascivious pleasing of a lute. But I, that am not shaped for sportive tricks, nor made to court an amorous looking- glass...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>"GLOUCESTER"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and that so lamely and unfashionable that dogs bark at me as I halt by them.</utterance>
   <speaker>116</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 117</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Edward knows what he is doing... Does he not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Essex looks concerned, but says no more.</context>
      <utterance>He promised us a mob. They'll be here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>"GLOUCESTER"</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plots have I laid!</utterance>
   <speaker>CANNONS DRAWN BY HORSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as they roll down a cobbled street. We are:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>"GLOUCESTER"</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inductions dangerous, by drunken prophecies, libels and dreams, to set my brother Clarence and the king in deadly hate the one against the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>117</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 118</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AN AUDIENCE MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pox on you!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pox on Cecil!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORE AUDIENCE MEMBERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The actors are getting nervous. People start throwing lettuce and tomatoes at them.</context>
      <utterance>A pox on Cecil! A pox on Cecil!</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is Oxford's man with the Groundlings?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>"GLOUCESTER"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hath she forgot already that brave prince, Edward, her lord, whom I, some three months since, Stabb'd in my angry mood at Tewksbury? A sweeter and a lovelier gentleman- Fram'd in the prodigality of nature, Young, valiant, wise, and no doubt right royal-</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The actor playing "Gloucester" hesitates. The audience is getting unruly.</context>
      <utterance>Down with Cecil!</utterance>
   <speaker>118</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 119</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up with Essex! To Essex House! To Essex House!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson heads for the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>This is what Essex is waiting for--  Oxford is bringing him a mob.</utterance>
   <speaker>NASHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would Oxford--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nashe and Dekker are baffled as Jonson rushes down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I don't know! But, the Tower-- Cecil, he already knows. He knows!  I-- I have to warn them!</utterance>
   <speaker>VARIOUS GROUNDLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up with Essex! Essex! Death to Cecil!</utterance>
   <speaker>BACKSTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shakespeare turns to Burbage.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must close the play. Now!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURBAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can start to HEAR the audience chanting "Ess-ex,Ess- ex"...</context>
      <utterance>Close the...? Are you off your head?</utterance>
   <speaker>"GLOUCESTER"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fram'd... in the prodigality of nature, Young, valiant, wise, and no doubt right royal-</utterance>
   <speaker>119</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 120 "Ess-ex, Ess-ex, Ess-ex"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then the cannon FIRES. There is PANIC all around, and-</context>
      <utterance>Fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>runs with the crowd, trying to escape.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Essex frowns.</context>
      <utterance>They should be here by now...</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he spurs his horse, and GALLOPS down the street.</context>
      <utterance>We go as we are! Now!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Southampton has no choice, and follows. So do the 60 or so men behind them.</context>
      <utterance>To the Queen!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>121</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 122</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY-IN-WAITING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>138 Omitted 138</context>
      <utterance>My lord. Her majesty will be with you shortly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>is in the middle of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson looks on in horror as Francesco is KILLED by a soldier wielding a pike.</context>
      <utterance>Signor Jonson! We are betrayed! Run! Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His men repeat his plea. And then, once again, another trap springs.</context>
      <utterance>To the Queen! To the Queen!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SLAMS closed. And--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take your aim!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>realizes--</utterance>
   <speaker>122</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 123</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUTHAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a trap!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before his men can obey--</context>
      <utterance>Spread out!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fire!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty! You must away! Essex is in armed revolt! He's come to usurp you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Essex? I-- Edward is-- She seems like a confused old woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>123</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 124</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes only an instant for that to sink in. She looks enraged. And then she turns with a flurry, and heads back the way she came. The guards that were with Robert Cecil follow her.</context>
      <utterance>You must flee! Quickly! Majesty! He means to kill you and take your throne for himself!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Oxford turns, devastated.</context>
      <utterance>She won't forgive him this, Edward.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford looks shocked.</context>
      <utterance>Essex will be convicted and executed for treason.  As will your son.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Didn't you think I knew? Of course I knew, Edward. My father told me all his secrets. All of them.  Though the most fascinating was not made known to me until after his death.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>124</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 125</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hated you, Edward, how he hated you. And yet he married his only daughter to you. I never knew why, until I read his last letter to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wanted his grandson to be an Earl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford now looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>No, Edward. He wanted his grandson to be a king.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford goes ashen.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth had several children, Edward, not just yours. She was sixteen for the first. Bloody Mary was still Queen, and our future Gloriana was out of favor. No one thought her very important at all. Except my father, of course. And when her first child was born, a male, my father took it, and hid it. The grandson of Henry VIII, the foundling of course had to be reared a nobleman. John De Vere, the previous Earl of Oxford, agreed to accept the task.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lie...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I?  Why do you think he worked so hard to become your guardian after your father died? He had it all planned years in advance. He would teach you everything he knew about statecraft, marry his daughter, and, after Elizabeth's death, proclaim you heir. His own grandchild to follow you on the throne. But he couldn't possibly predict what kind of failure you would become. How you would fail in politics, ignore your estates to the point of bankruptcy, all to write...  Poetry.  Or that you would commit incest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>125</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 126</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delicious isn't it? Right out of a Greek tragedy.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth would never have--</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Slept with her son?  I don't think she ever knew, to tell you the truth. Though you never know with the Tudors. They all have had such strange tastes in bed-fellows.  You could have been a king, Edward. And your son after you. Except for the fact that... you were you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a fair trial for Southampton... Evidence, witnesses, no false confessions. It must be above reproach. Though with a guilty verdict of course. Oh, and Pole--  If there is any mention of that play--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>126</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 127</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Make certain the secretaries refer to it as Richard the Second. There will be no mention of hunchbacks in the official record...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford looks over at her. Anne smiles. This news gives her great pleasure.</context>
      <utterance>Sentence has been passed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And she leaves him with that.</context>
      <utterance>They are to be be-headed.  Both of them. Essex tomorrow, Southampton in a week.  Your son is going to be killed, Edward. By his own mother. Put that in one of your plays!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kneels, resting his head on a wooden bench.</context>
      <utterance>Strike true.</utterance>
   <speaker>127</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 128</utterance>
   <speaker>ESSEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And BAM! Just as the axe lands we--</context>
      <utterance>God save the Queen!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People start to exit. But not Robert Cecil.</context>
      <utterance>Leave us. All of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty, I--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecil exits, obviously worried. When they are alone:</context>
      <utterance>Leave us!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford smiles sadly.</context>
      <utterance>You look old...</utterance>
   <speaker>128</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 129</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thank your majesty for seeing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cannot have him.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is our son.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did commit High Treason!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Equal to their birth.</context>
      <utterance>They only wished for a place in government equal to their station.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford kneels.</context>
      <utterance>You caused this! Your play, your words, caused my people to mob against me! Do you think I wasn't aware of your plot with this man Shakespeare, that I wouldn't recognize your voice? It should be your head on the block next week, not Southampton's!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth turns away from him, angered. She walks to a window, turns her back on him.</context>
      <utterance>Then take my head. In our son's stead.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He has corrupted your--</context>
      <utterance>Neither they nor I ever conspired against you. Cecil alone was our aim.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecil? He has kept me my throne!  Mary, Queen of Scots... Philip, King of Spain... Four French Louis's... Eight Popes-- they all wanted my head. My throne. All of them!  Yet here I remain... Because of the Cecils.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We would have protected you--</utterance>
   <speaker>129</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 130</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat before--</context>
      <utterance>You would have protected me? You? My "loyal" Earls?  You think Essex and Southampton were the first to conspire against me, to try to take my throne? No!  Only the Cecils could I trust! Commoners! They could never claim my throne. Never! Their wealth, their power, their survival, all depended on me. Me and no other!</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let our child live...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Does he know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I give him to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses for a long moment... And then she decides.</context>
      <utterance>He will never learn of it from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oxford dares to smile, relieved.</context>
      <utterance>He must never know... Never.  Take him.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But only after my death! Only then! When all is complete. After James is crowned king, his crown safe, only then can you claim your son... our son.  This Island will be whole.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>130</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 131</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth again looks out a window.</context>
      <utterance>One Island, one kingdom, one King.  Scotsman though he be.  That, that will be my final gift to my people.  And I shall remain pure... Un-taken!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she leaves the throne chamber. Oxford looks after her as the SOUNDS of BELLS slowly begin GONGING as we-</context>
      <utterance>Treason... that is all that has come from you... your son... Your plays... None will be claimed by you. None.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>A GOLD CROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as it is placed on a head. We are:</utterance>
   <speaker>131</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 132</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>feelings. All of Robert Cecil's desires have come true. Oxford's wife Anne is there, but Oxford is nowhere to be seen.</context>
      <utterance>is watching James. His face betrays his proud</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHBISHOP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God save the King!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVERYONE IN THE ABBEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God save the King!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You must accent the word sirrah--</context>
      <utterance>The line won't get a laugh that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will! Will Shakespeare!</utterance>
   <speaker>132</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare turns and sees Jonson heading his way. Jonson is completely drunk, waving a sword in one hand, a tankard in another.</context>
      <utterance>pg. 133</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Shakespeare immediately sees Jonson's condition.</context>
      <utterance>So! Off to the palace are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The actors on stage are all watching, nervous.</context>
      <utterance>A command performance for our new king! Even in bloody Scotland they've heard of bloody Will Shakespeare, have they? Fraud. Charlatan. Counterfeiter of wit! Murderer!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Jonson CHARGES Shakespeare. Shakespeare easily dodges the drunk Jonson. Jonson ROARS and attacks again. Shakespeare dodges again, turns, and manages to grab Jonson by the throat. They are face to face.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAKESPEARE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They stare at each other and then Shakespeare SHOVES him off. Jonson falls to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>You came to me, Ben. You came to me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Jonson looks up to see one of Oxford's servants standing above him.</context>
      <utterance>Master Jonson?</utterance>
   <speaker>133</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 134</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The servant doesn't know what to say.</context>
      <utterance>What is this man doing in my house?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will leave at once. My husband is quite ill--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was your husband who sent for me, madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I am dismissing you-- A SECOND DOCTOR exits the sick man's room.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson nods.</context>
      <utterance>Are you Jonson?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's asking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, your grace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor exits.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>134</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 135</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He points to a chair by the bed. When Jonson sits down he notices a big pile of manuscripts by the side of the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Come over here, Jonson...</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jonson looks on sadly.</context>
      <utterance>Did you know, Jonson, that my family can trace its peerage farther back than any family in the kingdom? We fought at Crecy. At Bosworth Field. At Agincourt.  I inherited my Earldom as one of the wealthiest men ever to breathe English air... and at last breath, I shall be one of the poorest.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jonson stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Never a voice in government. Never a sword raised in glorious battle. No immortal deeds for my heirs to know me by.  Words, merely words, are to be my legacy...  You alone watch my plays and know them as mine. When I hear the applause, the cheering, of the audience, all those hands clapping, they are celebrating... another man. But in that cacophony of sounds, I strained to hear the sound of two hands only. Yours.  But heard them, I never did.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>To answer is not an easy task for Jonson's ego. He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Death takes away all pretense and demands honesty from its target. You, you have never told me... never told me what you thought of my work...</utterance>
   <speaker>135</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 136</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men now looking each other in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>I find... your words... the most wondrous ever heard on our stage. On any stage... Ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Oxford smiles at the thought of it. Then--</context>
      <utterance>You are the soul of the age...</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise me... promise me, Jonson, that you will keep our secret safe. That you won't expose Shakespeare...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lord?</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he nods to the manuscripts by his side.</context>
      <utterance>I have seen it in your face... He vexes you. How could he not? But he is not your burden. He is mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jonson looks stricken.</context>
      <utterance>All my writings. The plays, the sonnets... Keep them safe. Keep them from my family. From the Cecil's. Wait a few years, and then, publish them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not worthy of this charge, my lord. I... I betrayed you... I told them of your--</utterance>
   <speaker>OXFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson looks at the--</context>
      <utterance>I have made it my life to know the character of men, Jonson. I know you. You may have betrayed me, but you will never betray my words... He puts the last manuscript on the pile.</utterance>
   <speaker>136</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 137</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out! You, your friends, your blasphemous theaters, have brought nothing but ruin and dishonor to this family.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Ruin? Dishonor? Madam. You, your family, me, even Elizabeth herself shall be remembered solely because we had the honor to live whilst your husband put ink to paper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecil steps back.</context>
      <utterance>I can make all this go away, Jonson... To be but a dream. Like one of your plays... Or, I can bring you so much pain-- pain that were you given a thousand years, and a thousand quills, you could never justly describe...</utterance>
   <speaker>138</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 139</utterance>
   <speaker>CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you have them. All his manuscripts. My sister saw you leave Oxford Stone with them under your arm. Jonson takes a long time before answering. Will he betray Oxford?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecil doesn't know whether to believe him or not.</context>
      <utterance>They were destroyed... burned... by your own men...</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's lying...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonson stares directly at Cecil, knowing he is speaking about Cecil as well as himself.</context>
      <utterance>My lord? Why would I lie? Is there a man alive who has reason to hate him more than I?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cecil stares into his eyes for a long moment, searching for the truth. Then he smiles.</context>
      <utterance>He was something I could never be. An undeniable perfection... that plagued my soul... And to him I was... nothing. A messenger. Nothing more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil turns to leave, but then turns a last time.</context>
      <utterance>Let him go! He tells the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil smiles at Jonson, who can only stare at him. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>And Jonson-- better him, won't you? Wipe his memory for all time. For you. And for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil's smile freezes and he leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I am afraid that this is not possible, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>139</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 140</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>140</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 141</utterance>
   <speaker>PROLOGUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A kingdom for a stage, princes to act, and monarchs to behold the swelling scene!</utterance>
   <speaker>PROLOGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King James' watches enthusiastically, Robert Cecil right next to him.</context>
      <utterance>Let us, ciphers to this great accompt, on your imaginary forces work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert Cecil's smile remains frozen.</context>
      <utterance>We had seen some of this Shakespeare's plays in Edinburgh, Sir Robert. I must tell you, we enjoyed them immensely, and look forward to seeing many more, now that we are in London... I presume you are as avid a theater man as myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA moves away from them and we realize we are on the theater stage where we started.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, your majesty...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>141</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pg. 142</utterance>
   <speaker>PROLOGUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben Jonson succeeded in his desire to be the most celebrated playwright of his time, becoming England's first Poet Laureate. And in 1623, he wrote the dedication to the collected works of the man we call William Shakespeare.  And so... though our story is finished, our poet's is not. For his monument is ever-living, made not of stone but of verse, and it shall be remembered... as long as words are made of breath and breath of life. The curtains close. END CREDITS start to roll...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
