<movie id="42" title="Antz">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel...isolated. Different. I've got abandonment issues. My father flew away when I was just a larva. My mother didn't have much time for me...when you have five million siblings, it's difficult to get attention.  I feel physically inadequate -- I've never been able to lift more than ten times my own weight. Sometimes I think I'm just not cut out to be a worker. But I don't have any other options. I was assigned to trade school when I was just a</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTIVATIONAL COUNSELLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YES!!! You know, people ask me, "Doctor, why are you always happy?" And I tell them it's mind over matter. I don't</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are we so successful?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTIVATIONAL COUNSELLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The motivational counsellor opens some blinds...and we see a vista of the ant-filled chamber below.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you asked me that question!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTIVATIONAL COUNSELLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you see out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Ants...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTIVATIONAL COUNSELLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down below, we see a group of ants carrying a boulder up an incline. One worker ants slips, and the boulder rolls down, crushing his leg. The other ants rush over -- it looks like they're going to help their fallen comrade, but instead, they climb right over him, and pick up the boulder, continuing with their task.</context>
      <utterance>Right! Ants! Millions of creatures, each with his assigned task, all pulling together!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTIVATIONAL COUNSELLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see? Being an ant is being able to say, "Hey --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTIVATIONAL COUNSELLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The counsellor ushers Z out of his seat and towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>Z...you need help.  Whoops! We're gonna have to stop there. Your minute is up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTIVATIONAL COUNSELLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now back to work! We've made</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z looks back, and sees the ants behind staring at him angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?! Earth to Z! You better snap out of it, or there's gonna be a lot of pissed off ants!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry Azteca. Here you go, fellas! Fresh dirt! Alley oop!  Shouldn't we be wearing gloves? I mean this dirt is very...dirty. Doesn't anyone think of hygiene?  Boy am I hungry. I'm so hungry I'm seeing double. It looks like there's</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The squeaky wheel gets the oil.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Z. The squeaky wheel gets</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the ants put down their tools. A beat. Then the WHISTLE BLOWS AGAIN. All the ants pick up their tools again.</context>
      <utterance>Thank goodness. Breaktime.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Break's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This colony needs another tunnel like a hole in the ground. Why are we even digging this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares, Z. All I know is, we gotta dig. We're not the ones in charge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GENERAL FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica steps on the foot of one of the "stairway" ants, who muffles a yelp.</context>
      <utterance>Cut the chit-chat down there!  We've spoiled these workers, Carpenter. They've never had it so good, and listen to them -- always grumbling and complaining...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARPENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three square meals a day...</context>
      <utterance>What have they got to complain about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARPENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, sir, we've cut them down to three roughly rectangular meals a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica and Carpenter have reached the top of the staircase. There, the two guard ants on either side of the massive throne room doors pull them open -- and one door hinge</context>
      <utterance>Don't give me statistics, Carpenter. I know what I'm talking about. DOORS!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica salutes and marches to her, Carpenter behind him. Note: Throughout this scene, the Queen is giving birth repeatedly. Each birth is accompanied by a herald playing a short "Happy Birthday" fanfare on his trumpet. Mid-wife ants bring each baby to the Queen for inspection, who COOS a few words. The midwives put the babies on a moving bassinet- line, powered by ants on a treadmill.</context>
      <utterance>Ah! General Formica.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General, the severe food shortage that faces the colony...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, what else?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Queen's attention is interrupted by another baby being put in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Please don't worry, your majesty. Leave the worrying to me. As you know, I'm not an ant of half- measures. I don't pussyfoot around. This crisis is my number one priority, and I promise you it's being dealt with swiftly, and decisively.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No snacking between meals! Off you go!  Now -- what were we saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will that be all?</context>
      <utterance>I do not recollect, your majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica clicks his heels and bows his head. Carpenter bows low. Formica smartly about faces --</context>
      <utterance>Yes, General Formica. Carry on, my good man! I don't know what we would do without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PRINCESS BALA hurries through a second doorway, carrying a swatch book. Something about her sets her apart from the HANDMAIDEN ANTS with her. Her tiara, probably. Formica tilts his head quizzically to Carpenter behind him.</context>
      <utterance>General Formica!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARPENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Princess Bala, sir. Your fiancee.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is there anything I can do for you?</context>
      <utterance>Princess! You look -- outstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>Well -- I thought -- since we're getting married...it might be nice if we...got to know one another.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bala has always been a hopeless romantic, General.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just that -- well, I'm honored that you selected me, and everything, I just thought the marriage might go a little more smoothly if -- we had a conversation?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Conversation...yes...well...  Wasn't she briefed?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, General! A darling baby soldier!  Don't try to be a hero! Just make sure you come back in one piece!  Next!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take your suggestion under advisement, Princess. In the meanwhile -- Formica turns to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General -- we have to talk sometime!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well. Carpenter, is there a convenient time to talk vis-a-vis: relationship?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARPENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, sir, we're ahead of schedule. We have thirty-six seconds available right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outstanding. Princess...? Bala's a little fazed...but grabs her chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, um...how was your day? What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...  I declared war!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...and I was afraid we had nothing in common...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARPENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fourteen-fifty hours, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strides across the floor. Bala watches him go, her antennae drooping unhappily.</context>
      <utterance>Duty calls!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see through the now-open doors into the throne-room as Formica and Carpenter double-time out of the frame. The Queen sees that Bala is unhappy.</context>
      <utterance>No squeak. Outstanding!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I felt the same way before I got married. Confused. Scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- but I did my duty and sorted out all those messy feelings. The wonderful thing about ant life is that everything is arranged. Even marriage. You're lucky -- General Formica is a paragon of anthood.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doors swing shut on them -- revealing the two guard ants who were CRUSHED in the wake of Formica's exit.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...he's wonderful...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The General's body segments are so...symmetrical.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bala hurls the swatch book against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>I'd let him order me into battle anyday.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Princess? What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong? How could anything be wrong? I'm going to marry General Formica and be a queen and have millions of babies, just like my mom.  Do I look fat to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pre-wedding jitters.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's go to the bar at the Royal Club!</context>
      <utterance>You just need to blow off some steam.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Club's so</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The handmaidens look shocked.</context>
      <utterance>The worker bar! Yes! That's where I want to go!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- we can't -- there'll be</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BARTENDER, a grizzled veteran, slaps down what looks like a couple of large green beer mugs. Actually, they're aphids, little green critters he fills up from a number of kegs hanging from the ceiling. The kegs are specialized ants with hugely distended stomachs, which spray liquid into the aphids.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>APHIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch! Ouch!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two aphid beers.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see that? How he gave</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on -- everybody dumps on us workers. You soldiers get all the glory. Plus you get to go out into the world, meet interesting insects, and kill them.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can see that Weaver is eyeing a nearby table of "Worker Babes", including Z's friend Azteca.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but you get to spend all day with those fabulous worker babes.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weaver, they're career girls. They're obsessed with digging.  No, I'll probably never meet the girl for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said there was a girl for you? I was talking about a girl for me.  Don't you want your aphid beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't help it. I have a thing about drinking from the anus of another creature. Call me crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Z, we've known each other a long time, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. You were born two seconds after me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And all the time I've known you, you've been grumping and groaning. You should quit making waves. Go with the flow.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down the bar, there's a commotion. A grizzled old SCOUT ant has had too much to drink.</context>
      <utterance>Weaver, I'm an insect, not a liquid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK SCOUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK SCOUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was cut off from my unit -- found it by mistake --  It changed my life!  You see -- ya follow the great yellow egg, and you come to the land of red and white --</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers pull him from the bar, carrying him out.</context>
      <utterance>You've had enough for one night! Come on, Gramps, before you get in trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, did you hear what he said?!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor guy's had one too many scouting missions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We shouldn't be doing this -- it isn't proper!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the Princess, aren't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course --</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do Princesses do improper things?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not --</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She adjusts her "disguise", a hardhat, tied down Jackie O.- style with an ant's version of a Chanel scarf.</context>
      <utterance>Then if I go to the worker bar, it isn't improper. Anyway, don't worry. No one will recognize us in our disguises.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Music starts. An ant BARKER takes the mic at one end of the dance floor.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just a common worker, cooling off after a rough day!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Every ant gets up to dance. Weaver turns to Z.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, folks. It's six-fifteen, and that means it's time to dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to cut a rug, Z!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not in the mood.  Even when they're off work, they follow orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weaver joins the rest of the ants who are lining up for the dance. The Barker calls out the steps in a bored monotone -- all the ants already know the steps. Everyone dances in perfect synch.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you just sit here and be a party-pooper.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE ENTRANCE, Bala smiles mischievously at her handmaidens.</context>
      <utterance>And a left-right-quarterstep-back step-halfstep -- a left-right- quarterstep-backstep-halfstep -- a left-right-quarterstep-backstep halfstep --</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to ask one of these mindless, primitive worker-types to dance with me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But General Formica would be furious!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The handmaidens are appalled. Bala whirls away from them, sets her sights and searches the crowd -- zeroing in on -- Z, who's watching the other ants dance.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a bunch of losers. Mindless zombies capitulating to an oppressive system --</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bala's standing right there. Z is</context>
      <utterance>Wanna dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I work in the palace, I don't get out much.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The palace, hunh? I bet those royals really live it up. Of course they're all a little, you know, from inbreeding --</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z starts doing his own, individual dance. With a suave expression on his face, he leads Bala in a helter-skelter mixture-of Tango, Charleston, and hand-jive.</context>
      <utterance>Here, I'll lead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure this is a real dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, actually, uh -- I'm sort of making it up --</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should everyone dance the same way? It's as exciting as watching fungus grow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You -- you think I'm right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bala starts to get into it, making up her own steps in reply to Z's, loosening up, having fun. For a moment, the two of them are actually sexy together. Then they get a little</context>
      <utterance>Why can't I just do whatever I want to do? Why can't I just go wild?! Yahoo!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's okay, I'll let him off this time.  Are you crazy? This guy's built like a pebble!  You know they do great prosthetic antennas nowadays --</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z's caught between a rock and a hard place. He doesn't want to get beaten up, but on the other hand, he doesn't want to lose face in front of Bala. More soldiers have gathered around, looking hostile.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't you gonna stand up for yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z glances over at Bala. Then, shaking with nervousness, he says defiantly...</context>
      <utterance>How come you don't dance like the rest of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because -- because I'm an</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDIBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look like a worker to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z, meanwhile, looks far away, ecstatic, as if he's just realized something very important. Unfortunately, just at this moment, A soldier pushes Weaver...Weaver pushes him back...somebody makes a dive for Z -- and before you know it, there's a regular</context>
      <utterance>Hey, lay off my little buddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Princess? You're a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! When can I see you again?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bala rushes off with her handmaiden, just before a squad of whistle-blowing POLICE wade into the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Let me think. Hmmnn...  Never. Bye!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she's already gone, leaving Z holding her scarf.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Princess! Wait!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get real, Z! She just dropped the scarf by accident!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? There were sparks between us! This scarf is a sign!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a sign that you're crazy! Do you know what the penalty for impersonating a soldier is?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's gonna go wrong?! I take your place for the royal inspection. Bala comes strolling down the line, she sees me --</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't think of any.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm gonna</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet! They'll really go for a sensitive guy like you!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weaver hands Z has helmet.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'll get lucky.  You know, Z, I wouldn't do this for anyone but you...</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wear this.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a real buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weaver points to a bunch of soldiers hurrying by in formation.</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell anyone you're a worker. Follow that column over there. And come right back after the inspection!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z skips off and joins the column, marching in time with the soldiers but too excited to keep from jazzing it up a little.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks! I owe you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers look at Z like he's nuts.</context>
      <utterance>Any of you guys know when the Princess will show up? She's kind of a personal friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUD VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ATTEN-</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the stage, Formica is squinting at the audience, trying to make out who was laughing, but there are just too many ants. He continues.</context>
      <utterance>Geez -- tough room.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ants survive as a species because we do what we're told. We survive because we work together, as one, we get the job done, we do whatever it takes to persevere!  Hell, we're not an army of ants...we're one</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I've heard a lot of scuttlebutt about a</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z applauds and whistles as the other ants look at him in confusion.</context>
      <utterance>Dammit, I'm proud to be an ant.  And I know each and every one of you boys will do your duty. Dismissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bravo! Bring on the Princess!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers turn to the right and start to march out past the reviewing stand. A COLONEL marches at the head of Z's column as Z looks around for the Princess.</context>
      <utterance>Stow the gab there, soldier! Let's move 'em out!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eyes...</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that idiot?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bala waves unenthusiastically, little more than flopping her hand back and forth on her wrist. Down below, Z takes this as a sign that Bala has seen him.</context>
      <utterance>Darling, you must encourage the troops -- wave!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z loses sight of the Princess as he's carried away. BARBATUS, a hard-as-nails "grunt" soldier ant, taps Z on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You new, kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I got a trial membership!</context>
      <utterance>I just joined up. But I'm quitting!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, Z is swept out of the cramped corridor they've been marching along, as the army emerges into the OPEN AIR outside of the colony.</context>
      <utterance>Trial membership? Kid, when you join this ant's army, you're in for the full hitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z starts to fall out of line, but Barbatus, looking concerned, stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, there's been a mistake! I've got to get back to the colony!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z swallows hard.</context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy, kid? They shoot deserters!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just stick by old Barbatus. He'll watch out for you.  Whatsamatter, kid? Leave a girl behind?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Well -- no. She's kind of playing hard to get. As a matter of fact, she's playing completely unattainable.  So, what's on the schedule? A brisk walk? a foraging expedition?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- we're going to attack the termites!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANT SOLDIERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hurrah!</context>
      <utterance>We ants go marching one by one, hurrah, hurrah! We slaughter termites just for fun, Hurrah!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So -- these termites, they're little, shy, retiring insects?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No such luck. Those dirty terms are five times bigger than us, and they shoot acid from their foreheads!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER ANTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Montage shots of an ant column marching diagonally across the screen, fading into another column marching diagonally downwards across the screen...</context>
      <utterance>We ants go marching two by two, hurrah! Hurrah! We'll all be dead before we're through, hurrah! Hurrah!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what exactly does our platoon do? Serve beverages? Process paperwork?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our platoon has the best assignment of all. We're the first into battle!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANT SOLDIERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...montage shot of Z's column crossing a bridge composed of living ants -- all of whom look extremely uncomfortable as they're getting stepped on...</context>
      <utterance>We ants are marching three by three, hurrah! Hurrah! Dead ants is what we soon will be, hurrah! Hurrah!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we're going back for more armor, right? I mean, these guys are from outer space, how are we supposed to beat them?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Superior numbers, kid!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z is swept along and up the side of the stump as thousands of ants invade the colony through every possible entrance. Up...over the lip of the stump...and down inside, to the very middle of the termite colony... Into a disquietingly</context>
      <utterance>Over the TOOOOOOOOOOOOO-OP!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they went out for the evening. Let's leave them a message and head home.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Within moments, Z finds himself in the middle of a</context>
      <utterance>Keep your head down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BARBATUS! You -- you saved my life!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Barbatus and some other soldiers kill the termite, the Colonel strides up to Z, puffing on a cigar.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get all sappy about it!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love the smell of formic acid in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stream of termite acid</context>
      <utterance>Look out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Z can say, "directions", the queen gives out a piercing, blood-curdling</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. I seem to be lost, and I was wondering if you could give me --</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm sorry, it was a mistake --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is terrific! Let's exact crippling war reparations! Let's set up a puppet government!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANT OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ants set about killing the disoriented termites when...we hear another</context>
      <utterance>Let's slaughter them all!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Z! Over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z looks down at his feet, where Barbatus's still-living, decapitated</context>
      <utterance>Barbatus?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be honest, kid -- am I hurt bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You've got good color in your cheeks.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, you're...lookin' good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- I can see it in your eyes. I'm a goner. It's alright, Z. In this ant's army, a soldier's life ain't worth a sack of fungus.  I can't feel my legs...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang in there, buddy! You can make it! Just -- take deep breaths, I'll try and find your body -- it's gotta be around here somewhere!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder...what...was it all...for...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barbatus, hang on -- Barbatus!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBATUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbatus dies, leaving Z heartbroken.</context>
      <utterance>Don't make my mistake, kid... don't...be a grunt...your whole life...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm new...I was born yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody told me digging was so much fun! You pick up the dirt, you move it, you pick it up again, you move it again -- lots of repetitions, you exercise the forceps, and the pincers --</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weaver whips his shovel up to his shoulder and salutes, as if he's dealing with a superior officer.</context>
      <utterance>What's the holdup here?!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sir -- I was just having a little chat with my friend --</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said you could have a</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Foreman heads down the line, shoving and berating the other workers as he goes along.</context>
      <utterance>You too? Well just for that, you lose your day's rations! Now get back to work!</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what came over me, talking back like that. I must be going crazy...</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I got you in trouble. But listen, you can share my rations.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you asking me out to dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- I mean yes -- I mean -- if you don't have other plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make myself available...Listen, better watch out with the backtalk. I don't know want you to end up like the guy who used to work next to me. I'm afraid he got...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EXCITED ANTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone waves little flags as the tuba player Oompah-oompah- oompahs... ...and Z walks into the hall, looking bedraggled and exhausted, his helmet hanging over his ears. The band slows to a halt. At the edge of the crowd, Azteca, sitting on Weaver's shoulders, can just about see over the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>The army's returned! Our brave boys are back!</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weaver looks distraught.</context>
      <utterance>It looks like only one soldier made it back!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Far down the hall, Z is describing the battle.</context>
      <utterance>Poor Z -- I should never have let you go!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The atmosphere is somber. This is a tough one to try and put a spin on...but that doesn't stop Formica from trying.</context>
      <utterance>It was horrible...a massacre, a massacre upon a massacre. First we massacred them, then they massacred us, then it was halftime. I've never seen such violence, such bloodthirstiness, such bad manners...I'm the only one that made it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- you -- you don't understand!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, I'm proud of you, boy. I wish I had a hundred ants of your caliber. The world would tremble. Now, time for some R and R. You're invited to the royal victory party!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Royal victory party? Will...will Princess Bala be there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. The entire royal family will be there to honor you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, that's no soldier -- that's Z!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Z?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, you're an ant after my own heart. A warrior. An ant that looks death right in the face and</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well she better -- she's engaged to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Affirmative.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...you two are in love?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In love?  I'm just a plain old soldier at heart. I'll tell you what I love -- the field -- blood -- death -- orders...and the company of other warriors. Formica gives Z a manly slap on the back. Z looks a little uncomfortable as we...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, what a spread -- you know, there's a food shortage in the rest of the colony.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and do you know</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negatory.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you son, sometimes, at night, I see myself in battle, fighting a horrible, faceless enemy, with the future of our whole species at stake. And always, the dream ends with each of us plunging his sword into the other's heart...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you call it when 10,000 workers are killed in a tunnel cave- in?  Who cares? They're workers! The officers laugh, but Bala looks bored in this stuffy social scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More laughter.</context>
      <utterance>But...don't you think the worker class is the very foundation of the colony --  I mean, uh, without them, who would we stand on?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the hero of the recent termite campaign, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z reaches for a tray of canapes that a waiter is carrying by, and KNOCKS the whole thing CLATTERING to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if single-handedly vanquishing the enemy and slaughtering a whole nestful of termites makes someone a hero, yes I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Princess Bala.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, yes.  Well, charmed, I'm sure. So, Princess, have you ever danced with a hero?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She frowns...there's something familiar about this guy. But then they start dancing. ACROSS THE ROOM: The Queen and General Formica watch the party.</context>
      <utterance>Just warming up...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All these parties are so marvellously</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I cut in?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, of course --</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, General. I'm dancing with the war hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bala YANKS Z back onto the dance floor, dancing away from Formica.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, sorry, General, I...I've always had this animal magnetism, it --</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dance...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Divinely?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica catches Bala's eye. She frowns at him, and decides to get a little shocking.</context>
      <utterance>No weirdly...You remind me of someone...</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she says these things, Z tries to act accordingly.</context>
      <utterance>He was swarthy...primitive... earthy...sensual.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a worker. I danced with him at a</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, uh, could you say it a little louder, I think there are some ants in the next colony who didn't hear you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what you said the</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- At the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angry officers begin to surround Z, who hides behind Bala in fear, using her as a shield.</context>
      <utterance>Can't we all settle this like adults -- we're not larvae anymore --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god! He's taking her hostage!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People shout and scream, as Z backs up with the Princess...into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>No I'm not -- I mean -- nobody move! Or the Princess gets it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRINCESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is thoroughly unacceptable!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up and runs back towards the colony entrance, where soldiers are already issuing to get her...</context>
      <utterance>You're telling me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But...just as Bala'a about to be rescued...what looks like a gigantic LASER BEAM sweeps along the rim of the colony, sizzling the ground as it moves along...and IGNITES the lead soldier into FLAMES! Bala looks stunned. Z watches in horror as another soldier ant is FRIED, and we look up to see a GIGANTIC MAGNIFYING GLASS casting the beam...we can just about make out the huge, grotesque figure (a seven year old kid) holding it. Bala, who has no idea what's really going on, turns from the colony and runs the other way.</context>
      <utterance>I'm coming! I'm coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...unfortunately, this draws the fire of the laser, which follows after her in what looks like a strafing run, SIZZLING in her footsteps. Z, who's running towards the princess, suddenly realizes that he's running towards certain doom...and joins Bala in legging it away from the colony; under a</context>
      <utterance>I'm going! I'm going'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z tries to flag down some passing bees.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, alright, I'll try to get directions from one of the locals.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, I --  Pardon me --  And they call them social insects.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bala points to a thin blade of grass. Gingerly, Z tests the grass and starts climbing up it...but his weight bends it, so that he's lowered back to the ground, face to upside-down face with Bala.</context>
      <utterance>Climb up that tree and get a better view!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been kidnapped by the village idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the bigger idiot -- the idiot who gets kidnapped, or the idiot who lets herself get kidnapped by the idiot?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z squares up with her.</context>
      <utterance>How dare you speak to me like that? I'm the Princess!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Theoretically, yes. But is the monarchical hierarchy applicable without the underlying social structure to support it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course! It defines society! To deny the precept is to say that order is an arbitrary distinction applied by the society itself!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But can there be a society composed of just two ants?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! There's no such thing as "just two ants." You never see just two ants -- you see a million ants!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around. She doesn't like what she sees. She glowers at Z.</context>
      <utterance>Look around, sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I --</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha! Don't make me laugh. You're crazy about me! That's why you lied and cheated to get near me!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come on,</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's an appealing offer, but...considering the options...  You go back. Me, I'm going to Insectopia.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell ya, I'm gettin' sick of bein' yelled at.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want, we're just workers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you're not just workers -- you can be whatever you want to be! Look at Z! He started as a worker -- then he became a soldier!</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right! He slaughtered hundreds of termites single-handedly!</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard about this guy.  He crashed a party at the palace. Then he took a hike with one of the royal babes! And when they tried to stop him, he just</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, because he's more than a worker...he's a...what did he call it, Azteca...</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Invisible!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- an</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone who follows his heart!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right...because every ant's important!</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that would mean</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Water...water -- oh, you already said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My skin's dry, my exoskeleton is cracking...I wish I'd never met you, you ruined my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode>the front wheel of a bicycle which is heading right towards
     them</mode>
      <context>Bala pushes Z out of the way just as the wheel rolls past with a cacophonous CRUNCHING, GRINDING noise -- like a gigantic millwheel.</context>
      <utterance>Look out!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to die!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No sooner has he said it than the</context>
      <utterance>Come on -- it's gone! What are the chances of that happening again?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't I listen to my mother ...why'd I have to go looking for trouble? Any ant would have given their left legs to be in my position...what's</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's...it's...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This lake is huge! And so close to the colony! Think of the vacation potential!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut me down a soft leaf so I can take a nap.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, "Princess", you can't order me around. Out here, you're not the boss anymore -- out here, you're just -- -- But before he can finish, a</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hlllllllp!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now the droplet has started</context>
      <utterance>Stop fooling around in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Princess, has it ever occurred to you that they're</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. How many other Princesses are there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five thousand three hundred and ninety -- no. About five thousand four hundred by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And only you can become a Queen?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...no, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what makes you so special?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...I</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z, overhearing her, slowly puts his hand on her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. There are as many Princesses...as there are blades of grass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Notice the big one, holding hands with the female?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARPENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, who notices workers, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one should have to. Have him brought to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this Z...he fancies himself an individual?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...I mean...well...I don't know, really, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well now</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. You're a good soldier.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weaver begins to relax a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So tell me. Where's Z?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I...I have no idea, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pats Weaver on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know what makes an ant colony strong, don't we? We know that no ant can be an individual. No</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that one.  Or that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica nods at Carpenter, who smiles and opens a door. Two soldiers walk in, holding</context>
      <utterance>No, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weaver starts to get up, but the guards behind him hold him down.</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell that tightass anything, Weaver!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica's face lights up.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Just let her go! Z's long gone anyway, following some golden egg to Insectopia! You'll never catch him!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guards exit with Weaver and Azteca.</context>
      <utterance>Insectopia, hunh?...See why individuality is so dangerous? It can always be used against you.  If this sissy here wants to dig, he'll dig. Send them both back to the tunnel project. Double their workload.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we have on this "Insectopia"?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARPENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing reliable.</context>
      <utterance>Scattered reports, sir. Rumors.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Desperate times call for desperate measures. Get me Ant Team Six.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARPENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ant Team Six...</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z keeps marching on.</context>
      <utterance>I swear, we've passed this blade of grass three times.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Face it, Z, we're lost! We must have walked halfway across the world by now! How did I get into this mess...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on...tell me there wasn't just a little...something between us that first night at the bar. The night we danced.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...The land of red and white...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're simply</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode>to Male Wasp</mode>
      <context>The Male Wasp zooms in closer.</context>
      <utterance>We're ants!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poopsie, we know some ants, don't we?  Are you related to the Fifth Avenue ants?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darling, do you have to talk to any insect from off the street?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just being friendly, Poopsie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? I'm not just "any insect". My mother is the Queen.  I'm Princess Bala!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a loud RUMBLING noise -- the family is about to sit down for their picnic lunch. Gigantic</context>
      <utterance>They're Eurotrash, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wasps dive in to the picnic, darting in for a bite, and then dashing away again...</context>
      <utterance>Well -- like my father used to say -- there's no such thing as a free meal!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WASPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- I'll have some potato salad -- thank-</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...my...God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she doesn't move. The Male Wasp stares up at the sky.</context>
      <utterance>Muffy! Muffy! Wake up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are only saved by the fact that they are so small - .the holes of the swatter pass over them. The woman, realizing that the swatter won't work on ants, throws it to the side and tries stomping on them... Before Bala can get away, a sneaker falls on her with a thunderous BOOM that shakes the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Bala, look out!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The shoe rises, as the person wearing it steps away...and we see that Bala is stuck in one of the ridges of the waffle- soled sneaker, adhering to a big piece of</context>
      <utterance>MMMffllmmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- But he does, instantly, as the shoe rises again, showing Bala stuck deeper in the bubblegum --</context>
      <utterance>Bala!  I'll never see her again...</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- The woman has decided to walk away from the picnic to get the bubblegum off her shoe...Z heart sinks as the shoe Bala's stuck on lopes off into the distance...</context>
      <utterance>Z!!! Get me out of heeeeere!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees a SECOND SHOE starting to rise --</context>
      <utterance>These things always come in twos...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z runs towards the shoe as it rises... and at the last moment catches on to the snaky, swinging</context>
      <utterance>Take me to your leader!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment, the sneaker seems to pause in the air...then it descends again, in a stomach-churning, roller-coaster free- fall as the sneaker on which Bala is stuck rises up again...</context>
      <utterance>Bala! Come back here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- But Z is trying to keep his lunch down as he descends. The sneaker hits the ground, and Z can feel himself again...it's now or never.</context>
      <utterance>Z!!!!!!! I'm stuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the sneaker rises again, he</context>
      <utterance>Aa-ee-ya-ee-yaaaaaaaah!!!!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sneaker descends again. Z and Bala hold hands and SCREAM as they see the ground rise too meet them... THUD! They're squished deeper into the bubblegum. The sneaker rises again...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Z...if we don't make it...I just want you to know....</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode>The person wearing it is
     balancing on one leg and about to scrape off the bubblegum
     with a penny</mode>
      <context>Just then, the hand holding the</context>
      <utterance>We're safe...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COMMANDO ANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Signs of a struggle.</context>
      <utterance>Z and the Princess were here, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDIBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get a read on that feremone track.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACKER ANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nnononononononoyeahyeahnononononono no... Finally the tracker stops swivelling, pointing in one direction and saying, "Yeahyeahyeahyeah..."</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMANDO ANT #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got 'em! Ten clicks from here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDIBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Z -- you dirt-digging, fancy-dancing, wisecracking, royalty-grabbing, rebel</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Z.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In one corner of the screen, we can see an irregular little hole through which a</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. You go ahead, I give up. I...I don't know what I was thinking. "Insectopia".</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTTERFLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah -- nobody stresses out in</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z and Bala look around. Just to get things straight, the garbage dump doesn't look disgusting -- that would be seeing it through human eyes. Instead, we're looking at it through</context>
      <utterance>...Insectopia?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like a kid at an amusement park, Z slides down the smooth side of the garbage bag, whooshing this way and that until he slides into one end of a straw (a red and white striped tunnel), and is</context>
      <utterance>C'mon in! The nectar's fine!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, I make it a practice not to trust anyone who shoots acid out of their forehead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRICKET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude, here in Insectopia, we don't judge people by how many arms and legs we've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, back home, they called me a fruitfly. But here, I'm known as...  Superfly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRICKET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The termite sticks his hand out. A drop of acid drips from his head and splashes at Z's feet.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway, big Gus is mellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z reaches out and shakes the termite's hand, as Bala watches, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Charmed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just looking for fun, adventure, trouble, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z takes out Bala's scarf, which he's been keeping folded in a pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Well, "trouble" is my middle name. Actually, my middle name is .985, but I don't tell people. Hey, Bala, I...I actually have something of yours...you left it at the bar that night.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, it's been through a war, not to mention everything else...</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You held onto this all that time?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands it back to her. Bala looks at Z, frankly, openly. For a moment Z is shy. Then he looks at her too. They're two lovers, leaning closer, about to have their first kiss, when --</context>
      <utterance>Well, I...I know it's a little strange, but...I thought it might come in handy if I...needed a scarf someday.  Well, to be honest, I just liked having it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEETLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z gets up to go with them.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. I wasn't busy or anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great timing, guys. Ever wonder why they call you "pests"?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDIBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMANDO #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a read on the Princess -- but target Z isn't accounted for.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDIBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's move in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CRICKET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if, like...we're just these tiny little things, and we're just like part of this whole other huge universe, that's like, so big we don't even know it exists?</utterance>
   <speaker>LADYBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment Ant Team Six rapels down from the top of the garbage bin, landing amongst the insects.</context>
      <utterance>Man...that's so deep...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, your girl is</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z looks around.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? This place is as cheery as a Roach Motel at check-out time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADYBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bala's been kidnapped! Some flying ants took her back to the colony!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z just stands there, heartbroken.</context>
      <utterance>She's been kidnapped?! But I can't live without her!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The male wasp is hovering nearby.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z hops on the wasp's back.</context>
      <utterance>I know what it's like to lose someone...I keep hearing the sound of Muffy's flapping wings...so I'll take you.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wasp takes off, leaving the other insects looking a little chastized.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, pal!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez. I feel like a real stinkbug.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From here, we can see the whole layout of the land around the colony...the "desert" (an asphalt path) and across it, the "lake" (the overflowing water fountain)</context>
      <utterance>Wow...I never saw things this way...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the wasp bounces up and down in the air.</context>
      <utterance>Things look so close together from up here...there's the desert...and the lake...  it's not far from the colony at all...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Turbulence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bala replies warily.</context>
      <utterance>Princess Bala. Good.  Where's Z?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's...he's dead.  You don't have to look for him anymore. He was eaten by a praying mantis.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a shame he died prematurely...I was hoping to kill him myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you'll never be able to hurt him where he is now.  I miss him already.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You miss him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MALE WASP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Z. For a wingless insect, you're alright by me.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands and the wasp flies off.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Chip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER ANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z's caught -- it's over. He turns around with his hands up.</context>
      <utterance>You there! Worker!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bite! I surrender!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER ANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z can't believe his luck -- and his curiosity is piqued.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing out here! All workers are to remain inside the colony, by orders of General Formica!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...if you insist...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind her,</context>
      <utterance>Very impressive, General.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Queen is looking around unhappily.</context>
      <utterance>Is there anything wrong, your majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica warmly places his hand on the Queen's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>It's just...How I miss Bala. I wish she were here for this special moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is, your majesty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TRACKER ANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment, Z's afraid. Then he sees the small Tracker Ant doesn't seem hostile.</context>
      <utterance>Z! Z! I smell Z!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tracker ant keeps sniffing. Z waves his hand in front of the blind ant's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You "smell" me? Well look, I -- I've been out in the wilderness for a while, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, wait, you're...you're one of those pheremone sniffers, aren't you? Maybe you can help me...I'm looking for a friend of mine, Princess Bala.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACKER ANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z picks up the tracker ant.</context>
      <utterance>Bala! Yeahyeahyeahyeahyeah! Find Bala! Yeahyeahyeahyeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z, carrying the little tracker ant, heads out, following its lead... Through this and that passage, as the Tracker Ant gets more and more insistent...And finally straight to a</context>
      <utterance>Just remember, I met her first.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bala's through there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACKER ANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bala...Yeahyeahyeahyeahyeahyeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z can answer his own question. He puts down the tracker ant, with a look on his face like a kid forced to eat broccoli, starts</context>
      <utterance>Great. More digging. This is why I left in the first place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z unties Bala and undoes her gag.</context>
      <utterance>Bala!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They HUG.</context>
      <utterance>Z! You came back!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do they have you tied up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From here, Z can see far down the tunnel to where the crowd is gathering.</context>
      <utterance>There's something going on, Z --</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can hear the sound of WATER SHIFTING somewhere above. He looks up the tunnel...in the distance, we can make out the silhouete of the commando set to break open the wall...</context>
      <utterance>They're having a ceremony to open the Megatunnel...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bala, that -- that lake we found -- I think the tunnel's right underneath it!  -- Formica's going to</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Z! what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it's crazy, but -- I can't just leave. Don't argue with me. If I've learned anything, it's that the problems of two people don't add up to a hill of ants in this world. Or beans. Something like that. Anyway, I've</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your majesty, I'm afraid matters of state keep me from attending the ceremony.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But General -- this tunnel is your baby! You're sure you can't stay ?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Fraid not, your majesty.  Goodbye, your majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well, General -- I know you -- all work and no play!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica, surrounded by his bodyguards, hurries off as the Queen readies to cut the ribbon...</context>
      <utterance>Alright, let's move out!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the name of the colony, I declare this tunnel open!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and then pull back to see Queen cut the ribbon -- she looks up and sees --</context>
      <utterance>Stoooooop!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bala!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z calls out to the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The workers are unconvinced.</context>
      <utterance>Listen up! We've all got to get out of here! This place is going to flood!</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? What makes you so special, Mr. Know-It-All?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The workers are even more sceptical. A laugh goes up from the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Z.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Z? Gimme a break! Z's ten milimeters tall!</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and he can kill termites with his bare hands! You're just some scrawny worker with a mental problem!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WORKERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey...it</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nearby, Bala and the Queen hug. The Queen looks over at Z.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it, pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...it's that social-climbing worker again -- what does he want?</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To save you all! Now we've got to go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AZTECA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no way out!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're all going to drown!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z clenches his fist...he feels utterly powerless...then he shouts...</context>
      <utterance>Z...what can we do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WORKER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...we don't dig any more. We're individuals.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We're too important to dig. You taught us that, Z. You hate digging!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I hate drowning more! Now</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nearby the Queen stands there, looking squeamish.</context>
      <utterance>That's it! Pass the dirt back to the center! Go on!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gingerly, the Queen reaches out for a clod of dirt...and passes it along. Next thing you know, she's practically</context>
      <utterance>Your highness...time to get your hands dirty!</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The "Z" cheer goes up, with everyone joining in. But the jubilation is short-lived, for, appearing on the ridge, surrounding the workers, is FORMICA'S ARMY, circling the mass of workers, backing them in towards the roiling water behind them. Formica himself appears in the front lines, with Carpenter and Mandible at his side.</context>
      <utterance>He did it! Z! Z! Z! Z! Z!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps forward to address the surrounded, trapped workers.</context>
      <utterance>Z. I should have known. All that work, all that preparation, come to nothing. All because of one stinking ant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WHERE'S Z?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Formica laughs, shaking his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Folks, you may have survived that flood, but there's</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Formica raises his swagger stick to order the attack, a lone figure steps out from the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Have it your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Z stands there, shivering with fear.</context>
      <utterance>Wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment, Z stands alone, under the glare of Formica's gaze. Then another figure steps out from the throng of workers.</context>
      <utterance>...I'm Z.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE WASP appears on the other side of the horizon.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, guys!</utterance>
   <speaker>WASP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, on all sides, A MASSIVE INSECT ARMY appears on the ridge, looking not unlike ambushing Indians in a John Ford film. Formica's soldiers stop in their tracks, awed by the unfolding spectacle. It looks like all of Insectopia has turned out: spiders, caterpillars, rhinoceros beetles, all manner of creatures crawling and flying have shown up, and now surround the army, dwarfing them.</context>
      <utterance>It's them!</utterance>
   <speaker>WASP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are these hooligans giving you trouble, Z?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ant army remains frozen, unsure of what to do next. Formica is furious. If ants had veins, Formica's would be bulging out of his face.</context>
      <utterance>Say the word, Z, and we kick their butts.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Make an example of yourself!</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?! ATTACK!!  Come on, you yellow-bellies!  Don't just stand there, Carpenter!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARPENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, actually, we</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Z goes to the edge of the precipice and looks over. Formica is struggling in the waters of the very flood he created, which are roiling not far below. He looks up into Z's eyes, a new expression crossing his features: fear.</context>
      <utterance>Help...help me...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica goes under for a bit, then his head comes up again -- but he's not going to be able to stay afloat for long... Suddenly he sees a line dropped down. Above, Z looks down on him.</context>
      <utterance>Please...I...I can't swim...Help me...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica looks at the line...and in that moment seems to realize his error...</context>
      <utterance>I thought you said that the life of one ant doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORMICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Formica reaches up and takes the line, and is pulled up by Z and a bunch of other ants (the line, we see, extends from a nearby spider, one of the cavalry from Insectopia). Formica is left, broken and alone, by the precipice, while HORDES OF ANTS surround Z to congratulate him. Bala fights her way to his side and the two of them embrace. Then the ants pick up Z and Bala, and, CHEERING, bear them away. Only Carpenter stays behind. He walks up to Formica, carrying his dented and dusty helmet. He cleans it the best he can with his jacket sleeve and hands it to his fallen general.</context>
      <utterance>I guess it does...to the ant.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARPENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, if it's any consolation, I still think you're completely worthless as an individual.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE UP OF Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As he addresses the audience, stand-up style.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, uh, that's pretty much it. Just your basic "simple worker overthrows the government and winds up with the princess" kind of a story. You know: there was the big parade and everything...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PULL BACK TO REVEAL Formica clinging to a wall, his belly hideously distended with honeydew.</context>
      <utterance>General Formica was almost unemployable. He eventually got a gig as a honeydew keg.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Queen asked me to take over his job, but I said "Sorry, but I'm really not the general type. I'm more the specific type." So they gave the job to Weaver instead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bala enters the frame, embraces and kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>And me, I guess you could say that I lived happily ever after.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, I've got the whole package, right? A great life, a beautiful wife, and a few kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
