<movie id="45" title="Apt Pupil">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Todd lets go as a chain behind the heavy door starts to rattle. Then it opens. An old man stands behind the screen. He is KURT DUSSANDER, a.k.a. Arthur Denker. Mid-seventies. Standing there in his bathrobe and slippers, a cigarette smashed in his mouth, he looks like a cross between Boris Karloff and Albert Einstein. Dussander stares at Todd, who tries to speak, but suddenly cannot.</context>
      <utterance>All right. All right. I'm coming. Let it go!</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door stops. Dussander opens it slowly. He unlatches the screen and slips his fingers around the paper. Todd does not let go.</context>
      <utterance>Don't forget your paper, Mr. Dussander.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me my newspaper.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander snatches the paper away and closes the screen door. Quickly, almost imperceptibly, the old man's eyes survey the area: across the street, up and down the sidewalk, the boy's bicycle.</context>
      <utterance>Sure thing, Mr. Dussander.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the front door closes, Todd speaks rapidly into the narrowing gap.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Denker. See?  Denker. Perhaps you cannot read after all. What a pity. Good day.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bergen-Belsen, January '43 to June '43. Auschwitz, June '43 to June '44. Then you went to Patin. The door stops, still partly open.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After the war, you escaped to Buenos Aires. From 1950 to '52 you were in Cuba, and then... From 1952 to '58... I don't know. No one does. But in 1965, you popped up in West Berlin, where they almost got you. The door opens wider.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, boy. I don't know what is the matter with you. But I don't have time for this game. Now, get out of here before I call the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call them if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The heavy door slams shut.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a flash the front door is open, so is the screen. Dussander is through the doorway and descending upon Todd with the rolled umbrella raised to strike him. Todd stumbles back against the porch rail.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay by me Herr Kommandant. I'm sure the police would love to meet the "Blood- fiend of Patin."</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Todd regains his composure quickly. He brushes himself off and levels his eyes at the old man who now hardly seems the threat he was a few seconds ago.</context>
      <utterance>You get away from this house, God damn you! I'll beat you all the way home.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After 1965, no one saw you again... Until I did. Three weeks ago on the downtown bus. If you want to call the cops, go right ahead. I'II wait on the steps.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll do no such thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't? Listen, old man, if I want to start screaming right here, I will. If I want to ride down to the police station and bring the cops back myself, then I will. I will do what ever I want. Do you understand?  But if you like, I could come in for a minute. We could talk. Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be out of my mind to let an insane boy like you into my home. Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander turns and steps back through the screen door. He stops at the threshold of the house and turns. He is holding the screen door open with one leg, the front door open with the other. He looks straight ahead. A moment later, Todd steps into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Is that what you want, to come into my home? So be it. There is no arguing with crazy people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd's attention drifts away and his fingers slip over to a lampshade next to the photograph. He begins to feel it as though he were inspecting it for something.</context>
      <utterance>My wife. She died in 1955 of lung disease. At that time I was working at the Menschler Motor Works in Essen. I was heartbroken.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Todd jumps back a little but then recovers.</context>
      <utterance>Stop that!</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, wasn't it Ilse Koch who made the lampshades out of human skin?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you do, Mr. Dussander.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Denker. Denker. Denker. You don't listen, boy. The television has fried your brain. Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your hands are shaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, they're shaking. I'm old. We all shake. You are most tiresome, and rude. Now if you have a point I wish you'd come to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're in no rush. If I thought you had plans, I'd say cancel them, but since I know you don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know nothing of my business --</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What business? You sit in that ugly chair and watch soap operas all day. Except on Friday afternoons when you walk down to the movie theater. And twice a week you take the bus downtown to do your shopping. You always use the express lane because you never have more than ten items.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have been following me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, I followed you. You think I normally go around to peoples' houses and accuse them of being Nazi fugitives?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps for me you made an exception.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd sits on the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>No, for you I had to be sure. For Kurt Dussander I had to be absolutely certain. ...Now, I am, and that's why I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, I see now. As I am this ex-Nazi fellow, as you say, then this must be the part where I offer you my hidden stash of gold, taken from the mouths of old Jewish men, of course, which I keep buried in the basement. Isn't that right, boy? Well, I'm afraid you're wasting your time. I have no money. If I did I might even give you some just to be done with this nonsense.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need money. You don't have any anyway. At least, I don't think so. You probably had to spend it all to sneak in the country. A good American passport is expensive on the black market, that I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you? Good for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do. I know it all, Dussander. You're my One Great Interest.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>personally, but, ...well, it's something I learned back in eighth grade. Our teacher, Miss Harmon, she said we'd have to find our One Great Interest in life. You know, the thing that would really grab us. Once we did that, everything would fall into place. Like hers, she said, wasn't teaching, but collecting nineteenth-century postcards. I guess there's no money in that, so she has to be a teacher. Anyway, she told us to start thinking about it. So I did, but nothing happened. Until the following summer, in Ronny Pegler's garage. That's where I found it.</context>
      <utterance>My One Great Interest. Well, not you</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of these has three girls doing it</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As young Todd stares into this secret world, his voice comes in...</context>
      <utterance>Hang on a sec.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was all there... pictures of stuff I'd never seen, stuff they</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then last year I wrote my big term paper on Dachau. I got an A+. It was the only A+ she gave. I mean I always do real well. A's on everything. That's why I'm accelerated.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Accelerated?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, accelerated. I skipped two grades, second and ninth. I didn't need them. That's why I'm already a junior. Dussander sits.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some kids resent me for it. That's not important. Anyway, my paper really floored my history teacher. I guess because I got through all those books without throwing up. But I learned something. I learned that when you talk about the camps now, you have to remember to sound really disgusted. I mean, you can't just say what happened like the magazines did and leave it at that. If I tried that the teacher would have freaked and called my parents in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd, lost in the sea of old photographs, doesn't notice Ronny at first. Then he looks up at him. In his eyes is a glint of a darkness that we will come to know better.</context>
      <utterance>Todd, your mom's on the phone. She says you have to come home for dinner. ...Todd?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Todd.</context>
      <utterance>Your mom's on the phone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nowadays you have to... soften it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I care about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd hops up and begins to pace the floor. Dussander stares at him blankly, unsure of where this is going.</context>
      <utterance>Because, I don't want it softened.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sure you trouble your parents to no end.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I'm pretty low maintenance. That's what my dad says.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told your parents about me, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd looks deep into Dussander's eyes. Dussander is uncomfortable. Slowly, Todd reaches out and brushes his finger against Dussander's hand. Dussander gets up.</context>
      <utterance>I think you're crackers, but go on. I'm riveted.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then it happened... I was on my way to the library. It was raining...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander stares back at him flatly.</context>
      <utterance>It was incredible.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of this... because of a rain coat?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it wasn't</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I got this little camera. Fits right in the palm of my hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clever boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But even then I couldn't be sure. I needed real proof. So I went to the mall and bought a fingerprint kit from the hobby shop and a book that tells you what you're supposed to look for and then dusted your mailbox while you were at the movies. Pretty smart, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... put dust on my mailbox? For fingerprints? You took photographs of me? What else did you do?... I don't believe any of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already had a copy of your fingerprints. They're on your want sheet from the Israeli government. It's on database at UC Irvine. Can you believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He storms toward the kitchen and stops.</context>
      <utterance>Bourbon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you care for a drink, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, you got a Coke?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander disappears into the kitchen. Todd stands alone in the living room. He lets out a long, nervous breath, showing for the first time the presence of something other than the cold confidence he has been putting up for Dussander. He knows he has crossed into dangerous territory from which there is no going back. But after a moment he composes himself; he has come this far. The sternness returns to his eyes. Todd is all business. He takes a breath, and then speaks loudly enough for Dussander to hear him in the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It takes eight good matches, they're called compares, actually, for a fingerprint to get accepted in court.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The SOUNDS of a refrigerator opening and closing come from the kitchen. Drinks being poured. Todd begins to move slowly toward the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>You should be a detective.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I will... Mom thinks I'd be good at it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander approaches him carrying a tumbler of milk and a glass of bourbon. He hands the tumbler to Todd, who brings it up to his lips and hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>I found fourteen compares.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have some.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...And two missing children.  Boy what you have done, I have to explain this to you because clearly you don't understand, what you have done is a violation.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A violation?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kind of like those experiments with the decompression chamber. Now, that was a violation, Dussander.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That fucking name. Enough of that. I demand it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I demand --</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You demand nothing from me. Ever. Get it? Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I will tell you this once more, and for the last time. My name is Arthur Denker. It has never been anything else. It has never even been Americanized. If you must know, and apparently you must, I was named by my father who greatly admired the stories of Arthur Conan Doyle. I did serve in the reserves, I admit, and in the late thirties, when I was first married, I supported Hitler. I supported him most, I suppose, because for the first time in years there was work and there was tobacco. ...Would you like a cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander turns toward the counter and pulls a kitchen match from a cabinet. He lights his cigarette with his back to Todd.</context>
      <utterance>No. My dad used to smoke. Mom made him quit. Now he's addicted to Nicorette... that's nicotine gum.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander's eyes drift to the collection of kitchen knives neatly stuffed in their block on the counter in front of him. He lingers a moment, pulls deeply on the cigarette, then turns and continues.</context>
      <utterance>Nicotine gum.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, Hitler lost his mind at the end, directing phantom armies at the whim of his astrologer. He even gave his dog, Blondi, a death capsule. On May 2nd, 1945, my regiment surrendered to the Americans. I remember that a private named Gonzales gave me a chocolate bar. I wept. Bored, Todd sinks into a chair at the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was interned at Essen where I was treated very well. We listened to the Nuremberg trials on the radio and when Goering committed suicide, I bought half a bottle of schnaps and got drunk. When I was released, I put wheels on cars at the Essen Motor Works until I retired in 1963. In 1967 I emigrated here, to California, and became a U.S. Citizen. I am as American as you are. I vote. No Buenos Aires, no Berlin, no</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, to hell with this and to hell with you. I'm calling the police. Your father is going to beat your behind when he picks you up at the police station.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. My parents don't believe in violence.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander steps past Todd and picks up the receiver of the phone hanging on the wall above the table. The boy still sits motionless behind him. Dussander dials a "9", and then, with more difficulty, a "1". He stands with his finger poised over the final "1". Tiny beads of sweat roll over his forehead. His shoulders drop. Todd stands up. Their faces are close together.</context>
      <utterance>Well, they should start. I'm calling.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang up the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is unforgivable. Do you know the things you're accusing me of?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly, Dussander brings the receiver down onto its hook.</context>
      <utterance>Do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't want money, what do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to hear about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hear about what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The camps. Everything. The experiments. The examinations. All the stuff the writers are scared to put in their books because people will think they're sick. That's what I want, ...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. And you're going to tell it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to history you're the monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could you ask me to remember such things? I can barely remember to take my heart medicine.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were there. You did those things. No one can tell it better than you can. And you will tell it, starting today. Right now. If you don't, I'll tell everyone who you are. I swear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I? Why should I do any of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you hung up the phone. That's why. ...And just so you know, just so there is no misunderstanding whatsoever. Everything I have on you, the compares, the want sheet, all the photographs, are all in an envelope under my mattress. I'm going to put it there every time I come to see you. If anything happens to me, if I should suddenly disappear, some one will find it. Believe me --</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a foolish thing to do. What if your mother goes in your room anyway? What if she hires a maid?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>You better hope she doesn't.  We're wasting time. Let's get started. I have to be home for dinner. Today I want to hear about the ovens. How you baked them after they were dead... and before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A boy... a boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But before we start, put your teeth in. You look better with your teeth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PROXMIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the teacher continues to lecture, the camera stops on JOEY, 17. On his desk is a folded note. He hands it across the aisle and motions for it to be sent to Todd a few rows over. The note moves across the room, avoiding the meandering teacher, on its way to Todd.</context>
      <utterance>But in 1902, Panama didn't exist. The country we know as Panama was part of Columbia.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROXMIRE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The FEMALE STUDENT across the aisle from Todd now has the note. She whispers to him but he doesn't hear. Todd is trying to say awake with great difficulty. The girl extends the note just as Proxmire passes. He stops, turns around, plucks the note from the girl's hand and heads for the front of the class.</context>
      <utterance>Now the nations of the west knew they needed a canal through Central America. They were tired of waiting for their ships to sail around Cape Horn. This was the new century, the age of modernization. And the U.S. was at the forefront. Teddy Roosevelt was in the White House, looking for any chance to assert the might of America. When Columbia balked at the offer made by the U.S. and England, Roosevelt sent his naval war ships to sit off the coast of Panama, just sit there, where they could be seen from the coast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROXMIRE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Without glancing at it, Proxmire crumples the note and drops it into the waste basket by his desk.</context>
      <utterance>Finally Columbia gave up the territory for about a tenth of its original price. And as Roosevelt would say later, "The U.S. stole the Panama canal fair and square."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy, Jesus. It's just me, flinch- man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got news for you. You're gonna like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two walk down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Walk with me to French.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone likes you. Someone good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I heard my sister talking on the phone with Lisa Herman, and... well --</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two CHEERLEADERS pass them.</context>
      <utterance>You going to tell me who it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't hear it from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Becky Trask.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that so hard?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So ask her out and the weekend after next you can double with me and Vanessa.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about this weekend?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm already planning on being grounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grounded? What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They arrive at the door of Todd's classroom as the BELL SOUNDS.</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell you been? Report cards were sent out today. I know that never affects you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joey runs off, leaving Todd looking after him.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. Don't forget what I told you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never seen anyone drink bourbon with McDonald's before. ...So, How did the stuff get to Patin?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In railroad cars marked "Medical Supplies." It came in long crates that looked like coffins.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cat jumps into Dussander's lap again. He throws it down, this time harder.</context>
      <utterance>That's fitting. Was it always Zyklon-B?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd sits up a little, leaning in.</context>
      <utterance>No, from time to time we would be sent something else. Experimental gases. The High Command was always interested in improving efficiency. Once they sent us a gas code-named "Pegasus." A nerve gas. Thank God they never sent it again. It...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't work very well. It was quite boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. You're lying. What did it do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cat jumps up a third time. This time Dussander picks it up and tosses it a good six feet. The animal hits the ground and runs away.</context>
      <utterance>It killed them. What do you think it did, made them walk on water? It killed them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.  Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finds the pack and fumbles a cigarette to his lips. He lights it. Todd watches calmly, giving the old man a moment to collect himself, and then...</context>
      <utterance>I won't. I refuse. Where are my cigarettes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did it do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It made them dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like Zyklon-B, it came in through the shower heads. After a few seconds the prisoners began to leap about. Some were screaming. Most of them were laughing. They began to vomit and to... to defecate helplessly.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Dussander ignores him, staring out into the yard as he begins to remember more easily.</context>
      <utterance>You mean they... they... shit themselves? ...Woah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They began to twitch all over and make high, strange sounds in their throats. At last they collapsed and just lay there on the concrete, twitching and yodeling, with blood streaming from their noses. But I lied to you, boy. It didn't kill them. Either because it wasn't strong enough or because we couldn't bring ourselves to wait that long. I suppose it was that. I sent five men in with rifles to end their agonies. These were five men I trusted. It would have looked bad on my record to have wasted so many cartridges at a time when the Fuehrer had declared every cartridge a national resource. I was always given high marks for efficiency.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander looks down at the remains of the meal in his lap. As if his own story has suddenly disgusted him, he balls the food up in its wrapper and shoves it into the paper bag.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you eat this crap everyday?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you just do the job yourself? You carried a gun, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was the commandant of the camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you never killed anybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not a real answer. I'm asking about</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>shovels a few more fries into his mouth, then looks up and sees Dussander eyeing him.</context>
      <utterance>I know what the SS was, Dussander. Who are you talking to? It was a bunch of dumb, rich kids who bought their way into the service so they wouldn't have to go fight on the front. Dussander stares at Todd, wanting to say something. Todd</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough for today, boy. I beg you. I'm tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, fine. That was good story though. You always tell them good, once I get you started. ANGLE on Dussander.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're tight. Don't hold your breath so long.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls off his headphones in disgust and hands the rifle to his father. Dick takes it and begins to reload it for him.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. I can't concentrate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know your upset. So am I. So is your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These honors classes... they aren't as easy as I thought they'd be. I totally admit it, I didn't prepare enough. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, fine, but now is not the time to slack off. You got a chance to finish at the top of your class--</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody wants that more than I do, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you haven't been hitting the books very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And seeing as you're not playing soccer this year it's not like you don't have enough time--</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That still bothers you, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, son. If you weren't enjoying it, then you shouldn't play.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dick decides to take a shot himself. He readies himself and fires.</context>
      <utterance>I think it bothers you and you're not telling me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(gives the gun back to Todd) I want to see your grades come up, buddy. That's all that bothers me. And if you say you need more time to study, then that's what we'll do. The first thing is to cut out all the time you spend reading to Mr. Denker. It's a nice thing to do, but it's not helping our school work a bit. Dick is looking at his son, unsure if he has just seen a contortion of rage on his son's face. But Todd is cocking the rifle and...</context>
      <utterance>That was lousy. Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Todd. You still with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... no. Dad, don't do that. Please. Don't punish Mr. Denker for something that's my fault. I mean, he'd be lost without me--</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll be fine without you. He was fine before and he'll be fine after. There's nothing wrong with wanting to help people, but you gotta make sure you got yourself squared away first.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not by a long shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then trust me on this. Don't lose faith in me because I blew a couple of exams. I</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, he's not...?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just checking.  All right... We'll give your way a shot. If you think you can do it, if you really do, and your serious, then... okay. You really like the old guy, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd aims the rifle down range and pulls the trigger. The gun jams. Todd tries to move the lever but it gets stuck.</context>
      <utterance>I'm making a difference in somebody's life. It's that simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dick begins to methodically unjam the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay.  Don't ever force it. Watch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Dussander mumbles contemptuously and then speaks so Todd can hear him.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get too drunk. We still have a little while.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to do that, you know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander comes back in with his drink and settles into his easy chair, which has been positioned in front of the hearth.</context>
      <utterance>Screw you. I'm doing this for me. This place is freezing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it must be fifty degrees outside. I'm sure to you it seems positively</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It slipped my mind. I will attend to it tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slipped your mind. I noticed it didn't slip your mind to stock up on a new case of bourbon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd finishes with the fire and sits on the floor a few feet away.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, so finish your story, because I'm still not clear. You cook up this stew, and you bring the prisoner in, and you let them smell it, and suddenly they tell you everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't misunderstand me. Certainly with a pistol pressed to their head, a prisoner would tell us everything we wanted to know, sometimes more. But mine was a much more ... elegant method. Remember, it had been months since they had smelled real potatoes simmering over an open flame, and boy, when that delicious odor hit their noses their mouths would drop and out would pour an account of every minor infraction their friends had committed, I mean it was magnificent...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you let them eat the soup?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we never promised them the soup in exchange for information. We never mentioned it at all. Pause. Todd is impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, that's really good, Dussander. I mean that's...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everything all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Becky smiles to herself, unconvinced.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're nervous. I think it's sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... No, I'm cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd just stares at her. He doesn't know what he wants. Becky decides for him. She slides down out of the frame. Todd is startled at first, but lets her. After a moment, he closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Do you want me to do something else?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out in the yard, the large cat emerges from the darkness and moves across the grass. It sees Dussander and, more importantly, the bowl next to him. We see that the bowl is filled with milk.</context>
      <utterance>Here kitty-kitty. Here kitty-kitty.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander sits perfectly still. Cautiously, the cat moves toward the porch.</context>
      <utterance>Come, puss-puss. That's right. I'll wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The cat creeps to the edge of the steps. It takes them one at a time.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, puss-puss. You can smell it now, can't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>After a moment the cat edges up to the bowl. Its tail twitches nervously. Finally, it begins to lick up the milk. Dussander crunches the cigarette out in his empty glass. His movements are slow and patient. From under the blanket he pulls a pair of yellow rubber gloves. He begins to put them on. The cat jumps back for a moment. Dussander freezes. He waits the cat out. Soon the animal is back at the bowl. Dussander continues with the gloves. He watches the cat's tail. As the animal gets comfortable, its tail flips under the rail of the rocking chair. Dussander slams the chair back. The CAT SHRIEKS. Dussander flips the blanket on top of the cat and wraps it into a tight, squirming, HISSING bundle. He stands out of the chair.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, kitty-kitty. That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotcha.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right. Maybe you'll be more in the mood later.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Becky lights a joint. She takes a puff and exhales toward Todd.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. That's never happened before.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you blow that the other way?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you don't like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment it is as though Todd's face were purple with rage. But a moment later the expression is gone. Todd turns away. Becky sees that her comment has hurt him.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you don't like girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She kisses him on the cheek. He nods reluctantly.</context>
      <utterance>That was a lousy thing for me to say. I'm sorry, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move across the room to the stove. With difficulty, Dussander pulls open the oven door, revealing the glowing red interior. The animal SCREAMS and claws at Dussander's neck and arms, escaping more and more from the blanket with every gyration of its body. With a mighty shove Dussander plunges the cat toward the opening, but the animal braces its paws on the edge of the stove. The two are deadlocked. But Dussander's hands are too close to the heat. He screams. His grip loosens just enough. With a desperate cry, the animal charges up Dussander's body, over his head, and leaps to the floor. Dussander dives after it.</context>
      <utterance>Oww, you mother-fucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But the animal is too swift. In a second, it is atop the counter and out the open window above the sink. Although defeated and exhausted, Dussander cannot contain his excitement. His panting gives way to a twisted, hearty laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Come here!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Inside the control room, a SCIENTIST monitors a volt meter, calling out the readings as Dussander yells for the voltage to be increased. As the meter rises, the girl SCREAMS more violently. Perhaps her eyes roll back, her tongue flutters in her mouth. Through all of this, the scientists call out and the record heart rate, blood pressure, brain activity, voltage, etc. Todd's eyes close. His breathing accelerates as does the motion of his hips until...</context>
      <utterance>Subject is a young Jewish girl, approximately sixteen years of age, no scars, no identifying marks, no known disabilities --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Todd loved that dog. A lot more than Dick did.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all loved that dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember when you had to put it down, Todd cried for two weeks. Just about broke my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse, me, Mrs. Bowden. Put it down? I've been here over twenty years but that's a new one.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander still looks puzzled. He looks to Todd, but Victor jumps in.</context>
      <utterance>Means put it to sleep, Victor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very humane.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd shoots him a fiery glare that the others don't notice.</context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some more pie?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As my departed wife used to say, 'One must never overdo the sublime.'</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was delicious, Monica.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, Arthur, if you don't mind me asking. What did you do during the war?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A quick moment between Todd and Dussander.</context>
      <utterance>Now don't get too personal, Victor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander's cigarettes are right in front of him. Todd fetches one and, bringing it to his own lips, lights it for him.</context>
      <utterance>I was a student at the University until my reserve unit was called in 1943.  But we were not a combat unit, thank God. Mechanical engineers. Help me find my cigarettes, Todd. Would you? In those days, not even the call of higher learning could exempt an able body from military service.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Todd Bowden!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear, I do apologize. My hands are too arthritic to strike a match, I'm afraid. Your son has been good enough to help an old man with his filthy habits.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...as long as you don't inhale.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cigarettes are gross, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Victor, you were doing your part like we all were, I suppose. Of course, if you were in the Pacific Fleet I'd have to shoot you. Everyone laughs, except Todd.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad is very proud of the fact that the Bowden men have hit every major conflict since the Civil War.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. Dickie served two tours in Vietnam. Earned a bronze star and a purple heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's one family tradition I'd like to put an end to. Todd and I blow a few caps down at the range every week. That's all the combat he needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps your son would excel in combat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd doesn't answer. His eyes are still on Dick. Dick notices him.</context>
      <utterance>Todd could excel at anything. Right, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Purple Heart. You were injured?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pause. Dick is embarrassed and offended by Todd's stab. He puffs on his cigar. Agnes comes in from the kitchen and picks up some more dishes. Dick stands suddenly to help her.</context>
      <utterance>He was knocked unconscious and woke up in a hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, let me get that for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't be so hard on your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you mind your own business.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, give me a frigging break, will you? Look who's talking to me, for Christ's sake. And what was that crap about the dog? If you were any more charming I was going to puke.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heavens, boy, wasn't that precisely the point? I used the evening to our</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>think there's anybody forcing me to come over to your scuzzy house and watch you slop up booze all day? Do you?</context>
      <utterance>You sure take a lot for granted. Do you</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lower your voice. People will hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander stops.</context>
      <utterance>So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start walking again. Dussander turns up his driveway. Todd follows.</context>
      <utterance>No, nobody forces you to come. In fact, you are welcome to stay away. Believe me, boy, I have no scruples about drinking alone. None at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, if they found out what you are, they'd spit on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander unlocks his door and steps in.</context>
      <utterance>I am sure they would have nothing but revulsion for me. But what would they say about you, boy, when I told them you had known about me for nine months... and said nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come and see me if you please, and stay home if you don't. Good night, boy. He closes the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, open it. Wait, I better pull down the shades, first.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just to be safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To hell with this. You open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd opens the refrigerator and pulls out a can of Coke. Dussander slowly sits back down.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, relax, old man. Sit down and open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to remove the bow, and then the paper. He moves very cautiously, as if the package might explode at any moment. Finally, he removes the lid and his expression shifts from one of fear to one of exasperation.</context>
      <utterance>You wrapped it yourself, I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see that the box contains a replica of an officer's S.S. uniform, complete with hat and jackboots. Dussander reads the label.</context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete's Quality Costume Clothiers - Serving You Since 1976.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, try it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you out of your mind, boy? What makes you think I would put something like that on?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you'd like it --</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like it? My God, you're a bigger fool than I thought. Maybe I'll put it on and do a little shopping downtown. Is that what you thought? You stupid, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't call me stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... You know, you are correct.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should smash you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indignities? What you've suffered with me is nothing compared to what the Israelis would do to you. Remember what happened to Eichmann? You forget that, I think. And, you know, that's my fault. I have let you forget. You have gotten comfortable with this situation. Well, don't you for one minute ever forget who holds the cards here. Don't you ever forget that envelope under my mattress. I tried to do this the nice way, I tried to do something to please you, but you don't want it. So fine, we'll do it the hard way. You will put this on because I want to see you in it. Now strip.</context>
      <utterance>Do it. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you go to hell --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The insignia is all wrong. The boots should be leather, not imitation.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That suit cost me over eighty bucks... with the boots.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this material... what? Polyester?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander ignores him.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet. Straighten that hat.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Straighten that hat, soldier!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander has gotten into a rhythm, marching faster in place.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. March.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander spins sharply on his heels. He continues to march.</context>
      <utterance>About face.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander is stomping in place vigorously. He spins on command, facing Todd. He gives a Nazi salute. Todd watches him march for a moment. At first he enjoys the domination, but as Dussander gets caught up in the marching, Todd's expression changes.</context>
      <utterance>About face.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander is still marching furiously.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, that's enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Suddenly Dussander stops. He collapses into a chair, exhausted. He sits there panting for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I said that's enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy... be careful. You play with fire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd throws up a clumsy shot. It misses.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck if I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're throwing it flat. Let it roll off your fingers more.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd adjusts his grip on the ball anyway. He shoots again. No good.</context>
      <utterance>I don't need a lesson.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd does not respond to his friend's attempt at humor. He is slamming the ball around with great force. He bounces it hard off the back wall to give himself a rebound. He is mumbling to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Your dad, man. I don't know. I mean, I'm a fuck up. My dad is used to this crap from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said something?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're talking to yourself, Bowden. It's not the first time I've noticed it. What is going on with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing, Joey. I fucked up. I'II fix it. I'II fix it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response from Todd.</context>
      <utterance>All right, man. Whatever you say. Look, I got to get to practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joey walks off. Todd continues shooting the ball.</context>
      <utterance>If you need to talk, you can call me. You know that. I'II see you around.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws up a shot. It is good.</context>
      <utterance>You're talking to yourself, Bowden. You're talking to yourself, Bowden.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A strange SQUAWKING sound is heard. Todd doesn't hear it at first, but as the sound grows louder Todd stops the ball and looks around. His eyes focus on the area near an open doorway. Sunlight streams into the empty gym. Todd walks closer, seeing that the sound is coming from an injured bird that has crawled in from outside. He goes up to it. The bird is black. Its wing is damaged. It SQUAWKS loudly, looking up at Todd. Todd begins mumbling again. He starts to dribble the ball thoughtlessly. As his words become clearer, the bouncing gets harder.</context>
      <utterance>I'II fix it. I'II fix it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Todd is bouncing the ball very hard next to him. The bird continues to SCREAM. Slowly the ball drifts from beside Todd to in front of him, gaining force with every bounce. He brings it up to his face and with both hands throws it down with all his might. When it comes back up, it is smeared with blood. He throws it down again, this time it comes up with feathers smeared in the blood. The squawking has stopped. Blood splatters on Todd's shirt. His eyes close. He stops the ball, looks around. No one has seen him. He notices his shirt. Calmly, he tears it off, wraps the ball in it, and tosses it in a nearby trash can.</context>
      <utterance>I'll fix it. I'll fix it. I'll fix it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck happened in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, boy... I burned my TV dinner, I'm afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander's studies Todd for a moment. Although Todd appears calm, his tone reflects a somber, business-like attitude.</context>
      <utterance>Something's come up. Sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd sets his grade card and the envelope on the table. Dussander picks up the grade card and examines it.</context>
      <utterance>I see.  What seems to be the trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You seem to have fallen on the rocks, my boy. One B, three C's and a D. Hardly the work of a "National Merit Scholar," or whatever you call yourself.</context>
      <utterance>Quarterly Progress Report.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't a joke, Dussander. I can't blame this on teachers or honors classes anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you have a problem then.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a problem? You still don't get it. I'm out of excuses. Do you know what's going to happen when my dad sees that? He's going to hit the fucking roof. He'll get it all out of me. The truth, you...everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, it's not my fault your grades have fallen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander throws Todd a dismissive wave. He gets up to get a drink</context>
      <utterance>Don't be so sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, you don't spend that much time here. I hardly think--</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Dussander looks at him oddly, a bit surprised. But then opens the cabinet and pulls out a glass, allowing Todd to continue.</context>
      <utterance>I can't study anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Dear Mr. and Mrs. Bowden, this note is to suggest that we have a group conference concerning Todd's first semester grades. In light of his previous good work in this school, the sudden deterioration in his grades suggest a specific problem which should be addressed before his academic advancement is jeopardized permanently. Such a problem can often be solved by a frank and open discussion. I am ready to work out a time for us to meet. In a case such as this, earlier is usually better. Sincerely yours, Edward French.' Who is this Edward French, the headmaster?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>French? Fuck no. He's a stupid guidance counselor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guidance counselor? What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He guides and he counsels. You read the fucking note. Do you realize I could have to go to summer school? Me, in there with all those fuck-ups. I do not want to go to summer school.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or to the reformatory.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, ...you have a far greater problem than your</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps, perhaps not. It's a gamble. How would you explain all those books you were reading to me? My eyes are not what they were but I can still read fine print. I can prove it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what? I'd say you tricked me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For friendship, because you're lonely and had no one in your life. No jury would take your word over mine. A Nazi? Forget it. Just get it out of your head. You can't threaten me and you can't scare me. What you can do is find me a pencil.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd sets the small paper bag on the table. Dussander opens it and removes a small bottle. The label reads: "ink eradicator." He also removes an x-acto knife and a few sheets of rub-off letters.</context>
      <utterance>A pencil, what for?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd sits down at the table. He takes the bottle from Dussander and examines the report card.</context>
      <utterance>That will take care of the report card, I think. About that fucking letter, I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander pauses. He knows Todd is right. Slowly, he goes to the counter and opens a drawer. He rummages through it as Todd sits with his back to him. Dussander picks out a pencil with an extremely sharp point. He holds it point out and approaches Todd. He gets closer, the point moves in toward the back of Todd's head. He holds the point inches from the boy's neck. He deliberates.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck... come on, a pencil. A sharp one. With an eraser.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd grabs the pencil. Dussander turns toward the window. He thinks for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Will this do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, does this French know your parents in a social way?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Him? Fuck, no. They wouldn't mix with a geek like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about professionally? Has he ever called them before?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I've never needed it. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have an idea. It will require you to make one phone call.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bowden?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a bit of hesitation on French's part, but they shake hands. Dussander notices the shoes on French's feet, bright red converse high-tops.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. French, a pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My, those are some... colorful shoes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To you, sir, I'm sure they seem quite out of the ordinary. But when it is your job to get confused sixteen year-olds to open up to you, you take whatever steps you need. Please have a seat. They both sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the shoes work?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They seem to help, believe it or not. Well, I thank you for coming down, Mr. Bowden, but I'll be frank with you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, please do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fact that you're here and not Todd's parents tells me a great deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander pulls out his cigarettes and then, thinking twice, puts them back.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure. My son and his wife asked me to come in and discuss this sorry business with you, Mr. French. Todd is a good boy, believe me. This trouble with his grades is only temporary.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right.  There's no smoking on school grounds, but if it will make you more comfortable, I'll never tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I suppose I should begin by informing you that my son and my daughter-in-law are having troubles at home. Rather bad troubles, I should think.</context>
      <utterance>A terrible habit, but thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate your candor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mother drinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. The boy has told me that he has come home on two occasions and has found her sprawled out on the kitchen table. He knows how my son feels about her drinking and so on these occasions he has put dinner in the oven himself and forced enough black coffee down his mother's throat so that she will at least be awake when Richard gets home.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's bad. Has Mrs. Bowden thought about getting professional help for her problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boy has tried to persuade her, but she is far too ashamed, I think. If she was given a little time... You understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Your son... Todd's father...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is not without blame, believe me. The hours he works. The meals he has missed. They take a toll on a family. I was raised to believe that a man's family came before his work or anything else. I tried to teach my son that... but --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's only so much we can teach our kids, Mr. Bowden. ...What about Monica's mother or father? Couldn't they talk to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her mother, Sabrina, lives in a nursing home in Florida. I'm afraid after her husband died she lost her will to live.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably not the best person for Monica to speak to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bowden, I don't have to remind you, I'm sure, of Todd's stellar academic record. National Merit Scholar finalist, Academic All-Stars.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I keep his certificates on the wall of my store. I run a small bookstore in San Remo. A hint of skepticism crosses French's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I see that. Anyway, Todd is, and I hate to phrase it this way, but he's one of the ones worth fighting for. He's a special kid, we both know that. But If Todd's grades don't improve drastically and quickly... he'll be opening a real nasty can of worms. Summer school would just be the beginning. His whole college acceptance schedule would be thrown way off course. The good schools won't know what to make of him. I'm sure he'd hate that and so would you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So let's get to the bottom line, shall we? What I'm proposing is some family counselling at the Counselling Center downtown. Everything is in confidence, of course. A man in charge down there, Harry Shumacher, is a good friend of mine. I think Todd and his parents should go see him together. It might be difficult for Todd to go to his parents with this; I think you should do it. Maybe we can get everybody on track by the end of the next quarter. It will be tough, but not impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure that would be the best thing for the boy. The parents might resent him if I took them that proposal right now. Things are very delicate. To swing the scale too far in the wrong direction might cause more harm than good. The boy has promised to work harder in his studies. He is most concerned by the drop in his grades, more alarmed than you might expect. He has his mind set on attending Stanford or Berkeley next fall and does not wish to see his plans altered.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, well --</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also, the parents would resent me. Monica already thinks I meddle too much in her affairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a great deal of experience in these matters, Mr. Bowden. And please understand that my interest in your son's marital problems begins and ends with the effect they are having on Todd. And right now I think they are having quite an effect. I really think counselling is in order here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allow me to make a counter proposal. You have, I believe, a system for warning parents of poor grades?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Interpretation of Progress cards. IOP cards. The kids call them flunk card. They only get them when their grades in a class fall below the seventy percent. That means a "D" or an "F". Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they are sent out when?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mid-quarter. That's about three weeks into the new marking period.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allowing for Christmas break, the next time they are sent out will be in late January, correct?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Then what I suggest is this...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told him you were getting back on track by your own accord. I gave him my word. If you get even one flunk card--</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you out of your fucking mind? I'm going to get three or four flunk cards. I failed an economics test today, so there's another one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, it was the best I could do without arousing suspicion.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could have done better myself --</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you didn't, did you? This is the way it is and now you are upset because the only way you can make things right is to work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can. And it will. You will work.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't take orders from you. Maybe you've forgotten --</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a done deal, boy. If you don't like it, you can discuss it at family counselling.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God! I wish... I wish --</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd is furious. He sees there is no other way, but continues fighting.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind your wishes. Your wishes make me sick. All I want to hear is that you understand the situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you gotta believe me. There is no way in hell that I can pull myself out of a half year slide in a couple of weeks. I wish I could, but we're just going to have to think of something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, the time for discussion is over. This is the way it is. You are going to work. And I am going to be right here with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their clothes tumble off around them.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He slides off her and opens the drawer by his bed. He pulls out a condom. By now she is naked. Todd slips out of his underwear and falls on top of her. The RADIO plays in the b.g. as Todd begins to grind away with his hips. She moans softly with delight. The CAMERA MOVES off of them to reveal a man in a lab coat setting up a volt meter. This is one of the scientists from Todd's laboratory nightmare. The CAMERA continues TO PAN across the bedroom, showing the other scientists preparing for the electricity experiment. The CAMERA STOPS on Dussander, clipboard in hand, observing everything carefully. Todd releases with a final thrust. Becky is MOANING in a series of high, fast yelps. Todd lies still on her body. Becky is speechless, still quivering from the unusually intense love making.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd gets up and tries to free his bike, but the mud and water do not make the job easy. He is almost finished when a gruff voice catches his attention.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Todd looks up and sees a figure moving toward him in the shadows of the tunnel. Todd quickly pulls out a pocket knife. He flicks open the blade and hides it behind his leg.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, kid, you having some trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure steps closer. The light catches his face to reveal Archie. He is an unshaven, filthy mess, and when he speaks his words are slurred from years of steady drinking.</context>
      <utterance>No. I got it... thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd eyes the man cautiously. He looks around. No one is nearby. The constant din of the rain echoes within the confines of the tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>That case maybe you could loan me a dollar. Help out a Vietnam vet? How 'bout it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd palms the knife out of sight and slowly approaches the bum.</context>
      <utterance>I... I don't know... I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, you got something for me. I know you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd's hands go into his pockets. He stops a few feet from the bum.</context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe... I have to check.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd moves closer. Close enough to touch the bum.</context>
      <utterance>See, I got to get up to L.A. Got a job waiting for me up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bum looks at him hopefully. Todd looks back at him, sizing him up, really noticing him for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I did have a couple of quarters...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(his voice drops) For a dollar I'll give you a blow job. Take you right up there where it's still dry. You never had so good, kid. You'll come your brains out. Todd freezes for a moment. The bum is right in his face. Suddenly Todd throws a handful of change at the bum and sprints back to his bike. He hops on and is gone in a flash, leaving the bum there to pick up the scattered coins. As Todd zips away, the hood is off his head. The rain begins to beat away the splattered mud from his face.</context>
      <utterance>You know,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander gets up and goes to the refrigerator.</context>
      <utterance>Well, this calls for a celebration, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I guess I owe a lot of this to you. I'm not proud of it, but it's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your gratitude humbles me.  How about some Ritz crackers and Velveeta?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander goes about his task, taking items from the cabinets, etc. Todd watches all of this intently, but without expression.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, what the hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would have expected you to be doing back flips down the hallway after such good news. You are so quiet. Todd does not respond.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today, I think, I give you the day off from studying. How's that? How about one of my stories instead? I still have a few good ones saved up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd is wringing his hand together nervously under the table. Dussander places a box of crackers on the table and goes back to the counter.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care. Whatever you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see. I could tell you about the special soap we made. Or there is always the story of how I escaped from Berlin after I was foolish enough to go back. That was a close one, I promise you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander slices open a pack of Velveeta and puts it on a plate.</context>
      <utterance>No, none of these I think. You don't seem to be in the mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He puts a glass of Coke in front of Todd and goes back to the counter. He opens a drawer, takes something out, closes it.</context>
      <utterance>I think today I will tell you the story of an old man who was afraid. He was afraid of a certain young boy who was, in a queer way, his friend. The boy proved to be a very good student, but perhaps not in the way his mother or his teachers had envisioned. At first the old man disliked the boy intensely, but then he grew to... to enjoy the boy's company. Of course, there was still a great deal of distrust between them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander goes to the cellar door. His back is to Todd. He opens the door and clicks on the light. Todd stands up silently.</context>
      <utterance>Each knew something that other wanted to keep secret. But over time, the old man began to feel that things were changing. He felt his hold on the boy slipping away from him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Todd has moved across the floor, careful not to let the floor creak under his steps. He is right upon Dussander. Dussander reaches out with one arm for a fresh bottle, grasping onto the railing with the other. His body hangs over the steep staircase.</context>
      <utterance>So. One sleepless night the old man got out of bed and wrote down the story of his involvement with the boy. Everything he could remember, from the first day forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He gets his balance again and turns to face Todd. Dussander holds the kitchen knife he was using earlier down at his side where Todd can see it. A tense silence passes between them. Todd is frozen. Dussander steps past him and back into the kitchen. He closes the cellar door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>When he finished his hand was stinging from arthritis but he felt good for the first time in weeks. He felt safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander sits back in his chair, cutting the seal on the fresh bottle.</context>
      <utterance>He climbed back into bed and slept until it was time for General Hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Todd sinks into a chair across from Dussander and takes a sip of Coke.</context>
      <utterance>On the following day the old man put on his best suit and went down to one of the local banks and rented a safety deposit box. The bank officer explained to the old man that he would have a key and the bank would have a key. To open the box both keys would be needed. No one but the old man could use the old man's key without a signed, notarized letter of permission from the old man himself. With one exception.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That exception is made in the event of the box-holder's death.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd understands what the old man has told him. He slams his glass down on the table and jumps out of his chair.</context>
      <utterance>Then the box is opened in the presence of a bank official and a representative of the Internal Revenue Service. The contents of the box are inventoried. In this case they will find only a twelve-page document. Non- taxable... but highly interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't... you can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My boy, it is already done.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd stares at Dussander in disbelief. After a moment he storms out the back door to the porch.</context>
      <utterance>But... Christ! Look at you. You could go at any time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then there is nothing for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there is. As the years go by, as I get closer to the grave, your hold on me will become worth less and less. A man five, ten years older than I worries more about his ailing heart than being extradited to Israel. And there will come a day - if I live long enough - when I decide what you know no longer matters. Then, and only then, I will destroy my document.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>sing softly, then gets caught up in the song... Todd turns away, angry.</context>
      <utterance>But... but so many things can happen to you in between. Accidents. Sickness. You could slip in the shower, for Christ's sake... Dussander shrugs and lights another cigarette. He begins to</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Dussander sees he has pressed Todd's button. He moves closer.</context>
      <utterance>Que sera, sera... Whatever will be, will be... The future's not ours to see... Que sera, sera...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander speaks with a near whisper in Todd's ear.</context>
      <utterance>My dear boy, I see you thinking about it, even now. It is in your eyes. Killing me. It would take only a flick of a knife. Or maybe push me down the steps, make it look like an accident? I am old. You are strong. You are angry. Good assets for killing. But there is something missing...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>There is a long pregnant pause. Then Todd lets out a sigh, as if to dismiss what he has just heard. He turns to face Dussander.</context>
      <utterance>To have some one in your control. To have them know that they are alive because you have not decided to the contrary. Do you have that power? Ask yourself. It is no easy question. I think you know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know this means we're through. You won't be seeing me around here anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I suppose I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm never coming here again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander pours a splash of bourbon into the boy's glass.</context>
      <utterance>And so it comes to an end. Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd picks up his glass.</context>
      <utterance>A drink. To our lives together, the beginning... and the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He CLICKS his glass against Dussander's.</context>
      <utterance>I think you should fuck yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My boy, don't you see that we are fucking each other? He drinks. Todd, reluctantly, does the same.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander is like stone, flashing the eyes of a man who is not to be harassed. Finally...</context>
      <utterance>Little blond-hair boy. ...What's the matter, you ain't his friend no more?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander stands, slightly rattled only to those who know him well. He looks down the street for the bus. Archie doesn't move. Rather, he inspects Dussander from head to toe, stopping on the shoes.</context>
      <utterance>You mistake me for somebody else. ...Pardon me, my bus is coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SQUEAL of brakes grows louder as the bus comes to rest in front of Dussander. He has become perceptibly more nervous as he waits for the passengers to exit. He climbs up the first step.</context>
      <utterance>Damn... Cuban high heels. Nice ones, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door closes behind Dussander. The bus pulls away. Through the window of the bus Dussander watches Archie as he continues his speech to no one.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't seen a pair like that since I was in Havana.  That's the only place you can get'em. Can't get'em exported... Government don't let you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd does as Morgan pours over Todd's files.</context>
      <utterance>Have a seat, Todd.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see from your record and from what Mr. French tells me that after a minor slip up last semester you're right back on course. Straight A's for the quarter so far. And I hear your little slip didn't bother the folks up at Stanford too much either.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A good break for you, Todd.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like that little talk with your...  grandfather... really helped. Well, we don't want to keep you too long.  You tell him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it seems Sally Chong didn't do to well in A.P. biology.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She failed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid so. She refused to take part in the fetal pig dissection. The teacher begged her to drop the class, but Sally thought she could pass anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stubborn girl... What we're telling you, son, is that because Sally Chang -</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chong.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because Sally Chong wouldn't hack up a baby pig, you snuck by her in the rankings. So if you can keep your grades up for two more months -- any reason that shouldn't happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Congratulations.</context>
      <utterance>Then you'll make valedictorian, Todd.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>French shakes Todd's hand, an uneasy moment passes between the two of them.</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations, Todd.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Todd, you really should be proud of yourself. To tell you the truth, I'm amazed you pulled it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was glad to hear you made varsity baseball. I spoke to the coach. He says your coming along real well.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's turning out to be a good year for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to go, but French stops him again.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps up to Todd and lowers his voice, as if he were hedging a touchy subject.</context>
      <utterance>Todd, wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Todd, you've got a lot of good things going on right now. You should be enjoying yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>French's looks says, "No, you're not."</context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd realizes he is not going to get out of this easily.</context>
      <utterance>How are things at home?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, things with my parents were bad for a while. But they're doing a lot better. Thanks for your concern, really. I should get back to class. He is pulling away from French as he speaks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Todd. I know this isn't the place to talk about this. But my door is always open...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd walks away.</context>
      <utterance>I know. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Todd does not turn around. French stares after him. The BELL RINGS, and Todd is swallowed by the stream of students emerging from the class rooms.</context>
      <utterance>And it's going to stay open.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd looks up. He seems pleasant, but there is little warmth in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>Hey there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. They look at each other. Joey wants to talk. Todd slips the chain lock into a pocket on his backpack. Joey jingles his car keys anxiously.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... ah, I heard about Stanford. I heard a couple of weeks ago actually. ...Congrats.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey shrugs. It's an awkward moment. He walks closer.</context>
      <utterance>I got into school to. Long Beach. It's no Stanford, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no... that's good, Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey reaches for Todd's backpack. He lifts it. The heaviness puzzles him. Todd takes it from him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, ...I just wanted to say hi. Here let me get that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Todd stares at him stone-faced. Joey doesn't like Todd's expression. Todd takes the bag from him and puts it on.</context>
      <utterance>What do you have in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You busy now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come with me. Hop on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hop on? I have a car now, Todd.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't drive where we're going.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is so cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Point it over here. That's the middle school. You can see right into our old class room.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hunting rifle, disassembled, sticks out of Todd's backpack on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah... But I still don't see what you need the rest of it for. Doesn't your Dad notice?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hasn't yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is trying to joke, but the seriousness is clearly in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>Yet?... Jesus, Todd.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey isn't looking through the scope anymore. He holds it out to Todd, watching him.</context>
      <utterance>And over here, that's your dad's office. And there's the old drive-in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd grabs the scope. But Joey doesn't let go. He finally locks Todd in a stare that he has been avoiding for months. He wants to say something. Todd takes the scope. He sees that Joey is serious. He takes a few steps toward the edge, toward the gun. He looks out.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks through the scope at the freeway. He picks out passing cars.</context>
      <utterance>It's such a rush, you know?... To be up here. Don't you feel it? So high above them they never know we're here. It's like an ant farm. We're the gods on Mt. Olympus, Joey. They can't see us, they can't hear us, but every so often we can make them feel us. Just so they never forget. Look...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joey takes a few steps backward. Todd doesn't notice.</context>
      <utterance>There goes a future track star. There goes a judge. A mom and her two kids. A policeman. That one's a school teacher, that one's a drug dealer... You see, Joey, it doesn't matter. It doesn't matter how smart you are ...or how many grades you skip. There's always someone who can take it all away. The right person snaps their fingers... and it's done.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd turns his head toward Joey, but it is as though no one is there. He looks away again.</context>
      <utterance>Todd, I'm gonna go. I'm gonna... walk home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Pause. Todd looks again. But this time Joey is really gone. A slight chuckle escapes Todd's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Todd...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can do that. I can help you carry those. Dussander jumps back. Archie stops.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander does not move. But slowly his face changes and we realize that he remembers Archie from the bus stop.</context>
      <utterance>You don't gotta be afraid. I can carry those.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts off again. Archie follows.</context>
      <utterance>I don't need any help. ...Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I ain't a bad guy. You don't gotta worry. I'm a veteran. I just want--</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a nice face.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, we're practically neighbors. I stay right over there most nights.  I see you walking down the street. I come up to help. It's called being</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander looks up and down the street. No one is around.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't no reason to be rude. You see, I know something about you. ...I know your a nice guy. I'm nice too, ...just like the kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I know you got some bourbon in these bags. I ain't ashamed to say I could use a drink about now. But I don't need no charity. If you want to invite me in, like a friend, we could have a nice drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You smell like a toilet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you let me use your shower. But first a drink. After that I'll do anything you say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, this is nice. Real nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander moves toward the kitchen. Archie watches him walk away. A smile crosses his face as he follows him to the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Let me take those.  Right this way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess your parents don't need a graduation announcement.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grandma and Grandpa aren't coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you told him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, I forgot. Todd, my aunt Patty, Dad's sister, died on Wednesday. Mom and Dad have to drive up to Fresno to settle her estate. We can't ask Dad to drive six hours each way for graduation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we ask them, they'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why. You understand, don't you, Todd? Todd thinks for a moment, realizes something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, Dad. It's all right. Tell Grandpa I'll spend the week with him and Grandma when they get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Mr. Denker? I almost forgot about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, He won't want to come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander picks up his glass to toast Archie. Archie CLINKS his glass to Dussander's and downs the shot.</context>
      <utterance>Ah-ah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe we need another bottle, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander goes to the cellar door to retrieve another bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Well if you're offering, I'm accepting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander pulls something out of a drawer. He goes to the table and stands right behind Archie.</context>
      <utterance>No trouble at all. Now where is my bottle opener? Ah, here it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Archie picks up the glass and begins to drink, slower this time. Dussander pulls Archie's tattered hat off his head and sets it on the table. He then begins to stroke the matted knots of Archie's hair.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you drink mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't mind do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I don't mind. ...Maybe in the morning - everything goes okay - you could let me have ten dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe even twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps. We shall see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can relax, you know, I've done this before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander raises a meat fork up to the back of Archie's neck. He starts to plunge it in just as Archie turns back to look at him. The fork goes in crooked. Archie explodes from the chair, HOWLING, his arms flailing like those of a grizzly bear. With the fork protruding from his back, Archie tosses the table to the side. The empty bottle tumbles to the middle of the floor and shatters. Archie spins and slams a fist into Dussander's temple. Dussander collapses against the counter. Archie moves about wildly, trying to grab the fork and pummel Dussander at the same time. Blood is streaming freely from his wound. Dussander grabs a frying pan from a rack of drying dishes on the counter. As Archie approaches, Dussander swings the pan into Archie's descending fist. Archie winces and staggers backward. He stomps down on the broken bottle and screams. His guard falls briefly. Dussander is upon him. He swings the pan, catching Archie squarely in the face. Archie brings his hands up to his face, which now oozes with blood. Blinded by the blow, Archie charges Dussander, who crouches to the side, and as Archie passes, hurls himself into the man's back, sending him through the open door of the cellar. Archie flies down the stairs face-first, tumbling into the packed dirt floor like a derailed train. Dussander, exhausted and bloodied, exhales deeply. Looking down at the crumpled body below, he straightens his tie, brushes the hair from his face, and then surveys the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right. So have I.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He rises slowly and brushes himself off before heading down the steps to finish the bum for good. After about three steps he stops abruptly. He appears puzzled, but after a moment the expression changes. A look of searing pain rushes across his face. Dussander brings his hand to his chest. He collapses on the stairs. He is having a heart attack and knows it.</context>
      <utterance>What a mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks down at Archie, up to the kitchen, then back down to the cellar. A moment of decision. The stairs appear ten times longer in each direction than they did a minute ago. Getting to his feet, he turns slowly toward the kitchen. He starts up the steps at a painfully slow pace, counting with each step.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ein... Zwei... Drei...</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monica... how long did we rent those jet skis in Hawaii?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About two hours. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This receipt says we had two jet skis for twenty-three hours a piece. The bill is fifteen hundred dollars. Didn't you look at the receipt before you signed it? Todd doesn't look up from his textbook.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Way to go, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That bill was written in Japanese. I told you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Numbers are numbers, Monica, in any language.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy didn't speak a word of English. I told you not to rent from him. The PHONE RINGS. Monica gets up to get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not the point. You should always read the bill before you sign. I've told you that a hundred times.  Fifteen hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Dick looks at the bill.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's in yen.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monica comes back into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, maybe you're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd rises from the couch. His mood shifts instantly.</context>
      <utterance>Todd, it's Mr. Denker. He sounds excited about something. You better speak to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT: between Todd in his living room and...</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Denker?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come over right away, boy. I'm having a heart attack, a bad one, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, that sounds exciting, Mr. Denker, but I was studying for my trig final --</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand that you cannot talk, but you can listen. I cannot call 911... at least not yet. There is quite a mess here. I need help... and that means you need help.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well if you put it that way --</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell your parents I've had a letter, an important letter, and I need you to read it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure. I'll be right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander hangs up the phone and falls into a chair.</context>
      <utterance>Now we see what you are made of, boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye.  I've got to run over to Mr. Denker's for a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everything all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he just got a letter from a nephew in Hamburg or Dusseldorf or one of those places.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought his family was killed in the war. Todd zips up his jacket.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So did he. That's why he sounded excited. I shouldn't be too long. I'll take your car, Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, you have a final tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I was almost finished studying anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be gone too long, Todd.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses Monica on the cheek. He is out the front door.</context>
      <utterance>See you in a bit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd moves to the center of the room, careful not to step in any blood. He doesn't know what to do. His attention falls on Dussander. Suddenly he rushes to him and begins to inspect his body carefully.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck...?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander does not respond. Todd shakes him harder.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you bleeding?... wake up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander stirs a little, aggravated.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up, goddamnit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>It's not my blood, for Christ's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was self-defense, boy. Go downstairs. You'll see what needs to be done. Dussander points to the open cellar door.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander only stares back at him, then looks away, almost smiling through his incredible pain, as if to challenge Todd.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you. I'm not going down there. What happened? What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander does not respond. Todd stares at him for a moment, then moves toward the cellar.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander shoves his chair under the doorknob. He drags the table against the door as he speaks. Todd is screaming on the other side and begins to kick at the door violently.</context>
      <utterance>Open the fucking door! Right now. Right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You give me no choice, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? Open the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you won't help me, then I'll make you help me. If you don't, we are finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd pounds awayat the door. Tears now stream down his cheeks. His relentless pounding has Dussander enraged. Dussander pounds back at the door to shut Todd up. It works.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, old man. This is your problem. I didn't do this. Open the door!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A surge of pain from his chest silences him. He recovers, speaking slowly and deliberately.</context>
      <utterance>Enough. Enough. Enough! If you don't stop screaming like a fucking school girl I'm going to...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now listen to me, boy, very carefully. If you don't help me, I'm going to die here. And if I die, there is no Stanford for you. There is no scholarship. There is jail. My document...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck your document. I got nothing to do with this. Don't make it sound like I do. I came here, I saw this shit, and now I'm getting the fuck out of here. That's what I'm gonna tell the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not tell them the truth? Tell them I locked you in the cellar. Tell them I wouldn't let you out until you buried the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not listening to this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be at the window, yes? As you can see I had it barred a few years ago. A bad element started to move into the neighborhood, you know how it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are wasting time now, boy.  Come back to the door. You are not going to find anything down there to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd runs toward the staircase and is only a few feet from Archie when he sees him. Todd, mortified, lets out a scream. This startles Archie, who cannot speak. He only gurgles a SICKENING WHINE, the fork still sticks out of his neck. Blood drips into his eyes from a gash above his forehead. Yet even on his knees, he is an imposing figure.</context>
      <utterance>Oh really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Archie is too disoriented to move. Summoning all his courage, Todd pokes the shovel into him, as if to prod him out of the way. But when the blade of the shovel touches him, Archie counters violently, grabbing the metal end and swinging it to the side. Todd holds tightly to the handle, an act which sends him flying across the cellar. The shovel stays with Archie, and now he wields it like it were a child's toy. He slashes it viciously through the air. Todd hides under the stairs, watching Archie duel with the shadows. Todd bumps into something. Archie hears him. Through the slats in the staircase we see Archie jabbing the shovel at Todd.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it! Stop it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fed up, he comes around from under the stairs and confronts Archie. Archie sees him and takes a step toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Archie steps closer. Instantly, Todd tightens his grip on the shovel. He is no longer afraid. He swings the shovel at Archie's head striking him. Archie staggers back, stunned, but then charges forward. Todd strikes him again, this time with more force and anger. Todd lifts the shovel to strike again, but this time catches the ceiling light with the metal blade. The glass shatters. The room goes black. A second later we HEAR a SHARP, authoritative BLOW, followed quickly by another, then another.</context>
      <utterance>I mean it get the fuck away from me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander points to the cabinet under the sink. Todd throws the door open and pulls out bottles of cleaner.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the fucking pinesol?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rags. I need rags.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd checks the clock, it is 9:25. He gets the bottle and a bucket and goes for the cellar.</context>
      <utterance>Cellar. Under the stairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ought to run this through your chest, you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It couldn't hurt more than a heart attack. He looks at the clock - 10:15.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, my parents are going to freak.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd dries the murder weapon and puts it away. For a moment he slows down, a hint of a smile suddenly comes over him. Dussander sees something is different about him.</context>
      <utterance>Stay calm, boy. You are doing fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The sound of Dussander's voice snaps Todd out of his funk. He is all business again.</context>
      <utterance>What are you thinking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd takes off Dussander's shoes and balls them up in the tattered suit.</context>
      <utterance>Your pants are okay. The shoes... no.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He holds up Dussander's bathrobe. The old man slips into it with difficulty as Todd dumps the bloodied clothing into a trash bag. Dussander looks at Todd's T-shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Put this on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that my undershirt?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up, for God's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd puts the mop away. He surveys the room as before. Dussander does the same. There is a strange silence as the two of them look around the room for anything damning.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you die on me, you old bastard. Not now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we're okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd turns to face Dussander. He brings his face up to his and speaks softly.</context>
      <utterance>Call an ambulance.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The key.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The safety deposit box. I want the key...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For God's sake, boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want the key and I want to know where the bank is. Dussander cannot argue.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hillcrest Savings on Domingo Avenue. The key is behind the clock on the mantle piece.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sign this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander starts to scrawl his name across the paper.</context>
      <utterance>Sign it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! At the bottom...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd nearly bites his lip in half. Dussander notices the slip and cringes.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's my friend, Mr. Du--</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Denker. He had a heart attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he conscious?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he's awake. I'm really scared. The address is 9 --</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have the address here. The ambulance is on the way. It should take about ten minutes. I'll stay on the line with you --</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I have to call my parents. Just send the ambulance -- He hangs up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Todd sees a pack of cigarettes on the table.</context>
      <utterance>It smells too clean in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander is not amused. Todd lights two cigarettes and lets them burn down in the ashtray. He picks up the phone again and dials.</context>
      <utterance>Cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy, it's me. Let me talk to Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just let me talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on --</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Todd, what's wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Denker had a heart attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Is he conscious?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he's awake.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God. Todd, call an ambulance.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. They're on the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, son. Don't touch him. I'll be there in five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up. He sits down across from Dussander. The old man is near death, but through the slit of an eye he watches Todd. The stare between them is lethal. For a long moment this continues until...</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The letter. Where is the goddamn letter? I told my parents I came over to read you a letter from Germany.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A letter. Yes, we'll say it's from Willi Frankel --</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need a letter. I told them it was your nephew, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My bedroom. Look in the dresser. Second, no third, drawer... from the top. There is a small wooden box. You will have to break it open. I lost the key. There are letters, very old ones. From a friend. All in German. None of them are signed or dated. A page or two will be fine. Todd turns to go and stops.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy? I don't read German, you numb fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would Willi write me in English? If you were to read me the letter in German, I would understand even though you would not. Your pronunciation would be terrible, but I could manage --</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd dashes out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>All right. All right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd doesn't like Dick's apprehension. He grabs his father's hand and leads him out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>You did real good, son.  You did real good...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon. Let's make sure he gets checked in all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David approaches the gurney. Lying prone is BEN KRAUSS, 70. David kisses him on the forehead.</context>
      <utterance>He needs to rest now. You can come back tomorrow after ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be back in the morning with the girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The orderlies lift Ben onto his bed.</context>
      <utterance>I can't wait to see them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doctor will be in to see you in a few minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The orderlies, the nurse and David leave the room. Ben notices his roommate in the next bed. It is Dussander, who has been watching all of this quietly.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander smiles politely.</context>
      <utterance>My nephew, David.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His parents died when he was very young. He is like a son to me. I have no children of my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David is very protective of me. Of course, I don't mind. I enjoy his company. A few years ago he started working with me at the university. I teach chemistry. My name is Ben, by the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arthur.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pleasure, Arthur. What do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>I'm retired.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These tubes in my arm. No one said they would itch like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben looks oddly at Dussander. The wheels of his memory slowly, very slowly, begin to turn.</context>
      <utterance>You will find, in time, you don't notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we'll see. Looks like I'll be here for a while. I didn't want to alarm my nephew just yet, but this break in my leg... well, we'll see what the doctor says.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>forgive me, my medication has made me drowsy. Do not be offended if I fall asleep.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course. But for now, you must</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Ben's words are lost on a sleeping man. He continues to stare at Dussander.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be offended if I keep talking anyway. It beats wondering if I'm ever going to walk again. I tell you, my friend, the ways of God are not meant to be understood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd is aware that Ben is listening, even though he is pretending not to. Todd goes to put the flowers in a glass of water. He sets the glass on the table by the bed.</context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't have.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits in the chair by the bed and lowers his voice.</context>
      <utterance>They're from my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He flicks a tattered photo onto the bed. We recognize it as one from the safety deposit box. It is a black and white portrait of a woman and a small boy.</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dussander grins weekly.</context>
      <utterance>Everything else I burned.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd drags a screen over to prevent Ben from hearing. Long pause.</context>
      <utterance>I had to protect myself from you, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suspect that we shall never see each other again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander looks almost hurt to hear Todd say it. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't think we will.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I better go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, boy... There is something I want to ask you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander waves him over with his finger. Reluctantly, Todd brings his ear an inch from Dussander's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd pulls his head back, stands up. He contemplates the question, ...confessing. He touches Dussander on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>...Was it like you thought?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns for the door.</context>
      <utterance>I should go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd resigns himself to stay. He picks up a magazine and begins to read, not even looking at Dussander.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps... perhaps I could persuade you to wait here just until I fall asleep. This medicine makes me quite woozy... please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd is startled.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, young man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a fine boy to visit your grandfather like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. But he's just a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right? Well, you are a good friend to him. Tell me, is he bad off? He doesn't talk much.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doctors say he'll be out soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd is starting to be wary of where this is going.</context>
      <utterance>That is good news, indeed. Tell me, from the way he speaks I'd guess he's been naturalized, like me. Is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's from Germany... From Essen. Do you know that town?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was only in Germany once. I'm Polish. Originally, I mean, I'm from Radom. I wonder if he was in the war.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really couldn't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter, I suppose. It was a long time ago, the war. Soon in this country we may have a president born after the war was over. How about that? Todd starts to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend is lucky to have you. A great man once said, 'No man is an island entire of itself.'</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd heads for the door. He stops, turns back to Dussander's bed. He contemplates something... waking him. He decides against it.</context>
      <utterance>John Donne. Take care, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good-bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd exits. Ben sits quietly for a moment, thinking. He turns on the television-- "The Price is Right". We hear it over the following. Ben glances over at the screen which separates him from Dussander. Slowly his eyelids begin to get heavy. He starts to nod off. But as sleep begins to envelope him, his eyes suddenly fly open. A surge of terror burns across his face. He sits up frightened. A single crutch stands next to the bed. He grabs it. He strips away his covers and the restraints on his leg, once or twice shoving his hand over his mouth to quell a painful scream. He gets to his feet awkwardly, hobbling, half-dragging his bad leg. Every step he takes is a study in agony. ANGLE on the screen. It slides out of the way, revealing Ben staring down at the sleeping Dussander. In the pained struggle to keep silent, he brings his face right up to Dussander's, close enough to smell his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Good-bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the nurse?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darren finishes with the IV unit and goes to the door. Dussander watches him, a bit puzzled, but his eyes are closed again before Darren is out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Darren. I'll be taking care of you from now on. I'll tell the doctor you've woken up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you need something?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is going on here? Where is Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Krauss has been moved. I'm going to give you something. It will help you sleep. Darren readies Dussander's arm for an injection.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Dussander can protest, Darren sticks him with the needle.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want it. Who is that man?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your surgery was a success. Just try to relax.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weiskopf sits on the edge of the bed. Dussander notices the pin on his lapel. A small, silver Star of David.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course, but you seem to have me confused with someone else. My name is Arthur Denker. Perhaps you want a different room --</utterance>
   <speaker>WEISKOPF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Weiskopf. You are Kurt Dussander.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dussander reaches for the Call button and stops in horror. He looks at his hands. His fingertips are smeared with black ink. He looks up at the men in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>I know no one by that name. Shall I ring for the nurse?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEISKOPF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man in the next bed was Benjamin Krauss. He was imprisoned for ten months at Patin. You were responsible for the death of his wife and two daughters. His identification of you was quite specific. I'm sure his reward from my government will help offset the burden of his broken leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Arthur Denker. I am an American--</utterance>
   <speaker>WEISKOPF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The detective, GETTY, snaps a few pictures of Dussander. The other man is FBI Special Agent DAN RICHLER.</context>
      <utterance>Please don't bother. Your papers will not stand up to serious examination and you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have all we need here, Isaac.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSSANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you men? What are your names?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Richler, FBI. This is Detective Getty from the Orange County Sheriff's Department.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEISKOPF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I think you know who I work for. When you get your strength back, you will be moved. Until then, this entire ward will be under surveillance. You can expect to be in Tel Aviv by the end of the summer. The three men are out the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The road ahead reveals itself, uh, God, no. The road ahead... grrrr, The fucking road ahead. Monica appears in the doorway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd doesn't notice her. He stares down at the card. Finally he looks up, as if it took her voice a few seconds to register in his mind. His response is hardly audible.</context>
      <utterance>Todd?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing there in the dark?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monica reaches in to his room to turn on the light. She touches the switch but then pulls her hand back. Todd is back at the note card. She looks at him oddly, worried, but then steps away from the door and goes downstairs. Todd's lips are moving, as if he were speaking to himself. He pauses. Then, in a sudden gust of inspiration begins to write furiously. He finishes and stands up, catching his reflection in the mirror above his desk. In the eerie half-light, he stares at the ghost-like image of himself.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, ...working.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. French.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands. French sees Dick and Monica sitting behind Todd. Before Todd can stop him, he introduces himself.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Todd. It's your big day, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dick and Monica are the picture of happiness, hardly the dysfunctional drunkards that French believed them to be. They all shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>These must be your parents.  Hi, Ed French. It's good to finally meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dick Bowden, nice to meet you. This is my wife, Monica.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>French is a bit puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Are you one of Todd's teachers?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WOMAN behind Monica taps her on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm his guidance counsellor.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monica turns away from French. Suddenly, the band strikes up opening notes to "Pomp and Circumstance."</context>
      <utterance>Monica, I thought that was you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's our cue.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was nice meeting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You too.  Good luck, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd and French dash off in different directions.</context>
      <utterance>I'll talk to you and your wife after the ceremony.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is polite applause from the audience as she takes her seat and Morgan goes to the podium.</context>
      <utterance>Thy sacred emblems to partake - Thy consecrated bread to take And thine immortal wine!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. More applause.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Miss Little for that superb invocation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Todd's eyes scan the crowd indifferently. He notices Becky, seated in the audience near some friends.</context>
      <utterance>And now it gives me great pleasure to introduce a young man who's academic achievement at this institution stands as testament to the power of hard work and determination. Todd had a tough time a few months ago, so by God, he buckled down, hit the books, and pulled himself through it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen, students and faculty, here to deliver the student remembrance for the class of 1985, this year's valedictorian, Todd Bowden. The crowd burst into applause.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We learn from our education that we are the master's of our own destinies. We learn what it is that separates us from the others, why we are special.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEISKOPF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Detective Getty comes in.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. All photographs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>They are Victor and Agnes Bowden, looking for Dick and Monica. Todd sees them too. He pauses almost imperceptibly. He looks back at French.</context>
      <utterance>We forge our own paths. Our education is but a stepping stone to the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Todd's grandparents come down the aisle to see Dick and Monica in the second row. They start to slide in, causing a slight ruckus. Dick is surprised to see his parents, but smiles and makes room for them. French watches all of this curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Our.. Our true destinies await us. There we become the...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A connection is made between French, Todd, and the Bowden family.</context>
      <utterance>There we become the men and women that will make a difference. But we must take away from this place a sense of purpose for ourselves. We now begin to see the road ahead. It is a road from which we cannot veer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd cheers as the graduates throw their caps into the air. The band begins to play.</context>
      <utterance>Andrew Woodman... Donald Young... Karmisha Youngblood... David Zedek... Kyle Zuckerman. The graduating class of 1985.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Todd, still pale, bolts off the stage. He reaches his parents. French starts to walk down to the Bowdens. Todd goes up to his mother.</context>
      <utterance>Now we invite all the friends and parents to join the students and faculty in the main courtyard for refreshments.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, I don't feel so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I feel like I'm going to pass out. Can we go home?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd ignores her.</context>
      <utterance>You looked real good up there, Todd.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to see your buddies?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd and his family start off. As they leave the CAMERA MOVES to show Ed French working his way through the crowd past the spot where they had been standing.</context>
      <utterance>I want to go, Dad. Right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Todd, my name is Dan Richler. I'm a special agent with the FBI. This is my associate, Dr. Weiskopf.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEISKOPF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of doctor are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEISKOPF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a school teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Weiskopf is a professor at the Judaic Institute in Munich. He is assisting the Israeli government in certain matters. He is here today, only as an observer. A moment passes between Weiskopf and Todd.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for calling us up, Mr. Bowden. You saved us the trouble of tracking through the 911 records.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, it was Todd's idea to call. He thought... we thought there might be some way we could help your investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Todd, if you wouldn't mind, I'd like to hear about your involvement with Dussander... but you knew him as Arthur Denker, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I never knew of that other name till I saw it in the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd starts to rub his stomach.</context>
      <utterance>How did you know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up before Richler can answer walks toward the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I met him at the movies. Last summer. ...He asked me where to pick up the number seven bus. He said his eyes weren't too good. ...Will you excuse me for a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He vanishes up the stairs. They all watch him go. Monica turns to Richler.</context>
      <utterance>I just gotta use the bathroom. I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Dick.</context>
      <utterance>He's not feeling well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I get you some coffee?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Todd, let me tell you what we're really interested in here. You told the admitting nurse that Denker had a heart attack while you were reading him a letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. I was. That's what I was doing there. It was in German but he insisted I try to read it anyway. Once or twice he got pissy about the pronunciation but I asked him what did he want from me. I don't speak German. Mr. Denker... Dussander... got really excited at one point. He yelled out, "Yes, that's what you would do all right." but I didn't know what he was talking about. Then he grabbed his chest.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's when you called the ambulance, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this is the part we can't figure out. The letter itself, Todd... do you remember what happened to it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it was still on the table. I couldn't swear to it, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, I saw a letter. It was in German. I didn't think anything of it at the time. But, yeah, it was on Airmail stationery.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it should still be there. This is our problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe somebody broke in.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>simply to steal a letter? ...Unless... there was someone... someone right here in Santo Donato who would want to protect him for some reason. Maybe a close friend, or even another fugitive. I know it sounds like a bunch of Robert Ludlum stuff, but when Dussander was taken to the hospital, we think our Mr. X scooted over to the house and swiped the letter.</context>
      <utterance>Why would somebody break into his house</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't make sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not, Todd?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if Denk... if he had an old Nazi buddy in town, why didn't he come over himself and read the letter to him? If you could have heard the way he corrected me at every word--</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A good point. Except maybe this other fellow is in a wheelchair, or blind.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys that are blind don't normally go scooting out to steal letters.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True. Did Dussander have any friends that you knew of?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>How about phone calls?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I heard his phone ring maybe five or six times in all the time I knew him. It was never anything out of the ordinary. Salesmen. Wrong numbers.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever hear him speak German on those occasions?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He hardly ever spoke German. He always said he would teach me someday, but he never got around to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEISKOPF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd looks at Weiskopf. This is the first question he has asked and Todd is more wary of him than of Richler. Todd shrugs innocently.</context>
      <utterance>Did he ever talk about his past?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. Little bits, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, don't you remember what he told us at Thanksgiving? Todd looks at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he was in college--</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Weiskopf stand. Dick is almost surprised that they are leaving so soon.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm sure this whole thing has come as a terrible shock. I think we've done enough for the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEISKOPF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weiskopf nods good-bye.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Todd. Mr. and Mrs. Bowden.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute... Agent Richler, before you go-- Todd's not a suspect in this, is he? I mean he's just talking to you, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because Todd always thought he was helping that old man. We didn't know any of this before today.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bowden, you and Todd have nothing to worry about. I assure you. Your son has been a great service to us. Thank you, Todd. For now that's all we need. Our next step is to turn that house upside down. We're bringing in some special teams to look through everything. We may come up with something. We'll be in touch if we need you. They are almost to the door, when Richler stops.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He holds the photo up to Todd. It is a picture of Archie in military dress, probably a blow-up of his military ID. Todd stares at it for a moment. His face shows no reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Todd, by the way....  Have you ever seen this man before?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles. Weiskopf opens the door and the two men leave.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything all right, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mother and I feel terrible... like we...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dick grabs his son and pulls him close. Todd doesn't know how to respond. For Dick, it is like hugging a phone pole. He knows something is terribly wrong. Todd stands stiff in his father's arms until he releases him.</context>
      <utterance>It's not your fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know we love you, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at his father, comfortingly. Dick is not comforted.</context>
      <utterance>I know, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, ahh, your mother and I are going to go down and talk to our lawyer. I don't want you to worry about a thing. It's just a precaution. I don't trust these cops. We're not going to be gone long.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about me, I'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your old man is on top of things, all right? I am going to take care of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dick kisses Todd's forehead. He turns to leave and stops.</context>
      <utterance>I know, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This afternoon, if you're up for it, we'll go do something. How 'bout it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dick tries to smile and goes out, the door, leaving Todd alone.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Todd.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two of them are standing on opposites sides of the car. French pulls a folded newspaper page from his pocket. He starts to move around the car toward Todd, but Todd circles the other way, keeping the car in between himself and French.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. French, what brings you to the wild side of town?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Todd... I found something troubling in the morning news. Are your parents home?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know the man in this picture is the man who came to see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's sort of a bad time right now. Why don't you go home?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will. But first I need a couple of things explained to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Mr. French, sometimes one thing just leads to another and before you know it... things get out of control.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid that's not much of an answer, Todd. When do you expect your parents home?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Ed. You want to come in and wait? I'll put on a pot of tea. We'll talk about old times.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's why I'm here.</context>
      <utterance>I think you might need some help, Todd.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me help you, Todd. I want to. You're too smart to do anything crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you something, Ed? You don't mind if I call you Ed, now that I'm out of your fucking school, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>French is puzzled by the question. He has no answer.</context>
      <utterance>You know all this crap you see on TV about forensics... hairs and fibers, that stuff? How much of it do think is true and how much is just bullshit?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, how would you know? You're a fucking guidance counsellor. French stops.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Todd, this is silly. Why don't we go inside?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd comes around the rear of the car and stops at the door to the back seat. He opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Here's a little factoid for ya. I'll bet you didn't know this one. Hairs fall out of your head all the time. But it's even worse when you're nervous. And you know what? I've been real fucking high-strung lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd bends down to get something from the back seat. His voice is muffled from the inside of the car.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Todd... Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd pops back up holding the rifle, fully assembled and aimed at French's chest.</context>
      <utterance>That's how it all happened, you know. One thing lead to another and before I knew it...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you showed up in my driveway, wearing those same fucking sneakers.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRENCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd rapid-fires. French's chest explodes red as his lifeless body sails back onto the grass. In the front yard, a dozen birds evacuate a tree in a panicked exodus. Todd swoons back on his heels, overcome by something. But it isn't pain, rather, it's a rush of pleasure. A laugh slips out.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa. To--</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
