<movie id="51" title="Austin Powers The Spy Who Shagged Me">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Mr. Powers.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SHOT TO MATCH EXISTING FOOTAGE: Austin gets out of bed. We see Vanessa putting on her robe from behind, and then EXISTING FOOTAGE: Austin and Vanessa kiss.</context>
      <utterance>And I love you, Mrs. Powers.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go out on the terrace. It's a beautiful night, we can look at the stars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look how beautiful the night sky is.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that the big dipper?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and that looks just like Uranus.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I've never seen that big star before.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin pulls out his telescope and takes a look.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, what is that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A VANESSA DOUBLE crosses carrying a bouquet of flowers, which obscure her face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh well, I guess it was nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa sits at the vanity with her back turned.</context>
      <utterance>Care for some champagne?  Here's to monotony-- I mean, monogamy!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Vanessa? What are you doing, luv?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Vanessa turns around she puts her hands up and PULLS OFF HER FACE revealing wires, transistors, and a speaker where her mouth should be.</context>
      <utterance>Just putting on my--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They fight. Midway through the fight, machine guns pop out of Vanessa's breasts.</context>
      <utterance>Vanessa, you're a Fembot!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Machine gun jubblies, how did I miss those?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, I know you're against race mixing and all that, but I met someone...</utterance>
   <speaker>KLANSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd WHOOPS.</context>
      <utterance>Don't say it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd goes crazy.</context>
      <utterance>I met someone... and he's black.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLANSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Klansman holds his hooded head in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>He?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY SPRINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A handsome Blair Underwood look-alike enters and hugs the Klansman's son. The crowd screams.</context>
      <utterance>Please welcome Tim.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>JERRY SPRINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Scott, tell us about your father. Share with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well he's the head of an evil organization that has aspirations for world domination.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY SPRINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where is your father right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in outer space, like frozen in a giant egg and stuffed inside a Big Boy rocket with his cat, Mr. Bigglesworth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY SPRINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Well, we have a surprise for you, Scott. Let's bring out</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT'S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lower Third Chyron: "WANTS TO TAKE OVER THE WORLD"</context>
      <utterance>father, Dr Evil. Dr Evil enters.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Scott, I'm back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you'd do this to me on national television!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They offered me a free makeover.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY SPRINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, we've seen a lot of the fathers here today open up to their sons, sons to the fathers. Is there anything you'd like to share?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Share?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY SPRINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, don't you have any secrets?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone is a little grossed out.</context>
      <utterance>OK. I have a vestigial tail.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Springer audience is stunned, slack-jawed and for once quiet.</context>
      <utterance>It's more of a nub, really. The spine just goes on a little longer than it should. Also, I've dabbled. I mean, perform fellatio once and you're a poet, twice and you're a homosexual. I remember once I was being fisted by Sebastian Cabot- but here's where the story gets interesting. He was lactose-intolerant. He could eat red meat all night long, but one sip of milk and it was gastric hell. And I remember we were caught in fragrance delicto by Henry Kissinger, and you can imagine my humiliation at having Hank hear me say, "Mr. French, no teeth." One of my greatest disappointments is that I never became a song and dance man. I could have been a quadruple threat, kind of like a despotic Ken Barry. Dancer, singer, actor, and I would possess nuclear weapons, the latter being the most threatening of the four. I once sat on a bus and tried to will myself a menstrual cycle. All I ended up with was a sense of failure and a mild neuralgia in my incisor teeth and perhaps a grudging respect for the weaker sex. I love toe cleavage. For the most part I distrust dogs. I slept in a horse once. It was quite roomy. On second thought, it was the Ritz. I named my left testicle 'piss' and my right testicle 'vinegar'. I wrote "It's Raining Men", or so the Christmas babies told me. Oh yes, I also made a Marzipan voodoo effigy of The Fonze while I was in coma after smoking some Peruvian prayer hash, but who at the end of the day can honestly say they haven't done that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLANSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you, some kind of freak?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Studio audience whoops at this.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, jagoff!</utterance>
   <speaker>KLANSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crowd goes crazy.</context>
      <utterance>I'll kick your ass punk!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil charges at Klansman and starts to bitch slap him. Security men, with headsets on, rush in to separate them.</context>
      <utterance>No one talks to my boy that way!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a BEAT, then Dr. Evil CHARGES the guy again, knocking him down.</context>
      <utterance>I'm OK, I'm OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come Scott, let's go to daddy's new evil lair.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, as the legitimate frontman of your organization, I seized upon the opportunity to invest in a small Seattle-based coffee company several years ago. Today, Starbucks is a far- flung empire with 2000 outlets worldwide.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh good, Number Two, I do enjoy a good cuppa joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil takes a sip of cappuccino, leaving a WHITE FROTHY MILK MUSTACHE on his upper lip.</context>
      <utterance>If I may continue, I believe if we shift our resources away from world domination and focus on providing premium quality coffee drinks, we can increase our gross profits fivefold.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Perhaps you've confused me with someone who gives a shit. Might I remind you that I run the show here? I demand a little respect.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, I think you--</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silence! I will not tolerate your insolence! Remember what happened last time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I add, I appreciate you reinstating me after our little... misunderstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Frau. She looks a little more 'masculine' than before.</context>
      <utterance>Frau Farbissina. Wie gehts is einen?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zehr gut, Herr Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are things?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a severe-looking German woman with one continuous eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>I have come to embrace the love that dare not speak it's name. To my right is my lover.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her name is Unibrau. I met her on the LPGA Tour.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil takes another sip of cappuccino, making the frothy milk mustache even larger.</context>
      <utterance>Right on. Welcome, Unibrau.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor, you have a 'milk mustache.'</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I know. I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a swarthy Greek army guy.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, I'd like to introduce the Greek assassin, Oedipus.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to my private army, Oedipus. Excited?</utterance>
   <speaker>OEDIPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could give a shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiss your mother with that mouth?</utterance>
   <speaker>OEDIPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr Evil begins to press a button labelled "Oedipus" on his control panel, but Number Two interrupts.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, as you know, the rate at which you liquidate henchmen far exceeds our ability to replace them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have so few pleasures left to me, Number Two. The key to life is to rotate your vices. One day it's executions, another day it's creamy French cheese. It's like frickin' heroin.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Dr. Evil, perhaps I have the answer. While you were frozen, we began a program to clone you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a few glitches, but I think you'll be pleased with the results.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC: dramatic sting We see the shadow of an approaching figure. The shadow looks like Dr. Evil, only much larger and scarier.</context>
      <utterance>Send in the clone!</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see that the source of the shadow is a MINIATURE DR. EVIL, just like the creepy mini-Marlon Brando in The Island of Dr. Moreau. He mimics Dr. Evil's mannerisms including holding his tiny pinky to his tiny mouth.</context>
      <utterance>He is identical to you in every way, except he is one-eighth your size.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mini-Me sits down in a miniature version of Dr. Evil's command chair.</context>
      <utterance>Breathtaking. I shall call him Mini- Me.  Mini-Me, you will sit to my right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bald Mr. Bigglesworth runs and jumps into Dr. Evil's lap. A bald MR. BIGGLESWORTH KITTEN jumps into Mini-Me's lap.</context>
      <utterance>Come Mr. Bigglesworth!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Mini-me, something to eat?  No?</utterance>
   <speaker>OK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tired. Gentleman, I have a plan. As you know, the most powerful man in the world is the President of the United States. But he is just that- a man, subject to temptations of the flesh like any other man. Here's what we do: we make it seem that the President has had "extra-marital oral relations" with- and this is the kicker-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil gloats. So does Mini-Me.</context>
      <utterance>With a White House intern!</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-hem.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Number Two nods.</context>
      <utterance>What, that already happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is ri-goddamn-diculous. Oh well, how about a frickin' time machine? Does the president have a time machine? Have I been scooped on that?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not that I'm aware of.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, time machine it is. As you know, every diabolical scheme I've hatched has been thwarted by Austin Powers. And why is that, ladies and gentlemen?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mini-Me hops upon the table and tries to push the "Scott Evil" button on Dr. Evil's control panel. Frau SQUIRTS him with a water bottle. Mini-Me glares at Scott and GIVES HIM THE FINGER.</context>
      <utterance>Because you never kill him when you get the chance and you're a dope?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, because Austin Powers has "mojo".</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mojo?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, mojo. The mojo is the life force, the essence, the libido, the "right stuff".</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what the French call a certain 'I don't know what.'</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you've got a time machine, why don't you just go back and kill Austin Powers when he's a baby or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, wouldn't it be easier to use your knowledge of the future to play the stock market? We could literally make trillions.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why make trillions when we could make...  Billions?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why think small is all I'm saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A trillion is more than a billion, numb-nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wall panel opens to reveal a Stargate-like wall of shimmering energy.</context>
      <utterance>Zip it. Unveil the time portal!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>First, I take Austin Powers' mojo. Then I begin my domination of the world.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen, I give you the time portal. As you know, Austin Powers was frozen in 1967. Therefore, I time travel to 1969, two years after he was frozen. Security will be lax and I'll strike when he is totally helpless.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I come?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil walks to the portal. Mini-Me follows, imitating him perfectly. They enter the portal. There is a FREEZE FRAME effect and they FADE AWAY, like in Star Trek.</context>
      <utterance>No, Scott, Daddy has a score to settle. Austin Powers is the snake to my mongoose, or the mongoose to my snake. Either way it's bad, I don't know animals. But I do know this: This time it's personal. Frau, Number 2, I'll see you both in 1969. Come, Mini-Me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Dr. Evil walks to the center of the room, chairs rise from the floor. Everyone takes a seat, but Dr. Evil gets caught in the middle as chairs rise around him. He is frightened. One of the rising chairs hits him in the crotch.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, here we are Mini-Me, 1969. Number Two, you look very youthful and healthy.  And Frau you look...right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, people, we now officially have a chair problem. If another one of these chairs hits me in the nuts, I'm gonna go postal. Mini-Me, I want you to meet Number Two.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mini-me says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Hello there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mini-me still says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Mini-Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil goes over and looks out the large window.</context>
      <utterance>Shy. Low blood sugar.  Gentlemen, Phase Two is beginning. I have an operative inside the Ministry of Defense. By this time tomorrow, Austin Powers' mojo will be mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha-ha-ha! Ha-ha-ha!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRITISH COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've had reports that there's a spy in the Ministry of Defense. The contents of this room are vital to the country. Be on special alert.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those bastards will have to kill me before I let anything happen to this wee naked hairy popsicle, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRITISH COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exchange salutes and the Colonel exits.</context>
      <utterance>Very good. And try and lose some weight for God's sake!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(sotto after the Colonel) I outta smash your teeth out with a Toffee Hammer Mr. English Colonel Telling-Me-What-To-Do-And-Stealing- our-Oil-Refusing-To-Recognize- our- Scottish-Independence! The Fat Soldier begins to play the BAGPIPES, a white vapor comes out of them, filling the room. The other soldiers COLLAPSE, unconscious. He bores through the ice and pulls out a Sixties high-tech syringe type device with an LED graph on the side. He places it in Austin's navel. The LED meter goes from red to green, indicating FULL MOJO.</context>
      <utterance>Yessir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BASIL EXPOSITION appears on the picture phone in the dash.</context>
      <utterance>Gor blimey, I'm on empty! That's funny, I just filled the Shaguar up this morning. Austin hits a button on the dashboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, I'm Basil Exposition, head of British Intelligence.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always are, Basil. Listen, the weirdest thing just happened, I've run out of petrol.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll send a man around immediately. How was your honeymoon?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vanessa tried to kill me, Basil. She was a Fembot!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah women, who can understand them? Moving on, let's discuss your new case.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New case? Very shagadelic, Basil!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be doing a photo shoot. We know that one of the models is an ex- KGB agent selling top secret material to the highest bidder.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds easy enough, you know what they say: all work and no shagging makes Austin a dull boy, man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="48">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REG, the photo assistant, enters.</context>
      <utterance>Tres chic, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>REG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, the models are ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ta, Reg. Bless your cotton socks. Hey, Reg, do you have any hobbies?</utterance>
   <speaker>REG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The models make their entrance. They are REAL SUPERMODELS, say CINDY CRAWFORD, REBECCA ROMAJIN and also one MODEL we don't know.</context>
      <utterance>Hobbies, man! I for one enjoy making models!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERMODELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin shoots a look to Reg like 'still got it, baby.'</context>
      <utterance>It's him! Oh my God! It's Austin Powers!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One at a time, girls. One. At. A. Time!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Cindy. I don't believe I've had the pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you haven't had "The Pleasure", we just met, baby, yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do, Austin? I'm Rebecca.  Your equipment is quite impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin comes to the unknown model. She is tall and angular.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Your breasts are amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what's your name, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>MODEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ivana Humpalot.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ivana. Ivana Humpalot.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin looks over the girls, trying to decide who is the spy.</context>
      <utterance>And I vanna toilet made of solid gold but it's just not in the cards, now is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy gets on all fours.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, baby! Love it. Turn and pout for me baby! Smashing!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FULL FRAME, cover of Vogue. Cindy with her head framed out.</context>
      <utterance>Great, darling. Give me some shoulder. Yes, yes, yes.  No! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rebecca looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>Show me love. Smashing! You're an animal. You're a tiger. Be a tiger, baby! You're great! You're Grrrrrr- eat! You're Tony, be corn flakes, baby, be frosted. Now be a lemur, baby! You're a ring-tailed lemur.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lemur?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FULL FRAME, Rebecca on the cover of National--Geographic.</context>
      <utterance>A small mammal native to the African savannah. C'mon baby, you know. Like this!  OK, predator coming! Now, burrow, burrow! You're a lemur. It's all you've got.  I take it back. Be a tiger again. Smashing!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin throws his camera to Reg, who catches it.</context>
      <utterance>And... done! I'm spent!</utterance>
   <speaker>REG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hel-lo, you forgot about Ivana.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reg shows the girls out as they PROTEST. Austin and Ivana are left alone. Austin CLAPS TWICE and the lights dim. He CLAPS again and the fire goes up. MUSIC: I'm Never Going To Fall in Love Again by BURT BACHARACH</context>
      <utterance>I didn't forget, baby. Miss Humpalot and I are going to have a 'private session'.</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you get "The Clapper"?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>November, 1964, Dutch East Indies, shore leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you cold, Mr. Powers?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ivana moves over to a chessboard set up nearby.</context>
      <utterance>I once had a bad experience with frostbite. I had to dip my tadger into a brandy snifter.</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know how we keep warm in Russia?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can guess, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We play chess.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guessed wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It takes a keen intelligence to play chess. Of course, you know what they say about men with big brains, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They wear large hats?</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they make better lovers.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ivana starts playing with the chess pieces sexily (like in The Thomas Crowne Affair).</context>
      <utterance>Wrong again.</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs the bishop across her lips sexily.</context>
      <utterance>I assume you know how to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin tries to match her sexy moves and CHOKES on a piece.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. The... horsey... moves in an L shape.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's stop playing games with each other... especially difficult ones. May I ask you a question, Miss Humpalot?</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin rolls around on the polar bear rug.</context>
      <utterance>Do I make you horny? Do I?</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls his shirt off, revealing his prodigious chest hair.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you anything you want to know, just make love to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are hairy, like an animal!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin takes the head of the bear skin rug.</context>
      <utterance>Grrrr, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grrrr. Ruf! Ruf!  Wait a tick, I don't want him watching me while I'm on the job!</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make love to me, monkey man.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We pan around the room, seeing all the stuffed and mounted wildlife who seem to be watching. Suddenly the camera stops. So does the music.</context>
      <utterance>Groovy, baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>IVANA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, I came as soon as I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin holds his neck very stiffly.</context>
      <utterance>There must be some kind of mistake, Basil. Maybe I was drunk and I didn't know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with your neck, Austin?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took a Viagra and it got caught in my throat. I've had a stiff neck for hours. Basil, is it true? Have I lost my mojo?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to run a few tests, Austin. Don't worry, old friend, we'll get to the bottom of this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Mr. Powers, I need to give you a sponge bath before we begin the test.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ALARM goes off. Bright LIGHTS come on. Basil enters.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, miss, just let me finish this article on the Suez crisis.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, everyone, we're done.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the test hasn't even started!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Haggerty was the test, Austin. Not only were you actually reading an article in that Playboy, but a candy-stripe nurse offering to give you a sponge bath didn't so much as turn your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, I can explain, man! I was going to shag her but the article was so fascinating--</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Basil shows Austin the mojometer, which reads EMPTY.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Austin, I'm afraid it's true: you've lost your mojo.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without my mojo, I'm useless to the Ministry and to Her Majesty. I think it's time to retire.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid that's not possible, Austin. You see, Dr. Evil has returned.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Basil shows Austin altered photos of Dr. Evil with famous villains, such as Sadam, Nixon, and Donald Trump.</context>
      <utterance>We have evidence that Dr. Evil has developed a time machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin tries to read them and gets queasy.</context>
      <utterance>Our researcher noticed that these photos from the archives have changed. That means Dr. Evil is traveling back in time and creating alliances with each decade's most despised villains.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin burps and swallows it.</context>
      <utterance>I can't read in the car. I get a bit vomy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it. I almost gipped.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A bright overhead light comes on spotlighting a brand new VOLKSWAGEN BEETLE CONVERTIBLE, painted up psychedelic by Peter Max.</context>
      <utterance>Our data indicates that Dr. Evil is in the year 1969. Luckily, we also have a time travel device. After years of research we've developed a machine that will transport you back to the Sixties.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Basil, isn't that the new Volkswagen Beetle?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what they'd like you to believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Basil, if I travel back to 1969 and I was frozen in 1967, I could go look at my frozen self. But, if I'm still frozen in 1967, how could I have been unthawed in the 90's and traveled back to the Sixties?  Oh, no, I've gone cross-eyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin gets into the car and turns it on.</context>
      <utterance>I suggest you don't worry about those things and just enjoy yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is smashing Basil. I'll go back to the Sixties, recharge my mojo, defeat Dr. Evil and be back in time for tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Austin.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin steps on the gas. The car lurches in reverse and smashes some equipment.</context>
      <utterance>Luck has nothing to do with it, Basil.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swinging Sixties, here I come, baby, yeah! The car takes off, heading for the wall. It DISAPPEARS, leaving flaming tread marks.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Care for a ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my Beetle, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin dives in as the assassin FIRES. The car speeds off.</context>
      <utterance>It was your Beetle. Get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin Powers, I presume?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Powers by name, Powers by reputation.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Felicity Shagwell, CIA. Shagwell by name, Shag-very-Well by reputation.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crazy, baby!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Austin, I think this time you may have met your match.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I've beaten Dr. Evil before, and I'll beat him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, turns, and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>I was talking about me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Light floods the pad, revealing hanging basket chairs, Hi- fi, and Warhol silk screens of Austin. Austin blows DUST off a table.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to my shag pad, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin hits a button and a bookcase revolves to reveal a wetbar.</context>
      <utterance>Care for something to drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin walks seductively over to the real wetbar and hits a button. It revolves to reveal a bookcase.</context>
      <utterance>Or perhaps something to read?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about a hot cup of coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I rather fancy a grind.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin hits a button and an automatic coffee-pourer pours a cup. MUSIC: Girl from Impenema by JOBIM</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Behave!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin hits a button and a series of actions take place: the floor opens up to reveal a sunken bed; red gels slide into place over the lamps; a painting slides back to reveal a reel-to-reel; an end table revolves to reveal a selection of massage oils. Felicity lies on her stomach. Austin begins to massage her.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like a... mas-sage? A sensssual mas-sage?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does that feel, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm, lower.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOW DOES THAT FEEL, BABY?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They laugh. Austin continues to massage her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches behind her and unties the strap of her evening dress, revealing her naked back.</context>
      <utterance>Wait, something's itching me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's better.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin GULPS and accidentally spurts way too much oil on her.</context>
      <utterance>Crikey!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin continues the back rub and Felicity stretches out on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin takes a peak-- nothing. He is panicked.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, anyone home? C'mon lads, do it for England.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that was so relaxing. Felicity stretches very sexily.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you 'like to see my etchings?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get you some PJs.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves over to him. He avoids her.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm ready for bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin holds up toothpaste and toothbrush. Felicity finally grabs him and pins him to the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you'll want to clean your teeth then.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I want to have sex with you, Austin.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Vicar!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin sits up.</context>
      <utterance>I've studied everything about you- your methods, your accomplishments, your preferences. You're the reason I became a spy. Now, I've waited two years to meet you, so I say we get busy making up for lost time.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Felicity, I used to think that way, too, but I guess... I guess I've changed. Not to make a short story long, or to ramble on and on, or to keep talking in a repetitive manner ad infinitum until it becomes impossible to remember what I was talking about in the first place, but- where was I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes. Felicity, I can't shag you. I've lost my mojo.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought coming back to the Sixties would bring it back, but it hasn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, don't worry. I know just the man to help you. He's my guru. Ringo recommended him and he's the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll warm up the Jumbo Jet, baby!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="50">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the GURU PITKA (played by Mike), an Indian man in a bright red sari.</context>
      <utterance>There he is. That's my guru.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guru, I'd like you to meet Austin Powers.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My chakras are aligned and I am in a perfect state of equipoise.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good on ya. I don't know what that means but it sounds fab.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guru, we need some advice.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guru walks to the front of the room and the disciples sink to their knees.</context>
      <utterance>Hold your horses and any other beasts- of burden. I must lead my disciples in meditation and then I will help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISCIPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhhhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is the Guru Pitka. I am a spiritual teacher and I have combined many disparate disciplines into a unified movement of human potentiality and equipoise that I learned from my guru, the late Guru Shastri, a chaste man who died mysteriously of a disease that strangely had all the hallmarks of syphilis. He would say to me, Sparky, love is all, life is breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISCIPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhhhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, perhaps you are wondering where I got the nickname Sparky. Well, when we were young we used to play a game called "Stinkmop". We would urinate into a bucket, dip a mop into it, and play tag. I did not care for "Stinkmop" and a very wise old man said to me 'oh lighten up, Sparky', and I don't know, the name kind of stuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISCIPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhhhhhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guru holds up a card which says "NOWHERE = NOW HERE!"</context>
      <utterance>Now, the reason I am a spiritualist instead of a therapist is that 'therapist' often becomes 'the rapist' and that will not help us attain potentiality. Now what is potentiality? It is the ability to achieve those goals that we wish to achieve for ourselves. People often say to me that they feel "nowhere", and I am going to change that to "Now here."</utterance>
   <speaker>DISCIPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhhhhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guru holds up a card which says "ASSUME = ASS - U - ME."</context>
      <utterance>And you have many assumptions about your goals, but when you "assume" You make an "ass" out of "u" and "me".</utterance>
   <speaker>DISCIPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhhhhh....</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guru holds up a card that says "NOT TINKER, NOT TAUGHTS, BUT THE GAP" with the familiar Gap font.</context>
      <utterance>The being, or that which we call 'ourselves', is not the tinker. It is not the taughts. It is the Gap between the tinker and the taughts! We are not our mind, we are not our body, we are the Gap!</utterance>
   <speaker>DISCIPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The heart of the matter is that you are the heart of the matter. There is no "I" in "team". Beer before liquor, never sicker. Don't take a wooden nickel. If your pipe is short and your pump is weak, you better stand close or you'll piss on your feet. He who goes to bed with itchy bum wakes up with smelly finger.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISCIPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally, the path to spiritual awakening requires the death of ego. Leggo of my ego! Let us end with the mantra: Om Ay Vant Yu Uh... Mo Ay Vant Yu Uh... Mo Ay Vant Yu Hu.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISCIPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guru takes a swig of Yoo-Hoo.</context>
      <utterance>Om Ay Vant Yu Uh... Mo Ay Vant Yu Uh... Mo Ay Vant Yu Hu.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The disciples file out. Austin and Felicity approach.</context>
      <utterance>Go with God, and pay at the door please.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guru, I'm having trouble performing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know- my bits and pieces are a bit sleepy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not understanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've forgotten the steps to the Mummy- Daddy dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still not clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My flag's at half mast and no one will salute it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Willie don't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you beating around the bush?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohhhhh, I get it.  No, I don't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's impotent!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, easy.  Felicity and I were all set for some hump Olympics and I couldn't bat for six.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no idea what I'm saying, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a word.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guru, I've lost my mojo.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, mojo! You should have said so. Well, you've lost your mojo because your chakras are misaligned. You have lost love.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lost love? Oh, you mean Vanessa?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Vanessa?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was an evil robot minion of Dr. Evil. I couldn't have loved her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Denial ain't just a river in Egypt, buddy. You will only get your mojo back when you surround yourself with love.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I get what you're saying now! He's talking about free love, baby! Tune in, turn on, and drop out!</utterance>
   <speaker>GURU PITKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am talking about true love. You must stay and study until you are worthy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way, man. The only way to surround yourself with love is to throw a swinging shin-dig! Yeah, baby, yeah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well done, Fat Bastard. May I have the mojo?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First things first, where's your shitter? I've gotta bleepin, turtle head pokin' out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Charming. Fat Bastard- you don't mind me calling you Fat Bastard do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a lot of demons kickin' around in my noggin, but weight issues ain't one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, Fatty-</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name is Fat Bastard! I'm the incorrect weight for my height and I was born out of wedlock, hence the moniker Fat Bastard. Hey, I'm not kiddin'. I've got a crap on deck that could choke a donkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fat Bastard, the mojo?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's my  money?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A gentlemen never discusses money.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, you can take your in' money and shove it up your , you stupid  prick! While you're at it you can suck my greasy, two-toned !</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vulgarity is no substitute for wit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>you!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil PRIVATE ARMY SOLDIERS drive in a forklift loaded with gold bars.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Bring in the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fat Bastard slowly draws out the high-tech syringe full of</context>
      <utterance>Alright, here it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOJO.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil is mesmerized.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mini-Me runs and snatches the mojo from Fat Bastard and gives it to Dr. Evil, who caresses it and places it on a SPECIALLY</context>
      <utterance>Mini-Me, fetch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREPARED PEDESTAL.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NUMBER TWO enters.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, I have some bad news. Austin Powers is back in the Sixties. One of our best assassins spotted him but he got away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is ri-goddamn-diculous, we have his mojo.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is another. Felicity Shagwell,</utterance>
   <speaker>CIA.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suddenly, Scott Evil enters through TIME PORTAL.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scott, what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I was sitting around watching the tube and The Courtship of Eddie's Father came on Nick at Nite, you know, and I was just listening to that theme song--  Anyway it made me think that maybe we could try and work things out. You know, you are my Dad and I need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott, very hurt, sits back in his chair and sulks. Dr. Evil hits a button and a model moon and a model earth descend.</context>
      <utterance>You had your chance, Scott. I already have someone created in my image. He's evil, he wants to take over the world, and he fits easily into most overhead storage bins.  Has anyone seen Mini-Me?  Mini-Me! Mini-Mouse? Mini-Driver? Hello! Mini Pearl? Can we put a frickin' bell on him or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil looks around and sees Mini-Me gnawing on the model laser. Dr. Evil takes it from his mouth</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, phase three. We place a giant laser on the moon. Let me demonstrate.  Where's my laser?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott SNICKERS.</context>
      <utterance>Mini-Me, don't chew my laser.  Not feeling well. He has an ear infection, but tit's OK.  No? Nothing?  Anyway, the laser is powerful enough to destroy every city on the planet at will. We'll turn the moon into what I like to call a "Death Star".</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing Darth.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you call me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.  Rip-off!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott SNICKERS again.</context>
      <utterance>Bless you? Anyways, since my "death star" laser was invented by the noted Cambridge physicist, Dr. Parsons. I thought we'd name it in his honor-- the Alan Parsons Project.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Alan Parsons Project was a progressive rock band from 1982. Why don't you just name it Operation Wang Chung, ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you get your own evil empire, you can call it whatever you want. Gentlemen, allow me to demonstrate the awesome lethality of the Alan Parsons Project. Fire the laser!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, Dr. Evil, you destroyed the Wihite House with no warning!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, that was just footage from the 1996 blockbuster motion Picture Independence Day, but it would be a lot like that. What do you think, Scott?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Codename: Thompson Twins was really impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm nineteen, I don't-</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shh! Shh-Shh. Shh-Shhhhhh-Shh. Shh- shh! It's Morse code.  Let me decipher... it says 'shhhhh!'</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are so lame-</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ssssss...huuuuuh...Shhhhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, what are we going to do about Powers?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Take care of it.</context>
      <utterance>Fat Bastard, in addition to being extremely rotund, you're a vicious killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be my pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an easy job. Without his mojo, Powers will be...powerless?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The party sequence is shot like Laugh-In. Very fast cuts to the music. Austin sees a VERY PREGNANT WOMAN drinking a martini and smoking. He gently lifts her drink and cigarette away from her.</context>
      <utterance>This shag-in is gonna blow your mind, baby, yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>PREGNANT WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another angle. Austin and Felicity dancing.</context>
      <utterance>You'll thank me later, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see RICARDO MONTEBLAN -smoking a hukka on a round chair.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Ricardo Monteblan, how are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICARDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Austin! Balls, said the queen and the king laughed because he had too.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crazy, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's split up and scope the scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felicity slaps Austin on the butt as he walks off.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do anything I wouldn't do- at least not without me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, behave!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're very exotic, baby. Do you have a little English in you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN ZEUS GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is ridiculous!</utterance>
   <speaker>LONDON COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever been picked up by the fuzz?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I bet it really hurts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Austin Powers Sexy Dictionary defines an Eskimo hooker as a frosty prosty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESKIMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are skin tight. How do you get into those pants, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin does a spit take.</context>
      <utterance>Well you can start by buying me a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIKING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were great last night. By the way, I'm Thor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Thor? I'm tho thor I can hardly thit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear about the contortionist who was engaged to be married?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I heard she broke it off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to where Fat Bastard and his companion are standing.</context>
      <utterance>Look at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not a pretty sight. Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until recently he worked security for the MOD, but we think he might be a double agent, possibly for Dr. Evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've noticed that his lifestyle has changed dramatically. He's made a lot of cash purchases, he's hanging out with foxes half his age, and he's becomes quite a fixture on the London party circuit.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fat Bastard exits.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but it looks like he's splitting.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felicity follows Fat Bastard out the door. Austin makes his way over to the girl.</context>
      <utterance>I'll follow him. You see what you can get out of the girl. We'll rendezvous later.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Powers. Fab party.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you today, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robin. Robin Swallows.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swallows? That's an interesting name. Are you English?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>German, actually. My maiden name is Spitz.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well which is it, baby, Spitz or Swallows? Either way, it's a pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She extends her hand. Austin takes it and shakes. As he shakes, her cleavage undulates like jello. Austin is transfixed and keeps shaking far too long.</context>
      <utterance>The pleasure is mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin. is shaking her hand so vigorously that she is in danger of popping out of her dress.</context>
      <utterance>Charmed, I'm sure.  How do you do?  Yes, quite.  I always enjoy meeting new people.  How's your mum? Good.  I love shaking hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, who was your friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Fat Bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It suits him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin is grossed out.</context>
      <utterance>He's my lover.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK. Would you happen to know if he's in business with a man named Mr. Evil?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know anyone named Dr. Evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? I said Mister Evil. Austin does a smug take.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something to drink? Would you like a Mister Pepper?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'd love a Doctor Pepper.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin does another smug take. Robin grabs Austin and pulls him close.</context>
      <utterance>Really? I said Mister Pepper.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a groovy boy, I'd like to strap you on sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, behave!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We pan to see Felicity beside him.</context>
      <utterance>...and I'll have a fried-prawn sandwich, with extra mayonnaise, two whole chickens, a kidney pie, a toad in the hole, bubble and squeak, bangers and mash, 3 orders of fish and chips, and... a Fresca. No ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love a man with a large appetite.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felicity swallows hard and forces a smile.</context>
      <utterance>And I love a woman with big , so let's shut up and get to ing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you a question?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what's the question?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. Would you like to shag? Would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin moves Austin into place as they dance.</context>
      <utterance>I'd love to, Mr. Powers, just come right... over... here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Austin looks into her eyes and sees the REFLECTION OF AN ASSASSIN (Oedipus) about to throw a knife. Just as he throws it, Austin spins Robin Swallows around and USES HER AS A SHIELD. She takes the knife squarely in the back.</context>
      <utterance>You're a bit of alright.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oedipus, Oedipus...</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry baby, too late. He's as dead as vaudeville.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN SWALLOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't win, Powers. Dr. Evil has your mojo and it's only a matter of time before he kills you and takes over the world.  Tell Fat Bastard I'll miss him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always get in' hungry after I get my end away!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never would have thought that a man of such tremendous girth could be such a, um, creative and sensuous lover!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rolls over to reveal his HUGE NAKED ASS. Felicity takes a homing device out of her purse, looks around for a place to plant it. She sees his enormous butt cleavage and realizes that there's only one place for the thing to go. ANGLE on FAT BASTARD'S face. He is delighted.</context>
      <utterance>You want some chicken? I have more!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is horrified.</context>
      <utterance>Frisky are we? Alright lets have another go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, what do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil reveals a giant laser. Mini-Me is humping it like a dog.</context>
      <utterance>Not what I want Mr. President, but I will receive. In 12 hours I will destroy Washington, DC with a giant laser.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, Mini-Me, why don't you and the laser get a frickin' room. Honestly.  I will destroy another major city every hour- that is, unless you pay me-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President and his advisors LAUGH.</context>
      <utterance>One hundred billion dollars!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil that's more than the entire federal budget for 1969.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't play games with me. The capitol will disappear if I don't receive</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His advisors LAUGH.</context>
      <utterance>One hundred billion dollars!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His advisors LAUGH.</context>
      <utterance>That much money simply doesn't exist. I don't think l00 billion is even a number. It's like saying I want a kajillion bajillion dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Mr. President...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Show me the money!" Dr. Evil looks around smugly. No one laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Show me the money!" He looks around again, expectantly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, kwan? Show me the money? No? Nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's 1969. That movie won't come out for another 30 years, ass. They don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President and his advisors MURMUR.</context>
      <utterance>Right. OK, see if you understand this: give me the money or I'm going to blow you to frickin' bits, OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But-</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil signs off.</context>
      <utterance>Talk to the hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott looks at him with disgust.</context>
      <utterance>I did love that, though. Cuba Gooding Jr. was outstanding. Oscar speech, very touching.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR.EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone leaves and he walks over to a panel bearing his logo. He presses a button, the panel opens up to reveal... A</context>
      <utterance>Okay, everybody clear the room!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, one last thing. I-- oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just... right. Would it kill you to frickin' knock?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT./INT. CARNABY STREET - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin and Felicity walk along the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, tell me about the Nineties.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I can't tell you details about the future, baby, it could alter history.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not details, just what it's like. You know, what's the scene? Where's it at?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There've been a lot of advances in the Nineties, baby. The economy is stable, people take better care of their health concern for the environment is on the rise and, um, let's see, there's an entire television channel dedicated to golf.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not so bad once you get used to it. The Nineties are about responsibility. You know, having respect for yourself and other people. I even got married.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You? Married? What about the sexual revolution?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it turns out there were some casualties, baby. Don't you think you'll ever get married?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not until I get a little more 'experience' under my belt.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Austin notices something outside and puts his hand to his mouth in fear.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, behave!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felicity is immediately on her guard. She pulls her gun.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it! Is it Fat Bastard?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin turns his hand around to show her. He has written 'oh my God' on his hand with the pen.</context>
      <utterance>No, written here on my hand, see?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Says 'Oh my God!' They laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin and Felicity duck into a CAMERA SHOP and come out an instant later with SUPER-8 CAMERAS. They run down the street filming each other.</context>
      <utterance>Austin, look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Felicity, I haven't had this much fun since I worked undercover in Amsterdam-- '66 I think it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin is impressed.</context>
      <utterance>1965, actually. You posed as a Dutch cheese expert to stop Dr. Evil from poisoning the world's water supply.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin starts to say something, then bites his tongue.</context>
      <utterance>I've studied your file, Austin. I want to be a trailblazer, just like you. The Seventies are right around the corner. It's going to be a glorious time for fashion and music and technology-- it won't be long before every flying car has its own 8-track.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The CIA has always been a boy's club until now. Well move over, this chick's taking over.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, your voice!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin and Felicity stop at an ICE CREAM MAN with his pushcart.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I think I'm coming down with something.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get some ice cream. Would you like some?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could I have two scoops of Vanilla, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>ICE CREAM MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right away, governor. Would you like chocolate syrup?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ICE CREAM MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you have any whipped cream?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ICE CR@ MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Candy sprinkles?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ICE CREAM MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crushed nuts?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, laryngitis.</utterance>
   <speaker>ICE CREAM MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut back to the ICE CREAM MAN to see him pulling off a very fake beard. It is BASIL (though it was clearly another actor before).</context>
      <utterance>Here's your change, sir. Oh, and Austin--</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basil!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Austin. What's wrong with your voice?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just had ice cream. Listen to me, I have dairy throat. "Mary had a little lamb and it was always gruntin'. She tied it to a five bar gate and kicked it's little-</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin! Things are heating up, so I thought it best to contact you in disguise. Felicity, your plan worked. You and Austin track Fat Bastard back to Dr. Evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how can we track Fat Bastard?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I planted a homing device on him last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Basil hands Felicity a tracking device that BEEPS.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, and we're starting to pick up the signal now.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get close enough to plant a homing device?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin and Basil are confused and grossed out at the same time.</context>
      <utterance>I shagged him, I shagged him rotten.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... him? Just like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Austin, we needed that information.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thanks to your effort, Felicity, we now know that-</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you use an elaborate set of pulleys? A block and tackle?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, you two follow the signal back to Dr. Evil's headquarters and then-</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just can't get my head around it, baby. You're so small and he's so ... not small. The sheer mechanics of it are mindboggling!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind, Austin, you two have work to do. You must find Dr. Evil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it! A Chinese basket with a counter-weighted ballast. That's how you did it, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, it almost sounds like you're jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then a-car pulls beside them. Two Dr. Evil Private Army guys pull machine guns and start SHOOTING.</context>
      <utterance>Who, me? That's not possible, baby!  is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felicity ducks. Austin reaches back and pulls ROBIN SWALLOWS from the back seat and USES HER AS A SHIELD.</context>
      <utterance>Get down!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're obviously on the right track.  It looks like Fat Bastard is-on an island in the middle of the ocean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to the readings, Dr. Evil's headquarters is over the next ridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I have a look?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin hands her the binoculars. Unfortunately the strap is still around his neck, pulling his face into her cleavage.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Question is, how do we get in?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmmmmm...mmmmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, did you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seem to be stuck in your dirty pillows.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the topographical maps that Basil drew up?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Felicity enter the tent. A LIGHT is on inside casting shadows of Austin and Felicity on the side of the tent. From the outside it appears the shadow Austin is leaning over with his back to-the shadow Felicity, who appears to have her hands up his butt.</context>
      <utterance>I think they're in the tent.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you got it out yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The shadow Felicity appears to be tugging a string of sausage links from his ass.</context>
      <utterance>Good Lord, Austin, what sort of things do you put in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, anything that catches my fancy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you manage to fit it all in?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The shadow Felicity appears to pull a tennis racket out of Austin's ass.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it stretches to fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you almost done? I can't hold it much longer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, that was fantastic, but I do have some bad news. Powers' is on the island.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How tedious.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Dr. Evil, we can get to him by using the girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have the perfect weapon. Frau?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC: It's Rainina Men by THE WEATHERGIRLS Three HE-BOTS enter in unison. They are robotic studs in Logan's Run type outfits.</context>
      <utterance>Bring in the He-Bots!</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, may I present the He-Bots. What kind of woman could resist these perfect specimens of masculinity? Their clothes are stylish, their posture is ramrod straight, and their buttocks are tight, like tigers. And, each He-Bot is armed with a secret weapon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil is disgusted by the last one.</context>
      <utterance>And deadly acid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(singing)</context>
      <utterance>Right. I object to the last one on aesthetic grounds, but I don't care how you get Powers, just bring him to me.  Ready Mini-Me? A one and a two and...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want everything to go back in?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Listen, Felicity, about Fat Bastard-</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The shadow Felicity tries to cram the tennis racket into what appears to be Austin's ass.</context>
      <utterance>It's my job, Austin. You of all people should understand that. Marakesh, 1962. Rome, 1964. Tokyo, 1966. I know your record backwards and forwards. You've had more sex on the job than a Swedish stewardess.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Pull back to reveal that THE HE-BOTS are watching. Felicity shoves the tennis racket extra hard. Austin stands up rapidly.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, Felicity, I can't deny it. But the world changed, and I changed too.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow!  My back hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The He-Bots shrug their shoulders and march towards the tent.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine, just keeping packing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ Almighty, it smells terrible in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the volcanic sulphurous emissions. We've put up some air fresheners.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, now it smells like someone took a shite in a pine tree.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, the laser has been loaded into the rocket. You're ready for launch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin and Felicity are brought in at gunpoint by Private Army Men.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just waiting to taunt my nemesis. I have so few pleasures, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Mr. Powers, Ms. Shagwell, welcome to my hollowed-out volcano.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We meet again, Dr. Evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, the only reason I'm keeping you alive is so you can feel the agony of watching my plan unfold.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin trails off as he spots his MOJO in the beaker behind Dr. Evil.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil your plan will never--</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, is that yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mojo!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what they say: finders keepers, loser weepers.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil, do you like real estate?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felicity kicks Dr. Evil in the balls.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you've got a couple of achers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oww! My stomach hurts!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care if he is evil, you don't give a man a shot in the pills. It's just not cricket, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guards lead Austin and Felicity away.</context>
      <utterance>Take them away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She just hoofed you in the sack and you're going to leave them alone in a jail cell with one inept guard? They'll escape, dipshit. You do this every time!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going the right way for a smacked bottom, young man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't own me!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do actually.  It's complicated. Usually it's illegal but this buddy of mine... but I digress. Fat Bastard, I'm leaving you in charge. I'm going up the moon to hold the world ransom with my giant laser, I shouldn't be long.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Powers?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The area around Dr. Evil's command chair, including the time portal behind it, is enclosed by a circular door, becoming part of the rocket. Steam begins billowing, etc.</context>
      <utterance>He's tucked away safely in his cell. He's harmless without that mojo. Guard it with your life.  Number Two, begin the countdown.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five, four, three...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel, you better have a look at this radar.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, sir, but it looks like a giant--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dick!</utterance>
   <speaker>CO-PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a look out of starboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO-PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, it looks like a huge--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pecker!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his binoculars.</context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over there. A rare red-billed woodpecker!  What sort of bird is that? Oh goodness, it's not a bird, it's-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnson!</utterance>
   <speaker>RADAR OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get on the horn to British Intelligence and let them know about this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are we going to get out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just shag Fat Bastard again?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, that is it! I don't know what happened to you in the Nineties, but I'm still here, in the Sixties, and I still swing! Don't try to lay your hang-ups on me just because you lost your mojo! That one hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch, baby, very ouch. I'm wounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Austin, that was a cheap shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, baby, you're right. I was wrong to judge you. I guess I am... jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the Austin Powers I knew was wild and crazy and free. He could never be jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Austin is gone. I've changed. I knew someone, not long ago, a very special woman. She taught me that life isn't about jumping into the sack with whoever comes along, it's about caring and responsibility. And while it is true she turned out to be an evil robot minion of Dr. Evil, I suppose I really did... love her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that your wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felicity is touched.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Vanessa.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Austin, I can't pretend to understand everything you've gone through, but I trust you. I'll make you a deal: if we get out of here alive, I'll give monogamy a try.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, silly.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Groovy, baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to lure the guard inside and get his key.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, what if I pretend to be desperately ill with food poisoning? The guard, drawn by my cries of pain, will come to investigate. Meanwhile, you dig a pit and line it with makeshift punji sticks made from sharpened toothbrushes. The guard falls in, Bob's your uncle, and we've got the key. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felicity charges towards the window in the door, ripping open her blouse as she goes, showing her breasts to the guard. We, however, can't see them.</context>
      <utterance>That might work, but how about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think of these, my man?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unlocks the door and enters.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard follows her into the cell.</context>
      <utterance>It's very hot in here, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard advances on her.</context>
      <utterance>It's very hot in here, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm very firmly wedged.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She PUNCHES the guard right in the face and he collapses.</context>
      <utterance>If you want something done...</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin falls flat on his face with a THUMP and pops back up.</context>
      <utterance>Almost... got it!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go get my mojo!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A couple of henchmen place BOOTS on Dr. Evil. He drops to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>My frickin' mascot is stuck to the ceiling, OK? Not good. Papa not happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody get the stick. Hold on, Mini-Me.  Begin laser- He's interrupted by terrible FEEDBACK. Dr. Evil taps and blows on the mic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>. Begin- Worse FEEDBACK. He holds it farther away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The laser's coils begin to glow RED.</context>
      <utterance>Begin laser ignition sequence.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lunar alignment in 6 hours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your mojo, Austin?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC: It's Raining Men by THE WEATHERGIRLS Suddenly, the lights dim. The three He-Bots descend from the ceiling on trapezes and acrobatic rings, their muscles rippling.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The He-Bots flip off their trapezes and land in unison, like a perfect Olympic dismount. Their crotch nozzles flip up one by one.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out, baby, He-Bots!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't fight them without my mojo.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC: seductive music Felicity does a very seductive dance, with hip thrusts and bumps and grinds. The He-Bots EXPLODE, succumbing to her mojo.</context>
      <utterance>Who said anything about fighting?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smashing, Felicity, you were making me very horny, man! Extremely randy, indeed!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Austin and Felicity turn to see Fat Bastard lurking in the background.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, give the lads a show. Take of your top. Put 'em on the glass! Make 'em bounce. Let's have a look at your tits.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fat Bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fat Bastard, holds the beaker and is flanked by a dozen private army men.</context>
      <utterance>Looking for this, Mr. Powers?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me back my mojo, Fat Bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guards approach.</context>
      <utterance>I give the orders,  for brains. Guards, take them back to their cells.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on, let me ask you one question.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin is grossed out.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, I guess I owe you that much for a night of carnal ecstasy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of stupid ass question is that? I'm in' rich and I'm up to my tits in clean stinky.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't answer my question, are you happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about my girth isn't it? Sure I could lose a few pounds, but I could shiva git!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I'm not happy. Look at me, I'm a big fat slob. I've got bigger titties than you do! I've got more in' chins than a Chinese phone book. I've got more crack cheese than a in' dairy. I've nay seen ma willie in two years. That's enough time to declare it legally deed! I can't stop eating. I eat because I'm unhappy and I'm unhappy because I eat.  I'm caught in a cycle and there's no escape!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe inside that Fat Bastard there's a thin bastard, trying to get out</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fat Bastard hands over the mojo.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe there's big crap inside me trying to get out, jack-ass! Enough of your in' new age aphorisms. Listen, I've run the gamut of self- help books. "Food isn't love", right, but how do you get it from the page to the in' fork? I'm so weak, I hate myself. I'm for shite. Here, take the mojo.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BASTARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate you trying to reach me, no one can do it for me, I know this now. There's a hole in my soul that food won't fill. This is the beginning of a new me. I'm gonna go to the gym everyday. If you'll excuse me, there's someone I have to get in touch with and forgive... myself.  Sorry. I farted.  It's a long road ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin drinks the mojo.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on, I have something very important to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sound as a pound, my spuds are boiling. Fancy a shag?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, we don't have time.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, luv, let's hop on the good foot and do the bad thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Evil's taken his laser to the moon. The world is in danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, the moon. I think I know someone who can give us a lift.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's been some sort of delay in the launch of Apollo 11, Walter, but we understand that America's first manned mission to the moon will be blasting off shortly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gor blimey, you'd have to be a rocket scientist to figure this stuff out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASTRONAUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A technician closes the hatch and the countdown begins.</context>
      <utterance>I am a rocket scientist.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISSION COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will have lift-off in T minus 10 seconds... 9... 8... etc.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Felicity, if you get frightened, just hold my hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISSION COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have lift-off! Apollo 11 has cleared the tower and is heading for a rendezvous with the moon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yaaaaa-hoooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, you have achieved lunar orbit. How was that lift-off?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To be honest it was terrifying. It felt like sitting on top of a bomb. As I punched through the atmosphere, I said 'Oh my God!' and I soiled myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happens all the time in that situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean I soiled myself just now when I said oh 'my God!'</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basil, it was amazing!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prepare for moon landing. We only have one hour until Dr. Evil fires the laser!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mission control, the swinger has landed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is one small step for man, but a giant step for shagging. Can you imagine it, baby, weightless? The permutations are mind-boggling.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin plants a UNION JACK on the moon.</context>
      <utterance>Naughty boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God Save the Queen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISSION COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Queen? This is an American show, goddammit. Let's roll that footage we shot last week in the studio.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I can't hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ALARM BLARES.</context>
      <utterance>Pay me 100 billion dollars or see Washington DC destroyed!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I just can't hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Capital will be destroyed- The ALARM BLARES.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry! I just can't- I think it's that alarm.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(shouting)</context>
      <utterance>Could someone shut off that frickin' alarm? I'm trying to hold the free world hostage here. Honestly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please Dr. Evil, be reasonable. That's more money than is in the entire Federal Treasury!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh well, I guess you have one minute to- "show me the money"!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still don't know what that means. I can't show you the money because we don't have the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I suppose you're up shit's crick without a paddle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Austin notices something.</context>
      <utterance>Let's find Dr. Evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points. We see a profile through a sheet of frosted glass. It is Dr. Evil's distinctive profile, with a machine gun. Austin takes careful aim and FIRES. We see the SHADOW take the hit, and fall.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, you've done it! You got Dr. Evil!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I did, baby, I got my mojo working overtime.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, I'm going ahead. Cover my rear!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felicity runs ahead. Austin runs over to where the shadow came from. He sees that it was not Dr. Evil, but MINI-ME, carrying a little gun. Austin is ashamed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, behave!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin chokes back a tear.</context>
      <utterance>Poor little bugger. He's so small, he's like a dog or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin runs after her.</context>
      <utterance>Poor little bugger.  Felicity, be careful! Dr. Evil is still alive! Felicity?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, slap-head, turn around. Slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wall panel in the main chamber revolves, revealing FELICITY, enclosed in a glass tube.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't you forgetting something?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Felicity!  What have you done to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brightly colored GAS starts to fill the glass chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, she's not dead... yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about me Austin. You've got to save the world!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin is torn. He looks back and forth between Felicity and the laser which is on the other side of the room.</context>
      <utterance>It looks like you have a choice, Powers: save the world, or save your girlfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got my mojo back, man, I can do both.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman manning the laser's joystick begins to MOVE IT. Austin leaps across the room and reaches her just in time.</context>
      <utterance>We'll see. Fire the laser!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wrestles with her a moment and then KNOCKS IT ASKEW.</context>
      <utterance>Hands off my joystick, baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil hits a SELF-DESTRUCT button. An ALARM blares.</context>
      <utterance>Damn you, Powers!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The base is rocked by EXPLOSIONS.</context>
      <utterance>Warning! Self-destruct sequence initiated!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, Dr. Evil I told you I could do both.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin looks over. Felicity has slumped over in the tube.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you spoke too soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin BANGS on the glass with his fists.</context>
      <utterance>Noooooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is too late. Dr. Evil runs through the TIME PORTAL and gets away.</context>
      <utterance>Felicity! Felicity. Wake up! Wake up! Please God, don't take her away.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin looks up to the heavens. We see a quick--</context>
      <utterance>Felicity, you have to understand, I thought I had my mojo back. This isn't fair.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to commandeer this vehicle.  Hey, aren't you Hutch?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We see PAUL MICHAEL GLASER (STARSKY).</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL MICHAEL GLASER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Starsky.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID SOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin jumps in and the Torino speeds off. Dr. Evil's car disappears into a car wash which is a TIME PORTAL. The Torino follows. A sign at the car wash reads: "1911"</context>
      <utterance>I'm Hutch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Suddenly the ship tilts at a radical angle. LEONARDO DICAPRIO, KATE WINSLET, and JAMES CAMERON slide by.</context>
      <utterance>Iceberg, dead ahead!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES CAMERON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil and Austin slide backwards into the TIME PORTAL they just came from.</context>
      <utterance>I'm king of the world!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to kill you, you bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before you do that, know this: Austin, I am... your... father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I can't back that up. I was just grasping at straws. I had nothing. But isn't it interesting, Mr. Powers, you really have become a product of the Nineties.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're more interested in your job as glorified policeman than you are in love. You won the battle, but I won the war. Love means nothing, you've proved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't think that Felicity was going to die, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin looks over and sees a TIME PORTAL. Through it he can glimpse the lair, and Felicity.</context>
      <utterance>What a cowardly response. I'm disappointed really. You have the power to go back in time and save her, but it means letting me go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Mr. Powers, which is it going to be? Me or the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin runs through.</context>
      <utterance>Felicity!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like you have a choice: save the world, or save your girlfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin runs over to the glass tube and SMASHES HIS FIST through it. The glass SHATTERS and Austin pulls Felicity out. She gasps for air.</context>
      <utterance>I choose love, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Felicity, I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I thought-</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin kisses her for a long time. She starts to twitch. She struggles. She hits him in the head and he finally stops kissing her.</context>
      <utterance>That was another place and another time, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't. Breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, baby, I got a little over- stimulated.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fire the laser!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Use your mojo!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have it!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Austin turns and gives a 'who me?' look over his bottom. The woman arming the laser stumbles backwards into the directional control just as it FIRES.</context>
      <utterance>Trust me, you do!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace.</context>
      <utterance>Austin, you did it!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh.  I think I just got my mojo back. Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, you had it all along. No one can take your, mojo away from you!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Evil hits the SELF-DESTRUCT button and climbs aboard the rocket, which blasts off.</context>
      <utterance>Good-bye, Mr. Powers, for the last time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RADAR OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, you better have a look at this radar.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RADAR OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>don't know, sir. It's hard to describe. It's... it's-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid CRIES.</context>
      <utterance>Just a little prick!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All done!  Good lord, what is that? If I didn't know better I'd say it's a-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHINESE TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the STUDENTS, dressed in a green Mao suit and clutching a red book is caught looking out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Wang!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINESE TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pay attention!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINESE STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Comrade Teacher.  was distracted by that enormous flying-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RACHEL HUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rod?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROD STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Rachel?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL HUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROD STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like a giant-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peters!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any word from Austin?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've picked up his signal, but the lunar base seems to self-destructing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASIL EXPOSITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, if you can hear me, use the time portal! There's no time to get to the lunar module! Use the time portal!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, you have to get to the time portal!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come with me, Felicity! It's the only way out!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Austin, will I fit in the Nineties?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TIME PORTAL is fifty feet away. Austin and Felicity run towards it. In the foreground, are a stack of conveniently placed barrels. As they run behind the barrels, an obvious AUSTIN STUNT DOUBLE and an obvious FELICITY STUNT DOUBLE emerge in their place. The stunt doubles grab a winch hanging above them and cross over to the TIME PORTAL in a dramatic series of acrobatic flips and stunts. The stunt doubles run behind another conveniently placed pile of barrels. Austin and Felicity emerge in their place and run through the TIME PORTAL. The TIME PORTAL reads "1999".</context>
      <utterance>If I did, anyone can. Let's go, baby!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felicity smiles broadly, revealing that she now has TERRIBLE TEETH like Austin's.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry baby it takes some getting used to. Let me ask you Felicity, do you feel any side effects from the time travel?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm as healthy as a horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Felicity.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to get married?</utterance>
   <speaker>FELICITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
