<movie id="55" title="Backdraft">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OLDER KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're doing it wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNGER KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's hard, but we get a sense of the room in the whipping beam of light. Huge, dark coats lined up like sides of beef on steel batons. Bent, stained helmets hung like African masks. Beneath them BRIAN, 7, and STEPHEN, 12, are trying to struggle into a pair of the ludicrously massive coats over their pajamas.</context>
      <utterance>You're doing it wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't go like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who asked you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you do it like that it'll open in the fire. Then you'll get burned and</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's going to die?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian. He's not doing it right, dad. He never does it right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's have a look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your brother's right. If you don't fasten these correctly they could open and you'd get burned.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And DIE!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't let me die, would you, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McCaffreys are smarter than fire, Brian.  How 'bout lunch, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fireman shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's with the mouth? Where'd you grow up, a barn?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Firehouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- The station suddenly fills with the BELLOW of an ALARM</context>
      <utterance>Cute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A young fireman, ADCOX, appears with the dispatch card.</context>
      <utterance>Never fails...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Medium deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to come along, Brian? Watch the old man earn his keep?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've come along a dozen times, Stephen, give your brother a chance. We'll be back in a few minutes.  How 'bout it, sport?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dennis scoops Brian up and loads him into the fire engine cab. The other three firemen climb aboard and take their places.</context>
      <utterance>Sure!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian nods vigorously, taking the command seriously. Dennis smiles and is off, dragging a hoseline with his crew toward a doorway they disappear into. Brian climbs down from the cab.</context>
      <utterance>Stay near the truck.  And keep an eye out for us, huh? We're short handed today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGINEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian smiles to the pumper operator. He just wants a better look. And he gets it: Smoke turned evil and dark now, taking on purpose.</context>
      <utterance>Don't stray too far, little man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to call louder... But suddenly everything is happening very fast in slow motion: -- Brian can see Adcox testing the ceiling with a pike pole as Brian steps forward, under the power of a flame that beckons him as -- Dennis suddenly THROWS his body against Adcox, knocking him clear just as a flame EXPLODES DOWNWARD from the ceiling fully against him as -- All the building's windows BLOW OUT and it's like the sky's erupted for Brian, a burning hailstorm that falls and pelts the ground around him. Plaster, wood, and something metal that cracks against the pavement and spins slowly. A fire helmet. And Adcox is coming out the door now, blackened and torn, hopeless tears streaming down his face.</context>
      <utterance>Dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And, spotting Brian, he runs towards him. And the helmet spins and spins and Adcox keeps running, and the sky is raining fire, and the flame on the roof has risen up now to its full, horrifying size and it's laughing now, laughing at the little boy as the helmet finally stops spinning, and we read the printing on the neck guard.</context>
      <utterance>Get us some backup! We need some goddamn backup!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CHIEF FITZGERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian's sitting in the seat opposite.</context>
      <utterance>Is this a joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it was a joke, sir, you'd be laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF FITZGERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You walked out on this academy six years ago. One week to graduation. You think we forgot that? You think I did?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want another shot, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF FITZGERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, everybody remembers your old man. Being his son, all you had to do was breathe to graduate here. Dead Hero Father Rule. But you blew us off. Why should I take you back?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you remember, sir, my test scores were in the top --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF FITZGERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I don't give a damn what your test scores were, maybe you could have been a good firemen, but you had your shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need another one, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF FITZGERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, but it's out of my hands. Try again next year.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it isn't out of your hands or you wouldn't even have met me. If I push you have to let me back in. Dead Hero Father Rule. Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF FITZGERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if you graduate this academy, you've still got nine months of probation. That's hard duty, son. If you don't really love this job, it'll kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As we hear the BLOW OF A WHISTLE</context>
      <utterance>See you Monday. Sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Completely out of control.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they shoulder their way inside, another CANDIDATE appears holding proudly a fistful of sealed envelopes.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are we waiting for?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANDIDATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tim and everyone else but Brian eagerly tear into them. Brian nonchalantly shoulders up to the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Hot off the presses, guys. Station assignments.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barkeep turns and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>A beer, Willy!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if it isn't the littlest McCaffrey.  Hey! You break anything with that you buy it!  Sorry, there must be something wrong with my eyes. I keep thinking that's a fire department uniform.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The candidates are ripping open their assignments, exclaiming to each other: "All right! Engine 117! That's a slum! They get cookers every day!". "Oh no, Engine 10, that's a nice neighborhood"... Willy turns to the bulletin board behind him and unpins a stack of business cards.</context>
      <utterance>It's in my blood, Willy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. Well, let's have a look at what else was "in your blood". I always look forward to getting these, they make such a nice collage for the bar... "Assistant Director, Sales, Aspen Snowmobile Tours..."</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't offer the kinda growth and challenge I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh. And "Pioneer's Pride, Mobile Log Cabins". That was in your blood about six months wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Management were pin heads.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Laguna Jamming, Custom Surfboards"?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee sucked.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And just this year, "Brian's Sound Spectrum". Your own company even. Big step.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was ahead of my time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tim holds an envelope marked McCAFFREY out to Brian.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I've got a perfect little spot here for "Brian McCaffrey, Fireman"...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you even curious?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Engine 115, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you know? These are supposed to be sealed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucky guess.  And a case of scotch to a captain in station assignments.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You crooked son of a bitch. Why 115?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lots of fires. They promote faster there. Take a look at the last Lt.'s list, half the guys on it came from that battalion. Gotta think about your future, Timmy. 115's the station.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Brian's reaction</context>
      <utterance>Ah man, if you're gonna bribe your way into a station, why not 17 with me and your brother?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jennifer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for calling.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... I've been sorta keeping a low profile... the academy... I graduated today.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... I see you're still in the neighborhood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite. Just visiting. I live in Lincoln Park now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? What have you been up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I work for city hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? No kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Tim OPENS UP the hoseline, DRENCHING Brian.</context>
      <utterance>What, you think I just dried up and blew away when you left? The world does turn once in awhile Brian, even without your permission.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian ducks the stream and PULLS a length of hose near his feet, FLIPPING Tim. Brian JUMPS him, shuts off the hose and pins him to the pavement.</context>
      <utterance>Don't want you overheating, Brian!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian walks back toward Jennifer</context>
      <utterance>Okay okay! Uncle!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>You've certainly matured.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if nothing else, it's nice to know we can still be friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another in a series of fire engines HOWL past. Tim grabs Brian by the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be your friend, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go, man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he's laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Tim! You crazy motherfucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'cha got?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Box alarm. Walton Ave.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll meet ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man. Something sure put a crimp in his evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The brownstone fire quickly transforms itself into noisy clouds of dirty white steam. And one of the firemen is coming back out now, walking toward Brian. When he's just a few yards away he pulls off his air mask and helmet and we shudder with Brian, because the man is a dead ringer for HIS FATHER.</context>
      <utterance>Backdraft.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look what we have here. Nice costume. Rent it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to thank you for coming to my graduation, Stephen. It was a great inspiration to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pats Brian's cheeks, leaving behind large charcoal smears.</context>
      <utterance>So you're going to fight fires now, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't work on you.  See ya around, little brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not likely.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, see you're wrong already. Had a talk with Chief Fitzgerald, and we decided in the interest of brotherly love, that maybe you shouldn't be way over on the other side of town. So starting tomorrow, your assigned to company 17. My company.  One case of scotch, you're getting cheap in your old age, Brian... And Stephen turns for his own men, Tim staring at Brian as clouds of smoke drift past like ghosts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen is leaning in the doorway, watching him.</context>
      <utterance>If you stare any longer Stevie, I'll start charging you admission.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a cause?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are the glory boys actually showing interest in Investigation's work? I may have a stroke.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale's flashlight finds a wall socket that he pries loose and holds up to the light. He lowers it, takes in the walls, the room.</context>
      <utterance>The glory boys just want to finish their report so they can go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna have to wait a few days on this one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're already climbing into the wagon. The driver smiles creepily.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you forgot... this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian looks across the fireground, sees his brother walking back to the fire engine. They share a brief, edgy glance.</context>
      <utterance>We always leave something for the dogs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid stares at him without a glimmer of recognition.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Sean. What's goin' on, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes his hand into a talking puppet.</context>
      <utterance>It's Uncle Brian. Y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid drops his toy truck and flees inside.</context>
      <utterance>"Spinach? We don't need no stinking spinach". Remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom! Mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A warm looking woman, 30's, HELEN, comes around the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Hellooo...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Helen. Man, you look great.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a tentative hug.</context>
      <utterance>You look like... Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Bout written you off. How long have you been in town?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four months.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four months?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen's expression suddenly saddens.</context>
      <utterance>I know, I know, Should'a called. I've been really busy. I joined the fire department.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little kid is peeking fearfully from the kitchen doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Brian...  You guys... you really know how to put each other through it, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Sean? Jeez, he's a giant.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you'd be surprised what three years can do to a kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sean, come on out, man. What, you forget your favorite uncle?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stephen told him you were killed in a hot tub accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the kid runs unexpectedly away, angry.</context>
      <utterance>Dad was kidding, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that's two things to strangle Stephen for. Where is he, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An embarrassed sting.</context>
      <utterance>Stephen's not staying here now, Brian. He moved out last April.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, man, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys ought to try picking up a phone once in awhile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stripped to the waist, Stephen's bent-over cleaning out the guts of the inboard motor. He looks confused to see Brian.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wrong thing to say. Stephen turns back to his work.</context>
      <utterance>I talked to Helen...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen straightens up, his forearms smudged with grease. Brian admires the unwashed cereal bowls and peeling deck paint.</context>
      <utterance>...Man, I thought dad's boat was finally retired to the family graveyard. Don't you worry about falling out of this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like what you've done with the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen tosses him a beer from the fridge. As Brian pops it, he sees the small pile of city-issue gallon size cans in the corner. Armorall, solvent, extinguisher foam.</context>
      <utterance>It's comin' along... want a beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been ripping off fire stations?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian winces at the music coming out of shot speakers.</context>
      <utterance>It's old stuff Adcox gave me that the department was going to throw out anyway. Still good enough though for this tub.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian lifts one of the tapes -- an 8-track -- and holds it carefully in his palm as if it were a rare and fragile relic.</context>
      <utterance>Bachman Turner Overdrive?  ...Buffalo Springfield?... Stephen Bishop? Oh man...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, an actual operating 8-track.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you've never seen one before?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the Field Museum once.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It works.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It worked when you were in sixth grade.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People actually used to pay you for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Millions, Stephen -- And sexual favors.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheep don't count.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? What about Laura --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian moves over to another speaker.</context>
      <utterance>That was never proved.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you come here, Brian?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to know why you messed with my station assignment. I mean, is this really gonna have to one of those big brother -- little brother "you broke my GI Joe and I'm still pissed" games?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it with you, man, huh? How do you manage to keep coming up with new and amazing ways to screw up? That scotch bullshit? Am I really supposed to believe you came crawling back home because you suddenly felt heart strings moan for the family biz? You were bankrupt, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You don't know me --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you cold, Brian. The scary thing is, you probably could have faked it for awhile. But you see, in this job there's no place to hide. Isn't like selling log cabins. You have a bad day here -- someone dies. And that's not fucking good enough. Want another beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's it? Big bad brother's gonna ride my ass till I cough blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian staples the last of the audio cord in place and switches on the tape player. The cabin fills with sharp, crystal clear -- Stephen Bishop.</context>
      <utterance>Big bad brother is going to treat you like any other probie -- that I don't think is going to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's only so much technology can do.  Thanks for the beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the speakers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, I told myself a million times I didn't want to be a fireman. I said bullshit to that line about tradition and family legacy. I know I split, and I know how you felt...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you know. You know what it felt like.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta do this, Stephen. I gotta know.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're gonna find out, Brian. Don't be late tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tim, in ladder truck 46, waves a small bye-bye as both rigs begin heading down the street.</context>
      <utterance>You're too late, probie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian bolts full-out for the engine. At the last instant before he falls on his face a fireman reaches out and drags him aboard.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it, Stephen...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Pumper driver, SCHMIDT, pops in a howling ROCK TUNE as they zoom off.</context>
      <utterance>Why baby McCaffrey, how ya doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know this rug rat?</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian shouts over the noise to GRINDLE, 35, one more seat down.</context>
      <utterance>Know him? I practically raised him.  And he never calls, he never writes...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grindle sticks his nose out the window, sniffs, then begins buckling up his coat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Brian and Adcox fasten up their own equipment --</context>
      <utterance>Boys, I do believe we have a barbecue...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate it when we gotta fucking go look for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh these moments do try me...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whistling to himself, Adcox SMASHES the brass coupling through the passenger window, runs the line through and SMASHES it out the other window before connecting up to the hydrant. Stephen and Grindle pull hose off the bed and move out. Brian's so jacked up he can't get his air tank on right. Schmidt calmly helps him into his gear.</context>
      <utterance>Be gentle.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen, Adcox and Grindle are crouched at the door, ready to go. Brian takes a hose roll and runs to catch up when he's cut-off by dazed Latin workers shouting incoherently at him in SPANISH.</context>
      <utterance>It's only rock 'n roll, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian pushes past the workers and takes his position on the hose line. Stephen reaches over and re-adjusts Brian's air tank strap.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, probie! How 'bout it, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen eases the door open. Thick smoke rolls sickly out over their heads.</context>
      <utterance>You're doing it wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And in they go...</context>
      <utterance>Stay beside me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wash it to the windows?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we'll hit the son of a bitch head on.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gonna flash, Stevie. We gotta get behind it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adcox and Grindle shrug and pull their helmets down tight, expecting the worst. Adcox opens up the nozzle, turning loose a high pressure BLAST OF WATER into the ceiling. The fire SCREAMS in manic anger and HEAVES a cloud of HOWLING steam that WHIRLS back and BAKES them like lobsters. Brian gasps for air as swirling ash batters his facemask. A window somewhere EXPLODES. Somebody shouts. Christ, you can't see anything. Stephen HOOPS in victory.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, listen to it. It's a pussy. It'll just steam on us. It won't flash. Go high in the ceiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya love it, probie?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in heaven, Lt.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian runs back to the wall to hook up his hose roll to the building water system. He goes to unscrew the cap with his hydrant wrench but it keeps slipping off the nut.</context>
      <utterance>Hook us up to a stand-pipe.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian finally gets it hooked up and runs back.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, how 'bout man, huh? We're gonna loose this!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Otis, is it...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it, where's our backup? Where's the second-in companies?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, man. John Wayne time.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The firemen hesitate. PENGELLY, the Truck Company Lt., looks at Stephen with concern.</context>
      <utterance>Dig in!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crews immediately gather in the center of the floor. They turn over tables, chairs, anything to form a barrier. A circling of the wagons. -- BOOM! rush-rush-rush -- BOOM! Each louder than the last. Stephen and Brian are ducked behind an overturned desk. Adcox and Krizminski clutch hoselines like frontiersmen's Winchesters.</context>
      <utterance>Dig in, goddamn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- rush-rush-rush -- CRAAAASH!! On an instant the world comes apart as all four walls of factory windows EXPLODE in a hail of glass. A wave of HOWLING FLAME POURS IN after it, SHRIEKING and HISSING. At the same moment, part of the floor beside a heavy sewing machine GIVES WAY and a ladderman, SANTOS, FALLS THROUGH, grabbing the edges at the last minute as flames BELLOW UP from underneath. He SCREAMS as his grip loosens. Grindle leaps to the ladderman's side, grabbing his arms and coat. Brian hesitates just an instant and Stephen SHOVES him out of the way to back up Grindle.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna love this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adcox's taken the hoseline and is opening fire. Water and flame crash and snarl across the floor in a blood curdling ROAR. It's a thrashing, murderous standoff. Stephen and Grindle have got Santos but the angle's bad. Blow it now and all three could take a header. Santos is panicking, losing his grip. Grindle bores his eyes into the man's with the calm and conviction of Moses.</context>
      <utterance>Help... Oh God...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They may all die, but they won't leave him. He calms a little, hangs on till they PULL him out of harm's way. Adcox continues with the hose as suddenly, everyone HITS the deck as the fire EXPLODES over them, BURSTING their coats into flame. Tim's company opens up their line, WASHING everybody down before CHARGING after the fire. A ladderman, NIGHTENGALE, steps on Brian's back.</context>
      <utterance>You go, we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHTENGALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian, stunned, sits up, his coat and helmet smoking. Stephen seems totally unaffected and is already on his feet and over the top of the barricade, the others backing him as he mercilessly drives the fire back, trapping it finally into a corner. The fire hisses, spits, shakes the walls with its furious anger. But it's all bluster now, the fire's dying.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry man, I thought you were dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENGELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stephen! BC's on the radio. Says they think a civilian got left behind downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adcox leads Tim downstairs. Brian looks shaken up. Stephen helps him roughly to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Adcox! Take Tim and do a search.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian burns at that and shakes his brother's arm off.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you fold on me now, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian's walking over to clear the hoseline when he hears it. small voice. Faint. "Help me..."</context>
      <utterance>Clear the hose for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody hears. -- Brian takes off down the other steps on his own.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I think it's coming from a different staircase.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got one!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sea of media flashbulbs ERUPTS in his face. The press have arrived in force, crowding the street. Brian pushes through them to a clear spot on the far side of the engine. Two fire paramedics rush over as he lowers the figure.</context>
      <utterance>I got somebody! I got somebody!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The paramedics suddenly stop their efforts. Turn to Brian.</context>
      <utterance>Is she... Is she alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARAMEDIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They step aside. Brian looks down. The woman looks strange. Mostly because she's a heavy store DRESSING DUMMY. The paramedics burst into laughter. Brian, looking pale and shaken, turns and walks away. He passes Grindle and Tim, sitting on the pumper's tailboard helping the REAL woman that was found inside.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid you're a little too late with this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Photographers have appeared and are flashing the woman. Dizzy, Brian wanders off, tries to help out with the choking clog of singed factory employees before finally turning quickly into</context>
      <utterance>Sorry to hear about the mannequin. I heard you two were close.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone else does too. Jennifer. Dressed now in a long expensive coat, she's standing at the end of the alley with a clipboard. Brian, ashes smeared across an ashen face, spittle on his chin, doesn't notice her.</context>
      <utterance>Shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen isn't pale. He's flushed and buoyant. All this hasn't taken anything from him. It's made his day.</context>
      <utterance>You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen leans against the wall. Folds his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Fine. I'm a little busy right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, you got an awful short memory for direct orders. I told you to stay beside me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- C'mon, Stephen.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen turns to leave. Brian yells after him.</context>
      <utterance>-- You split the team, man. And what was that crap with the standpipe? You'd think you and a hose were never introduced before.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it Stephen!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I told you to stay next to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I was doin' it! I was up there fucking doin' it. You don't know, man, you don't know what I did!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you did was drop the ball, Probie. Get that right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENGELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen turns to walk away. Pauses.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Stevie! They're callin' for ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Stephen leaves, we see that Jennifer's been standing at the end of the alley, listening to them. She's turns and walks as Brian looks up. We register his surprise. He watches her head toward a dynamic-looking guy in his 40s, ALDERMAN SWAYZAK, surrounded by reporters.</context>
      <utterance>Bet 30,000 dollars a year and twenty two days a month off sounded pretty good twelve weeks ago, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger, Paul... How's it going, guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another fire in this district. Getting to be Cinder Alley up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands Swayzak a clipboard.</context>
      <utterance>You used that last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Probie! We're still workin' here, man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stephen man, what's going through that guy's head? Takin' it on in the first room... this shit's happening too often. It could've flashed. Should've flashed.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it didn't. Guy knows.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adcox sees Brian. Smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Guy's lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, baby McCaffrey. First one's the clincher. You did okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Lt. might have something to say about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, everybody screws up some, Brian. You're working for the toughest Lt. on the job. Saw him once pick up a probie he thought was moving too slow and throw him into a burning building. It's just bad luck you're family.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, when you're in there... in the fire... do you ever see...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon ladies, let's roll some hose...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian turns and sees out the window Jennifer and Swayzak standing near Rimgale's red fire dept. sedan.</context>
      <utterance>-- Never mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alderman Swayzak.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Investigator Rimgale.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swayzak's leaning on it. We sense the dislike between them. Swayzak steps aside. Rimgale pops the trunk.</context>
      <utterance>I need to get in the trunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awful expensive shoes to be wearing at a fireground, Alderman. But then I guess you haven't been to too many fires.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to talk to you about Alan Seagrave's death. We still haven't gotten a fire report from your office.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have an answer as soon as I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People are asking how a prominent taxpayer got stuffed through the windshield of his own car. They're asking me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--The point is, Investigator, you haven't even told us yet if the fire was accidental. We're starting to get the feeling your office is dragging out this case to embarrass the Alderman because of his fire dept. reorganization program --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- You mean his firehouse closing program, -- Don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd just be very disappointed if it turned out your office was playing politics.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale cuts him off with the shutting of his trunk lid.</context>
      <utterance>-- Because I'm not. I care about this city, and I care about this department --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he walks back to the burned building.</context>
      <utterance>Alderman, I have a remarkably uncomplicated job. To decide if a fire's arson, and if so catch the pain in the ass doing it. But to be honest, if my methodical investigative methods just happen to muck up the campaign of certain mayor wanna-bees, well, I guess I can't say I sleep any less peacefully.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I could just fire the son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen's leaning out of an upstairs window. As the TV cameras turn, he drops down onto a fire engine hose bed and pops right into Swayzak's face with a murderous grin.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Swayzak!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grindle and Santos start walking for Stephen. Brian's there, following after them.</context>
      <utterance>We almost lost a whole company up there, Swayzee buddy. Isn't any back- up since you closed '33. And we really appreciate it, the guys and me. Honest. I know you've got my vote for mayor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look Lt., I'm on your side. If there's a problem, please, work with our task force to fix it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, your famous task force... three guys have already died this year because of the cuts made by your "task force"...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen silences Grindle with an outstretched hand. Swayzak leans close, out of earshot of the cameras.</context>
      <utterance>Stevie, c'mon man...</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see that funny glow that's starting to blink in the corner of your eye, Lt? That's your career dissipation light -- and it just went into overtime.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swayzak holds his ground. It's a tense, out of control moment between them. Rimgale turns from his work, watches Stephen with concern. Adcox suddenly inserts himself face-to-face with Swayzak and we see the raw hatred.</context>
      <utterance>If anybody's light's gonna blink, it's yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swayzak holds Adcox's gaze, then turns for his car. Brian watches Jennifer climb in beside her boss.</context>
      <utterance>You're in firemanland now, Swayzak. Do yourself a favor and just walk away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennifer shrugs as they pull away.</context>
      <utterance>This is your city job?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Franny. She likes firemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adcox watches Brian and Tim exchange looks. Tim shrugs. Brian sighs and pulls out the pike poles, starts across the floor before freezing suddenly at a murderous GROWL. Brian turns and sees a DOG. Sort of. It has the rib cage of a wild beast, fangs, long greasy hair. It blocks his way, SNARLING with hate.</context>
      <utterance>Tim, fill out the alarm card.  Clean the pipe poles, wipe down the ladders and hang some hose.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's The Thing. You can't stay unless he likes you. Slobber drools out of its mouth as it GROWLS.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian wipes some of the crusted grime from his face, looks back and forth between Franny and The Thing, and sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Have you guys got something against dalmatians?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian compares himself to the praise heaped on Stephen.</context>
      <utterance>Could you believe that fire? Man! First day! There I was, Adcox and me, pullin' that lady right out of the fire's fuckin' throat! I love it here -- No surround and drown for this company. Fighting 17th! Goddamn Stephen's amazing. You see how he took that fire by the balls? I'm gonna be that good some day, you watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know what Stephen said to me, right when all the shit was coming hard? "You never know till the moment the fire stares you down if you're just gonna do this job or be great at it".</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian shuts off his shower and walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Ah man, is he usin' that line now on you? What, you think he made that little gem up? Jesus Christ, I used to have to listen to my old man use that every morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian and Tim rush for their equipment. Grindle grabs their arms.</context>
      <utterance>-- C'mon! C'mon! Go! Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hustles them across the apparatus floor, through a doorway, and into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>No! C'mon! This way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENGELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dinner, Probies. Get started.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody digs in. The table is a craze of half a dozen different conversations. On the TV mounted above on the wall are news shots of Seagrave's body sticking out of the windshield. Adcox stands and tinks his glass with a spoon for silence.</context>
      <utterance>Or we feed you to The Thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, please... As 17's official toastmaster --</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And bullshitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adcox puts his arm affectionately around the mannequin, seated with honor at the head of the table. Right beside The Thing.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Santos. Did I happen to mention that you were cut out of my will?  I think it appropriate that we recognize the two asswipes -- I mean probationary firemen -- among us who today were baptized officially into the world of Old Man Fire. First to Tim, who despite being handicapped at birth with a rather dull expression and a really hideous pair of ears, not only took on the beast but pulled from its clutches -- assisted by a more famous and brilliant firefighter -- me -- a kicking and screaming civilian that will probably end up suing us for breaking her fingernail.  And to Brian, who's own contribution was both more beautiful and less likely to sue.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, when I heard that both McCaffrey brothers were going to be assigned together here, well, my heart was filled with... a sudden desire to transfer.  So raise a glass, lads. To funny- looking Tim, and the McCaffrey brothers, who despite years of getting on each other's nerves have managed with great effort... to still be pissed off at each other. Gentlemen!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPANY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The klaxon suddenly rings. Two bells. The ladder guys groan and get up.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll keep it warm for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shuffle for the door. As Brian passes,</context>
      <utterance>Okay, company dismissed. -- See ya guys tonight at Fitzgerald's retirement party.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want a ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian --  -- See ya tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHEERS as a one joke gift after another is laid on the Chief. Stephen sees his ex-wife, Helen, dancing with another man. He turns away.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santos and Grindle walk up.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta change the view...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian sees Jennifer across the room. She looks great. Refined as she expertly works the room, schmoozing and hugging and calling various politicos by their first name. As she speaks to one, a waiter offers a drink. As she accepts, a bottle appears over her shoulder and splashes it with red syrup.</context>
      <utterance>Heard you didn't make the list for captain, man. I'm sorry... Stephen just shrugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With grenadine, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her attention broken, the politico has slipped away. Annoyed, Jennifer leads Brian aside and speaks low, but angrily at him.</context>
      <utterance>Oooh, very sophisticated. Having fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm not the same girl who had nothing better to do than wrap her legs around you on a Saturday night. This isn't about fun. I'm working here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carrying Swayzak's notebook?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you something. Martin Swayzak is going to be this town's next mayor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Swayzak. Humanity's last hope. How can you work for that guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you think Marty came here tonight? Because he cares about your department. You don't know how hard he works. You don't know about his programs helping West Side --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- All I know is that his programs are getting firemen hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennifer instantly cuts off as a well-dressed COUPLE passes and switches stunningly into schmmoze-mode.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. Marty's plan is only about efficiency. I've got two cousins on the job, you think I'd work for him if I didn't believe in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Tom, how nice to see you. I know Marty'll be very happy you came. Thanks so much for the donation.  Marie... how's little Kevin? Really? Seen the polls? This is the year... They move away. Jennifer turns to Brian and switches just as fast back to their argument.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- The thing that really makes me angry is the way your union has -- Brian can't help it. He cracks up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that? Oh man, you have picked up a few moves since John Paul II Boulevard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well I like to think I'm just a little past hanging out on JP II watching the Irish pick fights and Litwalks barf in the planters.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian turns and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>I seem to remember some pretty good nights on JP II.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuck, what a scumbag.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' city transferred Sally three months ago out of parking violations into Swayzak's office. Now I gotta pay my own goddamn tickets and she's stuck with an asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pay more?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, I don't believe this shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they hold it up to Stephen we see a photo spread titled</context>
      <utterance>Somebody get a shovel! You seen this, Stephen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="53">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Probationary Fireman Brian McCaffrey, on his very first fire, showed the kind of bravery and courage of a veteran firefighter when he risked life and limb to double-check a burning floor alone, emerging victoriously with Anna Rodriguez, a seamstress for the North Shore Clothing Company... McCaffrey first gained prominence as the subject of a 1972 Pulitzer Prize winning photograph taken at the scene of his father's death..." The old photo is there too. Brian and his dad's helmet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen glances over the headlines.</context>
      <utterance>Whadda we gonna do about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other firemen jump in with drink orders. Dozens of them.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know, I think it's a union bylaw that if a guy gets in the paper -- especially if it's bullshit -- he owes the company a drink. In fact...  ...I'll have a double. On the hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tim shows him the magazine. Brian reads with horror as Alderman Swayzak appears beside him.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian McCaffrey, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian, this is my boss, Alderman Swayzak.  Brian's a big fan of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Big fan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm a huge fan of what you did to save that woman, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, I think there's been a mistake. I didn't save that woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No need to be modest, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you don't understand, I saved a mannequin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- That really was incredibly work you did. You and your brother, fighting fires together, helluva image, isn't it? You must feel lucky to be assigned under his command.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every little boy's fantasy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian, let me come to the point. I'd like to offer you a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This one's still with the fire department. One of our best investigators, Don Rimgale, is working on a very difficult, visible case right now. We think he could use another pair of hands and you're exactly the kind of guy I want representing us: An authentic hero from a traditional firefighting clan.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we got all kinds of traditions -- like dying young.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian looks at Jennifer, then smiles at Swayzak.</context>
      <utterance>Not every job in the fire department comes with a tombstone, Brian. This could be a great opportunity to move... beyond a fire engine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- A man suddenly steps between them to pump Swayzak's hand. Brian shakes his head and walks away. Swayzak shoots a concerned glance at Jennifer. She catches up with him at the buffet table.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks anyway, Mr. Swayzak, but fire engines sorta run in my family. Politics don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, took you all of thirty seconds to blow that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Jennifer, he's just another North-Side jag-off with a mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian, do you always have to be so stupid? Think about your future for once.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now you suddenly care about my future?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I didn't mean to take a piece out of you back there, I just thought you'd call when you came back. You didn't and...  Don't blow it just because of this garbage between us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across the room, Stephen's at the buffet, watching Helen dance with her fireman date, the drinks hammering him hard.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, sorry if I made you look bad in front of your boss. But I'm not gonna be a poster boy for him, I'm trying to do something here. There's five hundred smoke eaters in this room that do that stuff for real every day. Tell Swayzak to talk to one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENGELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw man, how can she dance with that guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate that guy. He's a dispatcher. I hate his voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever...</utterance>
   <speaker>PENGELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, I know women have gotta bang somebody, but why that son of a bitch? Stephen gives Pengelly an icy, sideways look.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen smiles and pushes off the bar -- right for Helen as she dances.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Stevie, he's an asshole...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Helen, I wanted to talk to you a second about Sean...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stephen, I'm kinda busy here, can we talk about this later?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin', Stephen?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson steers her away but Stephen isn't done yet. He dogs them.</context>
      <utterance>Jackson.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with right now? He's your son for christ's sake. He's --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Stephen, what about that dumb ass brother of yours, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen suddenly PUNCHES Jackson.</context>
      <utterance>Savin' a mannequin... How fuckin' stupid can a guy get?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't talk about my brother like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Stephen PLOWS into Jackson. Another fireman JUMPS to Jackson's aid. And Brian's there, defending his brother, PUNCHING OUT a fireman. The crowd finally pulls the two apart.</context>
      <utterance>Here we go...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it, Stephen, lay off!  You stupid dumbshit, you never know when to fucking quit, do you? You ever wonder why your career's in the fucking toilet? Why you're gonna be stuck a Lt. for life?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen takes a step for the bar -- then suddenly turns and JUMPS Jackson again. Brian pulls him off and drags him for the door.</context>
      <utterance>No.  I need a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Jennifer watches Brian lead Stephen out the door.</context>
      <utterance>You don't need a drink, man. You need to get outta here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah those McCaffreys... just hate leaving a party with anyone left standing...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen pushes Brian away and promptly stumbles to the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>I'm okay... leave me alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you got a 'roid going with Jackson or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian stands there and folds his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, he's nothin'. It's just sometimes... sometimes you just gotta punch somebody out, y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian lends an arm.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think I can get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Brian, a photographer. Maybe I can get on the cover of LIFE magazine, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, let's crawl home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He clearly can't. Brian slips them off.</context>
      <utterance>If you'd get out of my fuckin' way. I could take my own goddamn shoes off...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's just a grim wall lamp above Stephen's face.</context>
      <utterance>You're such a pain in the ass... You've always been a pain in the ass...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, it's too damn bright in here... Like a goddamn spotlight... I'm goin' blind...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian turns off the dim light. Stephen's breathing deepens.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... too bright...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian tucks the blanket around him.</context>
      <utterance>They don't know... they don't know what I hear in there...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen's voice drifts off into sleep. Brian watches a moment, the rare look of peace on his brother's face, then leaves.</context>
      <utterance>...This boat could be okay, huh?... Take it out weekends... Sean 'n me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian stops a beat. Rubs his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Knock it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone grows suddenly silent.</context>
      <utterance>This everything you wanted?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you guys at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, we just about got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sally must be finally ironing your shirts.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sight of uniform is too much for her. Her eyes cloud.</context>
      <utterance>It's just new. Couple'a shifts and it'll be as thrashed as the rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adcox reaches out and lets her weep on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss him... I just miss him, y'know?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen leans down close.</context>
      <utterance>This job... This fuckin' job sometimes... To buy it trying to go the extra yard, man, that's one thing, but to buy it just because there wasn't any back-up... it's bullshit...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat of understanding between them. Stephen looks back at the house.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's bullshit. So what? Fuck Swayzak. Fuck 'em all. We don't go into fires for them. You know that. Christ, you taught me that.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know Knowlton pretty well?</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adcox can't help but smile.</context>
      <utterance>Kind of an asshole, wasn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Biggest in two battalions.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna be okay, man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she going to get the divorce?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A ladderman, WASHINGTON, walks in with a memo.</context>
      <utterance>Hell if I know, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody clasps Pengelly on the shoulder. "Way to go". "All right, man". Brian turns and sees Stephen out on the apparatus floor, watching. Watches. Pengelly's younger than him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Pengelly, you made the captain's list!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tim picks up a roll of hose, 50 pounds, throws it over his shoulder and runs with Adcox to the foot of the building. There's a fixed standpipe that Adcox ties into as Tim drags the other end inside and up a flight of stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Alright... Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian lifts another hose roll under his arm and runs for the building.</context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian runs up two flights to meet Tim and connect his end. Tim heads down for another roll as Brian drags his up another two flights. It's a bitch. Sweating, he barrels back down the stairs, passing Tim coming up with another roll.</context>
      <utterance>That isn't a football, probie. Get it on your shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tim flips him off. Brian laughs and sprints for another roll.</context>
      <utterance>Having fun, fireman?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian holds it under his arm and takes off. Stephen grabs a roll himself, hoists it to his shoulder and runs alongside.</context>
      <utterance>You're not breaking any records, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian lifts it to his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Your shoulder. Like this!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come to the doorway. Instead of stopping, Stephen follows Brian in and runs alongside up the stairs. Without a word spoken it's become a race between them. Brian's face explodes in sweat. His heart pounds as they go up flight after flight. The hose rolls weigh a 100 pounds. A thousand. Neck 'n neck all the way; grunting, their throats burning, only one flight from the roof Stephen STUMBLES and SCRAPES his leg. Brian pauses. Stephen's already back on his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Pick it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian does, Stephen already gaining on him -- getting ready to pass him -- when they burst gasping out onto the roof, Brian the "winner" by a nose. Stephen drops his hose roll, sticks his face into Brian's, -- And laughs. Unsure, Brian starts to join in. Stephen stops suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>Run, damn you!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roll the hose.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adcox and Tim, down below, have already disappeared back into the station.</context>
      <utterance>What, are you kidding? By myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see now what Stephen apparently doesn't. He was scraped badly, his pant leg torn and leaking dark circles of blood.</context>
      <utterance>You heard me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, is it the stairs? Christ, I'll let you win next time.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a problem with drilling, probie?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Lt., I don't have a problem with drilling. But let's just have one drill. Not one for the company and one for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen turns and walks away. Brian stands there watching him in blind fury, finally exploding.</context>
      <utterance>Roll the hose.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An awkward beat between them that's interrupted suddenly by the station alarm klaxon. Stephen smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn you Stephen, I'm not gonna quit. You hear me!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thank God for fires...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My baby! My baby's still up there!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTALION CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen doesn't even pause and enters the building. Brian hesitates a beat, then follows.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on a sec, Stevie, we got a hoseline coming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen, with just his axe, CHASES up the stairs at the fire, HAMMERING at the flaming boards. The fire retreats into another room, SLAMMING the door shut behind it. Brian struggles up the stairs. The two of them slide up on either side of the closed door, Stephen cradling his axe like a SWAT team shotgun. The door breathes in and out and something animal scratches and snarls on the other side. Brian can feel the panic rising in his throat. That thing behind the door, that slobbering, evil thing. It wants out. It wants... him.</context>
      <utterance>Don't take that kind of shit from it! Don't let it know you're scared! Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, Stephen, let's wait for the hose team...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen HAMMERS the lock with his axe and KICKS the door open. A WALL OF FLAME ROARS out past their cheeks, then BACKWASHES in.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to it, Brian... Jump when I say... It won't get us.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen picks up the door, and using it as a shield CHARGES into the flames. Brian tries to follow but the fire WELLS UP, cutting him off. He hesitates. It's that goddamn flame again, leering at him. Daring him. It BUCKS suddenly, DROPPING Brian to his knee. He GROANS in pain. -- And now Adcox and Grindle are coming up the stairs with a hoseline WASHING DOWN the room. Clouds of furious steam bellow out and across the ceiling. Nobody could be alive in there. Except Stephen. His entire outfit smoldering, he emerges from the clouds like a fucking god, carrying in one arm a gasping child.</context>
      <utterance>Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SANTOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen walks up. Sits down beside him.</context>
      <utterance>They think she's gonna live...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I waited... I would have fucking waited...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what it's about, Brian. The point is there was a kid in there. And what if there'd been two? I went in because that's what I do. It's my way. It's dad's way. It isn't everybody's way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad's way? Where did he tell you that? In a fucking seance?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian lingers only a moment before standing.</context>
      <utterance>You said you wanted to know something, Brian. What did you learn today?  What do you say, Brian, huh? Time to move on?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian hands Stephen his helmet and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, Stephen... You win... You're the best, man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SECRETARY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian McCaffrey on line two for Jennifer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take it in my office.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go get him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Brian in his apartment.</context>
      <utterance>Brian?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking about what you said the other night... If the offer's still on the table, I'd like to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Okay. I'll arrange things with your assignment captain.  Marty's a good man, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian hangs up. He stares at it a moment, then SLAMS it against the wall. Jennifer stares at the phone with something almost like sadness.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid is dying a thousand deaths of humiliation.</context>
      <utterance>...So stop me if I get this wrong... The fire's almost out... You're upstairs on the unburned floor checking for heat. You've been told by your Battalion Chief, your Captain, by me, not to do anything up there until ordered. But now the itch starts, and all of a sudden comes the Glory Boy Flash: Hey, I'm a hero. Heroes don't just stand around. So on your own you decided to punch out a window for ventilation. Was that before or after you noticed you were standing in a lake of gasoline?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid shuffles off hang-dog. Rimgale's angry gaze falls on Brian.</context>
      <utterance>You could've crispered half your company with that little stunt, but more importantly you wrecked the physical evidence I use to prove it's arson. You've made my day longer, Probie. Go home and think about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, I'm Brian McCaffrey. Your new assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Rimgale walks into his office, leaving Brian marooned in the doorway. Stepping behind a small partition, Rimgale changes his shirt. Brian can just glimpse from where he stands a horrible burn that has consumed most of Rimgale's stomach. Rimgale catches the look.</context>
      <utterance>Your Dennis' kid.  I work alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you still here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get used to me, Inspector. I'm not going anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then go find a corner. I don't want you in my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should get something straight here. I was assigned to this office by the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale glances at his watch, puts on his coat, and picks up a small paper bag.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I knew your father, he had a helluva reputation on this job. But that don't mean you get any slack. Swayzak sends you down here, okay, I gotta eat you, that's the rules and I got nothing to say about that. But Swayzak or no, you live with me. Step out of line, and I don't care who knows you, I'll swing the hammer.  You think you're the first?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pest control.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shadow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin', Ronald. Staying comfortable?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't think you'd make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't miss this for the world, pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He works for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he a fireman?  I like firemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald's eyes pick up Brian's name on his prison ID badge.</context>
      <utterance>You like everybody, Ronald.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian McCaffrey...  Oh this is really a treat. Brian McCaffrey. Lost a dad to the animal, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, do I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about my -- Rimgale silences Brian with a threatening hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knock it off. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him about me, Shadow?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronald here likes telephones. Used to tape wooden matches to the bell striker and wrap it in cotton. Came up with a whole little thing there, didn't you Ronald? When you got bored, what did you do? You just started making calls... mostly day care centers and retirement homes, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he tell you how we finally met?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody cares, Ronald.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, but it's a good story, Shadow. You're depriving our famous young friend here...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE IN CORRIDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop helps Ronald to his feet and all four are marching down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... Ronald Bowland...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was on State Street, right?... Just your basic warehouse torch for the owner. Cakewalk. But the animal... turned on me... 'Ol Shadow here, he shows up -- whole place is going like hell -- my hair, my hands... could've just let the animal take me -- but Shadow, he's a good camper, so he tries to pull 'ol Ronald out. Guess he didn't notice the tub of phosphorous next to me...  Notice you're still a little shy about rolling your sleeves up, Shadow. Show him your stomach yet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...All right, the parole board has received Mr. Bowland's fitness report, his ID-44, endorsement from his section warden... Dr. Norris?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN PSYCHIATRIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As supervising psychiatrist I would describe Mr. Bowland's progress as remarkable. Taking into account his disability and the six years already served, I recommend parole.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bowland, do you regret your crimes?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I understand now the pain I caused.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If released, will you commit these crimes again?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you consider yourself ready for society?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The parole board shuffles their papers. It's a done deal. Rimgale suddenly stands and approaches Ronald.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure Ronald? You're ready alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Mr. Rimgale.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you do with little girls? A tortured look comes over Ronald's face. He's holding back. From the paper bag, Rimgale suddenly tosses a burned baby doll in his lap.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale then lights a cigarette lighter in Ronald's face.</context>
      <utterance>What do you do with them, Ronald? Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Burn them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And old ladies?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Burn them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the world -- the whole world.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The parole board stares, stunned. Rimgale stands.</context>
      <utterance>-- Burn it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See ya next year, Ronald. Gotta go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ENGINE LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Him" is our previous owner, David Benton, just his hands and a leg showing from under the collapsed door. Rimgale crouches beside it.</context>
      <utterance>We were lucky with this one. Could've taken out the whole complex, but the explosion blew out most of the flame. Good for us.  -- Not so good for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian does. The corpse's keys are still in the lock. So's Benton. Blown with such force he seems fused with the door. On the door's edge Rimgale notices a small patch of melted, sticky goo. With his penknife he scrapes a sample and seals it in a glass vial, stands, and walks into the office.</context>
      <utterance>Turn this over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale, now inside, silences him with an outstretched arm.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to do with --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Shhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale doesn't answer. His eyes drift over the scorched walls as he speaks softly to them.</context>
      <utterance>What are you listening to?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scratches at some soot. Smiles and lifts a small hand recorder.</context>
      <utterance>You sneaky little son of a bitch... Hide and seek... Come on, tell me what I want to know...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heavy smoke stains observed in entry room. Demarkation line high. Fire never got hot enough here to cook soot off. It started somewhere else...  Less soot here. More heat.  And very little soot here.  Get that couch out of the way. Brian pulls it aside. The lower third of the wall is completely untouched by soot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you were happy here. Warm and cozy and in no hurry...  Soot high, clean unburned wall low, indicates slow burn in thermal balance.  Find me some glass.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glass?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's some on the sill of a blown window. Brian hands a shard to Rimgale, who turns it over in his palm.</context>
      <utterance>Do we have a language barrier here? Glass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glass found in ignition room is in small, thin pieces, indicating explosion. Lack of discoloration indicates a long, slow burn. Explosion must of come after a slow burn.  You little tease... What were you up to you little bastard, huh? What made you that mad?  Or scared.  It started in this room. Took its time, hung out... but the air ran out. It couldn't breathe. So it was snuffed. But it wasn't dead... still all that trapped heat, lying low, waiting for some sucker to open the door and give it that one gulp of air...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale turns to the wall, a section where the plaster is severely damaged. He probes with a penknife.</context>
      <utterance>-- Another backdraft.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale follows the damaged wall down -- down -- to a melted wall socket.</context>
      <utterance>Finish coat burned away... Severe spawling of rough coat...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian chops it out from the wall. Rimgale crouches down, peels back the melted faceplate and examines the wires. The copper tip is severely melted. Rimgale sniffs the plug.</context>
      <utterance>That's our ignition point. Dig it out. Carefully.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Temperature in this room was about 2000 degrees, but copper wire in outlet is melted, which requires 5000 degrees. An accidental short in the plug could of created a spark of 7000 degrees, hot enough to melt the wire and start a fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale shuts off the recorder. Stares down Brian.</context>
      <utterance>No it couldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale opens a plastic bag and puts the plug inside.</context>
      <utterance>I mean you'd be right -- with normal wire. But that's gauge ten in that plug -- industrial stuff. Who knows why they put it in here -- but it won't melt at less than 12,000 degrees. And no natural spark short of lightning gets that hot.  In another life I was in high-end electronics.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale stands and walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Have outlet analyzed for any traces of flammable accelerants.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mention it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody turns at the voice and the air suddenly chills.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Tim.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you surviving without me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no replacement 'cause of your boss' cuts, if that's what you mean. If someone else goes out on an injury we're really screwed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Brian looks over the wall. A dirty puddle separates him from it.</context>
      <utterance>Swayzak's not my boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooooh, like the tie. Love the tie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grindle stares at him a beat, then wordlessly steps into the muck and pulls free a section of wall, dropping it on the ground in front of Brian. Santos and Grindle look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Grindle, scrape down that wall for me, huh? I would myself, but the tie 'n all, y'know...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Brian, if you're lookin' for smoke patterns, there's some good ones over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen appears around the corner. Sees what's happened.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, maybe that wasn't it after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just about enough, guys, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leave. Brian stands there, humiliated.</context>
      <utterance>See ya around, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's the matter with you, huh? You're steppin' in the shit again. You could've done it. You don't want this.  Wake up, kid. Brian burns with shame and anger as Adcox walks away. Stephen hands Brian a towel.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian snatches it from him. Glares at his brother.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Dry yourself off.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you are sorta making yourself fair game.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the insight.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian, look --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian walks away. Stephen calls after him.</context>
      <utterance>Just leave me alone, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Bri... Rimgale's okay. I don't get half the shit he's talking about, but then everybody says the same thing about me. Who the hell knows?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stephen, what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fixing my roof.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops and tosses the hammer aside. Looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>It's not your roof anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Sean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got piano lessons.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? How's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going to be a fireman.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give up, babe. You can't fight it. Believe me, my mom tried...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stephen, you gotta stop just showing up on the roof like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to, I don't know, not exactly apologize for the other night -- especially since I don't remember much of it --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- You remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I just thought I should say, I don't know, something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The great communicator.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I hit Jackson.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He deserved it. He was born deserving it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He treats you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I treated you better.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You treated me like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee? Nah, I gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong, Stephen?  C'mon, you only beat up the roof when something's on your mind.  How's Brian doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know he's out, but how's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, I treated him better than any other probie I ever had. He probably hates my guts, but I did the best thing for him. I made him finally look in the mirror.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah Stephen, that's what this is really about, isn't it? You always have to be right.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm the first one to admit when I'm wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? When was the last time?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a fire? Never.  Look, I'm his brother. I care about him, y'know? He was going to get himself killed. Maybe not today, maybe not in a year, but it would've happened. And I couldn't -- I just couldn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen sighs deeply.</context>
      <utterance>You can't keep being his father...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs and hops down from the roof to the driveway.</context>
      <utterance>You know what I realized today? I can't remember my dad's face anymore. There's pictures of him staring at me everywhere I go, but the guy behind them... he's gone...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She watches him as he walks lonely up the street.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see ya around, Helen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>RICCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If you say so. Brian's stomach does a half-gainer as he's confronted by two hideously charred bodies.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Alan Seagrave and Donald Cosgrove...</utterance>
   <speaker>RICCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian is discreetly avoiding his gaze, whistling quietly to himself as he looks over specimen jars on a shelf.</context>
      <utterance>...Both deaths due to close encounters with stationary objects; office door for Mr. Cosgrove, '89 Porsche for Mr. Seagrave. No non-relevant traumas. No significant blood toxicology. Attitude of both trajectories consistent with explosions.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They ran the residue you scraped from both crispers' front doors. It's a combination of plumber's putty and rayophene gum. Burns almost completely away when you light it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Putty? On both doors?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricco lifts Benton's charred shoulder. Underneath we see some of his clothes that have melted and co-mingled with his flesh.</context>
      <utterance>There's something else kinda interesting...</utterance>
   <speaker>RICCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A credit card has been fried right into Cosgrove's skin about where his back pocket should have been.</context>
      <utterance>See this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricco erupts in a honking laugh, then switches instantly back to a business tone.</context>
      <utterance>Guess he didn't leave home without it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, down here, take a look...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McCaffrey, hold this for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, I don't think that's in my contract...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With supreme reluctance Brian pulls the crisper's head and shoulder away from the table.</context>
      <utterance>I just re-wrote your contract. C'mere...</utterance>
   <speaker>RICCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian gathers the torso up and hoists him higher.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, he isn't gonna try to sell you insurance, lift him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See that patch of shirt? We wondered about the discoloration so he ran a spectro. On a lucky shot we picked up some traces of Trychticholorate. Nobody around here had ever heard of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trychticholorate? Alright, it's an absorption catalyst in toxic waste accidents. It's pretty rare, they stopped making it a couple'a years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably got in Cosgrove's clothes in a gas state from the fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell was it doing in the fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that instant, Cosgrove's eyes OPEN and his body SIGHS. Brian DROPS the body in shock and backs away, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>That's your job.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked you to hold him, not feel him up...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Read.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Trychtichlorate is a binary structured --"</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Go to the bottom. Under heat properties.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"During heat episodes of 2000 Kelvin or higher, Trych breaks down and dissipates. Will consume magnesium".</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale CLAPS his hands next to Brian's head, STARTLING him.</context>
      <utterance>Ever burned magnesium? It's so hot it takes water molecules and BAMM!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch tears 'em apart just to eat the oxygen. Wouldn't take much at all to melt ten gauge wire. Problem's burnt magnesium leaves a powder trace -- unless you could find something that would eat its residue.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale looks at Brian. He's getting tired of this.</context>
      <utterance>Trychticholorate. Then Swayzak can announce Seagrave was a murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, it isn't proof, okay? Someone may have put the chemical in the outlet, but we found it as a vapor in Cosgrove's clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the putty around the door?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if it was used to seal the air off, that doesn't explain why someone would go to the trouble of a backdraft. A gun's a helluva lot easier</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the right guess on this is arson.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some people say you don't do much of anything when it comes to this case.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't work for them, either.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arson.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Jennifer's calling from her office, she's busy signing papers brought to her and okaying campaign posters as she talks.</context>
      <utterance>Straightest answer your department's given me all week.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boss and I are up to about three words an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Green committed to a thousand.  There's another fund-raising party tonight. Marty'd really like you to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses a paper airplane.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I'm kinda swamped here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could use a date.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Well, maybe I can fit it in...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIMGALE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McCaffrey! Come here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian hangs up quickly and walks back into</context>
      <utterance>Call ya back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian walks over and RIPS OFF the lid. -- Instantly a tongue of flame SHOOTS straight up past his head and BLOWS out.</context>
      <utterance>Take the top off. Go ahead. Take it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale's grinning like a little kid.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it! Oh, that son of a bitch, he's different, goddamn it! You see what this tells us, huh? Our killer doesn't love fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>([p. 78])</context>
      <utterance>I got it after we talked to Ronald. Torches. Want to fry the whole goddamn world. But the fires that killed those guys never really burned up much. -- The burns were all lit in outlets surrounded by double firebreaks in the walls. And he made his burns backdrafts.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he killed these guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he could have killed everybody there. The firebreaks kept it from spreading in the wall. The backdraft blew out the flame. That's it. That's the reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What reason?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why backdrafts. Whoever fried Seagrave and Cosgrove went to a helluva lot of trouble to make sure they died by fire, but also made sure the fire blew itself out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why the sealant on the doors... So what have we got, a torch with a conscience?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we have a stone killer trying to make a point.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going public with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Do that and I guarantee you'll scare him off. I don't want him running away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey...  So are you dating your boss or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you weren't at least the 300th person to ask me that, I'd probably be pissed.  Boy, you sure know it's a man's world sometimes...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.  Are you dating anyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think that's really any of your business?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you did invite me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swayzak suddenly appears with his entourage.</context>
      <utterance>Marty did.  But I wanted you to come to.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. McCaffrey...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swayzak swings around and puts his arm cheesily around Brian's shoulder. Another staffer slaps a SWAYZAK FOR MAYOR sticker to Brian's lapel. Jennifer rolls her eyes to Brian. I'm sorry... Snap.</context>
      <utterance>It isn't mine.  Let's get a picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swayzak leads her off in pursuit. Left alone, Brian turns to the railing, stares off at the passing city. You can hear the wind-up of a siren. And there it is now, an engine company zooming along Wacker Drive. Something digs and kicks inside of Brian as he watches it disappear.</context>
      <utterance>Larry!  What does he do again?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's appeared again beside him.</context>
      <utterance>How's the job going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, Rimgale's as slow as a snail, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he's more of a dinosaur. Guy's not a dummy, though. He's juggling alot of balls on this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but it doesn't take Albert Einstein just to figure out if these guys were killed by accidents or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, give him a break. There isn't enough proof yet to go public. Sure, we found some chemical shit we think somebody dumped in the plugs to torch 'em, and we've maybe figured out why backdrafts, but you can't rush this stuff. Not 'till it's locked.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Rimgale's probably going to come around to arson.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a dinosaur kinda way, yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the invite.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got anything to drink in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, there might be something stashed away for emergencies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is one of the oldest fire stations in the city. Lotta tradition locked up in here. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Homey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See that trap door up there? That used to lead to the hay loft when they had horse-drawn engines. It was pretty different then... but kinda the same, y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you miss it?  You seem like you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I came back, I knew more than anything else that I wanted to be a fireman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why did you quit?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to be a good one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours her a glass. Jennifer takes a generous sip of her's, turns, brushes past him and breathes,</context>
      <utterance>Old firehouse trick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So show me your fire truck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, our specimen here is your basic standard issue piece of primary suppression equipment. This area is the pumping panel, which controls the rate of liquid insertion into the hose.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian lifts a narrow, tapered straight-bore nozzle.</context>
      <utterance>Uh huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. The air cracks between them. And is brushed aside. In an instant they're all over each other. Tangled lips and gulping breaths. Jennifer abruptly breaks it off -- And looks mischievously up at the hose bed, with its long curling rolls of soft cotton. Brian doesn't remember this precise scenario being discussed at the academy, but he improvises admirably, popping up onto the hose bed and offering a gentlemanly hand to Jennifer. As they tumble into the soft folds</context>
      <utterance>This is a six inch playpipe, cast bronze to keep it firm during hard flows.  This is our pipe extender, used in forward lays...  This is our hard suction line... Our adjustable insertion nozzle...  ...And this is the hose bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Tim, if you're going to kill yourself at least wait till the fire, it's better P.R.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls the shirt off his shoulder as we</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about the playpipe again...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know. There's alarms going off on three different floors.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They climb into the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>Wonderful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we know if the floor's going to be on fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the doors open and it's hot, don't get out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On cue something snakes past behind the walls, whispers and whines and shivers up and over them and then is silent. Grindle attaches a hoseline to the building standpipe.</context>
      <utterance>It's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These high-rise gigs give me the creeps.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Stephen's on the hunt now. Obsessed.</context>
      <utterance>Let's wait for a back-up, Stephen. We're early on this one, it hasn't even broke out yet. We're one short as it is with Brian gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to learn something?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen and Tim take the lead, their axes gripped like shotguns. Grindle backs them up with a charged hoseline.</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adcox, go with Pengelly and check the other side.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't safe, man. Don't go splittin' us up. Not with this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- What the hell's the matter with you? You always check the other side. I haven't got time for bullshit right now, okay? We got a job here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me take the lead, Stephen...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adcox folds. With a stricken look on his face he takes his crew down the other way. Stephen and Tim slowly feel their way.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it Adcox! Just do your fucking job!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They frantically climb into their clothes. The firemen haven't noticed them as they climb aboard. They've STARTED THE ENGINE.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse us.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tim's come to one.</context>
      <utterance>Lotta smoke, but it isn't rolling... that means it's hiding... staying sleepy... one of these doors...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tim doesn't hear. The axe is already up.</context>
      <utterance>Did you check the door for heat, Tim?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tim's committed now, coming hard at the door. And Stephen sees it for just an instant -- Small tendrils of smoke edging lazily around the door -- then being sucked back in.</context>
      <utterance>Tim?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rushes for Tim as Tim's axe SMACKS the door and a whine behind it builds and roars and howls and Tim's all follow- through now, hitting the door with his shoulder as The door EXPLODES OUTWARD, HURLING TIM against the opposite wall and for an instant he's okay but he freezes in terror as A SHRIEKING TONGUE OF FLAME SHOOTS OUT THE DOORWAY and Grindle shouts in horror and opens his hose line as the flames wrap Tim like a jealous lover as Adcox hears it and screams,</context>
      <utterance>Tim!</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Tim's screaming now too, because his helmet, his mask, his face, it's all melting and Grindle dives suicidally at the monster, BLASTING it with his hose as Stephen ignores the flames and puts his arms around Tim as Grindle DOUSES them both, killing the flames. The monster rolls wounded back into the room, into the air shafts as Tim whimpers incoherently, sliding down the wall as Stephen tries to help but oh God you can't tell what's face and what's mask and helmet anymore. Grindle looks back where the fire came from. There's a corpse in there, burned and lying between two doors. Adcox rushes to Tim's side sobbing and it's the end, the end of the goddamn world...</context>
      <utterance>Oh God! Oh God no!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he...</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do they think he'll pull through?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have been there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHTENGALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Voices rise down the hall. Turn to shouts. It's Adcox and Stephen, tearing heartbreakingly into one another. Brian can't make out the words but it's ugly, emotional. Abruptly it ends and Stephen emerges from the alcove, walking toward them upset.</context>
      <utterance>None of us should have been there, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen's got other things on his mind.</context>
      <utterance>You had to do it, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Not now, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had to take on another fire bare- handed, huh? Had to be fucking myth man in there instead of looking out for your probie. Is that what happened? Is it, Stephen?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had that fire. He didn't listen!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't listen? He was a fucking candidate! He was your responsibility. He shouldn't have been there in the first place, Stephen.  You burned him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian grabs his arm. Stephen SNAPS and roughly PUSHES Brian, knocking him against the wall. Brian comes off it in a flash and is all over Stephen. They go down and it's all thrashing and shouting now. A horrible, endless draw. Grindle and Santos are in it, pulling them apart, holding them up against opposite walls. Both brothers glare at one another, tears filling their eyes. Brian shakes Grindle off and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian's eyes wince closed.</context>
      <utterance>Goes on about how the break was made through the discovery of "chemical traces" and a "behavioral link". Oh, and Swayzak's quoted saying the chief investigator is closing in on the torch and expects an arrest "any time".</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your stuff and get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian. What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told Swayzak about our arson lead. It's all over the fucking news.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know it was a secret. There aren't supposed to be secrets between the city and its investigators --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Bullshit! You knew what I told you wasn't ready for the papers --</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you please keep your voice down, there's people --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- You could have scared the son of a bitch off. We may never bust him now. All for a couple's political points.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was doing my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? And just how much of all this has been "doing your job"?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you something, do you really think Marty had you assigned to arson because of your firefighting skills? Who the hell are you kidding? I was there, remember? I saw you and your brother --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave Stephen out of this --</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, he's the real fireman.  Who are you? Just another probie working for Swayzak --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I work for the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swayzak appears in the doorway. He looks haggard, as if he hasn't slept. There's something haunted in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You knew what we were asking you to do. Don't suddenly pull out a conscience now. The fit isn't right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. McCaffrey... Keeping busy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. In fact, I just dropped off a letter to the Times explaining how yesterday's arson announcement was a fabrication by your office. They loved it. And you know what? You were right, my family background in firefighting gave it weight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian shoulders his way past Swayzak and walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Brian...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inspector.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alderman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swayzak apparently doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>I usually have breakfast first.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When are you going to catch the prick that's doing this, Don?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Don?"</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have any leads at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time, Rimgale sees real fear on Swayzak's face.</context>
      <utterance>No Marty, I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We still haven't found a connection between the victims.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, open your eyes! Seagrave, Cosgrove, and now Holcomb -- fried in a goddamn high-rise!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sedan stops back at arson HQ. They'd gone around the block.</context>
      <utterance>Holcomb? I didn't know the name of that victim had even been released yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a connection between them, Alderman?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door shuts and Swayzak roars away.</context>
      <utterance>Just catch the son of a bitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale stares at Brian, appraises him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm finished with Swayzak. I'll do whatever you want me to do. I just want to help catch the guy that burned Tim. You gotta give me another shot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale rubs the white powder between his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>I thought 'ol Marty was acting a little strange... And he's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale stands at the spot in the short hall where the body lied between two doors.</context>
      <utterance>Backdraft?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian steps into the inner office.</context>
      <utterance>The backdraft was set somewhere in there. It fried Holcomb when he opened the inner door. But the outer door held... and waited for Tim...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian begins searching, probing. He finally stands. Defeated.</context>
      <utterance>So find me the fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian's eyes don't understand. From Rimgale's coat comes a plastic flask. He pours out of it a liquid onto the floor and lights a match.</context>
      <utterance>You're thinking too much of the building and not enough of the ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a word, Brian, what is this job all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WUMP. A small flame explodes to life.</context>
      <utterance>Fire. Rimgale drops the match.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a living thing, Brian. It breathes, it eats, and it hates. The fire's climbing a wall, chewing a corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FWUMP. It darts west. Licks the ceiling. The fire purrs and hisses. Stretches luxuriously and attacks savagely.</context>
      <utterance>The only way to beat it is to think like it. To know that this flame will spread this way across the floor not because of the physics of flammable liquids or heat convection, but because it wants to.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian stares at the flame. A goblin reaching out for him... -- Woosh! Rimgale hits it with a fire extinguisher. In an instant the goblin is gone, the genie in the bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Some guys on this job, fire owns them. It makes them fight on its level. But the only way to truly kill it is to love it a little, just like Ronald.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A young woman's entered.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you guys doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're the fire department, lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well color me stupid, I always thought the fire dept. put out fires.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You work here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Till yesterday. What do you think the odds are that a non-refundable ticket to Paris survived this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somewhere between zero and no way.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. What a mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem real broken up about Mr. Holcomb.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeff Holcomb? The Darth Vader of tax accountants? He was a sleezeball. Hopefully a sleezeball that carried some insurance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go talk to the building owner.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was the building owner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him like he's the dumbest human she's met all week.</context>
      <utterance>Our book lists the owner as Dekom Trust.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't investigators come in adult size?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stevie? Rimgale's here to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just wants to --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, then Rimgale himself enters.</context>
      <utterance>-- I'm busy goddamn it, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale takes in Stephen's room, the half empty bourbon bottle. Without a word, Rimgale walks over and pours it out. He sits down beside Stephen.</context>
      <utterance>What, they don't knock on your planet?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wave of pain rolls through Stephen.</context>
      <utterance>I still haven't gotten your fire report, Stevie. On Tim.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm working on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I deal with this stuff every day. But a fireman... you never get used to it.  What happened up there? He was a candidate. Did he pay attention? Was he listening?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...He wasn't listening to the right thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you listen to, Stephen?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know... nobody knows...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen's eyes meet Rimgale's and hold.</context>
      <utterance>I might.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It knows us. This one knows us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen takes Rimgale's notebook out of his lap, rips out a page, and writes angrily in huge block letters.</context>
      <utterance>I need that report, Lt.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen throws the sheet at Rimgale, stands, and walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Tim-went-to-the-fire-and-now-he- doesn't-have-a-face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey boss, Dekom Trust is owned by Pan Illinois... which is majority controlled by Lakeside Dynamics... which is a division of Windy City Ventures... who's partners are...  Alan Seagrave, Donald Cosgrove, and Jeffrey Holcomb.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch. They knew each other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Seagrave and Holcomb were accountants...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Cosgrove. Coppers figured he laundered money for the mob before getting into real estate. They weren't very high on Seagrave, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice bunch of guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, then he looks directly at Brian.</context>
      <utterance>Who all ended up wearing candles for faces...  Swayzak's up to his ass in this somehow. Guy can barely hold a drink in his hand, he's so scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to get a look at his files.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We still talking?  Look, I'm sorry about the other day --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swayzak knows something about the guys that were murdered. I want to know why he keeps that hidden.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know anything about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could check. It'd be in his files.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what you're asking me to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, four years ago I was working in a bakery. Two years ago I was bringing Marty coffee and he didn't even know my name. I run that office now. Marty believed in me and I believe in him. You want me to just throw that away?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And it hangs between them, two people lonely on the edge of the lake.</context>
      <utterance>Your boss is lying, Jennifer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits down beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Stephen?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... I... couldn't sleep...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cook and I are almost finished here. Have a seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen musses his son's hair and follows her out into the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Stephen... I... can I talk to you a second...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm sorry I --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- No, that's okay. It's just Sean...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- He's gettin' good on those eggs. And y'know, he told me he actually likes the piano.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blow's so long and hard and deep you don't even see it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to confuse him, Stephen.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Sean sticks his head into it.</context>
      <utterance>It's... It's just things have changed... you're the same, Stephen, but things are different now... you've got a son... you're the best at what you do Stephen, you always were, but you scare me now...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... Sean-man, your dad blew it. I forgot I had to work this morning...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw dad, c'mon...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen's turned away.</context>
      <utterance>Next time, huh? We'll do it up big. Promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.  Mom's crying, dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally the chair turns, revealing a haunted man. Polls are far from his mind.</context>
      <utterance>Latest polls came in, Marty.  Marty?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, Marty, what's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees a fire department file on the murders open on his desk.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swayzak's eyes are dead metal.</context>
      <utterance>We've come a long way together, Marty. I've staked my whole career on you. And now you're sneaking around this office, leaking things to the papers behind my back...  Is there something you're not telling me about these deaths?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he turns his chair around again. Jennifer stands there a beat. -- Then turns to the filing cabinets.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a manila envelope.</context>
      <utterance>Jennifer?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is --</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Just take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a dumb thing to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts her car.</context>
      <utterance>You're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Brian.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>REPAIRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale's looking through the report Brian's handed him.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell do you do with this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the copy of Swayzak's manning report that was released. Everybody on this job knows it's bullshit but we could never argue with the numbers. They're all airtight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dumps three more reports on Rimgale.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Airtight?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got three different drafts of the same report -- with different numbers that're all over the place. Looks like they were just making it up as they went along.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did a little check on the consulting firm that wrote the report. They did exactly one job -- Swayzak's manpower study. It's not even really a company. No employees, no directors, just a PO Box.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then who wrote the report?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian hands him something else. A photograph. Swayzak and the other three, posing on a fishing boat, 1970. Time of their lives.</context>
      <utterance>It had to be someone who knows numbers. Some kind of fancy accountant. But what's the connection?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's time Mr. Swayzak and us had a little heart to heart talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian climbs up to his feet and walks over to where Rimgale lies at a weird angle, a piece of wrought iron fence punched through his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... I sorta got a problem here...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well Brian, I guess you can say it's arson now...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale grunts.</context>
      <utterance>How ya feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you pull me out?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I say thanks?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wondering.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale suddenly kicks the bed frame in anger. He kicks it over and over with frustration till something finally SNAPS off. Brian waits, let's him vent his frustration.</context>
      <utterance>I hate hospitals. You're so... so goddamn useless...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do you want me to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been lying here hours... just thinking... We're close...  We're not looking in the right place, Brian. This one knows us and we're not looking in the right place...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian hands him a stack of murder files.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Mr. Life magazine. Come all this way just to say hi?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm close... but I can't get who it is...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ronald starts to read the files</context>
      <utterance>So you came to me...  Well, this is going to be an interesting afternoon after all...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, here's the deal. I'll tell you a story, you tell me one. Fair?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your first question should be who isn't. It isn't a spark, Brian. Not enough damage. And an insurance pro? Where's the profit margin?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then who --</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- No no, your turn. Tell me a story.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a story.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald drops on the table a dog-eared copy of that 1972 LIFE magazine with Brian on the cover.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Famous story even. Straight burn. Just an engine and truck first on scene. What did you feel, Brian, when you first got there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta tell a story too, Brian. It's fair. C'mon, don't think too hard --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I thought it was great. I loved it. It was nothing to these guys... medium deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Light smoke, low roll. Couple'a civilians hollering -- medium deal. So young fireman Adcox and Captain McCaffrey, they head up stairs, get out on the fire escape -- McCaffrey does the ballsy jump across... what were you feeling, Brian?  C'mon, you promised. Be honest.  Okay... Guard!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I wanted to be him. Right then I wanted to be him more than anything...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good, Brian. -- About your report here. The way to a torch's heart is through his tools. That's how you know him. It's the way he talks to the fire. And to you if you listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The outlets.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a probie answer. You're smarter than that, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trychticholorate.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a flash, Brian suddenly reaches across and grabs Ronald by the collar.</context>
      <utterance>Good. -- So our two heroes, Adcox and McCaffrey, they go back inside. Only there's another fire in there nobody sees. And it took your dad, didn't it Brian? Did you see him burn?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck is doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Ronald sees something in Brian's eyes. He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>After it took your dad... the fire... did it look at you Brian? Did it talk to you?...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian releases Ronald.</context>
      <utterance>You see, our world's aren't so different...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The arsonist smiles a creepy, horrible grin.</context>
      <utterance>Who's doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cold shock rolls through Brian as he slumps back in his chair.</context>
      <utterance>Think, Brian. Who doesn't love fire, but knows it better than anyone else? Who's around trychticholorate 24 hours a day?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not such a far walk after all, is it, Brian?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Footsteps. Brian spins around in stone shock as Stephen comes into the cabin.</context>
      <utterance>Oh goddamn it Stephen...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just... Just wanted to say hello...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian backs away from the chemicals.</context>
      <utterance>So hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, long as you're here you can help clean up a little. I've got a guy coming to look at this in a few minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're selling dad's boat?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's just another memory in my life right now. And I got way too many of them...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really should get back. There's... there's something I'm supposed to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? What have you got to do?  Look at you. Look at your face. All the things you must be thinking. Man, you must really hate my guts. Well, you know what? It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Stephen, maybe we can talk about this some other --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He KICKS the bulkhead wall.</context>
      <utterance>-- Okay, so you don't like me. You don't like everything I've done. What, because I wasn't such a genius the way I raised you? Jesus Christ, dad was gone, what was I supposed to do? You tell me, what the fuck was I supposed to do?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, Stephen, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian turns to leave. Pauses.</context>
      <utterance>-- I tried, y'know? Helen's right. I don't have all the answers, but goddamn it, I've got some.  Look, you're gonna do what you have to, and maybe I shouldn't have gotten in the way. I'm your brother, not your father. Go on. You gotta go somewhere? Go...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saw what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When dad died, I saw another fire...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw it before it got them. I tried to yell, but... He asked me to look out for him. And I didn't do it. I let him die.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Jesus, you been carrying that around for twenty years? For christ's sake, you were seven years old! You think he could have heard you in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate him so much sometimes, Stephen. You don't know how hard it was for me to put that uniform on...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I do.  ...What a fuckin' mess, huh?  People can change Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian sees the chemicals in the corner again and something freezes up inside. Stephen catches the look and there's horrible silence between them.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes right when you're looking at them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, Stephen, what's going on with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Brian... I don't know...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Stephen, wait a minute. I gotta talk to you. It's Adcox, he's --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw Adcox's back! I saw the burn! I put it there! Jesus Christ, Stephen, he's been killing people!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew when you came looking for the chemicals. Looking for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- What were they doing there?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grindles sticks his head out the back door.</context>
      <utterance>They were for the fucking boat, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta roll, Stevie...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're waitin' man.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grindle goes back in.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be there, goddamn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we going to do about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta go to Rimgale, Stephen.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian's eyes go to a window just above it. There, watching him, watching the whole exchange between brothers, is Adcox. Adcox stares at Brian a beat, then finally disappears as Brian hears the cough of diesel engines.</context>
      <utterance>I'm his Lt. He's my responsibility. I'll handle it. Me. Stephen turns and walks toward the station.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts running for the station.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Christ. Stephen...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are they? Where's 17?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian looks up at the smoke and whirling firestorm four stories above him, feels the bile of fear in his throat, the desperation, -- And begins strapping on an air tank.</context>
      <utterance>On the roof.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The helmets look up. Stephen and Adcox. Facing each other. Adcox cradles an axe.</context>
      <utterance>Stephen --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian starts to move beside Stephen but Adcox turns, tightens his grip on the axe, and now all the cards are on the table. A hissing black cloud drifts through. They're the only three people on earth. Adcox's eyes are clouded with tears.</context>
      <utterance>Brian?</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw man, Stephen, listen to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- What the fuck were you thinking, huh? Burning people? You're a fireman.</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were killing firemen, man. When Sally showed me what was in Swayzak's files... They were my friends, I had to do it. I had to do it for the department.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you do it for Tim?</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta let me finish --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just come down, John. Just --</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Shut up! Your dad would fucking puke if he saw how you've shit on his department!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Knock it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- You can't let him turn you against your friends, man --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- He killed people --</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- You know what Swayzak would do to the department if this got out? --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Stephen, this is bullshit --</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And there's a horrible glimmer of confusion on Stephen's face.</context>
      <utterance>-- What he would do to your dad's department? You gotta let me finish it --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're his Lt., Stephen...  Are you gonna handle it? Are you Stephen?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...What do you want me to do, Stephen? Talk to me. What am I supposed to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a fire. We've got a job here. Let's get on with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You crazy son of a bitch, why couldn't you stay behind a desk where you belong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"You never know till the fire stares you down if you're gonna be --"</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian helps him stay above water. The level continues to rise, bringing them finally even with an open doorway they scramble through.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shut up, huh?  I think I broke my goddamn arm...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stupid son of a bitch! What the fuck are you doing!</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adcox struggles against him, heaving and sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>Stevie... I...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Adcox releases the axe.</context>
      <utterance>Let it go! Goddamn it let it go!</utterance>
   <speaker>AXE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian's on his feet now, coming toward them, when a chemical drum below EXPLODES, the shock wave BUCKLING the platform and DROPPING it several feet before it HOLDS. Brian, cut- off, is HIT with a wall of debris. Adcox and Stephen are FLUNG across the platform and THROUGH the shattered railing. Stephen grabs a piece of broken, dangling strut and hangs on with one hand. In his other hand is Adcox. Hanging below him, his grip loosening.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... I'm so sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian's struggling to get out from under the debris. The railing Stephen's hanging onto is slick, his hand SLIPPING along it. But he won't let go of Adcox. His eyes bore into his best friend's with absolute conviction.</context>
      <utterance>Stephen!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The towering shots of FLAME from below have begun to IGNITE Adcox's pant leg. He's starting to burn. But Stephen won't let go. Won't let go even as the flames crawl up Adcox's back. And Stephen's hand is slipping and slipping and then it isn't slipping anymore because it's come off.</context>
      <utterance>You go, we go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start for him when another drum EXPLODES, FLATTENING them and launching their hoseline into a crazy, thrashing arc. The flame has cut them off from the hose. Stephen sees what Brian's thinking.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Brian's already moving for the catwalk ladder.</context>
      <utterance>Wait for another hose team...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian puts his feet on the outside rungs of the ladder and SLIDES down to the factory floor. He's heading for the hoseline when WHAM! -- The fire cuts him off. Not just any fire. That same one from so many years ago. Don't fuck with me, kid. I'm not in the mood. Nightengale's lost his helmet and it's lying near the flames spinning slowly upside down -- just like his father's. Brian stands there, paralyzed, as the fire laughs at him. Same old little kid with his finger up his ass. Then something different comes into Brian's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Wait for the goddamn hose team!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a pathetic little wall extinguisher mounted on the pole. Brian lifts it, approaches the fire. You can practically hear the flames laugh at him. Brian suddenly turns and SLAMS the neck of the extinguisher against the pole, BREAKING it off before HEAVING the cannister HISSING into the flames where it EXPLODES -- a cloud of extinguisher powder that STUNS the flames just long enough for Brian to dash through and TACKLE the hose. The fire shakes off the powder, rises up to kill -- Just as Brian spins and HITS it with the STREAM. -- And it's like a howling train wreck as the two grapple with each other -- Pengelly and Nightengale have an opening, and they're dashing for the catwalk ladder up to Stephen because the fire doesn't care -- it only has eyes for Brian now -- -- And Stephen sees Brian tackle the monster, and his eyes fill with tears -- -- And the fire's pushing Brian -- pushing him with the fury of a frightened street bully -- but Brian won't give -- and now the fire's back's broken -- it's whimpering, dying. And Pengelly and Nightengale have climbed up to Stephen now, pulling him away.</context>
      <utterance>No... No more.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the fire's just a little gremlin now, sighing sadly as Brian steps up with the hoseline.</context>
      <utterance>That's my brother! That's my brother goddamn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And whoosh, it's gone.</context>
      <utterance>Another time, friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell them about Adcox... Don't let 'em...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His brother squeezes Brian's hand, his eyes never leaving him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... I'm sorry I thought... I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARAMEDIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit, give him some lidocaine, now. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephen's EKG's begun to falter. The other paramedic fires off an injection into his IV.</context>
      <utterance>Who's your brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARAMEDIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The EKG's become erratic. Stephen's eyes never leave Brian's.</context>
      <utterance>His pressure's fading -- push some adrenalin.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man, don't you die... Don't you die...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARAMEDIC #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They put an ambo bag over Stephen's face. The eyes never leave Brian's.</context>
      <utterance>He's going south... He's gonna box damn it...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're breathing for him now. The EKG begins shrieking.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it don't you die now... Not now!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARAMEDIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The paramedics begin scrambling to load the defibrillator pads on Stephen's chest. But the fireman's eyes never waver from Brian. They look into his with complete conviction, complete acceptance, And then they don't.</context>
      <utterance>V-fib!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your brother was a good man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another couple of good men get burned up for their city? Is that how it's going to read?  You're the only one that knows.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale turns to walk back to his sedan. He pauses. Looks back to Brian.</context>
      <utterance>Like it never happened...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to help me with something?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Swayzak! How ya doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale sits on Swayzak's desk.</context>
      <utterance>Investigator...</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAYZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a little busy right now --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rimgale drops the manning report on Swayzak's desk.</context>
      <utterance>This'll only take a minute. There's two cops outside that want to ask you about this --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room explodes with questions. Through the din Brian leans over the desk very close to Swayzak.</context>
      <utterance>This is just a guess of course, but I think they're gonna want to know why you secretly paid Donald Cosgrove, Jeffrey Holcomb and Alan Seagrave to create a phony manpower study.  You guys'll wait, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian turns and pushes his way out. At the door he pauses and looks back at Rimgale. The investigator nods and smiles just a little...</context>
      <utterance>See that glow flashing in the corner of your eye? That's your career dissipation light. And it just went into high gear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>-- Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And there's just a beat between the investigator and his probie before Brian nods and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Don't keep looking over your shoulder for the ghost. It's gone now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think your boss is going to need some spin control.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I quit two days ago, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'll you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have the slightest idea...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see ya around, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a small town.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
