<movie id="57" title="Bad Lieutenant">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many times are you gonna miss the bus? Huh? All the other kids can get up in the morning, but you guys wanna be driven around like the fucking President. I'm your goddamn chauffeur!</utterance>
   <speaker>TWINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, man. It wasn't our fault! -- You think Sis is so perfect, well, if she hadn't hogged the fucking bathroom, maybe we -- I thought Aunt Lu was dead! She was in there so long...</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON RADIO: Chatter about Mets winning last night's game. It was the THIRD GAME straight that they've won so far. One more game -- set for tomorrow afternoon -- and the Mets will sweep the World Series. All listen.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Listen!</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna win the Series in four!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the way with Strawberry!</utterance>
   <speaker>TWINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TWINS whoop and shout, celebrating LT's -- and their own -- favorite player. They pass the PAROCHIAL SCHOOL BUS. It has stopped for a moment taking on KIDS. LT cuts off the TWINS' tirade.</context>
      <utterance>Strawberry!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT and the TWINS banter back and forth, poke each other and box around. The apparent hostility of their words is balanced by the laughter and gung-ho play of the rough-housing. The TWINS yell cat-calls as they drive past a BLONDE PEDESTRIAN. LT joins in. ANGLE - Through the WINDSHIELD, the PAROCHIAL SCHOOL comes into view. A CROWD of UNIFORMED KIDS is gathered outside. SEVERAL NUNS turn the CROWD into two neat rows, and usher the KIDS inside.</context>
      <utterance>Shit, man -- there's your fucking bus I oughtta make you late! Make the nuns whack the shit outa ya both.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BET COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT gives a cursory glance to the crime scene. A couple of COPS greet him; LT keeps walking. The BET COP digs his attitude.</context>
      <utterance>Two Black kids came up out of nowhere and shot those chicks. Then they laughed as they walked away. The Press is gonna call it the "Giggling Man Murders." I'll tell ya. What a world.</utterance>
   <speaker>BET COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FOLLOW LT - over to a GROUP of COPS. They greet him and everyone immediately crams into a parked CAR. The CAR stays parked for the duration of their meeting.</context>
      <utterance>But hey -- we make the best of it, man, don't we? Huh? How about them Mets!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No fucking way they're gonna do it in four games straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You serious, man? I wanna go Mets all the way!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, man.If you've got shit for brains. But if you wanna win the bucks, go with Oakland.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought Strawberry was gonna --</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BET COP speaks up first; hands LT some CASH. When he talks to LT, his fawning posture is obvious.</context>
      <utterance>I know that nigger like he's my brother. He ain't gonna let us off so easy. He'll make us sweat first. This game's going to Oakland. Not a doubt in my mind, man. Silence. The COPS think about it for a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>BET COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COP ONE SHRUGS his assent, gives CASH to LT. The OTHER COPS follow his example, place their BETS on OAKLAND. The COP BETS total $800 -- on OAKLAND. LT has obviously been the bookie for this precinct for a long time. He takes care of a lot of action and has these guy's faith. LT nods a goodbye, quickly gets out of the CAR. The BET COP and the OTHER COPS remain inside.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in. Here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. What are you gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want 15 on the Mets.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>ACROSS THE STREET - TWO GUYS approach a BUSINESSMAN in a raincoat and flash a KNIFE. The BUSINESSMAN gives up his WALLET and his WATCH. LT pays no mind to the robbery.</context>
      <utterance>How about 7 1/2?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, man. Don't give me that bullshit. Don't pussy-out on me. The Mets are a fucking lock. I wanna make some money.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT hangs up the PHONE, heads back toward his parked CAR. By this time, the BUSINESSMAN is running into the street, waving his arms and screaming.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT enters his car, drives off.</context>
      <utterance>Police! Police! Help me! Police!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JC gives it to him with a PIPE. LT takes a drag of CRACK. Then LT gives JC a large BAG of COKE, labelled "Exhibit A".</context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, gimme something cooked!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JC nods, bemused by LT's manic behavior. JC, in contrast, is mellow and in control. LT smokes; JC doesn't. LT COUGHS and SMOKES as he shouts to COPS downstairs (OFF).</context>
      <utterance>It's good shit. From when they busted those Columbians uptown. You can cut it in half.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JC watches LT smoking like a fiend.</context>
      <utterance>I got this guy. But there's someone across the street on the roof! The COPS  rush out of the building.</utterance>
   <speaker>JC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That stuff'll kill you quick, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you? A drug counselor or a drug dealer? And you don't even do your own product! What kind of businessman are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rich kind.  Jeez, man. The way you smoke that shit is suicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just give me back a little something for the road. LT takes a handful of the COKE and puts it in a DOLLAR BILL; pockets it.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JC splits, runs up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>See you in a coupla days. Have the cash ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT gives her the COKE. ARIANE takes some immediately. BOWTAY sloppily partakes. Before LT can even sit down, the GIRLS start bitching.</context>
      <utterance>Got something good for us?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna need some bread, man. This ain't fair. I'm always here for you, and you can't even take decent care of me. My landlord is bitching like a motherfucker! You're two months behind on the rent, Lieutenant!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didya ever think of moving to a cheaper apartment? $3,500 a month is crazy, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE - BOWTAY on the COUCH. It's obvious that she's going nowhere. And fast.</context>
      <utterance>It's nothing. This is New York, man...  Oh -- I forgot. Bowtay needs some cash to buy her new acting headshots out of the developers. It's a good investment, man. She could make serious money!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT breaks out more COKE and some GRASS.</context>
      <utterance>We've been rehearsing a new monologue. From Shad's Saint Joan, you know? Bowtay does it wonderfully well.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARIANE lifts BOWTAY to her feet. BOWTAY staggers into the center of the room, then falls back down on her knees. It happens to be appropriate for the scene. BOWTAY begins to recite the monologue from the very end of the play. "When will the world be ready to receive thy saints?", etc. BOWTAY messes up a line; ARIANE lashes her with a BELT. BOWTAY doesn't move, continues reciting. ARIANE joins in from time to time. LT is turned on. He begins KISSING ARIANE, then goes down onto the floor. BOWTAY is there already. Kinky trio sex scene.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Bowtay. Show us your stuff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's clear from the SEX SOUNDS (OC), that ARIANE and BOWTAY are still going at it.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT obeys. He leaves the KITCHEN.</context>
      <utterance>Go out and get some Diet Cokes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The UNIFORMED COP is a timid rookie.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KOREAN OWNER is still agitated. He tries to give his side of the story, mixing English and Korean. At the same time -- The TWO BLACK KIDS plead their case. They try to drown out the OWNER. It all gets rather noisy.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, Lieutenant, Sir -- The owner says they stole cash from the register. He was chasing them down the block when I caught up with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG BLACK KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT shouts in the YOUNG BLACK KID'S FACE. It's shockingly loud.</context>
      <utterance>We didn't do nothing, man !</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT turns to the UNIFORMED COP.</context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT is now alone with the KOREAN OWNER and the TWO YOUNG BLACK</context>
      <utterance>Go get me a Bud. A High Boy. And make sure it's fucking cold.  I'll straighten this out. The UNIFORMED COP looks at LT for a moment, then goes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIDS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>LT turns to the OWNER.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much did they take?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOREAN OWNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TWO YOUNG BLACK KIDS continue protesting their innocence.</context>
      <utterance>Five hundred dollars cash.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG BLACK KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT whips out his GUN and shoots a deafening BLAST between the TWO KIDS' heads.It almost takes off the left ear of one and the right ear of the other. The TWO YOUNG BLACK KIDS are stunned. Speechless. The YOUNG UNIFORMED COP rushes out of the MARKET, GUN raised in one hand, BEER CAN in the other. He's relieved that a cop wasn't shot, but the whole situation makes him uneasy. LT grabs the BEER, points to the KOREAN OWNER.</context>
      <utterance>We didn't --</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TWO YOUNG BLACK KIDS have regained some of their cool. They are still belligerent.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme the money! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG BLACK KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT jams his GUN down the PANTS of one of the KIDS. At the same time, he whips out his BADGE and thrusts it into the other KID'S FACE.</context>
      <utterance>We told you, man. We didn't take no --</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They give LT the CASH. The KIDS stand there.</context>
      <utterance>Give me the fucking money, assholes!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT swaggers around the store, GUN in hand, drinking the BEER, assessing the inventory with a proprietary air. He pretends to SHOOT at various products. Plays around. In the back aisle, LT aims his GUN at a BIG BOX of TOILET</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are ya standing there for? Be gone! The KIDS, stunned, split.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT comes and looks over her shoulder. He sees -- A PILE of BROWN HEROIN on a TIN FOIL SHEET. ARIANE is preparing the implements for "chasing the dragon." BOWTAY rolls over, sprawls on the floor in an even sexier position. On her face, an expression of utter bliss. LT abandons the BEER.</context>
      <utterance>I got you a present. Better shit then you got, cop!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brown Downtown... There hasn't been any smoking brown on the street in --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARIANE helps LT with the thin, TIN FOIL PIPE. She burns the SMACK on the TIN FOIL SHEET for him so that he can manage to inhale the PLUME OF SMOKE in time. He gets a nice, deep hit. ARIANE gracefully takes a hit of her own. They are both very high, already. Beginning to NOD OUT. ARIANE goes back to the IMPLEMENTS and prepares another hit. This time she catches the SMOKE in a SHERRY GOBLET and LT drinks it. LT is very high now. A meditative, hallucinatory state. ARIANE takes a DIET COKE and lies down on the BED. She slowly sips soda through a straw. Her eyes are closed. LT sits in an EASY CHAIR by the WINDOW. LT NODS OUT while watching the SUNRISE. What we see appears to be HIS DREAM. From the melting RED SUN, we --</context>
      <utterance>Who said anything about the fucking street. I've got more connects than you have, Lieutenant...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT bounds off the COUCH, Still half-asleep, he crawls to the TV, turns on GAME FOUR. The LITTLE GIRL starts CRYING.</context>
      <utterance>Did I win? Shit! The game!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ANCIENT AUNT pokes her head into the LIVING ROOM.</context>
      <utterance>What's the score? What's the fucking score?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT AUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She disappears again.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno...</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT leans into the TV, transfixed, as -- ON TV: STRAWBERRY makes a fantastic catch of a Canseco drive with runners on base. LT CHEERS. DOORS SLAM (OFF). The TWINS have come home from school. They burst into the LIVING ROOM, loud as Hell. Furious about something they out-curse each other.</context>
      <utterance>Why me, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up! Did you see that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT curses and stomps around. The TWINS mimic his every move. All three are pissed. The rest of the FAMILY pays no mind.</context>
      <utterance>It's 7-0: Oakland.  That nigger could have let it drop and gone home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>confidentially - to</utterance>
   <speaker>LT)</speaker>
      <mode> LT)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Willie got shot by one of his boys.  But there's a ki under the back seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT saunters up to the MURDER CAR, DEAD WILLIE still in the front seat. LT is obviously berserk to get the KI, but he can't show it. LT susses out the situation. Around him, POLICE TECHNICIAN-TYPES are busy lifting fingerprints and analyzing the CAR and WILLIE -- to no apparent avail. LT uses his Lieutenants' privilege to enter the MURDER CAR and begin his own investigation. TIRE TRACKS are discovered nearby. The OTHER COPS are distracted. LT takes his shot. He reaches for and finds the KI of COCAINE under the BACK SEAT. LT slips it under his COAT and emerges from the MURDER CAR. Outside the MURDER CAR, LT makes to stand up. In the act, he -- DROPS the BAG of COKE! LT is stunned. He can't believe the KI is actually in the shitty, gutter water, in plain view of the other COPS. The COPS spot the KILO of COKE. Even those COPS that were far away, somehow know what has happened. They quickly gather round the MURDER CAR, LT, and the KI. The PLASTIC BAG filled with WHITE POWDER floats on the DEEP</context>
      <utterance>I'll put it in my trunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUDDLE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>LT is silent wrath incarnate.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess he was a bigtime dealer...  What d'ya know... A kilo of 'caine... Among the gathered COPS, only a SERGEANT is not quite convinced.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT has successfully covered himself, but he walks off cursing and mumbling. VERONICA is laughing demonstratively in the background.</context>
      <utterance>Where the fuck did that come from? The other COPS ignore the query. LT walks away.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP A</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT stops in his tracks. The erotic import of this conversation has seized LT's imagination. He heads toward the cluster of COPS, cuts in.</context>
      <utterance>But I still can't fucking believe they'd rape a nun, man...</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this shit about a nun getting raped?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP B</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COPS turn away, continue to talk among themselves. LT walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Where the fuck have you been? It happened this morning, up at St. Dominiek's in Spanish Harlem. A coupla punks tore up the place and then gave it to the nuns but good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They raped a nun and tore up the church -- they even took a crap on the altar. Up in Spanish Harlem.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A COP opens his TRUNK -- he has a BAR inside. The COPS, including LT, respond enthusiastically. DRINK UP.</context>
      <utterance>She was only seventeen...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck could do this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD IRISH COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The young nun's just a kid from Ireland. Imagine having to come here to have that happen!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus... What's she gonna tell her mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD IRISH COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COPS keep DRINKING. All of them lounging around on or beside the CARS. LT watches quietly, taking it all in. As if following the motto: "He who defines himself, confines himself."</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna kill those motherfuckers.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Church already put up a $50,000 reward!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FIRST COP raises a TOAST.</context>
      <utterance>Well, one of us is gonna get it. I mean -- get them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COPS all whoop and cheer.</context>
      <utterance>Here's to payback for the nuns!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone got any leads, at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got shit to go on. Only that list of inventory -- what they stole from the church.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know they actually stole those wacky purple robes? And they took the chalice -- with the Host still inside!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did they want with the Host?</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COPS avoid each others' eyes. Competition has begun. No one shares information, each after the reward for himself. LT bursts out, swings into high gear.</context>
      <utterance>They were hungry. I dunno. They didn't want to hock the Host, they wanted to hock that golden chalice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the COPS laugh, others are offended.</context>
      <utterance>Leave it to the Catholic Church, man. Girls get raped everyday, and now they're gonna pay 50 G just because these chicks wore penguin suits!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD IRISH COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your fucking problem?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Church is a racket.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD IRISH COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what. Are you a Catholic?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD IRISH COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BET COP and a couple of OTHER, FAMILIAR GAMBLER COPS move in. They've got nothing on their minds but the World Series.</context>
      <utterance>Do you believe in God? LT doesn't reply. He's thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAMBLER COP TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's see some green!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you know what's good for you, you'll keep staying on Oakland!</utterance>
   <speaker>BET COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT nods "yes." An outright lie.</context>
      <utterance>Oakland? Is that how you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sure. Don't you get it? The series has gotta last seven games. The last two did, didn't they? It's a racket. Do you have any idea how much money they make selling television-time for commercials during the series? Especially if it's a New York team? They won't close the gold mine after only four games. It'll last a full seven. Too many people wanna milk it for what it's worth. You'll see!</utterance>
   <speaker>BET COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SEVERAL COPS, including some of the COPS who have been hanging out in front of the HOSPITAL, go double or nothing on OAKLAND. LT takes their BET MONEY -- $900. One COP doesn't go along with the deal. LT painfully pays him off.</context>
      <utterance>All right... I'm in. After all, you're the expert. Ain't that right, LT?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT sits back on top of his CAR, DRINKING heavily. He toasts STRAWBERRY. The others are uneasy. Why toast STRAWBERRY?</context>
      <utterance>You'll be sorry, man. But if you wanna be a sissy, here's your bread.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strawberry? I thought we were going with Oakland.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are, man! That's the point! If the Mets win, it's thanks to Strawberry. If Oakland wins, it's thanks to Strawberry. Nothing can happen out there on the field that don't gotta do with Strawberry. So here's to Strawberry! The others join in the TOAST, but are uneasy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT can't help but check her out and flirt.</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in charge of the investigation. Just checking security.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Security?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The NURSE looks at him, unsure, then walks off down the</context>
      <utterance>Do you want those guys coming back? For the nun? Or for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORRIDOR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes upon a DOOR that is plastered with "QUARANTINE" SIGNS. One too many, perhaps. LT senses the NUN is inside. He has to open the DOOR, but hopes he won't get a blast of disease in his face. He CROSSES himself -- wearing a smirk, but nonetheless. Going on instinct, LT opens the door a crack. He's right. It's the NUN. He positions himself outside the DOOR, keeping it open a few inches. He peeks inside without being seen.</context>
      <utterance>LT continues his hunt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARIANE can't stop thinking about the rape.</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever seen a naked nun? I tell you, man, I went to school with the nuns, I've seen hundreds since then and I've never even seen a nun's belly button, you understand? But this nun, let me tell you. What a beautiful lady...  And where'd the Church get the 50 G in the first place? The fucking Church is the biggest scam going. You know what's the real killer? It costs $8,000 per kid for them to go to parochial school. I've got three kids in there already, with two on the way! Christ. That fucking reward is my money, man! But that's Church policy. The Pope is the world's biggest bookie. Makes people bet on their own salvation! Double or nothing on Heaven. You go to Hell -- then go to Hell. In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get over what those guys did to her. I just can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're alive, aren't they? Come on, man! Everyone's making such a fucking fuss, just because she's a nun. Just because she wears a penguin suit, the church puts up 50 G for the guys who dared to rape her. Do you think they'd put up a dime if you got raped? Of course not. Or even for your little sister? The virgin? Like shit they would.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susie's not a virgin anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARIANE suddenly starts up.</context>
      <utterance>She's fucking nine years old! Jesus Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT thinks for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>And the nun's not a virgin anymore, either. Will they make her leave the convent?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT snaps out once again, grabs the TELEPHONE. He dials LITE. He's not in. LT leaves ARIANE'S NUMBER on LIMELITE'S BEEPER. Hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Who knows? Who knows what their policy is.  But I'll tell you, man, that nun... She was beautiful. Just beautiful... Tall... Real tall... I've never seen anything like it...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's horrible. They burned her breasts with cigarettes. Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT stubs out his CIGARETTE on the back of his hand. He does the move with intensity and bravado. ARIANE responds by calmly doing the same. But she does it entirely impassively, and rubs the CIGARETTE into her flesh longer than LT did. ARIANE comes over to LT and starts kissing and licking his</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? At least she's alive! I see people get killed every day! Worse yet, tortured first and then killed! The nuns got off easy. Jeez. Cigarette burns. Everyone's all upset about fucking cigarette burns. I'll show you cigarette burns!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARIANE kneels down in front of LT. As if in prayer. She starts giving him head. Before he can answer The Question, he is saved by the bell. The PHONE RINGS. LT picks up immediately. It's LITE. As LT speaks to LITE, ARIANE continues to give him head.</context>
      <utterance>Do you believe in God? Do you believe that Jesus Christ is the Son of God?. LT hesitates.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT hangs up, thinks ARIANE won't resurface the God Question. ARIANE does, even as she gives him head. Every time she speaks, she pulls away and it frustrates him. This dialectic continues throughout the scene.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know, I know all about it. Enough already about the fucking nuns. Yeah. Yeah. So just take the bet. Don't give me any hassles, man. Just put in my bet. 30 G's. Yeah. And I got $900 from the cops on Oakland. Yeah. Right. Strawberry's gonna knock em dead. Of course he is! You know that! Yeah. Yeah. Have faith, man! OK. Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT thinks about it, even as ARIANE gets him hotter and hotter.</context>
      <utterance>Do you believe in God?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Church is a fucking racket. I know how they operate. I've been part of the racket since the first time some faggot priest spilt water on my head. My Aunt Lu says I was crying all the way through. Yeah, I know their game inside out. Now I'm free of it and I'm gonna stay that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not talking about the fucking Church. Fuck the Church. But tell me. Do you believe in God?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's to believe?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT can't respond. He's distracted by his own pleasure. ARIANE does something OC that causes LT sudden pain. LT cries out. Snaps to attention. Looks at ARIANE.</context>
      <utterance>That Jesus Christ was the Son of God and he came to die for your sins.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARIANE gives him head again. LT is more excited now than before she hurt him.</context>
      <utterance>Your sins, Lieutenant!  And look around you! Where do you think all this shit came from?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You believe that man is the be-all and end-all?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if in answer. LT begins to RECITE THE ACT OF CONTRITION</context>
      <utterance>OK. OK. Fine. But -- do you believe in God?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This turns on ARIANE. She stops talking. Writhes and grapples him. LT is reaching climax. When describing Jesus rising again -- LT has an orgasm.</context>
      <utterance>I believe in God the Father Almighty, Creator of Heaven and Earth...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't put some religious trip on me, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERSEY GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-uh... What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT looks at their PAPERS. Points to the name to which the CAR is registered.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Show me your papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this person? It ain't you, and it ain't you, so who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Aunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you took the car from you Aunt. Stole it. Am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were gonna give it back! We're on our way home, now!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT gets into the CAR, looks around. He finds a BAG OF POT. LT waves the POT in front of the GIRLS.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT grins. He takes out his own ROLLING PAPER, starts to ROLL a JOINT with their POT.</context>
      <utterance>Now why don't I just call up your Aunt right now and tell her what's gone down. How about that? The GIRLS are petrified.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He blackmails them into humiliating sex scenes. On a side street off Eleventh Avenue, LT plays it out until dawn.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm sure we could arrange something... Unless you fancy a few days in jail...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ELDERLY NUN speaks up.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you tell us anything? Sisters? Anything at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT, on the sidelines, turns to an OLDER COP. LT mutters his commentary</context>
      <utterance>They broke my glasses. I didn't see anything, but I did hear them. They were young. And there were two of them. They spoke Spanish. One of them was named Julio.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ELDERLY NUN lowers her head. Shamed.</context>
      <utterance>Julio. Great. There are 20,000 spics named "Julio".</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the COPS are magnetized by the YOUNG NUN. She does not appear to need GLASSES. Evidently, she could give the COPS what they want.</context>
      <utterance>I would tell you more if I could. I am so sorry, Officers.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>POV LT - The YOUNG NUN smiles a quiet, intractable smile. COP 2 is screaming mad, but tries to hide it. LT has observed their interaction. Though he would have loved to have heard some information from the YOUNG NUN, her defiance gives him even more pleasure. The MONSIGNOR comes forward to "translate" the NUNS' stubborn silence. He is possessed by a conventional sort of ambition -- this is his big chance. He would like to be Cardinal some day, but never will be. He enjoys the spotlight as he pontificates.</context>
      <utterance>What about you, Sister? Won't you tell us anything? LT watches the YOUNG NUN as --</utterance>
   <speaker>MONSIGNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MONSIGNOR clears his throat demonstratively, takes a dicitous tone.</context>
      <utterance>Listen. One nun is nearly 80 years old. I'm not from this Church, of course, but I assume they'll be getting her a new pair of glasses. Apparently she's legally blind without them. The Sister who suffered a rape is just 17. She arrived from Ireland only a couple of months ago. This -- event -- is just too much for them to take!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONSIGNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It appears for a moment as if the YOUNG NUN makes eye contact with LT. But he can't be sure. LT leaves the crowd, disappears out the DOOR.</context>
      <utterance>Listen. The Church would like to know who did it just as much as the NYPD. These arrant criminals broke the laws of man, and the laws of God. The Church wants nothing more than to see them behind bars. That's why we're offering the $50,000 reward to whomever brings them in. I'm sure our hero will be one of New York's Finest. The YOUNG NUN shoots the MONSIGNOR an offended look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK asshole. You owe thirty grand. Now what are you gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna go double or nothing on the next game.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Double or nothing? Are you fucking out of your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna let that bastard take my money</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take your money? This guy will blow up your house and everyone in it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LITE looks his friend up and down as if he's lost his mind.</context>
      <utterance>There's just no way the Mets will lose this game. Gooden is pitching and Strawberry is ready to break out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck Strawberry. You're gonna end up owing 60 G to a homicidal maniac!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LITE gestures assent, but is not happy. He waits a moment, looks around. POV LITE - LT'S FRIENDS and FAMILY. LT'S DAUGHTER in her</context>
      <utterance>That's my problem. Just put in my bet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me Father, for I have sinned. It has been two days since my last confession. Father, my sin is a terrible sin. A sin of omission. There was another sin that happened at the same time, and in the same place, but my sin I think was graver stil.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The NUN LAUGHS. At first, it sounds like crying. But it is a strange, low laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Sister, we all know what happened to you yesterday morning. I expected that you would want to speak to me about it. But you could have come to my office. Your being here, in the confessional, implies that you, Sister, have done something wrong. You haven't. I assure you. I feared you might have misplaced feelings of guilt. If you condemn yourself because you experienced feelings of... curiosity or even... pleasure, you mustn't --</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, if it was so trivial, so natural, so -- No. I have sinned. And you must listen if you are to prescribe an appropriate act of contrition, and to absolve me. Father, what would you do if you had but one day in which to use your arms to serve God?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's funny, you knew. But the first thing I think of is kneading the bread that I help bake for the soup kitchen. Maybe that's because my the muscles in my arms still hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I also thought of that bread, Father. And of that night six days ago when the Mother Superior died, and I kept the cool, damp cloth on her forehead freshly moist. Father, what would you do if you had but one day in which to use your legs to serve God?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think of running for help, and falling to my knees in prayer.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I have prayed day and night since the desecration of this church yesterday morning -- and my sin. You see, Father --</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Outside the CONFESSIONAL. LT reacts to the explicit word. Shock. Titillation and fascination.</context>
      <utterance>Yesterday morning, God gave me but one chance to use something else to serve Him. Not my arms or my legs, but something I used for the first time, for the last time, and will never use again. My vagina.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those boys, those sad, raging boys... They came to me as the needy do. And like many of the needy, they were rude. Like all the needy, they took. And like all the needy, they needed.  Father. I knew them; They learn in our school. And play in our schoolyard. And they are good boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Who were they, Sister? Who are these boys? What are the names of these -- good boys you knew? Outside the CONFESSIONAL, LT stiffens. This could be the clue he needs to solve the case.</context>
      <utterance>You knew them?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>silent reactions embody both decadence and awe. This apparent paradox can find unified expression in his character, though at other moments it threatens to tear him apart. The tension between the two polarities will propel him toward his destiny.</context>
      <utterance>I could tell you their names now, and I know you'd be bound by a sacred vow to keep my secret. But I cannot tell you their names. For I, too, am bound. As I am bound now to confess my sins. So listen, Father Listen.  I am a nun. What did I give those boys that they could not have found elsewhere? Nothing. Nothing at all. There were always two of us in the act. The act was half my own. It does not seem to me the act was half the act of a once of Christ.  It is the lost chance that will remain on the ledger of my sins. Not the loss of my virginity. The rape forced upon me a choice. As a vessel of the spirit. I could have imbued my vagina with God. Or, I could have turned away from God and voided my body of spirit, so that all that was left for those boys was a lump of flesh. I chose the second path. The easier, path. The path of the material world. The path no nun has the right to take. And so, I sinned.  My vagina spread, but spread no word. It opened, on nothingness. It gave nothing at all and left nothing behind. No trace of my act, yes my act. For I was there, too, remains in the landscape of God. The NUN'S description of the RAPE is both a turn on for LT and a matter of profound curiosity. Something divine. His</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT can't help but start up. As if, telepathically, the NUN knew he was there and cried out to him. Asked him to complete her mission. LT senses the confession is over. As the PRIEST begins to speak again, LT snaps to and returns to his original hiding place, near the CANDLES. LT watches as the NUN exits the CONFESSIONAL, KNEELS, holds her ROSARY BEADS, and begins to whisper the ACT OF CONTRITION -- what LT recited as ARIANE gave him head. The NUN does penance. LT watches her, still hidden, and transfixed. Cut from THE NUN to --</context>
      <utterance>Jesus turned water to wine. I ought to have turned bitter semen to fertile sperm -- hatred to love. And maybe to have saved their souls. They did not love me. I ought to have loved them. As Jesus loved those who reviled him. I ought to have surprised those boys. Instead, they surprised me, and got no surprise at all. No, they did not rape a nun. But a nun has been raped. And the nun must now atone for her sin. For a God-given part of her was wasted. A part which other women use for procreation, for conjugal fulfillment, for expressions of love. I had but one chance. And I did nothing but react in pain.  When those boys placed their hands upon my breasts, they had nothing but an assortment of skin cells in their grasp. They ought to have felt, through me. The bosom of their Redeemer. When they lay on top of me and looked down into my eyes, they saw fear. They should have met the eyes of a lover, And felt the presence of the Prince of Peace...  My vagina. I shall never have again. And never again shall I encounter two boys whose prayer was more legible, more poignant, more anguished. Two young men who threw themselves upon the altar and took me with them. And I did nothing for them. I can only hope that someone will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have the money?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What money?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT keeps doing COKE off hs wrist, even as ne speaks to LITE. LT can't seem to wipe the smile off his face.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bullshit me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't got it. Not tonight. You can't get blood from a stone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This psycho can.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooo... Big fucking scary guy. Just put $120,000 on tomorrow's game.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a fucking joke, you know that?  He's been waiting for the money since the fucking game ended. And I've been waiting here since -- forget it. Listen up. You're gonna get us both fucking killed. You know that!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A COCKTAIL WAITRESS delivers LT's VODKA. LT orders another one, flirts with her -- she's gone in a flash. LT downs the VODKA in one shot.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-uh. I'm gonna win. Just make sure the bet gets in.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do know that he's gonna blow up your house, kill your wife and kids --</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I'll give him an extra 10 grand for his trouble. I hate that motherfucking house and --</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gonna kill you, man. Do you hear me, motherfucker? You. Dead. Get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This breaks LT up. He laughs until he cries. LITE watches the spectacle. Falls silent. They sit quietly for a moment. LT, impatient with the delivery of his second VODKA, takes a bottle cut of his COAT and re-fills his GLASS. DRINKS it down. LITE tries changing the subject.</context>
      <utterance>I've been dodging bullets since I was fourteen. No one can kill me. I'm fucking blessed. I'm fucking Catholic.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the case going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What case?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fucking rapists, man. The punks who raped that nun. The $50,000 reward from the Church! Remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sure. Yeah. We're on it bigtime. Lots of leads. You bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT looks as LITE as if he's crazy. He shakes his head. Sing- songs at him as if trying to teach an impaired student.</context>
      <utterance>That 50 G could help you --</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A change comes over LT. He leans in, gets seriously excited. LT is possessed by his memory of this afternoon's game.</context>
      <utterance>The Mets are gonna win the Series. They're a lock.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get this, man. I was at the game today. Face to fucking face with Strawberry! Jesus! I saw him strikeout. And you know what? He looked at me, and I looked at him, and he laughed and I laughed and it was like we were all alone in that whole stadium and only we understood that it was all a racket, that he struck out on purpose, and that he's saving it up for the Big One. Tomorrow. Today I understood for the very first time that --</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT shakes his head. Repeats himself in that sing-song, didactic way.</context>
      <utterance>You've really got a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- that there was never any other way it could have gone.  Never any other way. So you had better just put in my fucking bet. $120,000 on the last game. The Big One. Come on! Are you a bookmaker, or fucking what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LITE stands up. He writes the BOOKIE'S NUMBER on a MATCHBOOK and gives it to LT. LITE leans over and gives LT a final warning.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Look I'll give you the psyho's number You call him yourself and tell him wnat you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT LAUGHS. He's already onto the next thing. He checks out the GIRLS at the other TABLES. LITE takes to go. Then decides to try once more to get LT's attention.</context>
      <utterance>You couldn't pay 60. You lose, you'll be in for 180. To a guy who kills people for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT is still laughing as LITE leaves the V.I.P ROOM. Before going out the door, LITE turns to look one more time at his friend. POV LITE - LT is engaged in a clumsy come-on. Oblivious. The last thing LITE sees is LT grabbing a COCKTAIL WAITRESS' LEG and falling out of his chair. LT LAUGHS all the way to the</context>
      <utterance>I was supposed to meet him at midnight with the 60. It's already 1:00 AM. Be careful. I mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOOR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT gets up a moment later, brushes himself off, and swaggers out of the V.I.P. ROOM.</context>
      <utterance>LITE lowers his head and exits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you doing, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JC notes LT's bizarre manner. Decides to humor his paranoid catatonia.</context>
      <utterance>Very good. Very good. The Mets are gonna win tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JC reaches into a bookcase, looking for something. Meanwhile, LT looks around the room. POV LT - A SHRINE is in the corner. CANDLES are lit before PLASTER SAINTS, AFRICAN DEITIES, other icons abstruse and exotic. A large "MADONNA AND CHILD", painted on black velvet, hangs above the SHRINE. The MADONNA AND CHILD are BLACK. LT takes this all in. JC startles him. JC is holding a CIGAR BOX. He opens it. It's full of CASH. JC hands it to LT.</context>
      <utterance>I know. Here. Just a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>JC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAMACITA takes some VIALS of CRACK out of her APRON. SMILES. JC takes them from her, give them to LT.</context>
      <utterance>This should be it. Oh, wait.  Mamacita?</utterance>
   <speaker>JC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There. Now you've got your profit and more. You'll have more product day after tomorrow, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh - right. Sure. The Mets are gonna win tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(beat - looks at LT with concern) Take care of yourself, man, OK? Be cool. LT nods, puts MAMACITA'S CRACK VIALS in his pocket. He notices that -- POV LT - CU - The CIGAR BOX is inlaid with a CROSS, made of costume jewels. Other strange symbols surround it. It could be cursed -- or blessed. LT turns to go. The DOOR closes behind him. He's gone.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="43">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ariane laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Someone just took a shot at me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT turns on her. Adamant. Pleading with her to believe him.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, baby Sure And you don't do cocaine, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not the drugs, Ariane, it's -- it's someone who wants to kill me.  You gotta believe me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARIANE walks away, speaks with her back to LT.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT lays his COAT down on the BED. Puts the CIGAR BOX of MONEY under it. LT sits down near the PHONE. He lights his CRACKPIPE with a MATCH from the MATCHBOOK on which LITE wrote the BOOKIE'S NUMBER. Then he tries to reach the BOOKIE. Some sort of wacky Mob joint answers.</context>
      <utterance>Just kick back, baby. Make yourself at home.  But of course it won't be nobody's home, if you don't come through with the fucking rent!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Is LARGE there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOB VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, man. Lite gave ne this number. OK? Just take a message. Tell Large to fucking call me right away at 123- 1234. Got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOB VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(laughs)</context>
      <utterance>Sure, I get it...</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT tries to strangle the PHONE.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a good friend of Lite's, man. It's urgent that -- The MOB VOICE  HANGS UP ON LT.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT REDIALS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The line is BUSY.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ! Shit! I could kill them all with my bare hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT makes the strangulation gesture again. ARIANE laughs at him.</context>
      <utterance>Those fucking Mob assholes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mere. You got some good blow, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARIANE pulls out a pristine NEEDLE. LT comes but flinches at the sight. Apparently BOWTAY overheard that drugs are on the way. BOWTAY appears out of the KITCHEN. BOWTAY sits down near by, awaiting her DOSE. ARIANE starts preparing the DOSE. She's got all the paraphernalia: SPOON. COTTON, a CANDLE FLAME, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Then c'mere. I got something for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First I'll put your Uptown in the spoon, then, to make it more exciting, I'm gonna add some Downtown. They call this thing a speedball, honey, but then you must know that...  First time shooting up?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That decides it for LT. He sits down like a little boy and lets ARIANE shoot him up with the potent mixture of COCAINE and HEROIN. ARIANE shoots up BOWTAY, next. They do it on the BED, exploiting all possible erotic connotations. When LT rushes, he gets totally paranoid. Jumps at sounds, sneaks to the WINDOW, hears noises that aren't there. Then he flips, and becomes crazy-bold. Opens the DRAPES. Sticks his head out the WINDOW, waves his GUN at specters. Then he becomes shit-scared, again. His behavior is lunatic. ARIANE LAUGHS at his antics. Finally LT becomes wildly sensual. Revealing himself with total abandon. Dances. In the midst of this -- The PHONE RINGS LT is seriously startled. Then he realizes who it may be. He slowly answers the phone. LT can hardly speak. He is NUDE, and communicating from another world syllable by syllable.</context>
      <utterance>Sure it is. You're a virgin. Just like that nun. And I'm gonna rape you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Large?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARGE</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, cop. I want my money.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's still my money. If you want to have a chance at any part of it, shithead, you will take my $120,000 and bet on tomorrow's game.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARGE</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the money you owe me on yesterday's game?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck yesterday's game. The World Series is seven games not six. Put in my bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARGE</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BIG SILENCE on the PHONE.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing to think about. Either you put in my bet or you ain't getting nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, really?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, really. I'm no fucking asshole, man. I'm a fucking cop!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARGE</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>LT absorbs this, then bursts out.</context>
      <utterance>OK, cop. I want you to give yourself and your friends on the force a message. Tell them I've got my own reasons to be very interested in whomever did the job on the nuns. I'll double the Church reward if you bring those punks direct to me. 100 G cash. Get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LARGE takes a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck the nuns, man! I'm talking about Strawberry! Is the bet down?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARGE</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's the deal: You meet me tonight across from the Garden. 33rd &amp; 8th. At the beginning of the Ninth Inning. We'll listen to the end of the game together. You bring your cash, I'll bring mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT HANGS UP, turns to ARIANE.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sucker. You better be there!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you believe the nerve of this fucking guy? He kills people for fun, and then, he puts up 100 G to bring in some guys who raped a nun. What a sick fuck. Man...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARIANE'S eyes light up.</context>
      <utterance>A wiseguy. Paying 100 Grand for the rapists if I turn then over direct to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you could do it, baby. We could use the bread...</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT leaps up. He's on a manic roll. Conceives an insanely captivating, impossible idea. As he speaks, he speeds more and more until he seems to be reciting a rapid-fire tongue twister perfect.</context>
      <utterance>You mean you could use it. ARIANE SHRUGS, waves his dig aside.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it, man! I will find those kids. And I'll get the 50 G from the Church! Then the kids'll go to jail. I'll be in charge, of course. After a little while, I'll break the fuckers out -- and I'll turn them in to shithead I was just talking to. And pick up his 100 G. No. I'll hit him up for 200 G. Or 250 G. l can do it -- 'cause I've got the kids. Then, of course, there's the 180 G I'm gonna pick up on the Game tonight -- when the Strawberries win!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The Strawberries"?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARIANE has been grooving on it until now. She sees a problem they've overlooked.</context>
      <utterance>The Mets. So anyway, chalk up another 180 G for the Game. Jesus Christ! That's almost half a million dollars. Ariane! Wait. That's not good enough, I'll ask the shithead for 280 G for the kids. Then it'll be a perfect 500 thousand. Yeah. Perfect. 280 G for the kids. Yeah, it's good I prepared, or I wouldn't have thought to --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come all those guys who're looking to get 50 from the Church haven't come up with shit? You got some kinda inside track?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARIANE LAUGHS, decides to go with it. LT, out of breath from his tirade, lets the Downtown half of his dose kick in but good. He sits down in the same EASY CHAIR in which he nodded out the morning of the desecration. Nodding out, he stares out the same WINDOW. His eyes close. As it was that morning only four days ago, the SUNRISE is blood red. As if it is LT'S DREAM, we --</context>
      <utterance>I'm a Catholic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The NUN turns to run.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, Sister, listen to me good. The other cops'll just put the guys through the system. They're juveniles. They'll walk! Get it? But I'll beat the system and do justice. Real justice. For you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT is desperate. He lunges forward. Pleads with her.</context>
      <utterance>I have already forgiven them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on lady! They put out cigarettes on your tits, man! Get with the program! Don't you want them behind bars? Or away from the world for good? How could you forgive these motherfu -- excuse me. These guys. How could you? Deep down, don't you want them to pay for what they did to you? Don't you want the crime avenged?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have forgiven them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The NUN turns to him, simple and pure, pure and simple.</context>
      <utterance>Nun! These boys still have their weapons, Sister. Your forgiveness will leave blood in its wake. What if they do it to other nuns? Other virgins? Old women who die from the shock? Do you have the rights let these boys go free? Can you bear the burden. Sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have prayed for days, Lieutenant. I have prayed for the souls of the boys who raped me. And I have prayed for my own soul, too. I know what I must do. And I know what I must not do.  But you -- you -- it is you who needs to pray. Now, why do you want to kill these boys? Why -- really?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. Sister. No one has to get killed. We can solve this together. You and me -- as one. These boys are lost sheep. Both Catholic -- did you know that? And they're sick, Sister. With a stress of the mind and of the soul. They need help. Not just jail. Not just psychiatry. They need the help that only the Church can give. Please help me to help them. Help me find them before the others do. The night is full of evil men, chasing these boys with guns and clubs. We have charity and love on our side. I know that together, we could find them first, even in the dark...</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This blows him away. He has nothing to say to that. The NUN has finished her morning prayers. For a moment, she looks deep into LT's eyes. Then she gets up and leaves LT alone in the CHURCH. LT comes face to face with the mammoth CRUCIFIX. He is transfixed. POV - LT - JESUS on the CROSS. Soon, LT hears a VOICE. LT is not shocked or even surprised. He speaks to JESUS as to someone he's known all his life.</context>
      <utterance>The good reasons are not always the real reasons. Talk to Jesus, Lieutenant. Pray.  You do you believe in God -- don't you? That Jesus Christ died for your sins?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESUS</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESUS</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't forgive me. After what I've done.  I've fucked up bigtime. I've been bad. Real bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>POV LT - The CRUCIFIX takes on an hallucinatory radiance. Taking that aura with him, JESUS comes down off the CROSS, and moves toward LT, who is still kneeling at the ALTAR.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Please don't forgive me. I've always hated you for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Why can't you hate me? Hate me! Please! Help me!  Hate me! Help me! Hate me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JESUS kneels down, knee to knee, face to face with LT.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Jesus! Why me? Why can't I wash the ashes from my forehead, year after year after year? And why am I still drunk on your blood, the taste of your flesh on my tongue? Worst of all, why can't I feel the nails in my palms, the spear in my side, the crown of thorns round my head? Why do I have to know, over and over, that it was you. You who died; died for my sins! And that I will die for nothing. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT rises, moves around the interior of the CHURCH. He stumbles, struggles, pleads. Falls, rises, falls and rises again -- as if wrestling with an invisible assailant. He collapses in a corner.</context>
      <utterance>Why do I dream every night of the whore who brought you water on your road to death? And why have I never forgotten that if she, then I -- LT averts his eyes. When he looks up again -- JESUS is back on the CROSS. Inert, and yet --</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, my God. it's goddamn good to be good. Forgive me. Father, for I have sinned. It's still goddamn good to be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgive you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At first, she doesn't speak at all. LT begins to CRY. Begs her to tell him. Then he wields his PISTOL, repeats his plea. Then breaks into TEARS. She speaks at last.</context>
      <utterance>The chalice. Tell me! Who gave it to you! Tell me where the fuck you got it! Take me there! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gun in hand, LT gets down on his knees.</context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the name of God, you must.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My husband will give me Hell, Mister.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She meets LT's eyes, seems to understand something. Calmly, she tells him what he needs to know.</context>
      <utterance>We've already got Hell, Sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very hard. He's a -- you're not a cop, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN lets go of the CHALICE. Now LT holds ten CHALICE in his hands, alone. He speaks as if entranced.</context>
      <utterance>My husband is a fence. He got this chalice from a couple of kids. Just yesterday, I think. I stole it out of his shop so as to return it to where it ought to be. It's a holy thing, you know. A holy thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly purposive, LT grabs the ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN by the arm. Starts pulling her out of the CHURCH. He holds the CHALICE with the other arm, picks up the CIGAR BOX on his way out. Manages to carry both items. When LT and the ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN reach the door to outside, they both pause to GENUFLECT. Then LT grabs her again and they rush out.</context>
      <utterance>A holy thing.  Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You took the chalice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You brought it back to the Church. And then it made it's way back to me, again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Th FENCE bursts out LAUGHING.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you all right, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>FENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN is obviously relieved.</context>
      <utterance>I was gonna bring it back myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>FENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT speaks up suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, woman! What did you think? You thought I'd get mad like I did that time you took that set of pots and pans? That was twenty years ago. And how do you compare pots and pans and a chalice?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a beat, the FENCE and his WIFE start LAUGHING. LT joins in.</context>
      <utterance>They both hold stuff you eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>FENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY BLACK WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to know who brought in the chalice.</utterance>
   <speaker>FENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FENCE thinks again.</context>
      <utterance>That's no mystery. Julio and Paolo brought it in,  You don't want to hurt those boys, do you? I mean, they sure as Hell have got something coming, but it ain't what the Law wants to give them. You understand?  No. How could you understand. The FENCE seems to study LT. POV FENCE - LT. Wretched.</utterance>
   <speaker>FENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>POV LT - Through the WINDOW of the FENCE'S SHOP, a busy DRUG CORNER is visible.</context>
      <utterance>Well -- maybe you do. But I don't know where those boys are at right now. You'll have to ask around. Those boys on the corner'll know. You'll have to get it out of them. But they know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT leaves. CHALICE in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. And I'll make sure the chalice gets back where it belongs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The STREET DEALER uses his WALKMAN and the resulting "deafness" to excuse his total lack of response. LT starts MOUTHING WORDS silently at the STREET DEALER. No response. Then, he -- silently -- begins to shout. The STREET DEALER's alarmed that he seemingly can't hear at all above the WALKMAN music. He moves the WALKMAN away from his ears but doesn't take it off.</context>
      <utterance>Hey -- Have you seen Paolo or Julio around?</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT points to a PUDDLE in which the STREET DEALER is now Standing.</context>
      <utterance>You know, my Uncle used to wear a walkman all the time. The walkman looked just like yours. And you look something like my Uncle. But one day he was standing in a puddle -- the puddle locked just like that one --</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The STREET DEALER tries to consider what this crazy guy has just told him, but before the STREET DEALER can even react. LT leans in on him, shows his GUN and then his BADGE.</context>
      <utterance>And he got electrocuted.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The STREET DEALER answers with absolute ease. That was all it was about? No problem.</context>
      <utterance>Look -- I don't know you, and you don't know me, but I'm really in the mood to kill someone today and you are at the end of my gun.  Have you ever had days like that? Yeah, you have, so now you understand where I'm coming from.  Tell me! Where is Julio and Paolo ?</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CU. LT - It hits him. The CRACKHOUSE where the kids hang out has always been right next to the CHURCH/CONVENT where it an began! It suddenly makes sense to him. LT completes re transaction, pays the STREET DEALER for the DRUG BAGS. He takes the CASH out of the CIGAR BOX, revealing dozens of thousands of dollars. The STREET DEALER stares at the wretched man with a box full of cash.</context>
      <utterance>They were at that abandoned building last night. Second floor. They're probably still there now. It's next to the old Convent. Downtown a ways. You know the place...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JULIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fu--</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT sits down next to the KIDS. SMOKES with them, watches the Game. LT must hold the PIPE for them, as they are HANDCUFFED. LT gets them super-high, and himself likewise. He still holds his GUN. The KIDS go along with it. Taking it moment to moment. All three, despite the situation, are heavily into the Game.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. Let's watch the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strawberry...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment, LT gets up. The KIDS understand that they must do the same.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KIDS hand over the PURPLE ROBES and LT puts them on.</context>
      <utterance>Give me the robes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not a cop are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT exits. Taking the KIDS along. He carries the CHALICE and the CIGAR BOX.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT turns around and looks at JULIO and PAOLO, both of them HANDCUFFED in the back seat. POV LT - CU - JULIO and PAOLO both have TEARS running down their cheeks. Silently.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus died for your sins, you motherfuckers! Not me. No. I didn't die for your sins. No, not me. Jesus went and did it.  So why did you do what you did? If you want to live, tell me now, motherfuckers! Tell me now!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT starts CRYING too, at the same time CURSING at the TRAFFIC. He drives wildly toward the Port Authority Terminal. The Mets are coming up from behind -- but it is a long shot. LT doesn't seem to care. He stares into space.</context>
      <utterance>I forgive you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE BUS: He makes them board at GUN POINT.</context>
      <utterance>Get out. The KIDS do. LT follows fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LT uncuffs them and the KIDS get on the BUS, dumbstruck. LT hands JULIO the CIGAR BOX. His "salvation." The KIDS don't even know what is inside. They take it. LT gets back into his CAR, takes off.</context>
      <utterance>If you think you're not getting on this bus, you're dead wrong. No fucking way are you gonna miss this bus, man! You were probably the kind of kids who had your father drive you to school cause you couldn't catch the fucking bus. But no more, man. You're getting on this bus and you're taking it to the last fucking stop. So get on the fucking bus, man, 'cause you're life ain't worth shit in this town.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
