<movie id="59" title="Bad Teacher">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANDY PINKUS, 40s, sporting a ponytail, smiles, clearly enjoying the small compliment.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's been another great year here at JAMS. Who can forget Mr. Pinkus' haunted classroom? Sandy, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other teachers laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't afraid of no ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or the wild success of...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Wally turns to AMY SQUIRREL, late 20s, cute and wholesome. Any trace of sexuality she might have is wiped away by her adult pigtails. She treats students and adults alike -- like students.</context>
      <utterance>Wally, can I just say one quick thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wanted to remind everyone the school day's not over. So let's keep the drinking under control, hmm? That's it. Back to you, Wally. A bunch of teacher roll their eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A broad-shouldered teacher with spiky hair, MS. SAVICKI, nods.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Amy,  . Or the wild success of the book drive for the women's prison sponsored by Ms. Savicki's class?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But now as the summer is upon us, it's time to not only say goodbye to another school year, but to also say goodbye to a member of our faculty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>ELIZABETH HALSEY, mid 20s, pretty and petite, walks up to the front. She sports an enormous diamond ring and dresses slightly more cosmopolitan than the other teachers.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, can you come up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth gives Principal Snur an appreciative smile. The Teachers lightly applaud.</context>
      <utterance>You've only been with us for one short year, but know that you'll always be a part of the JAMS family.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Wally hands Elizabeth an envelope. She opens it and. pulls out a gift card: BOSTON MARKET. $37.</context>
      <utterance>And we got you a little something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost forty dollars. Thank you!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you say a couple words?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Um... I'm not really good at this type of thing so I'll make it quick. I know I've only been here a year, but there's so much I'm going to miss...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth's class is horsing around, enjoying the last days of seventh grade. A dim-looking BOY tentatively approaches her desk with his yearbook in hand. He hands it to Elizabeth, who considers what to write for a beat, then smiles as she signs it.</context>
      <utterance>My students, probably most of all.I'm not saying they were little angels, butthey were all there to learn and that'sthe greatest gift a student can give a teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth passes Amy's classroom, where she is carefully removing inspirational posters from her walls and rolling them into cardboard tubes.</context>
      <utterance>And I wish that I had gotten to know all of you better, but between four classes and planning a wedding, I had my hands full. From the little I do know about you, I know that our students are in good hands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth comes up behind them.</context>
      <utterance>And I can't believe it's all over. This year flew by. And even though I'll never teach again professionally, I've realized that I don't need a blackboard and classroom to set an example.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Burnouts' eyes all go wide and they freeze. One of the burnouts hands her the joint.</context>
      <utterance>Hand it over.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The kids look at each other and then pull out a bag with a couple of joints. They hand it over to Elizabeth.</context>
      <utterance>Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was a warning. Next time, I don't call the principal. I call the cops.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DIM-LOOKING KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth's car comes barrelling toward him and nearly hits him. She accelerates into the speed bumps, almost hitting the JANITOR from the opening shot, who's changing the plastic letters to read, "HAVE A GREAT SUMMER!"</context>
      <utterance>You are... Illit... Illit...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slow down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CALLING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby Doll?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>MARK, early 30s, exits the bedroom in his underwear. He's shaved his head to avoid signs of early balding and is also a full four inches shorter than Elizabeth. Thankfully for him, he has money.</context>
      <utterance>Coming!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises her glass for a toast. He raises his.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You should have seen it. What a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's to me never having to work again. And I owe it all to you, Lover. Elizabeth takes a big sip.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - FLIRTATIOUS</mode>
      <context>Something drops in the bedroom. Mark, alarmed, turns towards the door. Elizabeth brushes past him into --</context>
      <utterance>So I made a reservation at Ruth's Chris, and then I booked us a suite at the Drake, and I thought we could finish the night in "anal alley." Hmm?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, the wooden chest at the foot of the bed SNEEZES. Elizabeth opens the latch to find SHEILA, 23, dressed only in a thong, scrunched in the fetal position. She stands, revealing LARGE FAKE BREASTS, and steps out of the chest.</context>
      <utterance>See? Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>TO MARK</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Motherfucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm sorry.</context>
      <utterance>How could you do this to me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bless you.</context>
      <utterance>You are buying me the biggest pair of yellow diamond earrings they make! I'm talking serious blood diamonds. Sheila SNEEZES again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>TO SHEILA</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of my house, bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to her like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark puts his arm around Sheila. Elizabeth eyes Sheila's large breasts.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me? I love her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You love her? She's a hooker.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>She's not a hooker. I dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - SWEET</mode>
      <context>Sheila SNEEZES again.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Marky, you made a mistake. You're human. I'm human. And this time it was you. Maybe six months from now, you'll walk in on me. I don't know, but probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up.  And. maybe I'm talking crazy, but I don't want to throw away our life together over something like this. We're getting married! I'm willing to fight for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheila squeezes his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not. And you know why? Because Sheila loves me -- and not just for my money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry if I care that my future husband can support me. We didn't all grow up with a silver spoon in our mouths. You can't even imagine what it's like going to bed hungry, night after night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?! Both your parents are CPAs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My parents worked their asses off to send me to private school. Do you know what it's like driving a Pontiac when everyone else gets a Beemer the second they menstruate? That shit stays with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's over, Elizabeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the record, there's a shitload of things that I hate about you, but I still, would've gotten married.  Because I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs her bag and heads for the exit. Mark follows.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna need the ring back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sad little troll! I hope you and your hooker enjoy chlamydia together!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth. The ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ring!</context>
      <utterance>I'm not even listening to you anymore. She starts to open the door. He closes it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries pulling it off.</context>
      <utterance>Like I even want your gay-ass ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mark takes her hand and removes the ring with ease. Elizabeth steps out into the night. The door SLAMS behind her.</context>
      <utterance>It's not coming off. I'll go to the jeweler's tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth Halsey, as I live and breathe!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amy Squirrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know we barely got a chance to get to know one another last year -- what with you planning the wedding of the century and me juggling all my extra-currics -- but I just want to say that I'm super excited to be across-the-hall-mates.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I know you kinda skated by last year, doing the bare minimum thing -- you were kind of a lone wolf -- but now you're back and I just know that you are going to rededicate yourself to the task at -- Amy notices Elizabeth's bare hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your beautiful ring?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh my gosh!</context>
      <utterance>My fiance and I broke it off. I found him in bed with someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was another man.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>INCREDULOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the front door!  Somebody needs a hug.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth takes an apple from a desk.</context>
      <utterance>Hm. Another time then.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>RE APPLE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These washed?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRUNCH. Elizabeth takes a huge bite out of the apple.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. I'd never serve a student unwashed fruit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>MOUTHFUL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought the teachers got the apples.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I think the students teach me at least as'much as I teach them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth tosses the mostly uneaten apple into the trash and exits. It hits the rim and lands on the floor. Okey-dokey.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh sorry, am I interrupting?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um -- kinda.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to grab some lunch?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>My treat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in the middle of something, Lynn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you excited for tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is tomorrow Saturday?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's the first day of school.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, I thought I had a week to get my class together.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that was last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you hate teaching so much, why don't you just get another job?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do what? Sell perfume at the mall? Work at a day care center?  You know, when I first got into teaching, I thought I was doing it for all the right reasons: short hours, summers off, no accountability.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love my summers. Fresh corn. Mmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From now on, my full-time job will be finding a guy who will take care of me --</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god, I pray for that --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that makes a shit ton of money and doesn't ask too many questions.  I spent most of my summer hanging out at the bars near where the Bulls practice. Had some fun, got some cool souvenirs that I Ebayed, but those guys aren't looking to settle down. And they all wear condoms. And then they take the condoms with them. That's how paranoid they are that a girl will try and get pregnant. Like it's so easy to get pregnant from a guy nutting into a condom.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna find someone great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking about it a lot. I mean, I figure I'm like an 8, 8.5. But once I get my new tits, I'll probably be a --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to do that. You're already so pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I'm hot, Lynn, but I don't stand a chance against all those Barbies dolls out there. Anna Nicole had it right, may she rest in peace. Lynn checks her watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should finish up. Wally's doing that big orientation for teachers in the auditorium.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm not going to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's mandatory.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooohhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I probably won't go either. I don't know I might. I'll probably go, but just sit in the back. Maybe leave early. Maybe stay till the end. Play it by ear. Or just stay till the end. Lynn takes both their, trays and dumps them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it was alright. When you said you were taking me to lunch, I kinda thought it was going to be nicer, but this was okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. You can get me next time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her chest intently. She's not bothered by it. Go bigger. Kirk enters his bedroom and slams the door.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Kirk, what do you think about me with Jessica Simpson's tits?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at the clock: 3:14 AM.</context>
      <utterance>Cool, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck my ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He made me feel sooo comfortable.</context>
      <utterance>The photographer was, like, sooo nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHASE</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might get flown to Kansas City for their fashion week.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode>RIVETED</mode>
      <context>Chase and her friends turn to face Garrett, who's as surprised as they are that he spoke.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Garrett quickly turns away. Chase rolls her eyes. An angry-looking kid, TRISTAN, wearing a MICHAEL VICK JERSEY, turns to Garrett.</context>
      <utterance>Stalk much?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRISTAN</speaker>
      <mode>FAKE SNEEZING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Faggot.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode>EARNEST</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRISTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth, with large bags under her eyes, enters the class. Tristan, on a dime, heads back to his seat. The class immediately quiets down. SASHA, 12, dressed like a paralegal, walks up to Elizabeth with a large Tupperware tray.</context>
      <utterance>What'd you say to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Sasha. It's a pleasure to meet you.  My mother baked these for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sasha, confused, gently puts them down and stands there. After a moment, Elizabeth looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Just leave them on the desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need something?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth takes a DVD from her bag. She points to two KIDS in the front of the class.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone here seen "Stand and Deliver?" Show of hands.  No one? Edward James Olmos? Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The two kids, SHAWN and SPENCER, roll the TV over. Sasha shuts off the LIGHTS.</context>
      <utterance>You and you, go grab the TV and roll it up front.  And you, go shut off the lights.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're watching a movie on the first day?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHASE</speaker>
      <mode>TO ELIZABETH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's awesome. You rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth pops in the DVD. "Stand and Deliver," starring Edward James Olmos as a tough-as-nails calculus teacher in an inner-city school begins. Elizabeth takes a bite of one of Sasha's cookies and immediately spits it out.</context>
      <utterance>I agree with Chase.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes the Tupperware tray into the trash next to her desk. Sasha looks on, sadly.</context>
      <utterance>Ugh. Oatmeal raisin?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRISTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Direct hit. The cole slaw nails him in the shoulder. Garrett picks some of the cole slaw off his shirt and eats it. He continues writing. Amy races over to Tristan and writes him up. Elizabeth watches, bored, struggling to keep her eyes open. Amy heads over to Elizabeth.</context>
      <utterance>Incoming!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody's got a case of the sleepies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see what just happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that one kid hit the other kid with the cole slaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't at the orientation the other day, but we're doing something new this year. It's very exciting. We're splitting the cafeteria into quadrants. Elizabeth yawns.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, anyways, in order for the quadrant system to work, it's vital that each teacher maintain order within their quadrant. Because it's really tough for me as head lunch monitor -- or another teacher -- to leave their quadrant to discipline a kid in another quadrant. I know it's a lot to take in. I'd be happy to sit with-you after school and explain all of the new guidelines.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what. Why don't you send me a memo, and if I have any questions, I'll come to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Elizabeth. Sounds like a plan, Stan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - TO ELIZABETH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I meant to ask you. Did I hear that you were showing a movie this morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I know what you heard?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fair enough. Listen, I don't want to tell you how to run your class, but maybe it might be fun to do some ice-breakers. Like "Telephone Charades" or "The String Game." Or start doing practice questions for the state test. It's never too soon to start.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we gonna have a problem, me and you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shishkebobs, no. If I gave you that impression, I am so sorry. Actually, I was really hoping that we could be more than across-the-hall-mates.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you've heard, but I don't munch box.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, of course not. I don't even know what that is. I just meant friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like getting manicures and going shopping on Sundays? Shit like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking out for one another.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! Yes! And helping each other out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth doesn't wait for an answer, walks off.</context>
      <utterance>That's cool. Tell you what, friend, I'm gonna get going. Cover for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>NERVOUS</mode>
      <context>(looks at clock)</context>
      <utterance>But you can't leave. Lunch doesn't end for another...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>VERY FRIENDLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi there. You look a little lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Can you tell me where Room 124 is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do you one better. I'll take you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you don't have to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you stop? It'd be my pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks! I feel like I've been walking around in circles for the last fifteen minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>EXTENDS HAND</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scott Delacorte. I'm the new sub.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands a beat too long. Elizabeth notices Scott's VERY EXPENSIVE WATCH.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth Halsey, 7th Grade Language Arts. Welcome, welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helluva watch. What's that -- a Jaeger- LeCoultre?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good eye!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I love men's watches. It's kind of a hobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a bummer knowing my watch could feed a village for .a year, but my grandfather designed it, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? Your grandfather designs watches?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The family business. My mom's maiden name is Jaeger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth smiles and they start walking down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>My parents had a minor meltdown when I decided to join the Peace Corps and become a teacher. But they've been cool about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Integrity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.. The poster. "Integrity." What a great message for the kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn a corner. Garrett wheels his backpack past them.</context>
      <utterance>That's why I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ms. Halsey!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slaps him five. Scott notices, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Hey... dude...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, I can't wait for the day that I have my own classroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... So did you and your wife just move to town?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not married.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me neither. I was engaged until I walked in on my fiance cheating on me. With his brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's horrible!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>NOTICING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooh, 124! This is me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you, Scott Delacourte. Hopefully, we'll be seeing a lot of each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>HALF-JOKING</mode>
      <context>He heads into the room. Elizabeth cocks her head, checking out his ass as the door closes.</context>
      <utterance>Only if a teacher gets sick. Great meeting you, Elizabeth Halsey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>TO HERSELF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very nice meeting you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DR. VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you can see, the weight is evenly distributed and there's minimal scarring.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode>TAH DAH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Vogel.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Best Hands in Chicago."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DR. VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth reaches out, squeezes Danni's breasts.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. Take them for a spin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh. Elizabeth notices Dr. Vogel'.s watch.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. And the nipples are just... I love them. I'll take two.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maurice Lacroix. That's a great watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CURIOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how's that going?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's my rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>Danni puts her bra and blouse back on and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, thanks, Danni.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking, you know, maybe a D.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>IJh huh, uh huh. I ,would say, though, with your frame, you might consider something smaller. A large B, maybe a C cup. You'd be surprised how significant those would look.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm. Yeah, I think I'll go with the D's, really turn some heads.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DR. VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Elizabeth, breast enhancement's not a cure-all. I just want to make sure you have realistic expectations.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor, I lost my fiance to a woman with monster fake tits. So now I need monster fake tits so that I won't lose my next fiance. Those are my expectations. Is that realistic enough for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you'll be off your feet for about two weeks... what works for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do December 19th. Start of winter break.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth laughs. Danni laughs.</context>
      <utterance>The 19th it is. So the total is $9300 for the surgery plus one night stay at our facility. How would you like to pay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's absurd. What if I don't spend the night at your facility?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The night's included in the price. Did you not read our literature?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MIDDLE-AGED DOCTOR walks by.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi...  Listen, I'm a teacher, not a drug dealer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We accept all major credit cards.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My credit situation is complicated.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but if you can't pay, I can't schedule the appointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode>LEANING IN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, there are less expensive options. Have you looked into South America?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth dramatically scoops a handful of mints from the bowl and storms out.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>ON PHONE</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth pokes holes in the Lean Cuisine with a knife and turns on the microwave.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I just really need some money. It's, for a surgery I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - ON PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, as a matter of fact, it is about my breasts, dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, limpdick, you owe me for breaking off the engagement. Do you know how embarrassing that was?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth hurls her phone at the wall. It smashes.</context>
      <utterance>Lover, I don't want to fight. It's just 10000 dollars and it would really mean the world to me. Lover? You there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Kirk pokes his head out of his bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Fucking Troll!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you call my name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I said 'fucking troll.'</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and heads back in to his room.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I thought you said Kirk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you got ten grand?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirk closes his door. After a beat, he opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He closes his door. The microwave BEEPS. Dinner's ready.</context>
      <utterance>Also, I might be a little short on the rent this month. Like, a lot short.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. That's a lot of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. And I hate asking a friend for money -- especially as good a friend as you. This has its desired effect on Lynn.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I could sell that jewelry my grandmother gave me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That turquoise crap? Blech. No one's buying that.  But it looks great on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. What about Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What type of person do you think I am?! That assbag cheated on me. Did I ever tell you that he has a mole on the tip of his dick?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy walks over.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to better myself. I don't think that's asking for so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drops quarters into the vending machine, but doesn't bother selecting an item. This was clearly her "in." She turns to Elizabeth and Lynn.</context>
      <utterance>'Scuse,me. Just gonna scooch in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sooo... I know it's none of my business, but I couldn't help but overhear your conversation and I just want to say, that you shouldn't change a thing. You should be happy with the way you are. That's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy stammers.</context>
      <utterance>Huh. Well, do you think mental retards should be happy with the way they are?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lynn, you teach them. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONSIDERING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never asked them.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would never --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't all have your tits, Squirrel. So maybe you should think before you interrupt a private conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy pushes the coin release on the vending machine and takes back her change without getting a drink. Amy heads back to the couch.</context>
      <utterance>I guess that's what you get for trying to help...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott enters. All of the female teachers light up. There he is!</context>
      <utterance>That's right. Walk away. - There he is!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look what the cat dragged in!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish it was under better circumstances. Stu Riley's car was vandalized last night. Right in his driveway.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gang members, probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>QUIET RESIGNATION</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth and Amy nod vigorously.</context>
      <utterance>The public school system failed them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE CLARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So forget about the way it used to be. This is not a damn democracy! We are in a state of emergency and my word is law! There's only one boss around here, and that's me. The HNIC.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MS. LEVIAS</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>The bell RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Head Nigger In Charge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The students shuffle out. Garrett hustles after Chase.</context>
      <utterance>We'll pick this up again tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chase gives him a weird look and then exits with her friends. Sasha lingers by Elizabeth's desk.</context>
      <utterance>Quite a film, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a student leader for the D.C. trip --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shocker.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we're having our car wash this weekend. If you're around, maybe we could wash your car.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got some Mexicans who already do it for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands Elizabeth a flyer. Elizabeth glances at it.</context>
      <utterance>It's for a good cause. This year, we're trying to get some extra money so that we can go on a Duck Tour!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arkady and Principal Snur both look up. He holds up his finger -- "one minute." Elizabeth notices his cheap dolphin watch.</context>
      <utterance>Blugh!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arkady nods and quickly exits.</context>
      <utterance>So why don't you think about that and I'll let your teachers know that you're working on it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I didn't realize you were in with anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were just finishing up. Elizabeth, I actually meant to talk to you. Did I hear that you were showing movies all last week?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... some clips, maybe. I think in a lot, of ways, movies are the new books.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth tries a different tact. She picks up a dolphin- shaped clock from the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this new? I love it! I think dolphins are smarter than humans.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too! And if you like that, you'll love this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT`D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He lives in the Cayman Islands.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Principal Snur visibly relaxes. He's sitting across from a kindred spirit.</context>
      <utterance>What a great story.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what else is new?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I was thinking that I want to get more involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a nice surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Specifically, I thought I could supervise the car wash.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amy's been running it the last two years...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She just does so much. It might be nice to give her a little rest. Especially that early on a Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so happy that you're dedicating yourself and becoming a real member of the JAMS family.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just feels so good to help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth?! For the seventh grade carwash? That's bonkers!</utterance>
   <speaker>32.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amy immediately regrets saying "bonkers."</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I didn't mean to blow my stack.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just thought it was nice to see some other teachers step up.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We raised over $6000 last year. That's a record. Is this really the best time to start experimenting?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him -- clearly, this is a touchy subject.</context>
      <utterance>Amy, I see you taking on a.lot of responsibility, what with directing "Annie" and all your work with D.A.R.E. I'd just hate to see you get overwhelmed like you did in 2004.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns on her heels and walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. Well, I should skedaddle. Looks like someone needs to plan a Saturday morning bike ride.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A couple of PARENT CHAPERONES stand in small clusters. Tristan, the bully, cocks his arm and aims a soapy sponge at Garrett.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm gonna get you guys!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRISTAN</speaker>
      <mode>NOTICING SOMETHING</mode>
      <context>The CAMERA FOLLOWS Tristan's gaze. ELIZABETH steps out of her car. She's wearing HIGH HEELS, DAISY DUKES and a BIKINI TOP. She looks both spectacular and ridiculous. A couple of PARENTS look over at Elizabeth, in shock.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MOTHERS vigorously nod in agreement. A DAD pipes in.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to say something about her outfit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other DADS vigorously nod in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if it helps raise money...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth looks up and sees Sasha hiding behind a TRUCK, clearly spying.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Get out of here, Dummy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you stealing our money?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How dare you?! I'm here early on a Saturday for you guys. And for the record, nobody likes a tattle tale.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't tattled. Yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Cause if you do, I'll deny it and flunk your ass. How will that look on your resume?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode>TEARS UP</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say I would say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sasha walks off. Elizabeth picks up a hose and sprays her.</context>
      <utterance>Alright then. Now beat it. I've gotta finish counting this money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth waves to SASHA'S MOTHER, who eagerly waves back.</context>
      <utterance>See you Monday!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He instinctively covers himself with the brochure.</context>
      <utterance>Wally? Are you in here? It's Amy Squirrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amy? What are you doing? Get out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This'll just take a sec. I thought you might want to know that Elizabeth Halsey showed up at the carwash in a bikini top and short-shorts. It was pretty racy stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode>THRU STALL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we talk about this later?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Later we'll all die, said the gator to the fly."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Josh Gershman's dad called and said that the carwash was a huge success. And Lauren Rissman's dad called and said the kids had a great time.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to speak out of school, but I happened to be pedalling by and saw her get.pretty chummy with the money. ,And remember, we barely know anything about her. She was a real lone wolf last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you accusing Elizabeth of embezzling from the seventh grade car wash?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something about this doesn't pass the smell test, Wally.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy takes a deep breath. Her face is BEET RED.</context>
      <utterance>Well, they raised over $7000, so whatever she did worked. And next time you accuse a fellow teacher of stealing, you better be damn sure. We're done here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy exits. Immediately, there is an IMMENSE ERUPTION from the other stall, followed by a sigh.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the pep talk. Have a super day, you two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy looks behind him at the dozing teacher. "Is she talking to me?" Guilty.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Are those new Doc Marten's?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's Period 5?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, thanks for asking. We got a new bassist and we finally got a regular gig, which is nice because it's earned. It's time to show the world that a bunch of teachers can really rock out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awesome!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>Sandy goes to the fridge. Elizabeth pulls visine from her bag, and as his head goes into the fridge, she squirts the entire container into his coffee mug.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, would you mind grabbing me my yogurt from the fridge? Sure thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He hands her the yogurt.</context>
      <utterance>You should come to one of our shows.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth exits. Sandy sadly takes a sip of his coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't even tell you the dates.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth goes to the DVD player. There's a knock at the door and the SCHOOL SECRETARY walks in holding a box. She hands it to a confused Elizabeth.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, today, we're starting "School Ties." Classic.  You, shut off the lights.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHOOL SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here it is. Good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here what is?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHOOL SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the pre-test for the state standardized test. It was in the memo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Secretary leaves. Elizabeth stares at the box. Tristan and.a couple kids start making farting noises with their hands.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. In the memo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Zip it. Zip your shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth turns to a student who COULD BE GAY.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, look, we all know these tests are gay --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth passes the box to the front of the class, where the kids dutifully take Scan-trons and test booklets.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH.</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Twenty-five pencils hit paper in unison.</context>
      <utterance>According to this memo, I'm supposed to give you forty-five minutes per section. Blah blah blah. Clear your desks, pencils out and -- begin!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - MARVELLING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little bitches.</utterance>
   <speaker>TURN TO REVEAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl at the table starts BAWLING. Amy, also on duty, races over to console her.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth and Lynn on lunch duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a phony.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major phony. But she also cares a lot, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's going on with your boobs?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott walks down the ramp and HIGH-FIVES a bunch of kids. He gives them a big wave.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. Shit is going on with my boobs. I'm never gonna get married. I'm gonna die broke. I should just blow my brains out.  There he is!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love how his eyes sparkle when he smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to sit on his face.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really making a habit out of this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha, yeah. Actually, Sandy Pinkus in the Math department, I guess he got that stomach bug that's been going around and I got the call.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard he pooped himself in first period. A kid had to walk him to the nurse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth gives her a "can you get out of here?" look.</context>
      <utterance>Lynn, would you mind grabbing me a milk?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scott, do you want anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn walks off.</context>
      <utterance>I'm good, thanks for asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Scott -- Lynn comes back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skim? Whole? 2%? Chocolate?</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, what kind of milk do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Surprise me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn walks off again.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'll get you skim. No, no, 2%.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth notices Amy looking at her as she continues to console the girl. Elizabeth turns back to Scott.</context>
      <utterance>She's funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Scott, I was thinking, I would love to hear about your experiences in the Peace Corps. I love Haiti. Maybe we could go grab a drink some night. Maybe tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it Back-to-School Night?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Silly, I meant after.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool! Let's get a group together.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, definitely! Or just the two of us. Scott looks around, then lowers his voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Um, listen, I'm really flattered. You're one of the nicest people I've met here. But... I'm actually seeing someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we've been keeping it quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because she's ugly?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. She's beautiful. She's great. She really cares about the kids. It's just... when you're dating a co-worker...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>REALIZING</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth whips around to see Amy, who's now sharing a frozen yogurt with the formerly bawling girl. Amy looks up, smiles and gives a thumbs up to Elizabeth and Scott, signalling that everything's okay with the girl. Elizabeth NOTICES Amy's LARGE BREASTS straining against her blouse. She quietly seethes.</context>
      <utterance>Squirrel?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott crosses through the cafeteria. Lynn returns with a four cartons of milk.</context>
      <utterance>Anyways, thanks again for asking me out. I'm honored. And I'll take a raincheck on that group date. See ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you go. I got you one of each.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sasha's Mother eagerly raises her hand. Elizabeth points to her.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, my name's Elizabeth Halsey. Soooooo... Any questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth points to her sign on the wall -- "Don't Question My Authority."</context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Sasha's mother. We waved to each other at the carwash. I'm a little concerned with the importance you're placing on movies. What about the state test?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's exactly what I say to my students. Listen, I'm a good teacher. And the school hired me because I'm good at what I do.  And the reason your son loves my class is because I inspire him. Movies are one tool that I use. I also use other multimedia techniques, which I'm not going to get into right now. Look, I could take you day by day through my entire syllabus, but that's not how I do things. I'm not one of these stuffy teachers who's totally by the book. I talk to the kids like they're little adults. It's about mutual respect. So that's my spiel, as the Jews say.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>A "refreshments" table. A lonely package of OREOS rests against a PITCHER OF TAP WATER. Elizabeth tries to sneak out the door, but is stopped by a sharply dressed PARENT.</context>
      <utterance>Help yourselves to some delicious snacks and drinks in the back. Class dismissed. They head to the back of the class. ANGLE ON</utterance>
   <speaker>PARENT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Ms. Halsey.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARENT #1</speaker>
      <mode>EXTENDING HAND</mode>
      <context>From Elizabeth's reaction, she clearly has no idea who Chris is.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Chris' dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You must be so proud.</context>
      <utterance>Chris... Great kid -- and precocious.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS' DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, what a relief. I just wish his grades would reflect it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I know Chris, he'll get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS' DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris' dad shakes her hand. Elizabeth opens her hand, sees a tightly folded HUNDRED DOLLAR bill. She looks back up at Chris' dad.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I know you have a full plate, but if you could keep an eye on Chris, my wife and I would really appreciate it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Chase's parents? Great kid -- and precocious. You must be so proud. The parents beam.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A student like that would benefit so much from some extra attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHASE'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think we should hire a tutor?  I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONSPIRATORIAL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be happy to do it myself. It's just hard in a class of twenty-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHASE'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, to be a teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just so hard, on my salary, having to pay for my supplies, my fiance cheated on me with his twin sister... and, unlike a lot of these other teachers, all I truly care about is helping your child learn. And as their personal tutor, I guarantee a full grade higher -- or your money back. Chase's mom takes out her check book.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it out to "cash."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thank you.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're referring to his poetry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be so proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am. So so so so so proud. So proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A kid like that, if I could just give some more one on one time, he would just blossom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>would really benefit from that.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so happy to hear you say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately, in a class of twenty- five...</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ugh. Class sizes are ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And with the amount they pay teachers...</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank god you love what you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth offers her hand, palm up. Melody stares back at her blankly.</context>
      <utterance>I guess what I'm getting at is, maybe you could help out by giving me a little -- you know -- somethin somethin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just, it's really tough to teach the way that I want to teach when there's so little money. I mean, look at this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melody opens her pocketbook. Elizabeth smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You know what I'm going to do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She opens her date book and writes herself a note.</context>
      <utterance>I am going to start a letter-writing campaign to the school board, to my congressman, to the mayor -- and keep writing until you get what you deserve.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Melody pulls Elizabeth into a warm hug.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm writing myself a reminder!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Melody exits. Elizabeth is left in the classroom by herself.</context>
      <utterance>You are a saint.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Elizabeth pulls out the CASH she just made, we hear the opening beats of COOLIO'S "GANGSTER'S PARADISE."</context>
      <utterance>So long, Crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sasha motions for her to roll down the window. Elizabeth doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that marijuana?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is. But it's medicinal. Doctor gave it to me. Not that it's any of your business.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay. Feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mom and I made you holiday cookies. Here. Sasha pulls out a tupperware container.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are those oatmeal raisin?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth considers, then manually rolls down the window a crack. She grabs the container and quickly closes her window. Elizabeth starts eating a cookie.</context>
      <utterance>Sugar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sasha shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>You have anything to drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Word to the wise: stop dressing like you're running for congress.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to run for congress. I want to be president.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sasha shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>See? That's what I'm talking about. Keep saying stuff like that, you're gonna get punched. You really want to be President or is that what your parents tell to be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to decide right now. Who knows? Maybe you wake up one day and decide that you love giving massages and you want to be a masseuse. Salary plus tips. Think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I think about it, will I get extra credit?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hopeless. Watch your feet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees a HOMELESS GUY leaning against the storefront.</context>
      <utterance>Seriously?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Homeless Guy looks at her strangely.</context>
      <utterance>Why's the store closed?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth looks around. The streets are empty. Not a person in sight.</context>
      <utterance>Seriously?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever.  Hey, you got a lighter?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth walks back to her car, empty-handed. A MINI- VAN passes. Stops. Reverses.. The window rolls down. It's Garrett and his Mom.</context>
      <utterance>I don't smoke. It's bad for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ms. Halsey! Hey, it's me, Garrett!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas, Ms. Halsey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Going to see your family?</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing the rest of the day?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>UNCONVINCING</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth-shuffles her feet.</context>
      <utterance>I'm probably going to meet up with some people. We're having a big potluck, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ms. Halsey.  Elizabeth. Would you like to have Christmas with us?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a real treat for Garrett. He doesn't have a lot of friends come by the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I find that hard to believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CHECKS WATCH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I hate to eat and run, but I've gotta head over to the shelter.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we could play board games!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A shelter. That is so inspiring.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I love helping bums.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, but you have to wait for dessert. We have a real treat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's cheesecake, I'll stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's even better than cheesecake!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Garrett, why don't you run and get some of your new poetry?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god, no one wants to hear it. Oh god, I'm so embarrassed!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Garrett runs out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be shy, Marbles.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're not really serving dessert, I'm gonna have to get going.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One poem? If you like it, maybe you can read it to your homeless friends.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is called "The Chase," by Garrett Tiara.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode>READING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>XOXO /My love for you is XOXO/ Her hair is long and straight / Isn't it great? / About her smile / That I would walk a mile for / About her personality / That makes me see the best in me / And at night when we sleep / Our souls locked in deep / So that when we sleep / We can stop pretending / And embrace our beautiful ending. Melody applauds. The Aunts join in. Elizabeth claps, then gets up to go. Garrett shakes them all off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She sits back down.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes his journal. Everyone applauds. Melody looks to Elizabeth for a reaction.</context>
      <utterance>We'll dance our dance / We'll revel in romance perchance / One glance / One dance / Because together we can achieve...  Ba-lance... Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior likes to rhyme.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women exit, leaving Garrett and Elizabeth.</context>
      <utterance>Patty, Nancy, why don't you give me a hand with dessert -- give them a chance to talk about the poem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So your poem's about that girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chase, yeah. You got the subtext.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I give you some advice?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth puts her hands to show teeth going off in different directions.</context>
      <utterance>Number one, stop writing poetry. Two: stop reading it. And three: don't set your sights so high. I mean, she's really hot. If I were you, I'd try for that chubby girl that sits up front -- the one with the teeth?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I like Chase.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not gonna happen. Look, I was that hot girl. Hotter, even. And I never would have gone out with a kid like you. And I'm not saying that to be mean. I'm saying it to be helpful.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know? You don't-even know our names.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you what I know: a kid who wears the same "Gymnastics" sweatshirt three days a week isn't getting laid until he's 26. That's what I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode>EMOTIONAL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This sweatshirt was my dad's. It's all he left when he left.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's a reason he didn't pack it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth pats Garrett on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck being a loser. Thank your mom for dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him the finger over her shoulder and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Happy New Year. Are you spending that alone, too, or do you want my mom to invite you over?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, welcome back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn grabs some towels and blots at the stain..</context>
      <utterance>What is that, vomit?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and a little blood. The kids had too much sugar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyways, a bunch of us are going out tonight to see Period 5 play. Do you want to come?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth heads out. Lynn, still blotting, follows her.</context>
      <utterance>Ugh. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, guys. Are you coming to 'In Cahoots' tonight? My band's doing a few songs. Could be fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, yes! That sounds like a party.  Lynn, do you want to come?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll all grab a drink!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. I need to get drunk. I mean, not drunk drunk. But a strong buzz. Still be able to drive home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we're cooking with grease!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode>SINGING</mode>
      <context>Scott joins in, harmonizing.</context>
      <utterance>Everything's gonna be alright / rockabye...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rockabye, rockabye...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye, bye... Bye, bye...</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth eye-fucks Scott. She catches his eye and he quickly smiles before nervously turning his attention to Amy. Elizabeth watches Amy dance in SLO M0, her BREASTS bouncing up and down.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't they terrific?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should hear some of their originals. She turns to the bartender.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two more.  You want anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks... You know, I was thinking that if you still need that money, you should.try and go for the bonus. Can't hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What bonus?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(off Elizabeth's look)</context>
      <utterance>For the state test.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whichever teacher has the highest scoring class gets a bonus. We talk about it all the time in the faculty meetings.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>$5700. Could be good, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>Lynn runs out onto the dance floor and joins Amy.</context>
      <utterance>Let's dance!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>TO GARRETT</mode>
      <context>Garrett rolls his backpack over Elizabeth's shoe.. Elizabeth winces and glares at Garrett. The rest of the class enters, stops, noticing WORK PACKETS on each of their desks.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, Sylvia Plath.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHASE</speaker>
      <mode>LOOKING AROUND</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the TV?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>ALL BUSINESS</mode>
      <context>Shawn turns to Spencer.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone, take your seats.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spencer shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class, still confused, quickly take their seats.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, come on. We have a lot to cover so sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The kids slowly take out their books. We HEAR the distinct sound of twenty-five book spines cracking as they're opened for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Alright then. Now. Open your To'Kill A Mockingbird to page one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Now, who can tell me why Jem cries when the hole in the tree is filled with cement? Anyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids chuckle. Chase looks back at Garrett.</context>
      <utterance>Because she's a cry baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>TO GARRETT</mode>
      <context>Garrett clicks up the handle on his bag and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Everyone looks down.</context>
      <utterance>We're here to learn. Anyone else have a problem with that? Good. So who has the answer to my question?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's read this book? It's on the syllabus.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never assigned it to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Panic.</context>
      <utterance>Well, now I am. And we're having a quiz tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the first hundred pages.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do that! I have band and jazz band tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We haven't had homework all year!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Zip your shit! We've fallen behind, and honestly, your practice tests scores sucked balls -- which was embarrassing to me both on a personal level and as an educator.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things are about to change. Recess is over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses her a bag of chips.</context>
      <utterance>Did you get my Cool Ranch?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirk walks into his room and closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>You owe me two bucks..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one raises their hand.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, now, what is the significance of the Mockingbird in the novel? What was Harper Lee trying to tell us?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - SURPRISINGLY SUPPORTIVE</mode>
      <context>This is as close to real teaching as we've seen from Elizabeth. Sasha raises her hand. We see that she already has two gold star stickers on her forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, you guys know this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chase raises her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone else?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth puts a sticker on Chase's forehead.</context>
      <utterance>It's a symbol for, um, equality?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, good. Can anyone add to what that girl said?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRISTAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, seriously. You're gonna side with Chase and Shawn over me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Use examples from the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter what race the defendant is. You've just gotta look at the facts-. Elizabeth nods in agreement. The bell RINGS.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The students all dutifully drop off their papers, placing them in a neat stack next to other ungraded PAPERS. Principal Snur exits, giving Elizabeth a thumbs up.</context>
      <utterance>Good work today. And don't forget to leave your closing statements on my desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - CALLING AFTER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love the tie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you know how I hate to gossip, but I heard that one of the custodians walked in on Omar -- you know, that Arabic boy -- giving...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oral sex to Matty Feldstein after swim practice in the boy's locker room.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just starts younger and younger.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode>EARNEST</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nice to finally see the Jews and the Arabs getting along. Elizabeth enters. Scott looks up and smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ms. Halsey.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your shirt's mis-buttoned. Her shirt's mis-buttoned.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>LOOKING DOWN</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth turns away from them and starts rebuttoning. Sandy tries to sneak a peek. Scott shoots him a dirty look. Sandy gives an innocent shrug.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit. Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've just been such a mess the last few days. Working myself to the bone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's been quite a change.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth smiles for Scott, like, "You get me."</context>
      <utterance>Well, I think it's great. Some teachers just sail by, doing the bare minimum. It's good to know there are still some actual educators out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy and Elizabeth smile thinly at one another. Elizabeth squeezes Scott's shoulder as she exits. Amy notices.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I should get going. Nice seeing all of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>RE ELIZABETH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a good egg.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else, Sasha?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I told you about the car wash money.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't prove that. What else?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I've told you everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And no more movies in class?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we're actually learning. Did you know that Animal Farm isn't even really about animals --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>SNAPPING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Animal Farm?! That's not even on the syllabus!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're forgetting something. Do you want extra credit on your diorama or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want it! Let me think... Oh there was... never mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was okay. It was medicinal.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. Hold your horses. What was medicinal?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ms. Halsey was smoking in her car, but she told me her doctor prescribed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>TO HERSELF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy guacamole.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRISTAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth looks at Tristan. As she writes, we HEAR --</context>
      <utterance>Atticus Finch is a good lawer because he's a good person whose a layer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Proofread.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this English?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth crosses out with one line, so it's clearly visible beneath. From out in the hallway, we HEAR the loud, aggressive BARKING of the DOGS. Tristan runs to the door and peeks out.</context>
      <utterance>Are you fucking kidding me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. Drug dogs. Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth races to the window.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH (CONT'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth takes her seat and leans under her desk, obscuring her from her class. She opens her pocketbook and pulls out a CIGARETTE CASE. She pops it open and we SEE three neatly rolled JOINTS. Without hesitation, Elizabeth POPS the first one into her mouth and starts chewing vigorously. As she. makes her way through the second and then the third, the chewing becomes slower and the BARKING becomes louder and louder. Elizabeth starts CHOKING as the door opens and the Police Officer and the German Shepherd enter, followed by Principal Snur and Amy.</context>
      <utterance>Keep reading.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth,. still choking, digs into her purse. She grabs her cough syrup and takes a huge swig. Elizabeth wipes her mouth, breathes normally.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, sorry to bother you. This will only take a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The German Shepherd continues barking.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I had something caught in my throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dog comes bounding at Elizabeth. Elizabeth's eyes go wide. Amy licks her lips. The Dog sideswipes Elizabeth, almost knocking her over, and jumps onto Garrett.</context>
      <utterance>What is it, Axel? Where is it, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The'Police Officer starts rummaging through Garrett's bag and pulls out an opened bag of CORN CHIPS.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth glares at Amy -- "I know you were behind this." Amy glares back. Principal Snur looks at Amy and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>All clear. Dog must've responded to these. Happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even though that wasn't drugs, junk food is still contraband. That's detention, Buster.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough, Amy. I think it's time we call off this witch-hunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth takes a long beat before answering.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay, Ms. Halsey?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Class dismissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the bell didn't ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class uncertainly gathers their things and heads out. From outside Elizabeth's window, we SEE the SCHOOL BUSSES idling curbside. Elizabeth stares at the papers she still needs to grade. The papers stare back at her.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of my face.  And leave the corn chips.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But first, a nap.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She knocks the stack of ungraded papers to the ground. After a beat, she collects herself, goes to pick the, papers off the floor. As she starts tossing them into the trash, something catches her eye: a PRACTICE TEST MANUAL. And in the corner, an address:</context>
      <utterance>Balls!</utterance>
   <speaker>54 LAKEVIEW STREET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peoria Il, 61602</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth tears off the corner and pockets it.</context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>PRE-LAP - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's Elizabeth Halsey...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRAT GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Tucker here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAT GUY</speaker>
      <mode>DISAPPOINTED</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth just stares at the Frat Guy. He turns away. Tucker, dressed identically to the Frat Guy but twenty pounds overweight, hustles down the stairs. He has a tattoo of intertwined teabags around his bicep.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, hold on. T-baaaaag! Someone's here.  So you coming to our "CEOs and Corporate Ho's" party tonight?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you ever talk to my brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He dumped me, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and my brother always had the histrionics.</utterance>
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, do you want to come to our party tonight? "CEOs and Corporate Ho's?" We're kinda light on Ho's.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I told "Frat Guy 1," I'm not interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need some date rape drugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two things. Number one: who do you think I am? Yeah, I like to party and yeah, I'm in an awesome frat, but that really hurts. And two: they're not "date rape" drugs. It's called GHB -- and it's for weightlifting. It helps build mass, okay? Why do you even want it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>DEADPAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For lifting.</utterance>
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tucker walks over to a chest, opens it, and takes out a small lockbox. He unlocks it and takes out a small bottle containing a clear liquid.</context>
      <utterance>That's all you needed to say. No need to get all histrionic on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth hands him some cash. He hands her the jar and then gives her a big, warm hug.</context>
      <utterance>One capful makes you feel really good. Two capfuls will knock her out for a couple hours. You don't want to take any more than two.</utterance>
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I know you and my brother aren't together anymore, but I still think of you as a sister, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your hand off my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, didn't even know I put it down there. Good luck with your lifting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I.S.A.T. How can I direct your call?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, my name is Marjorie Goodman and I'm calling from the Chicago Tribune. Who could I speak to regarding allegations of racial bias on your standardized tests?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please hold.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Marjorie" turns and we SEE that it's actually ELIZABETH, wearing the "Little Orphan Annie" wig. She's sipping a cocktail.</context>
      <utterance>Marjorie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face lights up, excited to be in the company of such an attractive woman. Elizabeth stands and extends her hand. Carl notices Elizabeth's very short skirt.</context>
      <utterance>You must be Carl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth motions for him to sit down.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for meeting me on such short notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode>NERVOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You find the place alright? Good drive?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great drive. I love downstate Illinois.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First time to Peoria?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm mmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of people don't know this, but it's the largest city on the Illinois River.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. I did not know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup yup. And it was actually founded before Chicago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Jeopardy! Have you ever auditioned?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I should, I should. Definitely thought about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I'd love to sit here and chat with you all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm sure you're a very busy man, so I'll get right down to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've spoken to various, um, black citizens who are alleging that your tests are biased towards white people and Orientals.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't use my name, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I told you on the phone, every couple of years, we get calls from all over the state with these cockamamie charges. You should hear what they call me. And I'm not a racist. I voted for Obama.  That, you can quote me on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth takes out a notebook and pen and starts jotting down notes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Marjorie, I know my tests aren't perfect. But what's the alternative? I'm all for free thinking and creativity, but how do you formulate an education budget without hard numbers from one of my tests?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't need to convince me. But you know what would help, Carl? For me to see one of this year's tests.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth lights up.</context>
      <utterance>No problem at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll send you one the day after the schools administer them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd really love to see it sooner. I'm on a bit of a deadline.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl holds up a lanyard with a STATE ID CARD and some keys attached.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I could, but unfortunately, you need one of these bad boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>totally get it. Enough business for one night.</context>
      <utterance>Ooh, you look like you're CIA. Listen, I</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna have another drink before I hit the road. What's your poison?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White wine.</context>
      <utterance>My poison is the white devil. Wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fantastic.  One white wine, one tequila sunrise, and two shots of tequila.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Marjorie, this is the best night I've had in a longtime.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth gives Carl "fuck me" eyes. He nervously sips his drink.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that makes two of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What turns you on, Carl?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He giggles nervously.</context>
      <utterance>You know what turns me on, Carl?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - WHISPERS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sex in an office. Getting fucked really, really hard against a wooden desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode>SWALLOWS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine's metal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this is the desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl goes to a mini-fridge and pulls out an already opened bottle of white wine.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have anything to drink?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Carl pours a glass. Elizabeth swigs from the bottle.</context>
      <utterance>White wine in the office. You're a bad boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any music?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl goes to fiddle with his computer. Elizabeth quickly reaches into her purse and pulls out the bottle of GHB. She pours a little into Carl's wine. And then a little bit more. As he turns around, she hands him the glass.</context>
      <utterance>Um... I could put on some internet radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A toast. To new friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLINK. Carl downs his glass.</context>
      <utterance>To new lovers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - NERVOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna take off my shoes. Is that okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever, man. I'm gonna hit the lady's room.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl starts carefully clearing everything off of his desk.</context>
      <utterance>K, first door on your right. Don't be long.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl stumbles towards her. Elizabeth deftly moves around the desk and exits into the bullpen.</context>
      <utterance>Easy, Cowboy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marblorie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A couple of groans. A couple of frantic moves to fill in more scantron bubbles.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, pencils down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The students dutifully place their tests into a neat stack on the corner of Elizabeth's desk and exit. Elizabeth waits for all the kids to leave and then slides all of the exams into the trash. She pulls out a match and lights the exams on fire. She then reaches into her bag and pulls out a new stack of completed exams. She places the new exams into an official-looking folder and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, come on. It doesn't even matter. Bring your tests up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy sits. Principal Snur addresses the teachers.</context>
      <utterance>If anyone has any information regarding the whereabouts of the missing "Annie" wig, please let me know ASAP. Because if that wig isn't found, you can bet your bottom dollar the "sun will not come out tomorrow." Back to you, Wally.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Amy. Um, okay, I'm sure everyone wants to go home, so I'll be quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode>PIPING UP</mode>
      <context>Scattered laughter. Elizabeth rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Fourscore and seven years ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Teachers applaud.</context>
      <utterance>So I have here the results of the state exam -- and I'm happy to announce that John Adams Middle School had the fifth highest scores in the state.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I want to single out one of our own, who showed that with hard work and dedication, one person can make a difference. She makes me proud to be her boss and she's now $5700 richer. With the highest scores in the county -- yes, you heard me right, in the county ---I want everyone to please give a hand to --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh boy, third year in a row. This is starting to get embarrassing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth leans over to Amy, who's sitting beside her.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth Halsey!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All of the color drains from Amy's face as Elizabeth stands and waves at the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>This is unexpected.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott playfully punches her shoulder. Elizabeth playfully punches him back.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, if it isn't Professor Smartypants.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>FLIRTY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better not mess with me. I'm a lot stronger than I look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you gonna do with your new- found riches?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy walks up and gives Elizabeth a big, fake hug.</context>
      <utterance>Something big. Maybe two big things.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Ism so proud of you. If someone told me at the beginning of the year that you -- you! -- would get the bonus, I would've said to whomever it was, 'you must be joshing me.' And now, here we are. Here we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should go out and celebrate.  Your treat?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're not dating anyone now, right?</context>
      <utterance>What a good, fun idea. Unfortunately, Scott and I have to go over the itinerary for the D.C. trip. We're the chaperones. We're going together.  We're dating, so it'll also be romantic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got my eye on someone, but he's dating a major cunt.  Pardon my French.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, she sounds terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy and Scott head off. Scott turns around.</context>
      <utterance>Well then. Scott, we should skedaddle. Those itineraries won't schedule themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rain check on those drinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>TO HERSELF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can bet on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth slides the bonus check across the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Almost done. We don't normally deal with cash here. At the doctor's office.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth slides four credit cards across the desk. The MIDDLE-AGED DOCTOR from earlier walks by.</context>
      <utterance>And this is endorsed. And the rest you can put on these.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode>TO ELIZABETH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when would you like to come in?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MIDDLE-AGED DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes into his office. Elizabeth turns back to Danni.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when would you like to come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danni checks her calendar.</context>
      <utterance>Today. Tomorrow. As soon as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A week from tomorrow, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danni slides Elizabeth a packet of literature.</context>
      <utterance>Book it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a 48 hour cancellation policy. Anything after that, you'll be charged 50% the cost of the surgery -- unless there are extenuating circumstances.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth pulls her shirt away from her body and looks down at her breasts.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't miss it for the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So long, suckers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>No response from the class.</context>
      <utterance>Who did this?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Amy presses the apple to her ear.</context>
      <utterance>Oh come on. Nobody wants an extra sticker on their all-star board?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Amy places the apple up to her ear.</context>
      <utterance>Who brought you to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - MUPPET VOICE</mode>
      <context>Amy takes a bite of the apple and then addresses the class.</context>
      <utterance>What's that, Mr. Apple? You want me to take a bite? Alrighty-roo.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough horsin' around, let's get started.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All set?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we're good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, thanks again for hopping in last minute. You really saved us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Amy going to be okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be fine. But to be honest, I think she was scaring some of the kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet, I bet. Well, let her know she's in my thoughts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KIDS</speaker>
      <mode>SINGING</mode>
      <context>Hey, Sasha!</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Sasha!</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I hear it again!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wanted on the telephone!</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode>POINTING</mode>
      <context>Chase rolls her eyes. Up front, Scott and Elizabeth sit next to one another and share ipod buds.</context>
      <utterance>If it's not Chase, then I'm not home!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott smiles wide. Garrett walks up the aisle. He looks at Elizabeth, then turns to Scott.</context>
      <utterance>You guys are amazing. Period 5 is definitely going to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Delacourte, do you think we could go to the poetry museum?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott looks to Elizabeth, like "please help."</context>
      <utterance>Oh, um, I don't know, Champ, um --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, honey, I bet everyone would just love to walk around and look at all the poetry on the walls, but unfortunately, the itinerary's really tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you talking like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Garrett gives her an annoyed look and then heads back to his seat. Scott smiles at Elizabeth.</context>
      <utterance>Just go sit down, sweetie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, you are such a natural.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you love what you do, it comes easy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never lose my keys!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAINTENANCE GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with your face?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with your face?!?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAINTENANCE GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finds the right key and opens the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Just making conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAINTENANCE GUY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All set.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy immediately opens the desk and rummages through it. She pulls out the "Annie" wig.</context>
      <utterance>Super! Thanks a bunch, Amos! The Maintenance Man exits.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She pulls out a test booklet. There's a piece ripped out from the front page. Amy's eyes narrow. She runs to the floor, where she has neat stacks of what used to be in her desk. She finds her test booklet and compares the two, clocking the I.S.A.T. address.</context>
      <utterance>Busted.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like somebody's in big, big trouble.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're the one that might be in some kind of trouble! Did you or did you not give her a copy of the state test?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I did was give her a couple of quotes ,for her article and that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What article?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the Tribune. She's a reporter there. Right? Amy's eyes go wide.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you want me to take your picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns away.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, well let me know. I've got my camera and my battery's fully charged.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awesome.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>OFFERING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fruit roll-up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>RE JEFFERSON</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth tries to dislodge a piece of the fruit roll-up from the back of her mouth with her tongue.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so conflicted about this man. Did you know that he had slaves?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, everyone knows that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth continues struggling with the fruit.</context>
      <utterance>I just hate slavery so, so much. An unquestionable evil. I hate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slavery's the worst.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth gives him a sideways glance, like "no shit."</context>
      <utterance>If I could go back in time and undo slavery, I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really hate slavery, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth finally dislodges the chunk of fruit roll-up.</context>
      <utterance>I hate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott squeezes Elizabeth's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>You get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for listening.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Test-tampering. Here? At J.A.M.S.?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And like I said, she stole the wig. I think we're dealing with a criminal master-mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to be the bearer of bad news, Wally. You know how much we all like her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. It's a tragedy. But Amy, let's keep this between us. The last thing we need is a scandal on our hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You betcha.  You know what scares me the most? This is just what we know. This could be the tip of the iceberg. Who knows what else she's capable of?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth tries pulling off her shirt. Scott pulls it back down.</context>
      <utterance>Harder, harder.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my gosh, I'm dry-humping the shit out of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erg. Dry fuck the fuck out of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott rolls off of Elizabeth and exhales deeply. There's a wet spot on his jeans.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my gosh, I'm so close... I'm... pfft. Ugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I'm sorry. But this isn't me. And I. know this isn't you. I'm in love with Amy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we're so good together. We both hate slavery, we both love teaching. And call me crazy, but I always imagined us spending summers at your family's compound in Hyannisport.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. And you're awesome and you have a huge heart and I love your empathy. It's just, when I was dry-humping you, I couldn't stop thinking about dry-humping Any.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's because of my tits, isn't it? Well, I'm getting new ones in, like, two days. Don't make a decision until you see them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, I think you're beautiful just the way you are, even with your flat chest. And I think Amy's beautiful. But I just have to do what's right. I made Amy a promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth angrily gets up and pulls on her socks.</context>
      <utterance>What're you -- 13?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, Elizabeth. Don't go. Spend the night here with me. You can sleep on the other bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>FAKE EXCITEMENT</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth opens the room door and exits. She tries slamming the door, but it's on a spring so it closes very, very slowly.</context>
      <utterance>Ooh, like a slumber party? I'm leaving. And for the record, your band sucks, asstard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>ON PHONE</mode>
      <context>She ends the call.</context>
      <utterance>Wally. Why would I cheat? If I'm guilty of anything, it's teaching too hard. Great... I've got nothing to hide.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Scott, wearing a Thomas Jefferson souvenir T-shirt, and all of the students look over at Elizabeth.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH.</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Tour Guide looks around uncertainly before continuing.</context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUR GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sasha's hand shoots up.</context>
      <utterance>And does anyone know what Abraham Lincoln's nickname was?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honest Abe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TOUR GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Garrett takes this in. He looks over at Chase and then, after a beat, raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>"Honest Abe", that's right. Because Lincoln always said what was on his mind, even if that meant being unpopular. Abraham Lincoln always showed great courage.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUR GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes turn to Garrett. Chase looks mortified.</context>
      <utterance>I love Chase Streeter-Rossi.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUR GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay then. Any other questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Chase. I've always loved you. And even though you pretty much stopped talking to me in fifth grade, I don't care. I remember the Chase that wrote me a card when my dad was overweight and had to go to the hospital because of his heart --</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was from the whole class.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Sasha, I'm talking about a different card.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then, a year later, when he left my mom and moved in with his trainer, you wrote me another card. What happened to us? Remember when we had a sleepover in the second grade and you wet your bed and you were so embarrassed and you made me promise not to ever tell anyone. Well, I never did and I never will. I know we're really young, but remember Romeo and Juliet were only 13. A lot of people don't know that. So there it is. My heart on a sleeve.  Don't let me leave / Always believe / A beat. Chase stares at Garrett.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chase's friends all start laughing. The rest of the class joins in. Garrett runs down the steps, away from everyone.</context>
      <utterance>Gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Tour Guide looks around, uncertain.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, guys, let's settle down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUR GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode>POINTING</mode>
      <context>The Tour Guide leads the group inside. Elizabeth looks back and sees Garrett on the steps, his head in his hands. She rolls her eyes and walks down to him.</context>
      <utterance>And these columns here are Doric columns. Now let's move inside to see the interior murals painted by Jules Guerin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Abe Lincoln, get up. Tour's not over.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode>UPSET</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She just laughed at me. Called me gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll get over it. Get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going back. Leave me alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Garrett runs off.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth starts running after him in heels. She immediately breaks a heel.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, come back here you little --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>,SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Wait, wait. Where's 5? Who's 5?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's Garrett Tiara.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Garrett! Garrett! Nothing. Scott looks around, stricken. SCOTT   And where's Ms. Halsey? Nothing. SCOTT   Alright, everyone on the bus!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KIDS</speaker>
      <mode>CHANTING</mode>
      <context>Scott sits up front by the driver. He's on his cell.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go home! Let's go home!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>FRANTIC </mode>
      <context>The chanting immediately stops.</context>
      <utterance>I'm freaking out here. They've been missing over two hours. I'm just a substitute!  Shut up!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>WHEELS SPINNING</mode>
      <context>Amy scratches the turtle's neck as it continues across the table.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my gosh. We just might have a Mary Kay Letourneau situation on our hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. You think?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. The woman's a criminal mastermind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is such a mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I need from you is to focus and get our kids home safe. I'll take care of everything here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Amy. You're a lifesaver.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up the phone and cockily kicks her feet onto the table, accidentally knocking the turtle to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>It's what I do. Love you, Scooter.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CALLING</mode>
      <context>Her phone RINGS. She checks the CALLER ID -- "HOT SCOTT."</context>
      <utterance>Garrett! Garrett!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - ANSWERING PHONE</mode>
      <context>She powers her phone off and continues down the street. She passes two PROSTITUTES.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for him! Stop fucking calling me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, guys. Hi. I'm looking for a young kid, about 13. Really annoying, kind of a cry baby. Have you seen him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSTITUTE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSTITUTE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You best step off, bitch, because this is my block. This here's Poetry's block.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poetry?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSTITUTE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause that's how she fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSTITUTE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something occurs to Elizabeth. She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I fuck like that. Lyrical.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth walks off and sticks out her hand, trying to hail a cab. She passes a bunch of HOMELESS MEN warming up by a trash can fire.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Poetry. And Poetry's friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CAR slows next to Elizabeth. A JOHN rolls down the passenger window and leans out.</context>
      <utterance>Won't get a cab in this neighborhood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, sweetheart. How much for a titty fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, I need a ride, too. Right through those titties.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I need a ride. Like you driving, and me pointing mace at your face. I'll give you ten bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>A BEAT</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth hops in.</context>
      <utterance>This is weird. Twenty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can you. tell us about the alleged romance between Elizabeth Halsey and a 13 year old student?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONFUSED</mode>
      <context>The students step off and the Parents swarm them.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARENT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sasha's parents engulf her in a hug.</context>
      <utterance>Oh baby, are you okay? Did she touch you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SASHA'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Sasha!  You expect this stuff to happen in Florida, not here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's closed. Won't be open till morning. Come on. Let's get back to the hotel. I'm sure everyone's mad at you. Garrett stands his ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not leaving without talking to the poet laureate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think that some Shel Silverstein wannabe is going to tell you the meaning of life?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you care?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to be here. You're a teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Garrett takes a seat next to Elizabeth.</context>
      <utterance>Not for long. I'm getting fired for cheating as soon as we get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. you came looking for me on your own?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.  And you owe me a new pair of Nanette Lepores.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to know what to say to Chase to get her to like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What?</context>
      <utterance>You know what you should do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just go out and sleep with as many girls, as you possibly can. Get her out of your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll probably reject me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, probably. But life's about how you deal with rejection. You can either hide in a corner and cry or you can get stronger every time. And I figure a kid like you with not much going for him -- if he were to choose the latter -- might end up becoming a pretty strong man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode>TOUCHED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now come on, let's get out of here. I'm freezing and Mr. Delacourte's probably shitting a brick.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't go back there. All the kids will laugh at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seriously think they haven't been laughing already?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Chase is wondering where I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hate to break it to you, kid, but I don't think anyone gives two shits where we are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else can you tell us about Garrett and Ms. Halsey's relationship?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy snorts.</context>
      <utterance>It was strictly student/teacher. Garrett's a gifted poet and Ms. Halsey was trying to bring that out of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they ever spend time outside of the classroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Detective glances at the Principal, like "Oh boy."</context>
      <utterance>Aside from Christmas at our house? Absolutely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy gives her version of a sexy look to the Detective.</context>
      <utterance>She used to give all the guys that look. That sex look. You know --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Tiara, I think we might need to consider the possibility that Elizabeth Halsey has abducted your son and that the two of them are involved in a sexual relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode>INCONSOLABLE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marbles doesn't even have armpit hair!</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should send out an Amber Alert. We need to catch this Sicko.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In front of the school, the Reporter turns to Principal Snur.</context>
      <utterance>A school official close to the scandal confirms that in addition to her alleged sexual relationship with the unnamed seventh grader, Elizabeth Halsey has been investigated for possible drug use, standardized testing fraud, and the theft of an "Annie" wig from a school production. The TV Report flashes an unflattering photo of ELIZABETH with a BLURRED OUT GARRETT.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you comment on any of these allegations?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The superintendent will speak to the press shortly, but for now, I'd just like to say that I hope Ms. Halsey does the right thing and brings back our student.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark starts laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Am I shocked?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was always very cold to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRISTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been telling him to hit that all year. That's my boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"No child left behind." How ironic. That a child was left behind. In Washington, D.C. With a statutory rapist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The taxi pulls up to the curb and Elizabeth and Garrett .exit. CHAOS. They're immediately swarmed by everyone. The Cops struggle to push past.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck?  Did you steal something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELODY</speaker>
      <mode>BESIDE HERSELF</mode>
      <context>The reporters thrust mics in her face.</context>
      <utterance>Marbles!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH ,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cops get through and smother Garrett in a police blanket. A FEMALE COP roughly leads Elizabeth to one of the squad cars.</context>
      <utterance>Just the once on the train. What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is crazy! He's a kid. Elizabeth is put into the back of squad car.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth bangs on the window. Amy smiles and waves.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a good person! I don't fuck minors!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're quite the celebrity.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want an autograph?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth picks up the phone. The Sergeant gives her some space.</context>
      <utterance>You get one call.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you need medical attention, we're required to provide it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just take me back to my cell.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again, speaking on behalf of the whole administration, I just want to apologize for what happened. Clearly, there was a miscommunication.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirk puts his hand up to Elizabeth, like "I'll take care of this."</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than once!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth pulls Kirk into a lawyer/client huddle.</context>
      <utterance>And she has touched the lives of those around her -- until last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kind of sound like a pro.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRK</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think they're going to find out that I didn't pass the bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context>They break from their huddle.</context>
      <utterance>You're doing great.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your administration jumped to conclusions, set off a media fire-storm and has humiliated one of its own. As Ms. .Halsey's chief counsel, I've advised her that we have an extremely strong case of libel and that it's certainly within her province to sue the district.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERINTENDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we make this go away?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirk slides a piece of paper across the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Ms. Halsey is not a litigious woman. She wants this whole matter to go away as quickly and painlessly as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Superintendent and Principal Snur scan the list.</context>
      <utterance>This is a list of our demands.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERINTENDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth starts crying. Everybody looks at her, aghast. And as quickly she started, she stops.</context>
      <utterance>Don't answer right now. Let it marinate. Oh, and I should mention that if this goes to trial, I can cry on cue.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, if you'll all excuse me, I should be heading to fifth period. I hate to be tardy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth doesn't acknowledge her and continues walking toward Amy, only feet away now.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth! I was so worried. You gave us quite a scare, you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>BAM! Elizabeth punches Amy square in the nose. Amy drops to her knees and grabs her nose, now squirting blood.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody's being a grumple--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Polite laughter.</context>
      <utterance>I think that was a huge s-u-c-c-a-s-s.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth smiles.</context>
      <utterance>But seriously... With summer around the corner, it's time to not only say goodbye to another school year, but to also say goodbye to one of our own.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Amy, her face completely healed, steps forward, with a pursed smile.</context>
      <utterance>Amy Squirrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After six short years of outstanding, tireless work here, Amy is transferring out of the district.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SNUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know she'll bring her love for learning to her new students. Sandy, the ponytailed teacher, pipes up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speech! Speech!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy looks over to Elizabeth, who motions for her to continue.</context>
      <utterance>Although leaving was a difficult choice...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Teachers applaud, Scott the most enthusiastic. Elizabeth steps up to Amy, who flinches.</context>
      <utterance>When the superintendent personally asks you to work at one of the worst schools in the state, you say yes. I'm looking forward to bringing my brand of zany energy and lust -- not love, lust -- for learning to the underprivileged students at Malcolm X High. I welcome the challenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth hands Amy a poster tube. She.opens it and unravels the "Integrity" poster that Elizabeth stole.</context>
      <utterance>Here, I got you this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth heads for the door. Scott catches up to her.</context>
      <utterance>And good luck. Somebody's gonna need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Stranger.  Listen, now that Amy's transferring, maybe the two of us could go grab a drink.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>EIGHTH GRADE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sasha clearly enjoys the attention. Elizabeth smiles. Garrett walks by, hand in hand with Chase. Trailing both of them are identical rolling backpacks. He sees Elizabeth and runs over.</context>
      <utterance>Do me! Do me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and Chase, huh? She likes the poetry?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She likes that I'm kind of a celebrity. But I'm cool with it. I'm the man around here!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points at her breasts.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I should get going. See you around, Ms. Halsey. Oh, and nice...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>TOUCHED</mode>
      <context>Garrett smiles and walks off. Lynn walks by. She's cleaning another big stain from her shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks! You're the first student to notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, hey! How was your summer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was great. I met a doctor! Plastic surgeon, actually. He's amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The internet?</context>
      <utterance>He sounds amazing. How'd you meet him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, in recovery. And I looked like ass, so I know it's real.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like a fairy tale.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is. Storybook. Well, not total storybook. It's a little messy because his wife filed for divorce last week, but we're gonna get through that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you want to grab lunch later?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure! My treat.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
