<movie id="60" title="Bamboozled">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WHITE LETTERS ON BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WE HEAR the VOICE of PIERRE DELACROIX.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satire. 1a. A literary work in which human vice or folly is ridiculed or attacked scornfully. B. The branch of literature that composes such work. 2. Irony, derision or caustic wit used to attack or expose folly, vice or stupidity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We see a tall figure move in and around the space.</context>
      <utterance>Bonjour, my name is Pierre Delacroix. I'm a television writer, also a showrunner, a creative person.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm one of those people responsible for what you view on your idiot box.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monogrammed cuff sleeve - the initials P.D.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The problem is not enough of you have been watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monogrammed shirt pocket - the initials P.D.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the onslaught of the internet, video and interactive games, nine hundred channels to choose from and whatnot, our valued audience has dramatically eroded.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Delacroix YELLS.</context>
      <utterance>To put it in much more simple terms...</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like rats fleeing a sinking ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The handsome face of Pierre Delacroix.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Delacroix turns to the CAMERA and addresses US.</context>
      <utterance>People tuning out by the millions.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is not good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mass begins to move.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, let's get to it. You don't dance, we don't eat. Simple as that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We snooze. We lose.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. We slow. We blow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manray takes a small bow. A few, not many, people have stopped to look.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. I know everybody is in a hurry to work, ready to begin another day in this rat race. But don't sleep us. I'm Cheeba and I introduce to you the world renown MANRAY, the man with the educated feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As we continue our world wind tour, we would like to give you a little somethin', somethin' before you go off to make that money. I give you Manray.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>People are digging into their pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much but please don't go without giving us some cheddar, cheese, money. We prefer two's than fews.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A WOMAN is about to dump some change in the brown paper bag.</context>
      <utterance>I would like to add that both of us are homeless. Not that it means anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cheeba looks at her and she quickly pulls out a 5-spot from her purse and drops it into the bag.</context>
      <utterance>I said homeless. Ladies and gentlemen. Senorita, do you know what that means?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cheeba works his way over to Delacroix.</context>
      <utterance>Muchos gracias.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Cheeba.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning to you, Mr. Delapot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>De-la-croix.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know what I mean. Got a gig yet for Manray and I yet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix hands Cheeba a ten dollar bill.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix moves towards the revolving doors of CNS.</context>
      <utterance>Gracias.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manray, Sloan says you're too talented to be dancing on the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well do something about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Marie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not gonna be a good morning for you if you don't get into Dunwitty's staff meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What staff meeting?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The staff meeting that started 30 minutes ago.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunwitty looks at his Rolex Chronograph - Daytona Model.</context>
      <utterance>Monsieur Delacroix, this very important meeting commenced...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...exactly thirty-two minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I'm late.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know how much information can be dispensed in one minute alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix looks at his Jaeger-LeCoultre.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't find out about this very important staff meeting until...</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are you telling me everyone knew about this get-together except you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes are on Delacroix and he feels it.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't told about this until Marie informed me as soon as I got off the elevator.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunwitty via remote turns off the lights and turns on an overhead projector.</context>
      <utterance>People, you can attempt to pull a Rodman like our friend Delacroix, but I guarantee you'll be sent packing just like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are the standings. Read 'em and weep. As you can plainly see the Continental Network System is languishing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ratings charts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at 'em people. We are BOOTY, CA CA. We are DOO-DOO. Doo-doo on a stick, if you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunwitty.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dunwitty turns on the lights. JOAN, one of the writers, raises her hand.</context>
      <utterance>I do not like to be the laughing stock of the broadcast industry. I have pride and people, you better start getting some too. These numbers have to go up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Question?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do you want us to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It, it, it...</context>
      <utterance>What I want everyone to do is write some material that is FUNNY. The junk you've been writing is about as funny as a dead baby. It's not funny, it's not new. It's not sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People scurry out.</context>
      <utterance>SUCKS. Thank you, Fish. This meeting is over but I want everyone to seriously think about what I said and how you can deliver.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monsieur Delacroix, in my office now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me about this staff meeting?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody told me anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What good are you if you don't tell me stuff like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't my fault. If I would have known, I would have known.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what C.P. Time is?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both laugh.</context>
      <utterance>C.P. Time is Colored People's Time. The stereotypical belief that Negroes are always late. That Negroes have no sense of time - time except when it comes to music or dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's sit down over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>9.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunwitty and Delacroix sit on the sofa.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about my blowup but I have to have a whipping boy every meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. But again, in all honesty I was not informed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix doesn't join him in his laughter because he doesn't know how to take that comment or where Dunwitty is headed with it.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. I believe you're my most creative person I've got on staff. You're hip. You know what's happening. I got some corny white boys and girls writing for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand Black culture. I grew up around black people all my life. If the truth be told I probably know "niggers" better than you, Monsieur Delacroix. Please don't get offended by my use of the quote-unquote N word. I got a black wife and three bi-racial children, so I feel I have a right to use that word. I don't give a damn what Spike says, Tarantino is right. Nigger is just a word. If Dirty Ole Bastard can use it every other word so can I.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would prefer you not use that word in my presence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it again. C'mon, say it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunwitty. He's a bloody pulp.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He straightens his tie.</context>
      <utterance>Delacroix.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>POW. This is a fantasy in Delacroix's mind. We go BACK TO REALITY. Everything's how we left it.</context>
      <utterance>Who's a nigger now?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The material you've been creating is too white bread. White people with black faces. The Huxtable's, Cosby, revolutionary. But that's dead. We can't go down that road again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't agree. The Negro middle class does exist, and it's rich material for a dramatic series or sitcom.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to his desk, picks up Delacroix's scripts and starts throwing them one by one against the window.</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you it's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The middle class black family moves into a white suburban enclave. The middle class black family moves into a small Southern town that is run by the KKK. The middle class single black father raises his teenage daughter. The middle class single black father raises his teenage daughter. The middle class single black mother raises her teenage son. And so on and so forth. It's too clean, too antiseptic...</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...to white? I still feel all of my scripts would make good shows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix, wake up, brother man. The reason why they didn't get picked up was because nobody - and I mean NOBODY - niggers and crackers alike wants to see that junk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never been given a fair shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got your head stuck up your ass with your Harvard education and your pretentious ways. Brother man, I'm blacker than you. I'm keepin' it real and you're frontin', trying to be white.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm an oreo, a sell out? Because I don't aspire to do HOMEBOYS FROM</utterance>
   <speaker>OUT OF SPACE, SECRET DIARY OF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is that what you think?</context>
      <utterance>DESMOND PFEIFFER, A PJ's or some as you might put it, some "nigger" show? I'm a Tom? I'm whiter than white and you're blacker than black?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's exactly what I think. I want you to create something that people want to see. Let's be honest, the majority of the people in the country are deaf, dumb and blind and I'm including 35 million African-Americans. You know and I know "niggers" set the trend, set the styles. This is a golden opportunity now. These idiots have to be led to the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure if I can deliver what you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will or you'll be back at BET so quick you'll never know what hit you. I need a mid-season replacement and pronto. It will be on the fast track.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it you want from me? Some plantation follies? Some sitcom that takes place on a watermelon patch? Some show that follows four nigger generations of junkies and crackheads? You want me to go back to the ante bellum days?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Yes! Yes! I want a show that will make headlines, that will have millions and millions of households tuned in, glued to their televisions every week. I want advertisers dying to buy on this show. I'm gonna squeeze this show out of you if it kills you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm starvin' like Marvin.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My world famous, famous world Arroz con pollo will be ready very soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up, I wanna watch HBO.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Did we get our bill yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess that will come with the rent, gas, and Con Ed bills, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh, the luxuries of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You hear me.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, check it. This is good and all that but one day soon I want to have much Benjamins so I can have a nice crib and pay all my bills.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chill, I'm the brains behind this outfit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm the feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, you gotta show some patience. You want me to snap my fingers and presto chango - you're an overnight sensation. Son, there is no such thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm tired of waiting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheeba, he has a sheet pulled over his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manray, who's sawing logs, snoring loudly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COPS are running up the staircase. People try to escape with as many of their belongings that they can hold.</context>
      <utterance>Not this way. Out through the fire escape.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My tap shoes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CU OF DELACROIX AND SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix picks it up. They yell in unison.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manray!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manray!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It hit me like a ton of bricks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's scary.</context>
      <utterance>How can this be? You and me at the same time, the exact same thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The idea was out there in the universe. Now what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ran out without my shoes and the floor. I gotta get my stuff. What about our savings?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manray looks at his friend, he knows he is right, at least this time.</context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy? The joint is crawling with cops now. You wanna go to Rikers? Go to the hoosegow?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manray was under our nose the whole time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know how you will use him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet, but this thing will never get made.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lost me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunwitty wants a Coon show. And that's what I'm going to give him, it's going to be so racist, so negative, he won't have the balls to put it on the air. Hence I'll prove my point.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What point is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The point being that him, the networks don't want Black people on television unless they are buffoons.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds risky to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You getting cold feet?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in till the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I'm going to need your support.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you just quit? Walk away?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's what I intend to do.</context>
      <utterance>And lose out on my money? The only way I get paid is if I get fired.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Dunwitty was off my back for now.</context>
      <utterance>Everything was going according to plan. I was working on the outline.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there was a catch. A big catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sloan.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manray and Cheeba were nowhere to be found.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was like they had disappeared off the face of the earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheeba.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had no contact numbers, no address, no beeper.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manray.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No nuthin', no clues...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe something happened to them. Maybe they're lying in an alley bleed to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manray better not be bleeding to death. I need him. After we're done he can do whatever he wants to do, until then, he's ours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Delapoint.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WE have no one by that name.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delapot. Dela-something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manray turns around and sees Sloan.</context>
      <utterance>De La Soul ain't here either. Let's go. Out. Off the premises.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The security guard stops.</context>
      <utterance>Sloan! She knows us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's alright. They are associates of Mr. Delacroix.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Ms. Hopkins. They both walked in off the street without an appointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you need an escort?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That won't be needed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hugs them both.</context>
      <utterance>Eureka! Where've you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sloan and I have been looking all over for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd take no offense if we called you DeLa for short?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No offense.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix smiles at Sloan.</context>
      <utterance>Manray needs a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got evicted from our home. We've both been on the streets for the last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We was coming to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's not too much trouble could you order us some food?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're starving.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I apologize. What would you like to eat? Anything you want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have this concept for a TV pilot. There's no guarantee it will get made but regardless, you'll still make some money.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First things first. I have to know if Manray is up for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I have to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some tap dancing, some singing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do I sign?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of show is this gonna be?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Different.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How different?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me. Of course I still have to pitch it to my boss, but we'll have an answer one way or the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DeLa, I'm aboard. As long as I get to hoof and get paid too!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. Money turns the wheel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about in the mean time? Not the in between time?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll both get an advance and you can stay with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would like to change your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're now Mantan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mantan? I don't even care as long as I'm dancing. Which reminds me, I need some new kicks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never had a really real pair before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've never had any formal training, either?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a class, not a thing, just picked stuff up by myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I had your natural talent. God only makes that visit once in a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sing and dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little. I just graduated from NYU film school. Cinema studies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's up with you and DeLa?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Y'knowwhatI'mtalkin'bout.</context>
      <utterance>Are you and him kicking it? Knocking boots.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we're not knocking boots. I got this internship while I still was at NYU, DeLa was impressed with my get up and go and hired me to be his assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure that was the only thing he was impressed with. You look beautiful like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that was suppose to be a compliment, I thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome. You shouldn't give up on performing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you say that? You've never seen me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that would probably make you the happiest. When I'm hoofing, I mean really doing my thing, hitting it, nothing compares to that feeling in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I envy you. That's the way I want to feel about my work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Li'l Sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You idiot. You almost gave me a massive coronary.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to scare you like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me some?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not huggin' you in the middle of the street. You must be crazy, Julius.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, hold up li'l sis'. I done told you 'bout that. Julius ain't my name, you better recognize Hopkins was our slave name. My true name is...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mommy and Daddy named you Julius.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not callin you Big Black Africa.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hugs her, she becomes lost in his huge arms and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>BIG BLACK is the first name and AFRICA is the last.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, Sis, you don't keep no food up in here in dis' piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I order out mostly. So what do I owe this visit to?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My group we need some exposure. Was wondering if you could hook a brother up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hook you up? The Mau-Mau's? You must be smoking. Why in the world would I want to hook up a bunch of red, black and green flag-waving pseudo revolutionairies?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now I see where you're coming from. Just because we ain't rapping about Gucci, Timberland, Rolex, Benz, Cristal, ho's and bitches, we're pseudo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you revolting against?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're revolting against the powers that be, that been enslaving the minds and hearts of all people of color. And we won't stop rapping till we bring about the overthrow of the government of the U.S. of A.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you were really down you would get us together with that boss of yours. What's his name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think he would write a show about the Mau-Mau's.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, why not? The Monkees had a show. Look at all that other junk that's on TV. We got underground cult following.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have the demographics.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are you telling me that you wouldn't even introduce me to Delacroix or set up a meeting? I'm talking 'bout me, your only brother, ya own flesh and blood, hook a brother up, youknowwhatI'msayin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'swhatI'msayin'. I'm not blowin' my young career, brother or no brother, for you or anybody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is a name, a term for your kind, the likes of you. Back in slavery days, you would be classified as a house nigga.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you think I'm a house nigga then that's your prerogative. You got your ways to affect change, I have mine. And I would appreciate it very much if you took ya field nigga ass out of my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My own sister throwin' me out. I hope to seeya later when you get ya mind right. Don't bother letting me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Black slams the door.</context>
      <utterance>That's mighty black of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix, I'm glad you got your mind right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You know my assistant, Sloan.</context>
      <utterance>It's right and tight. Good morning, let me introduce you to everybody.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Cheeba.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is Manray.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I like the names. Very theatrical.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're all happy to be here and I'm going to paint a picture for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm wid it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's about promoting racial healing.</context>
      <utterance>I've done a lot of soul searching and once again you are right. In my previous work it's been all surface, superficial. I have never really dug deep. Not anymore. As Mark Twain fully understood satire is the way. Race has always been a hot button in this country's history and it needs to be pushed harder. If we are ever to live side by side in peace and harmony.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on. Good so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HeeHaw?</context>
      <utterance>I know you're familiar with minstrel shows. They came about at the turn of the 19th century. It was a variety show in which the talent was in blackface - singing, dancing, telling jokes, doing skits. Dunwitty, I ask you when was the last time there was a good variety show on the air. Carol Burnett?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Word!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So let's take this great form, this very American tradition of entertainment into the 21st century, into the new millennium.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name of the show?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is called: MANTAN - THE NEW</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunwitty starts walking around his office, pumping his first.</context>
      <utterance>I'm lovin' it. You know how I know? Because I'm getting a boner, my Johnson is hard, no disrespect my sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm feelin' dis'!</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will take a lot of courage and backbone on the part of the CNS to get this on the air. In fact, I would understand fully if the subject matter is deemed too risque, too controversial.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about that, that's my department. Now who do we cast? We need a star. Can Whoopi sing or dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if Whoopi is the way to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are these our two stars, sitting here in front of my nose? Which one is Mantan again?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a great handle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mantan and Sleep 'n Eat. Two real coons. I know we're way out there but it's satire.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sloan looks at Delacroix with concern.</context>
      <utterance>I want you take it there. All the way to the edge and back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every week we follow the trials and tribulations of two real coons - Mantan and Sleep 'n Eat. The Dusky Duo.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are there character traits?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ignorant, dullwitted, lazy, and unlucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly!</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mantan is an uneducated Negro who always by some stroke of unbelievable stupidity makes his best laid plans go haywire.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Sleep 'n Eat is his comical sidekick?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep, you guessed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This could be bigger than "Amos and Andy."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Protest finally forced "Amos and Andy" off the air. Could stop us from ever getting on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix looks at Sloan.</context>
      <utterance>Let'em try. I will kill to make this happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negroes would be in an uproar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what. We would just give the NAACP a donation that would be the end of that. No such thing as bad publicity. So what. Earlier you said singing and dancing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mantan right here is a gifted hoofer. He has educated feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are the other characters?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunwitty is dying with laughter. He's the only one.</context>
      <utterance>Do we have characters? How about Honeycutt, Snowflake, Rastus, Nigger, Jim, Sambo, Jungle Bunny, and how could we forget Aunt Jemima.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gonna hit 'em wid da BOMB DICKEY on dis' one. What's the setting?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the projects. Like Eddie Murphy's "The PJ's."</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya first bad move. Projects been done. That's one of the problems now, everything, movies, TV, are set in the urban jungle, da hood. That's so tired. Mantan's Millennium Minstrel Show should be set on a plantation. In Alabama.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And every week these Alabama porch monkeys will make us cry, make us laugh, make us look at our own humanity. Make us feel good to be alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know about that plantation angle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talkin' 'bout? It's the move. Stay wid me now. We're movin' fast. What does everybody else think about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs, it's a fake one at that.</context>
      <utterance>We'd get a lot of mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Dunwitty, there wouldn't be another show like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always wanted to be on television.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like you. Sleep 'n Eat. That's funny. Mantan, how do you feel about performing in black face?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as the hoofing is real, that I can do my thing, I can blacken up. Let me hit it, beats and rhythms, express myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mantan starts to put on his new tap shoes.</context>
      <utterance>Show me a little somethin' somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mantan is ready.</context>
      <utterance>Delacroix, you dug deep, deeper than deep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to work out.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna give you just a taste. My tap shoes are brand new. I haven't trained 'em yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dunwitty clears his desk of everything, just knocks stuff flying onto the floor. And Mantan taking the cue, jumps up on his desk and really starts hitting it.</context>
      <utterance>Rhythms, rhythms, rhythms. Beats, beats, beats. No Fred Astaire here, baby. Just rawness.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'swhatI'mtalkin''bout. That'swhatI'mtalkin''bout! He's off the hiz-hook!</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sleep 'n Eat, what do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I play the straight man. I do some singing and dancing also. I also manage Mantan.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh you do so?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the man behind the man behind the man.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You da man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you da man.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna run upstairs with this. If CNS doesn't want to do this, somebody else will have da balls to pull the trigger. I want to thank each and every one of you. This is great, Delacroix. I'll get back to you later today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life is beginning to look up. It's all good in da neighborhood.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might be right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His smile is a mile wide.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you smiling so?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, not you. It can't be. That hottie Sloan Hopkins.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's that bad, huh? It's all over my face.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shame in ya game. She got ya nostrils, ya chnoz is wide open. Sloan's what we certified ladies' men call low hanging fruit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certified ladies' man, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's also moorish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moorish. Ya get a little taste of dat booty, ya wanna get some MORE.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seconds and thirds, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sloan is all 'dat. I try her. I'm a tri-sexual.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd try anything. I got first dibs. You get ya own stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's you.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, just jokin'. That's you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to start using the name Mantan and not Manray if you don't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to start getting into your character.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cheeba turns quickly towards Manray.</context>
      <utterance>At the risk of sounding ignorant...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Delacroix hits the remote button. The TV and VCR are powered.</context>
      <utterance>...don't say a word but who is this cat Mantan you keep talkin' 'bout?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Mantan Moreland.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSER ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Television. Mantan reacts to seeing a ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a clown, a buffoon but he was funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DeLa, I don't know 'bout this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, the show, our show will be satirical. You know what that is, don't you? Trust me on this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We might need some mo' money behind this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That can be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mantan?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mantan!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Black takes a long, long drag on a joint, then he quickly empties a 64 oz. in one swing without missing a beat, without missing a head nod.</context>
      <utterance>How 'bout...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The whole group goes crazy with the title of the song.</context>
      <utterance>Black Iz Black?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUBLE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's da bomb.</utterance>
   <speaker>MO BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's gonna give me some inspiration.</utterance>
   <speaker>JO BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gonna make me get my flow on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone starts high-fiving each other.</context>
      <utterance>We should call dis da BLACK album.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOTH BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, check it out. We have never conformed to none of the white man's rules and regulations and later for that ole slave owner Webster. Therefore I respectfully submit BIG BLACK that we from now on, hence forth and whatnot spell BLACK: B-L-A-K, not B-L-A-C-K.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARD BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel dat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must think I'm some kind of fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks delicious.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hear me talkin' to you. The only time you come up here when something is wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Mommy, don't start with that I'm an ungrateful son stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits down with him.</context>
      <utterance>I said no such thing. All I said is that something must be wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the food?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't beat it with a hammer. Well, since you asked, it looks like I may have a new show, a pilot being shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He talks between mouthfuls.</context>
      <utterance>That's wonderful. Isn't that what you always wanted, a show of your own?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was. It is. But this is a different kind of show.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If at first it's not what you want, just work that much harder, Peerless.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy, please don't call me that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, Peerless is your name. Now you might be one of these Hollywood types, change your name and all that but Peerless Dothan is on your birth certificate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what's on my birth certificate. You heard from Daddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess he's still on the road. What kind of show is this? Are they some Negroes in it without being buffoons?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To answer your question, there are a lot of Negroes in it and what is your definition of buffoons?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peerless, I didn't raise a buffoon. We have enough of those on television already.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please let me know when you hear from Daddy, get a number or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix gets up from his seat and hugs his mother.</context>
      <utterance>I will. And good luck with your show. I hope it's a huge success. You've worked very hard. You deserve it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel like somebody hit me upside da head with a sledgehammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DeLa - what's the matter with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't happy about the green light?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People show their happiness in a lot of different ways.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, homeboy, looks like he's at a funeral.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pressure is on.</context>
      <utterance>I'm happy for all of us. It's just we have a great responsibility now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pressure? DeLa, you don't know what the hell real pressure is. SHEEETT!!! This is lightstuff. Now when you scramblin' out on the street in da January winter and the hawk is talkin' to you with NO money and NO prospects of money anytime soon, now that there is some pressure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean it to sound like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the way it came out. Let me ask you one question. Have you ever been in want, in need your entire privileged life?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I'm privileged?! Why? Because I didn't grow up on food stamps and welfare? Because I didn't call home a cardboard box? No, I never ever went to bed hungry and I'm proud of it, too. Whoever told you that living in poverty earns you somekind of badge of honor flat out lied to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix gets up from the table and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>The point I'm trying to make is that this is a blessing. It's going to be fun doing this show and we should all look at it that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cheeba and Mantan laugh, give each other some dap. A highly attractive PUERTO RICAN female walks over to their table. This is JESSICA GRILLO.</context>
      <utterance>Must be the pressure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cheeba and Mantan are in awe.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, girl. This is my best friend, Jessica Grillo. I invited her down to celebrate with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Cheeba.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both rise.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Mantan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, have a seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sloan never told us she had friends like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In fact, we never knew she had any friends period.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Later for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has a lot of friends</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Male?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sloan and Jessica laugh at the expense of these guys.</context>
      <utterance>Enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs an empty glass and pours herself some champagne.</context>
      <utterance>I propose a toast.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Everyone raises their glasses. CLINK!</context>
      <utterance>To the success of your show. Good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sloan gets up from the table and takes after Delacroix.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait here.</utterance>
   <speaker>43.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She goes to the ladies' cubicle.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix. He leans against the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My problem is MANTAN THE NEW</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you even come up with that shit if you didn't want it made?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was the principle. Dunwitty had to be enlightened. I was making a point. I take pride in my work. Plus, I already told you I wasn't gonna walk away from my money.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck da money. Why do through all this effort? Why? Are you looking for love from Dunwitty? For respect? Dunwitty and his likes don't give a goddamn about you. So now what are you gonna do? Someone begins to pound on the bathroom door.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you please let me in? I have to use the toilet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She returns her attention to Delacroix.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna have to hold it in because we're not finished yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...QUIT then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if money wasn't an issue, Dunwitty will still go ahead without me and that could be more dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the chances of MANTAN being picked up?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't bet against it. My Negroidal ass is stuck between the proverbial rock and a hard place.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The banging starts again.</context>
      <utterance>Like I said, all this for some twisted, distorted sense of principal. Dunwitty, he just tolerates your Negroidal ass, he doesn't respect it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sloan unlocks the door and they exit.</context>
      <utterance>Please open this bathroom door immediately. You are being very inconsiderate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I strongly feel that a Negro should direct this. This kind of satire is a high wire act in a gale storm. One misstep and we're doing "Amos and Andy." Only a Negro will have the sensitivity and cultural awareness to navigate this dangerous terrain.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To hire someone solely on their ethnicity, gender or religion is not right. It's un-American. I will hire someone who is most qualified for this particular job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping to perhaps direct some episodes myself, if not the pilot soon after.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a hot, young white director. Maybe the kid, that pheenom who just did that hot new sexy Madonna video.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me some white boy is gonna direct this pilot?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want you to meet him. Keep an open mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, what does he know about Negroes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably nuthin', but that's why it's such a sexy way to go. Sometimes an outsider has a fresh new outlook, a different unique perspective. A black director, y'know what he's gonna do given the subject matter? With this kid, the possibilities are endless.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are his qualifications besides being a white male and directing a hot new sexy freaky Madonna video?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Spielburg can direct "The Color Purple" and "Amistad", our whiz kid can direct the Mantan pilot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's exactly my point. Has he even directed actors before in anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!!! Just meet the guy. That's all I'm asking. Look, I'll even let you choose your own musical director. You can have that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the immortal words of Derrick Coleman, WHOOOPDEEDAMNDOO!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix stares at Dunwitty.</context>
      <utterance>Derrick Coleman, he possessed all the talent in the world, coulda, shoulda, been a great ballplayer but alas D.C. didn't want it bad enough. Delacroix, do you want it? Bad enough to kill for it? Do you want it that much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, for those of you who don't know me, I'm Pierre Delacroix. I'm running things and this here is my assistant Sloan Hopkins.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never worked with any of you and you've never worked with me so we'll be starting from scratch. I'm a fair person, a straight shooter and I don't hold my tongue. Everybody up in here should know I had nothing to do with you being hired.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>MONA raises her hand.</context>
      <utterance>I would have preferred at least one other Negro writer. Any questions? Comments?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He, I'm Mona.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mona.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I perfectly understand where you're coming from. As a minority I can relate to your struggle also. But I think you should give us all a chance. We want this pilot to be successful just as much as you. Please don't be so quick to judge us based only on our whiteness.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETH jumps in.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, is that what I'm doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SETH pipes in also.</context>
      <utterance>I think because of our background we can bring a unique perspective to Mantan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fresh pair of eyes. A new look, insight, new angle that hasn't been seen before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I've heard this somewhere before.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David, I appreciate your comments. Anybody got an ideas? Everybody just talk out loud.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always liked the format of Rowan and Martin's "LAUGH-IN."</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That could be cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about something like "The Jeffersons?" I grew up in Idaho so that's how I got my understanding of black people. Through Sherman Helmsley, LOUISSEE!!!.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Good Times" was better. Kid Dy-no mite!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You pole are going to far back for me. I think we have to go after a hipper feel. Like the stuff Eddie Murphy used to do on "Saturday Night Live."</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or Martin. You go girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the black exploitation films? No one has ever tried making that work on TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And for reason. Have you ever seen "Scream Blacula, Scream?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think, and Delacroix will agree with me, the politics of this show have to be right. We should always be laughing with our characters, not at them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was amazing. Who had told these Negroes that this was what we were looking for? The same old image, it damn for sure wasn't me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lulu.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were people this desperate to get work?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix. He interrupts Lulu.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Ms. Lulu.</utterance>
   <speaker>LULU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I had several more poems.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lulu scurries off stage.</context>
      <utterance>That's good. We've seen enough. We'll get back to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RUTH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Mau-Mau's run onto the stage, yelling and screaming. They are all fired up, in fact several fire their 9mm's into the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Next.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - TWO SHOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix and Sloan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the group I was telling you about.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one is your brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The big one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ruth.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get started here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big Black preens around on the stage.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's right, the Mau-Mau's.</context>
      <utterance>The Mau-Mau's are up in dis place.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My righteous name is BIG BLACK.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what are the Mau-Mau's going to do for us today?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gonna drop some knowledge, wisdom and understanding. The Mau- Mau's, we be scientists. We drop science.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brothers introduce yourself.</context>
      <utterance>Microphone check. One. Two. One. Two. One. Two. Hold up. I gots to give my peeps some props.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUBLE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, I'm Double Black.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check it, Black Black.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOTH BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Smooth Black, the lover in dis' piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARD BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard Black.</utterance>
   <speaker>MO BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's Jo Black.</utterance>
   <speaker>JO BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he's Mo Black.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Needless to say, the Mau-Mau's did not fit into our plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I told Sloan, there's a black sheep in every family.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACKSTAGE - LATER THAT DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix is screaming at the top of his lungs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finland. This is a travesty. A debacle. A mockery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix. This is the director I was telling you about. Jukka Laks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUKKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So nice to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you. If you don't mind me asking you - how old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUKKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just turned twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna leave you two creative geniuses alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunwitty, don't leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>54.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunwitty is out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUKKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helsinki, which is the capital of Finland.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finland.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUKKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Finlandia vodka? Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know. Jukka, have you ever seen a Negro person before? Even had a real conversation with a real Negro before?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUKKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a Negro.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUKKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhh!!! I never heard of that term before. I thought you were BLACK of African-American. No?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well before there was BLACK or AFRICAN AMERICAN, there were</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get this gig?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUKKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My visual style is very erotic, sexy, how do you say - hot?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a TV show, not a music video.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUKKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then will you teach me what I need to know. Maybe we learn from each other, if that's possible, no?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a travesty. A debacle.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've said that already.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna slit my wrists. Cut my throat. For the love of Joseph.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not be held responsible for these revisions. These changes are not the way I want to go. This is an outrage. This is a sham. A violation!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUKKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Finland, when we get upset...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't give a good goddamn about Finland, Norway, Sweden or wherever ya blond ass came from.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just punched it up a bit. Made it funnier.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funnier to who and at who's expense? Dunwitty, when Negroes start to run amok, the boycotts, when the demostrations commence, I'm giving them your home address. Let's see how you like it when they picket your lawn in Greenwich, Connecticut.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seriously doubt that will ever happen. Didn't I tell you I know your people better than you do. But if by some miracle you're correct, I'm gonna invite them inside my house and we'll have a sit down, discuss it like civil human beings.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just want to say good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives Mantan a kiss on his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Break a leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. Hold up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I kiss you too?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw. I'll take the zero.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feel good, not nervous?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not nervous? Relaxed?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sloan, will you take your boss out of here so I can get ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the audience?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fired up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you feelin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I'm not sure about this material.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sloan cuts a look at this liar.</context>
      <utterance>The material is fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're trying to do something new here, some groundbreaking stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the bone breaking stuff I'm worried about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's gonna be alright. You and Mantan will be huge stars after tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your life will never be the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's leave the man in peace so he can get ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both lied to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just don't lie to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Jukka. Do a good show.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUKKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much. I always try my best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to meet my lovely wife Verna. Honey, this is Pierre Delacroix and Sloan Hopkins.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pleasure is mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My husband has been raving about the awesome work you've done. How did you ever think of something like this? It's absolutely brilliant. Pure genius.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it was divine inspiration.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hope to see you both after the taping. Congrats in advance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TWO SHOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix and Sloan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Divine inspiration?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was trying to be nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to apologize about my brother and the Mau-Mau's. I should not have imposed them on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon. You were only doing what family is supposed to be doing for family. You gave your brother a shot. That's all anybody can ask for, an opportunity, a chance, a shot. He got his.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mantan puts some corks in a dish.</context>
      <utterance>We should blacken up like they did it back in the day. Keep the ritual the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pour some alcohol on the corks, then light it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He watches the cork burn.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let them burnt to a crisp, and when burnt out, mash them to a powder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Add water, mix to a thick paste.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And voila! You have your blackface.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my best friend Sleep 'N Eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is my very best friend Mantan.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience lets out nervous laughter. They don't know what to think.</context>
      <utterance>We're two real COONS!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both left the hustle and bustle of Uptown, Harlem...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the big apple, New York, New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To come back to our roots.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our Alabamy Home. Now we're getting countrified. We is Bama's.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No mo' "city slickers." Ahh, can't you smell the sweet aroma of the ripe watermelons and high cotton?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell 'em what you mean Mistuh Mantan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thank you Mistuh Sleep 'N Eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mantan begins to do a slow, steady step.</context>
      <utterance>Give or cousins some of dem educated feets.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cousins, first, second, third and distant, let's have Mantan take us all the way back to a much more simpler time. A time wen men were men, women were women, and Neggras knew their place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cousins, I want all of you to go to your windows. Go to your windows and yell. Yell, I'm tired of the drugs, the crack babies born out of wedlock to crackhead aids infested parents. I'm tired of the inflated welfare rolls while good wholesome Americans bring less and less of their paycheck home every two weeks. I'm tired, you're tired, we're all tired of these so-called bible- thumping God fearing, whore mongling Professional athletes. Aren't you tired of these basketball-dunking, football-running, hop-hip rapping ebonic-speaking sex offenders who got ten kids from ten different Ho's? I know I am and so is Sleep 'N Eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tellin' the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to your windows and yell out, scream with all the life you can muster up inside your assaulted, bruised and battered bodies. I'M</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has to be a big mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The big mistake was my not believing in your genius earlier. From the gitgo, from jump street.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on a sec, I got a call.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gots to go, it's my Moms.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to meet her one day, please tell her the great news. I'm OUT like Vanilla Ice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be right over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's up with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The good stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm an asthmatic. Been one all my life. Can't go anywhere without an inhaler.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to rap to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants you to come and see him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's performing at some place outside of Richmond, Virginia.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't go all the way down south.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Richmond is not all the way down south.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even know why you're still concerned over him. Daddy's not with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Regardless, he still is your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gonna be hard for me to get away with the show taking off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even more reason to see him. He'll be overjoyed with your success.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Mommy. Daddy hasn't been impressed with anything I've ever done. From winning my fifth grade Spelling Bee to the present.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peerless, last time, go see your father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his index finger over his mouth - "Quiet."</context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to seduce me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He quickly jumps up on the bench, does some intricate steps then pulls Sloan up from her sitting position.</context>
      <utterance>You think that's gonna work, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cuse me. Please. Can you please show me some respect. I'm up here trying to make a living.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind yo' business.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sparse AUDIENCE laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Don't make me have to come over there and whoop you upside ya head.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He continues on with his show.</context>
      <utterance>Just messin' with ya. But please if you and your lady need to discuss something, take it outside. Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy looks him up and down.</context>
      <utterance>Brother man, that's my father up there and I drove a long way to see him perform. Please take this fifty, go buy you and the young lady some drinks in the club.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix nods.</context>
      <utterance>That's yo' Daddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The guy grabs his friend by the wrist and drags her kicking and screaming out the room.</context>
      <utterance>Don't need yo money for drinks. Besides, she's drunk already. C'mon, let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This gets the biggest laugh of the night.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bring your woman out if you can't keep her in deep check. If my woman ever did something crazy like that I'd put my size 12 dead up in her ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to speak with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away, unless you got my money.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me, Peerless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son. Good to seeya. Good to seeya.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull up a chair. Oh, excuse me, this is my lady DOT.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleased to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad to meet you, too. You are all your father talks about.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that so?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both sit down as drinks are poured.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, pour me and my son a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses Junebug on the forehead before leaving.</context>
      <utterance>I'll leave you two alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good woman. I trained her right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy, she's younger than me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up his drink and kills it in one gulp.</context>
      <utterance>My game is still strong. No Viagra for me, don't need no chemicals. Just my tonic.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Purely for medicinal purposes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you had promised Mommy you stopped.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. I'm not an alcoholic. I just like to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you end up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix takes a sip of his drink.</context>
      <utterance>How did I end up at the third rate chittlin' circuit greasy hole in the wall in West Hell, Virginny? Is that what you're asking ya Daddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm askin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I had too much pride. Too much integrity. I wouldn't lick nobody's butt. Some material I refused to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junebug pours himself another stiff one.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy, it can't be just because of that. There had to be other factors.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the only reason, period. They only want one certain kind of black comic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another one of your conspiracies to hold ya career back?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He downs another one. Junebug drinks like a fish.</context>
      <utterance>All I know is what happened to me. All that other mess I just file into the "life's too short" category.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough about me, what's happening with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The same old, same old. Trying to get my stuff through.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dem white boys giving you a hard time?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nuthin' I can't handle.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truth is never let them seeya sweat. You do that, that's half the battle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you go from here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three nights Charleston, South Carolina.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean that, in life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In life? I'ma keep on living, having a good drink, got me a good young woman, make a couple of dollars and make people laugh. Haven't I always tol' you all nigga's are entertainers? The question is what are you gonna do, Peerless?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not an alcoholic. I just like to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know that baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get him over to the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lay him down on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Baby, you treat me so good. Peerless, you're a good son, I love you. You never gave me no trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you too, Daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNEBUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dot takes off his shoes. He's out like a light. Gone.</context>
      <utterance>Always keep 'em laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long has my father been like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that often. He was excited to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So he drank himself into a stuper?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The drinking is for the pain. It doesn't kill it, just dulls it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's up with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix pulls out his billfold and gives Dot five crisp new model hundred dollar bills.</context>
      <utterance>I was a hostess at this club, your Daddy was performing and I had never laughed so hard in my life. He asked me to come with him. I quit my job and we've been together ever since.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell him it's from me or he won't take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father is proud of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never showed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix kisses his sleeping father of the forehead.</context>
      <utterance>He did the best way he knew how, Junebug is stubborn just like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Daddy. I'm not mad at him. Not at all. Junebug was the reason I got into this business in the first place.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I thank him for that. However, it did me no good seeing him in that state. Daddy was a broken man. He had been a strong man, with conviction, integrity, principles and look where it had gotten him. I had to ask myself did I want to end up where he was?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody say Ho!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDIENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ho!</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audience applauds.</context>
      <utterance>That'swhatI'mtalkin'bout! That'swhatI'mtalkin'bout! I want to be the first to welcome you to the second taping of Mantan - The New Millennium Minstrel Show.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Honeycutt and I want to try something different. Can you do this for me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna start a chant and I want y'all to follow me. Let's make our own 2 real coons know you're ready to start the show.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Honeycutt claps the cadence.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go Niggers. Then clap five times like this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUDIENCE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go niggers!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDIENCE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go niggers!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know my lady Lucindy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one with da big...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not her, the one with the little...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow is her birthday and I want to get her something really nice, like a...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not that. How 'bout...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She hates dem.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad. How 'bout a dress?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sleep 'N Eat, one of dem slinky, sexy, little foxy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get her one of dose...</context>
      <utterance>Mantan, way too short, too tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...to big. The in-between one, not too tight, not too lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mantan cocks his limp wrist. The audience ROARS.</context>
      <utterance>That'll work. I just bought one for myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for me, my woolly headed cotton pickin' friend for...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you got rid of...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dat dress will cast ya round...</context>
      <utterance>...that was Vicki, her best friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...dat's too much money. I can't 'ford it. I needs me a dress that cost no mo' than...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...aconite get it dat cheap.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll buy her a less expensive dress, so I can have some money left over to take her out to dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should go out on a double date.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard ya lady is wild.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Who's married to Li'l Bit.</context>
      <utterance>No. That's her second cousin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, because on our first date, she let me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...no, she didn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...yes she did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I heard different, thought that was...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...not that time...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So when are you comin' to pick us up?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Around...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...too early...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...then what about...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...too late, maybe around...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...perfect...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We git along...</context>
      <utterance>That's what I like about you and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...like macaroni and cheese...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...like grits and butter...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...like fried and chicken...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OFF-SCREEN we HEAR the VOICE of MASSA CHARLIE, he's the overseer of this plantation.</context>
      <utterance>...like sleep and eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASSA CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who goes in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd better hide.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hide behind some boxes.</context>
      <utterance>It's dat mean, evil overseer Massa Charlie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASSA CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say who goes in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Massa Charlie enters the chicken coops with a SHOTGUN blazing. Sleep 'N Eat and Mantan do a jig as they try to escape the buckshot.</context>
      <utterance>There's nobody in here 'cept us chickens.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's side are you on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix starts to crack a smile. He is definitely trying to hold it in.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I can't help it. It's too funny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was the Day of Reckoning. After a massive advertising and publicity campaign...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delacroix stares at the blank screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frankenstein.</context>
      <utterance>...the public would finally get a chance to view Mantan. I was feelin' a little bit like Dr.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would their reaction be? I hadn't the foggiest.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody shut up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calling all my cousins, you're about to take a trip down to Hang 'Em High Plantation, home of your two favorite coons, Mantan and Sleep 'N Eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why they gotta make my nose so big?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at my lips.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it looks cute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DA BOMB. Yo. It's 125% pure pleasure MALT LIQUOR.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOCHIE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Da Bomb, Baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYA #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Da Bomb, Baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clinical testing has found that Viagra doesn't work on black "johnson's." That's why our scientists developed Da Bomb for you. It makes you feel like a MAN and it makes dem bitches feel like Natural Women - I mean Ho's.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYA #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It makes my nature rise.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOCHIE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to get funked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Honeycutt takes a big swallow from his 64 oz. Jugular. Two statuesque ladies sandwich him, grinding up on Honeycutt. He takes the jugular from his lips. As he speaks, flames come out of his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>DA BOMB - 125% pure pleasure malt liquor.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooooo-weeee!! Da Bomb makes me wanna get my freak on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWO MO' HOOCHIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honeycutt, let's get our swerve on@</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TIMMY HILLNIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DAWG 1 steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, my name be Timmi Hillnigger. I was born and raised up in Strong Island so you know I know about my peeps, my niggaz in the git-toe. I design and own TIMMI HILLNIGGER 125% Authentic Git-Toe active wear.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWG #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hillnigger keeps it real.</utterance>
   <speaker>86.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DAWG 2 steps forward also.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWG #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Timmi's gots all da latest gear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMY HILLNIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hoe 1 laying in a white thong on top of a white Rolls-Royce.</context>
      <utterance>If you want to keep it really real, never get out of the git-toe, stay broke and continue to add to my multibillion dollar corporation, keep buyin' all my gear. The Timmi Hillnigger collection. We keep it so real we give you the bullet holes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's Git-toe Fabulous.</context>
      <utterance>All my niggaz wear Hillnigger or they don't wear a damn thing at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was sunk, dead. My goose was cooked. The cat was in the bag and the bag was in the river.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you watch MANTAN - THE NEW MILLENNIUM MINSTREL SHOW last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT CLINTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I did and I can honestly say I feel it promotes racial healing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know all of you have seen the overnight ratings. Through the roof. But in this game you gotta be one, two, three steps ahead. I introduce you to Myrna Goldfarb. She's the best media consultant in the biz.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYRNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First, I would like to say I love the show. It's very courageous. My parents marched in Selma, Alabama with Dr. King.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYRNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good question, straight to the point. I like your style. Because of the content of the show we can expect some spirited reactions.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Myrna is here to help us plan our strategy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYRNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best defense is offense.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was the other way around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYRNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get my point. I've mapped out some strategies to help bolster our position.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYRNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That this is fun. Nice wholesome fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goldfarb, run it down for them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MYRNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If they can't take a joke, "F" 'em.</context>
      <utterance>The Mantan Manifesto. Catchy ain't it? Number One. We gainfully employ African Americans, in front of and behind the cameras. Two. Let the audience decide. Three. Who put these critics in charge? These so-called cultural police? Four. Who determines what is black? Five. Mantan is a satire. Six.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all stick to this, it's smooth sailing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sounds kinda simplistic to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYRNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've done my research.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are black folks we're talkin' about, not some lab mice in a cage.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYRNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monsieur Delacroix, I got my PhD in African-American studies from Yale, so I do feel I'm qualified.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let Myrna finish.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYRNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. And always smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She ignores him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, show dem pearly whites.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYRNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wear Kente cloth, invoke the name of Dr. Martin Luther King, use the word "community" often when talking about Mantan. And finally our biggest plus is you, Pierre Delacroix.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MYRNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This show was created, conceived by you, a non-threatening African- American male. Voila. End of argument. It can't be racist because you're black.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not black. I'm a NEGRO!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you have your small victory, now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A small victory isn't that small when you've been use to losing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix opens his gift. It is one of those old cast iron Black Collectibles. This one is called "THE JOLLY NIGGER BANK," a head of a Negro, big lips, big nose, wide eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No matter what you think, you did come up with something unique. Open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He puts a quarter in the hand.</context>
      <utterance>Put a coin in the hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She pushes the lever and the mouth opens, the quarter flies in and his eyes go to the top of his head.</context>
      <utterance>Watch this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Delacroix reads.</context>
      <utterance>Read it on the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Jolly Nigger Bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is authentic, not a repro, circa turn of the century.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was appropiate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that good or bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all good. You got a hit show, you're gonna need a bank. Plus, I love these old black collectibles.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To me, it shows part of our history in this country, a time when we were considered inferior, sub-human.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GARY BYRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our guest today is Pierre Delacroix. He is the creator of the highly controversial TV show MANTAN. Let's get right into it. You have been called by some in the community a traitor, a sellout, an Uncle Tom. Why does your show generate such feelings?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because race has always been a sensitive issue in this country. Gary, I have no problem with people disagreeing with the show, it's when folks start trying to mess with my inherent right as an artist, that's when I get mad. No one, in any way, shape or form should be censored.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARY BYRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No matter how sexist or racist the material may be?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. And I say yes because who is to judge? Who is to stand before us and say this is righteous and this is not? Who? Who can play God?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARY BYRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the line has to be drawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you people get it? We're in the 21st Century. Slavery was over four hundred years ago. All that stuff people talked in the old days, it's over. Folks always crying, white man this, white man that. Let's all grow up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARY BYRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to excuse our Holocaust?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I finish? Thank you. I had a great Aunt, we called her Sister. She went to her grave not believing man had walked on the Moon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON AMERICAN FLAG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It blows majestically in the wind.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When American people want something, they want it now, they want it big.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSREEL FOOTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kids swinging in their hula hoops.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They wanted the hula hoop...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSREEL FOOTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kids playing with their yo-yo's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They wanted their yo-yo's.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSREEL FOOTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A young girl petting her Pet Rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who could ever forget those lovable pet rocks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Mantan - The New Millennium Minstrel Show at www.nigger.com was getting 500,000 hits a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep trying.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they can be on TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sound like the media.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is nothing. It will blow over by tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same thing Giuliani said.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Mantan a wrapped gift.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow it will be all about cruelty to animals or some sex scandal. Besides, there is no such thing as bad publicity.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mantan opens it. He pulls out an old pair of tap shoes.</context>
      <utterance>Rest your mind. It's a little somethin' something.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mantan starts to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Those were the last pair of tap shoes worn by Bill "Bojangles" Robinson. In fact, he died with them on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No joke. Serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hope the same thing doesn't happen to me. That's some big shoes to fill.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DOUBLE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that handkerchief head...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...dancing monkey...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that simpleton is holding back the race. They got rid of us and keep those two buffoons, Mantan and Sleep 'N Eat, y'knowwhatI'msayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARD BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Big Black, Sleep 'N Eat ain't even a nigger, y'knowwhatI'msayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOTH BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's Mexican, y'knowwhatI'msayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MO BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's Dominican, y'knowwhatI'msayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>JO BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's Peter Rican, y'knowwhatI'msayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same thing, y'knowwhatI'msayin', y'knowwhatI'msayin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1/16, tru' 'dat. True 'dat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUBLE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me gat him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, too easy, this has to be symbolic, has to be on the world stage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a nice place. It must have cost a pretty penny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sloan, I got it like 'dat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh you do, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little something' somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you save a little somethin' somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gots no intention of ending up broke.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, at the beginnin' of the century, African-American had to perform in blackface. You ever heard of Bert Williams? He was a great artist.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, before my time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't read, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never read a book in my whole life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you need to start.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I need to do a lot of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bert Williams and the rest, they had to black up. They had no choice. They were considered 3/5ths of a human being. Did you know that's written in the Constitution of the United States?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why all of a sudden are you flippin' on me? This blackface thing was part of the deal from the git-go. Don't even try to play it like you ain't a part of all this. You down with Delacroix.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just don't want you and Cheeba to get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can look out for ourselves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fell out of my bed last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You slept too near where you got in?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I slept too near where I fell out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You expect the unexpected in circumstances of that peculiarity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sleep 'N Eat, what's the matter with you? Using all dose ten dollar words?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mantan, it is possible that my hyphenated sentences are entirely too complex for all the intellect contained in that diminutive coconut?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't cross words with me.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on, you allegorical hypothesis.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't Jemima on the pancake box?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dat's yo Uncle Ben. That reminds me, I've seen a lot of troubles lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How be dat?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know who I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll be an Alabama porch monkey's uncle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Years ago I married a widow who had a grown-up daughter. My daddy visited us often, fell in love with my stepdaughter and married her. Thusly he became my son-in-law and my stepdaughter became my mother because she was my father's wife. Soon after dis my wife gave birth to a son, which of course was my father's brother in-law and my uncle, for he was the brother of my step-mother. My father's wife also became the mother of a son. He was of course my brother and also my grandchild for he was the son of my daughter. Accordingly, my wife was my grandmother because she was my mother's mother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sleep 'N Eat, I was my wife's husband and grandchild at one and the same time. And lo' and behold, as the husband of a person's grandmother is his grandfather, I Mantan, became my own grandfather.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both start to do the jig.</context>
      <utterance>Mantan, dat sho' is a whopper.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You couldn't hold out any longer, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel a song a comin' on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Porch Monkeys kick in and Mantan sings.</context>
      <utterance>A song a comin' I feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sleep 'N Eat takes over.</context>
      <utterance>I fell right dead in love/wid da sweetest little dove/little LuLu Snow from Tennessee/she made a slave of me/an' from her I'se never free/I'd do anything she'd ask me to...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SLEEP 'N EAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody joins in for the chorus.</context>
      <utterance>De money I did save/to dat yeller gal I gave/for to keep till we was wed/she told me dat nobody'd get away dat cash/I'll take good care of date, she said.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKCANINNINIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's de cutest gal in all dis world I know/If you met her you would say it so/Oh, Lulu, Lulu, ev'ry day I pines for you/no other gal will do/All I've got is yours for life, my little, my little yaller Lou/A week ago dat Lou wid anudder nigger flew/took ma money too, all I had/She broke ma heart in two/when I heard dat she had flew/Do you wonder dat I feel so bad?/She told me not to cry 'case she didn't say good bye/but she'd take care of dat red/and nobody would get de cash away from her/She'd keep her word to me she said.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mantan was being hailed as groundbreaking, barrier breaking, also earth shaking. I looked forward to my awards. Just vindication for all my hard work, all my talent that had been previously overlooked.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEC BALDWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A starlet hands him the envelope.</context>
      <utterance>The winner for Best New Sitcom is... The envelope please...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEC BALDWIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Delacroix jumps out og his chair and starts sobbing. Two ushers have to help him to the stage. He is overcome with emotion. The audience is on their feet with a standing ovation. He hugs Alec Baldwin.</context>
      <utterance>The winner is... Pierre Delacroix for Mantan - The New Millennium Minstrel Show!</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alec Baldwin is shocked. He grabs Delacroix in a bear hug and they both cry like babies.</context>
      <utterance>Alec Baldwin, this is the very first time we've ever met, you don't know this, I'm your biggest fan and I want you to have my Emmy. It's for you, out of the deep bowels of my heart - I don't deserve this. You take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I did that I'd be assured to work forever. Delacroix the grateful Negro.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY HARRELSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The winner for Best Sit-Com is...</utterance>
   <speaker>103.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woody opens the envelope.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY HARRELSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Delacroix jumps out of his seat and sprints. He gets down on the stage and starts to breakdance, even spinning on his head.</context>
      <utterance>...Pierre Delacroix for Mantan. Come on up and get your Golden Globe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That routine would go over like gangbusters. I would be a dancing fool, Hollywood's new favorite Negro, move over Danny, Morgan, Samuel L., move over Whoopi.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had it all planned. To the T.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mantan does the step with ease.</context>
      <utterance>I'm tired of you pickaninnies messing up my choreography. It goes like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The dancers do it once more.</context>
      <utterance>Try it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cheeba walks in. Mantan checks him out.</context>
      <utterance>Better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They quickly file past Cheeba without saying a word. The rehearsal space is just the two.</context>
      <utterance>Let's take a ten minute break.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not drinking the Kool-Aid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim Jones, y'know. I'm not drinking the Kool-Aid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I've got a broken back from carrying you all these years anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's what you been doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn skippy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in this up till ya neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot me, I'm just the piano players.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can walk away. We both can.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You never had any talent.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's easy for you to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cheeba walks out.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so tired of you running that. I always worked hard for you. You think I'm a leech, a kling-on, I quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the star of Mantan, so you do that. Quit, walk away. And don't come crawling back, either.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you call him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what? He left. Not me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure this is a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her, she doesn't resist.</context>
      <utterance>My people love me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a long, deep kiss she gently pulls back.</context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be down front. You better start putting your face on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look beautiful like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you so very much. Show me some love.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The audience applauds.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. My name is Honeycutt and I want to welcome you to a very special evening. It's always great coming back to the World Famous Apollo Theatre.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The curtain goes up and Mantan the Marvelous stands there, arms raised. He starts to do his thing.</context>
      <utterance>As everybody knows if you can make it here on this stage in front of the most discriminating audience in the world you can make it anywhere. Ladies and gentlemen, let's show some real Uptown love for Mantan The Marvelous!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mantan is distraught.</context>
      <utterance>Pull ya self together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Are you a punk? Punking out on me?</context>
      <utterance>What are you? A man or a mouse?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You getting scared because some people don't like what you are doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, DeLa, they tried to lynch my black ass up in dat piece.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've made it from the guttermost to the uppermost. Don't you know you should never let them see you sweat. Y'knowwhatI'msayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now is definitely not the time to bitch up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAVIS SMILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our guest tonight is the extraordinary, talented performer, Mantan. Thanks for coming in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tavis, thank you for having me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAVIS SMILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before we begin, I want to thank you for coming on my show for your first television interview. You could have chosen Mike Wallace, Barbara Walters, Jane Pauley, whatnot but you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm more comfortable around my people.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAVIS SMILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's jump right into it. Your show has sparked a world of controversy, provoked a tone of dialogue. How do you see all of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Tavis, check it out. This is the two-one, the 21st century and it's all about the money. Like my man Mase says, "it's all about the Benjamins."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TAVIS SMILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Money and nothing else?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Money makes the world go round. It ain't no joke being poor. I know whatI'mtalkin''bout. Y'knowwhatI'msayin'? I've lived on the street. I've been homeless. I've learned how to play the game, work the game, be in the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAVIS SMILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it inevitable that the game plays you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No if you go with the flow, Tavis. That's what a lot of Negroes don't understand. Protesting isn't gonna do a damn thing. If people don't like our satire in our number one hit show then don't watch it. Or better yet write your own show. Do it better.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAVIS SMILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you feel that is a simplistic retort?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what a retort is, but it's simple. Mantan - The New Millennium Minstrel Show is UNIVERSAL. It's not just for Negroes in Compton or 125th in Harlem. This is America. Our ancestors helped build this country, we got a right, just like everybody else. I'm not gonna box myself in. This show makes people think, and they're laughing at the same time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAVIS SMILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I admit, that's a very hard thing to do. Quickly let's go to the phones before we pay the bills and hear from our proud sponsors, DA</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Microphone check, one, two. One, two. Yo Tavis, I be lovin' yo show but Mantan you is foul. Why you perpetrating? You a sellout.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's our opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a traitor to the race. A tool for the Caucasoids.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Because I'm successful? Because I don't use "Causcasoids" as an excuse for not fulfilling my dreams?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't hearing all dat noise. You getting played and you don't even know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAVIS SMILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Big Black from Brooklyn, what do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAVIS SMILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a revolutionary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a job?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a full time job, especially when sellouts like you are running around, acting insane.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAVIS SMILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TAVIS SMILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen, there is no need to go there. We can all agree to disagree without making threats.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you and Hambone been hangin' out?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're friends.</context>
      <utterance>You're the one that put us together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That crazy brother of yours doesn't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just playing big brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, is he? You getting jiggy with Mantan?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't go there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunwitty and I feel you've been getting too close to him, getting his mind all messed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't lie to him. If he asks me something, I tell him what I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have to be so damn forthright?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come into the light.</context>
      <utterance>DeLa, you should try it sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Light?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That which has been hidden in darkness is now in the light. This bucket of blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can talk all that mumbo jumbo if you want to but your hands are much bloody. I know where I made my big mistake. I have a general rule, never get involved romantically with somebody crazier than you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss, fall half undressed upon the motel bed.</context>
      <utterance>That's why it will be so much fun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a mistake, but I don't regret it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first and only time. A big mistake. I'm gonna have to ask you not to see Mantan anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Work related or otherwise?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Otherwise. I trust you know the difference. You're an intelligent woman, finished at NYU.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DeLa, kiss my big black ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sloan pulls a 3/4 inch cassette out of her bag and hands it to him.</context>
      <utterance>And that's how you got me in the first place.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to please view this. It may save your Life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't even be mad at me over Sloan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you did is dead wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, is it? Buddy boy, in this business if people don't produce, they get fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sloan is the hardest working person I've ever met.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you a question, if I may. How do you think she got the job in the first place? I don't mean to burst your bubble, Mantan the Marvelous, but Sloan is an opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In fact, go ask Sloan yourself.</context>
      <utterance>Do I have to spell it out for you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get this gig?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worked my black ass off, first as an intern, then worked my way up to this position.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You leave something out?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After my internship expired, Dela was impressed and offered me a position as his assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop playing me Sloan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just ask me what you want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you gonna make me say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say what, Manray?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever sleep with DeLa?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did it one time, only once. It had nothing to do with the job, it was stupid. Everything I've got I've earned.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, c'mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's ancient history. That has nothing to do with you and I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you say. Sloan, you wuz gonna use me up just like you used Dela? Work it to the top. I never imagined people in this biz could flip on you like "IHOP." I'm damn happy DeLa fired ya ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget about me, are you a puppet for DeLa?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't try to change to the subject.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I won't be your puppet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wuz leaving anyway, for good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm doing okay. Been reading about your show, it's all over everywhere. I watched it's all over everywhere. I watched it once. I thought you said there would be no buffoonery.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to attack me too. The show is a hit. Aren't you happy for me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I'm happy for you. You've worked very hard for your success.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I have, very hard. Has Daddy called?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how your Daddy is.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If and when he calls, please don't forget to ask him if he's seen Mantan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORCHID</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't forget. When are you coming up here to see your mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix hangs up the phone. He takes out some change from his pocket and puts a quarter in the hand of his Jolly Nigger Bank.</context>
      <utterance>Soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Delacroix slowly, carefully approaches the bank and picks it off the table.</context>
      <utterance>When I thought or imagined that my favorite Jolly Nigger Bank, an inanimate object, a piece of cold, cast iron, was moving by itself...</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I knew I was getting paranoid. Did I really see what I saw or was I buggin'?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is you a nigga?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The AUDIENCE CHEERS WILDLY. Honeycutt points to an old WHITE LADY, LOUISE, a senior citizen.</context>
      <utterance>Hell yeah, I'm a nigga.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma'am, is you a nigga?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The AUDIENCE loses it as Honeycutt hugs Louise as if she's a grandmother.</context>
      <utterance>Yesiree Bob, you darn tootin' I'm a nigger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a nigger?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo!</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a nigga?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stacy gets a standing ovation.</context>
      <utterance>Honeycutt, I'm a really real niggress.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You. You. Him. Her. We're all God's niggas. Even the lost souls who don't know it are niggas cuz niggas is a beautiful thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunwitty looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Delacroix. What?! I'll be right down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix walks over to Mantan who stands in a corner.</context>
      <utterance>You better talk to him. He won't listen to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mantan, we got a show to tape.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Manray, goddamnit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kook and the Gang, it's Manray. Let's do the taping. You go back to your dressing room, get dressed and blacken up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not playin' myself no mo'.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you sound?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't do it anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manray, I'm very sorry about ya boy Cheeba and Sloan. Believe me, it gave me no joy pulling ya coattail about her, just lookin' out for a brother. I feel you, all this stuff happenin' at once but you can't let if affect your work. You gotta be professional.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm always gonna be that. But I ain't doing no more buck dancing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No costume. No blackface.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="169" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manray leads the way to the stage.</context>
      <utterance>No. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should notify Dunwitty.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I should put my foot dead up in yo' ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't be held responsible.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEYCUTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We apologize for the holdup but without further delay, ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls, let's give it up for Mantan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="170" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bunning drops the curtain. Security rushes onto the stage and grabs Manray.</context>
      <utterance>Drop the curtain. Drop the curtain.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Escort him out the building now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't finished doing my dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The security guards move Manray as Dunitty glares at Delacroix. Honeycutt is all smiles, he's being bumped to the top.</context>
      <utterance>But you are finished. Done. Nigga's like you are a dime a dozen. I'm gonna slide Honeycutt right into ya spot. We won't miss a step. Get him outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DeLa, I'll deal with you next.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="171" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one comes out.</context>
      <utterance>Whaddup?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The doors open and the Mau-Mau's file out.</context>
      <utterance>Whaddup?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You truly are a dancing fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mau-Mau's are dying laughing. Manray tries to walk through them. They block him. Manray attempts to climb over the suburban. He's quickly nabbed, give a good ole Brooklyn Beatdown, then thrown into the rear of the vehicle.</context>
      <utterance>Don't start none, won't be none.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="172" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mau-Mau's laugh.</context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brothers, he asks what did he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUBLE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't know there is nuthin' we can do for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nigga, you will be executed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For singing and dancing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MO BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whole world will be watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Mau-Mau's had come up with a brilliant, sadistic plan to broadcast Mantan's execution LIVE over the internet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JO BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody will find you till it's too late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="173" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Delacroix SCREAMS.</context>
      <utterance>It's no joke getting grilled by the FBI for five houts.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know you're involved in this abduction.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="174" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHEEBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know more than me. Why would I do something like that to my best friend? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI AGENT #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="175" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The X-Force was brought onto the case. When something involves the internet, these are the people IBM, XEROX, the CIA, FBI, even the US Government go to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a race against time. The Dance of Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I come to you with a heavy heart.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, my name is Thomas Dunwitty. I'm the Senior V.P. of the entertainment division here at CNS.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This abduction is a cowardly, vile, sinful and dastardly act and I promise these creeps will be prosecuted to the fullest extent of the law. This is an attack on your American way of life...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNWITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We here at CNS are offering a $100,000 cash award to any information that leads to the safe return home of our dear friend, Mantan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="176" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go, time's wasting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They sent the notice out on an anonymous remailer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's used to mask the origin of an email, also the computer from which it's sent.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There oughta be a law...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet, anyway, it's legal. We will find the source where it's being broadcasted and hosted. We'll get the people that bushwhacked Mantan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before Manray is dead?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="177" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The both of you should go home. We will keep you abreast.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix holds Sloan as he leads her out. She is having difficulty breathing with her asthma.</context>
      <utterance>This is looking like a needle in a haystack. It's hopeless.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The X-Force always gets their man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="178" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whereas Mantan is a TOM...</context>
      <utterance>We are LIVE on the cyberspace.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whereas Mantan is a disgrace...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOTH BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whereas Mantan is a head-scratching, foot-shuffling Negro...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whereas Mantan the dancing fool, you are condemned to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>JO BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>1/16th Black unties Manray.</context>
      <utterance>The Dance of Death.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="179" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manray taps.</context>
      <utterance>Dance nigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOTH BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got anything to say for yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're gonna kill me, kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOTH BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="180" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't Blak.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUBLE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blak you ain't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="181" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MANRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manray is shot in one foot. Then the other.</context>
      <utterance>There is nothing you can do to me. I'm wearing the taps of Bill "Bojangles" Robinson.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manray somehow manages to right himself and starts to dance again. The Mau-Mau's can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>Let's seeya dance now, Mr. Bojangles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="182" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up and put that tape in.</utterance>
   <speaker>133.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She points the gun at his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Delacroix takes the cassette tape off his desk and puts it in the 3/4 inch desk.</context>
      <utterance>Do what I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make me have to use this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix hits the PLAY button.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't think this was in your studies at NYU.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="183" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delacroix can't watch the monitor.</context>
      <utterance>Watch this. This is what you contributed to. Because of you, Manray is dead. Mu brother's dead. It's all because of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for it. BOOM! Sloan screams.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I didn't know anyone would get hurt. I'm sorry, please give me that gun before you hurt yourself. Give me the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You never listened to me.</context>
      <utterance>I told you but you wouldn't listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reluctantly hands it to him.</context>
      <utterance>Give me the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sloan runs out. Delacroix slumps to the floor, WIPES HER FINGERPRINTS off the revolver.</context>
      <utterance>Go, get out of here. Go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="184" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything I did, no matter how great or small, was always extraordinary to her. With Daddy it was a different ball game. He never saw me. Pierre Delacroix.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now it was time to buy the farm, for me to meet my maker. Goodbye cousins, and please tune in next week for the Best of Mantan - The New Millennium Minstrel Show.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks at Mantan.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELACROIX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Delacroix slumps over dead.</context>
      <utterance>For the love of Joseph and Mary, what have I done? My God, what have I done?!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
