<movie id="65" title="Basquiat">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The beam of light shines through a small hole. It falls upon a sleeping, dreaming, delighted face. It belongs to JEAN MICHEL</context>
      <utterance>Everybody wants to get on the Van Gogh boat. There's no trip so horrible that someone won't take it. The idea of the unrecognized genius slaving away in a garret is a deliciously foolish one. We must credit the life of Vincent Van Gogh for really sending this myth into orbit. How many pictures did he sell? One? He couldn't give them away. We are so ashamed of his life that the rest of art history will be retribution for Van Gogh's neglect. No one wants to be part of a generation that ignores another Van Gogh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OUTDOOR, DAYTIME SOUNDS filter in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hearing the voice, Jean frowns at being woken up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Beyond him, a HAND gropes its way out of the box. It tosses a can of YOOHOO chocolate drink.</context>
      <utterance>In this town one is at the mercy of the recognition factor. One's public appearance is absolute.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jean sees the start of a crisp, colorful autumn day. The urban park around him is alive with a typically full range of the good and bad in life. He eases himself out of the oversize box in which he has spent the night. There's something about the way that he stands while waking up that suggests he's almost surprised at his own body, the adultness of his limbs - just a subtle hint of him coming out of a dream. He squints in the sunlight. He has a soft, gentle, Haitian face. His hair is pulled tight to his head. He wears two pairs of blue jeans (one cut like chaps over the other) a paint-covered Wesleyan University T-shirt, and the inside lining of an overcoat. His appearance is unruly, but it's deliberate. He's stylish. He shakes himself off and collects his stuff, which includes: a small book of Pontormo drawings, a can of black spray paint. and a cigar box made into a loudspeaker with pencil holes and masking tape. Jean walks out of the park and looks up past the buildings at the sky:</context>
      <utterance>I consider myself a metaphor of the public. I am a public eye. I am a witness. A HEAD appears from the box. It's Jean's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean thinks about it, eyes still following Gina.</context>
      <utterance>What'll it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ummm. It'll be great. We'll live together in peace. What's her name?  He looks up at the waitress.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gina. What'll it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves and whispers something to Gina. Gina turns and glances over at Jean. Jean pours more syrup and starts writing his name. At the grill, LESHKO, the burly Owner/Cook, has his watchful eye on Jean. He doesn't like what he sees. Jean smears the syrup thinly, so it doesn't erase itself. He draws a picture of Gina, using his fingers and the silverware, rendering her last expression strikingly with a few quick lines. A GAUNT YOUNG MAN saunters up to Jean's table. He's sort of a tall Puerto Rican Alain Delon with sleepy eyes. He is BENNY.</context>
      <utterance>Pancakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey - Willie Mays.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Willie Mays.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nurse!!! Oh!!! Nurse!!! Carrot juice. Tofu burger. Rapido!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't serve that - amigo.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine... A greasy cheeseburger. Fries - and a vodka.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Devil, man. Rene Ricard. Art critic - writes for Artforum. People read him. Tell him who you are..</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who am I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waits on a MAN at a nearby table.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah.. Rene lands at the counter. Jean's gaze is still on Gina.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the special today?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hurries past Jean.</context>
      <utterance>It's your stomach.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slows down, not wanting to.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She looks at her portrait in the syrup... She can't resist smiling.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me. I've never been done in maple syrup. Here's a rag.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her finger in the syrup and licks it off. Benny takes it all in. Leshko is upon them.</context>
      <utterance>Gina?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESHKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean takes Gina's rag and begins cleaning his mess, seemingly compliant.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. Look at you, staring at this girl, making a mess. He waves Jean toward the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brings out a roll of dimes to the tabletop and splits it open. Dimes roll all over the table and stick in the syrupy parts. The manager explodes.</context>
      <utterance>How about those pancakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESHKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK! Goodbye!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pipe down, Lech. Let him order.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESHKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You nuts? Let him order? You on his side? You're not such a good waitress. You get out, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just don't think you're being fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESHKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny gets up to leave very casually.</context>
      <utterance>I need this? Gina quietly removes her apron in disbelief.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Willie Mays.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESHKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. You go with them. Make babies</utterance>
   <speaker>LESHKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>the government has to pay for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They button up their overcoats, about to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Catch you later. Benny leaves. A CHILLY WIND picks up. Jean's mood is suddenly downcast.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The truth is, he feels awful for causing Gina's trouble, but shows it by moping like a child.</context>
      <utterance>What's a job, anyway?  What's wrong with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, don't tell me - you just got fired by your crazy boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess I just got sick of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I walk you home?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs after her.</context>
      <utterance>I think I could do that alone. Gina walks away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, I'm in a band....We're at the Mudd Club on Halloween. I'll put you on the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gina turns and looks back at Jean.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gina notices a dead leaf in his hair and picks it out.</context>
      <utterance>I hate the Mudd Club. He catches up to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been camping? You could use a scrub.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm clean. Smell me. I always smell good. I don't know why, I just do! He leans forward, offering his neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do! You definitely do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just come to the Mudd Club on Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't go there. Too many party girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Party girls? Can I call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Here, this is for you. I made this. He hands her the small speaker.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. She admires the speaker watches him walk off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean takes a cookie. She does likewise. They eat in silence, looking at each other, communicating what they can. Time passes. In between cookies her fingers find and break the stems of the pillow feathers.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, mom. She smiles slightly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>His mother brightens. She drinks the milk. They finish the cookies.</context>
      <utterance>I met the girl I'm gonna marry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATILDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like it here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like it better in Hawaii.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"She loves me. Oh yeah she loves me! She loooooooves me, Oh yeah she loves me!" Bring me some chicken, baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you shut the fuck up? You hear what I'm doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny turns off the piano and lights a roach, angry at Jean's self-centeredness. Jean digs through a pile of garbage. Finally, he finds what he's looking for - a pile of "SAMO baseball cards" - color Xeroxes of his favorite images and words. He pockets them.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah man. I'm jealous. You're always great, Benny.  "Her name is G-I-N-A Gina And she lo-oooves me." I did say chicken!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew I left these somewhere. One of these'll send your kids to college someday.  Here - I made this for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Your dad called again - something about a job. He hands Jean a slip of paper. He notices the number on Jean's pants.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a date already?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>index finger.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean turns on the TV. He notices the roach. He picks up the paper Benny gave him with the message from his father and sets it on fire. He lights the roach with it. He looks up; on television, we see a BUM being interviewed. Jean turns up the volume. The bum's on the ground, looking beat up. Jean picks up a pocket recorder and turns it on:</context>
      <utterance>G'night... See you in court tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean mutes the sound on the TV. He rewinds and proudly plays back the words "Boom, for real." He picks up the phone and dials. He turns on the speakerphone. Jean holds the recorder to the speaker as someone answers the phone. (Jean walks in and out of frame throughout the following.)</context>
      <utterance>The guy just hit me and I was on the ground!!!! Boom, for real.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-Is this the s-s-suicide h-h-hotline?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. My name is Chris. What's yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean Michel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a beautiful name. French?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean opens his notepad and looks down a long list of seemingly random words. He comes to the words (in order) "liquid, hijack," and "Marlboros."</context>
      <utterance>Haitian. I'm going to kill myself. I'm taking pills. Reds, blues, greens.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Wait a minute... talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life doesn't... make... sense. This city's k-killing me. I want my liquid hijack Marlboros!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Life's beautiful. Depression isn't permanent. Don't you believe that?  What is it - did your girlfriend leave you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean spies an electric pencil sharpener and plugs it in.</context>
      <utterance>No! I have a boyfriend. He loves me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see? You have someone to live for.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't. I'm alone. We all are. Especially here. The world's unjust. The respect fools get. The disrespect I get.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it you want? Respect? I have respect for you, just for making this call. One philosopher said "Sadness is a sin against the richness of the world." Think about it. Feel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jams a pencil into the electric sharpener and holds the receiver right next to it, giving the guy an earful:</context>
      <utterance>You don't even know me. I want real respect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fame. My liquid hijack Marlboros and the moon and the cow that jumped over it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>P.A.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean sits in a chair onstage with his band members. Benny plays the organ. The other band members play percussion and guitar. It works. The crowd loves it. The song ends abruptly. We begin to hear James Brown's "Sex Machine." Jean looks out into the crowd and notices Gina. She's looking right back at him from the bar. Pleased to see her face, he says to himself -</context>
      <utterance>One philosopher said "Give me my liquid hijack Marlboros. Life's beautiful. You have someone to live for. What do you want? RKKKK! That's a beautiful name... French?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see him walk offstage into the crowd. They meet.</context>
      <utterance>Boom, for real.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you hated this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC segues into PIL's "Public Image".</context>
      <utterance>I do.  I just said that. I was never here before. I actually like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads her towards the exit. They step out of the club.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LANDLADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and peeks through the security hole. He sees a middle- aged Hispanic woman reaching to unlock the door. He opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Cardinale... Open up for me, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDLADY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She stares at him levelly.</context>
      <utterance>Ohhh, Dios mio!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDLADY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want the rent.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean draws on a piece of paper on the counter next to him. He hands it to the landlady. It's a a little shack with a big head next to it that says "'Here' For Rent." The landlady looks at him like he's crazy. She balls up the drawing and puts it in her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you say so? Damn! She's asleep!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The landlady wags her finger at Gina.</context>
      <utterance>What're you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDLADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gina and Jean look amused as they watch her leave.</context>
      <utterance>Next Monday.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna go get some breakfast?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend of mine offered me a job doing a little work installing a show in a gallery. He's an electrician. I was supposed to be there an hour ago. She looks at the bugspray drawing on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jean kisses her neck as she looks at the drawing. We HOLD on the drawing.</context>
      <utterance>Ohh, that's nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean, could you get me a Phillips screwdriver?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Phillips head. From the toolbox.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean searches through the toolbox. He picks up a screwdriver and reads the handle: "CRAFTSMAN"</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Phillips head,' right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean shakes his head and puts it back. He tries a couple more - they each say "CRAFTSMAN." He puts them back. Finally, he finds one with a different handle. It says "G.S.C.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have any!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible. I've got, like, five of 'em! He comes down off the ladder.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Albert Milo comes into view, tailed closely by Rene Ricard and MARY BOONE - well dressed, petite, intense, 30. Milo, (also about 30), wears casual clothes splattered with paint. Mary Boone is engaged in conversation with Milo. Rene chatters away. Greg climbs back up the ladder. He holds a piece of wire down to Jean. Jean stares at the group while trying to be invisible.</context>
      <utterance>You're holding one in your hand!!!  You've never done this kind of work before, have you?  See, this is a regular screwdriver, and this is a Phillips head. The cross thing... I'll tell you later what all the tools are so you'll know. A GROUP of people arrives.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to make a call, Mary. You don't mind, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rene picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly not. You can use my line.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To Paris. Bernard Picasso -  You know Bernard -</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be my guest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean watches the group talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Y'know, I'm an artist, too.</context>
      <utterance>Jean? Hold this, please.  You'll get there. But it's good to have something to fall back on. That's why I became an electrician. It pays the rent.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sculpt. I'm really just starting to find myself. How old are you? Twenty? You're just like I used to be. I'm forty-one. And I'm glad I haven't gotten any recognition. It gave me time to develop. Jean watches Mary and Milo talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary yells across the room to Jean.</context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you how happy I am with this show.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Milo watches to see what he's going to do.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me - you - what's your name? Would you move those tools there and put them somewhere else? He looks at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Jean Michel Basquiat. Have you heard of me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Should I have?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a painter, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. Huh. Too bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean looks at Milo. Milo looks back at him.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, would you please move those tools?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Jean. Get rid of your cigarette. Concentrate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am... On Gina.  Fuck - I didn't think we were actually gonna do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean shoots. It flies up, up, up - and over the backboard. He runs after the ball, gets it, and dribbles clumsily.</context>
      <utterance>Concentrate on the ball. Shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're shattering all my myths.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your people.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoots and misses again. He throws it to Benny, who does a picture-perfect lay-up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh - you mean black people!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>During the following, Benny performs a series of amazing shots while Jean looks on admiringly.</context>
      <utterance>How long do you think it takes to get really famous?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>For a musician or a painter?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever. Famous. To where you can do your stuff all day without thinking about anything else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoots. Swish.</context>
      <utterance>Ummm... Four years. Six to get rich.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He shoots again. Swish.</context>
      <utterance>First, you have to dress right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, you have to hang out all the time - with famous people - the right people, the right chicks, the right parties. He shoots again. Swish.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Benny tosses Jean the ball. Jean walks off the court.</context>
      <utterance>And you gotta do your work all the time when you're not doing that. The same kinda work, the same style - over and over again, so people recognize it and don't get confused. Then, once you're famous, you have to keep doing it the same way, even after it's boring - unless you want people to really get mad at you - which they will anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean shoots the ball and keeps walking. The ball goes in. He doesn't notice. Benny runs after it.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. I hate this. I'm no good at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Famous people are usually pretty stupid. You're too smart. You'd get bored to death. You don't wanna be like John Henry - fighting the machine. Just do what you do. It's about integrity. Follow your heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's John Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man! Folklore guy - worked on the railroad. Y'know, pounding in spikes and laying down track. Then one day they invented a machine to do it. And he says "Fuck that, I'm a MAN" and he challenges the machine to a race to lay down a mile of track. It takes two days. Neck and neck the whole time. They get right to the end, and he beats it by one spike.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They watch a long stretch limo cruises up across the street.</context>
      <utterance>He drops dead! See? Just do your shit like you do it! Your friends like you, you get laid, everyone walks by, sees your stuff everywhere. It's good. What else do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LIMO DRIVER opens the back door. Andy Warhol and Bruno Bischofberger step out.</context>
      <utterance>Like I said - my liquid hijack Marlboros.  Check it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy Warhol. He's famous and he's not boring.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing? You're doing something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the best painter in the world. I'm gonna give him one of these.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny watches Jean crosses the street. Jean passes the limousine. Inside, the driver (a 24-year old Rasta) takes a hit from a joint and watches Jean.</context>
      <utterance>Don't give him anything, man. Your art's worth a lot. Trade. That's what real artists do with each other. Besides, he'll just use you. He's famous for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The driver's eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>"REDEEMABLE BECAUSE OF HIS YOUTH."</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bruno watches the non-interaction between the two.</context>
      <utterance>Andy stares dead ahead, Sphinxlike.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He taps Jean's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE'D</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's ok.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bruno picks up one of the cards.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, Mr. Bischofberger.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna buy some ignorant art? Ten bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ignorant art?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Like - stupid, ridiculous, crummy art.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohhh. That's new. That sounds good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten bucks apiece.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can give you five. You didn't do very much to these.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't even work on your stuff!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter how much you worked on</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can get ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take two. This one and... that one.  Can I borrow some money, Bruno? Bruno pulls out a hundred dollar bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As WAITER arrives with the tray, Jean pockets the bill.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Do you have change?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves all the cards and walks toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>You made a good deal. Here, you can have these, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Gina.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT - GINA'S APARTMENT - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flowers and groceries are strewn on the counter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basquiat, those are my best clothes!!! What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're beautiful now.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, baby, I painted them for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean wipes his hands off on his thighs and puts his arms around Gina, holding her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to my parents this weekend. What am I going to wear?  How could you do that to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I'll buy you some new ones.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what he's saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What who's saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manzanita....  ... if one day I die, and you read this piece of paper, I want you to know how much I love you. Although I'll never see you again, Gypsy, Gypsy, your hair, your hair, your face, your face' Gina looks up at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>No longer crying, Gina leans her head against Jean. We HEAR a CALL from the window:</context>
      <utterance>'Even though you were never mine And you never will be You have a piece of my heart You have, you have, you have...'  'Gypsy, Gypsy, your hair, your hair, your face, your face.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Willie Mays!!! Willie Mays!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on in!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>See you later. She leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Nice underwear...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. She picks up the mail from under the door and walks into the room. There's a lump on the floor. It's Jean.</context>
      <utterance>Basquiat?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She shakes his arm. No result. She lifts his head, revealing his painted hair. She shakes him harder. His body is totally limp. The whites of his eyes are red; his pupils slowly float up, vanishing.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up! I'm back!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean, what did you do to yourself? She listens to his breath, then to his heart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes him until his eyes unglue. His pupils float into their proper place.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do this to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, Basquiat, you scared the shit out of me. How the fuck could you do that to yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Monday morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not Sunday? I missed you. You shouldn't leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're blaming me? I had to go see my family.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm your family.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean tries to pick himself up from the floor. He gets up stiffly, like Pinnocchio. The long sleep made his limbs wooden.</context>
      <utterance>Basquiat, what did you take?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finds an old joint and lights it up.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing special - just some weed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basquiat, don't lie.  This is smack.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers her the joint.</context>
      <utterance>You want some?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean takes a taste with his finger... He tastes his tongue and makes a face.. He snorts part of his line, anyway, to make sure. He frowns. They continue onwards. Jean still carries the window.</context>
      <utterance>For real?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna carry that around all night?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I'll paint on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROCKETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>You did that, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean hands him twenty dollars. Rockets hands him two dime bags. As if thinking better, he hands the bill back to Jean.</context>
      <utterance>I gave it to Maripol. She let me stay here for awhile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ROCKETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean re-pockets his money. He gestures to Rockets as if to say "fine - it's a deal." He and Benny sit down across the room and split a bag onto the window, as before. This time, it's good. They lean back into it, slumping down into the couch. Nearby, Rene sits on a couch with THREE STREET KIDS - artists (who we've seen at Milo's opening). They sit on their knees looking out a window passing binoculars back and forth. ARTIST 1 looks through the window with a pair of BINOCULARS. He points down towards the street, trying to get Rene's attention.</context>
      <utterance>Do one for me and it's free. How's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIST #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rene lunges towards the window. The stereo BLARES (Curtis Blow's "Survival")</context>
      <utterance>Check this out, Rene.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIST #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chill, man! Be cool! This isn't even my apartment!</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man, you a FINE nigga! You know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIST #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut it out, man! And don't be callin' me that shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artist 2 is still mad at Rene.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my, there goes the neighborhood. Who's house is this, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>(resumes singing)</context>
      <utterance>That's what I like about you straight boys. You're so sensitive!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The name of the game is survival, Survival! Survival! only the strong survive"</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIST #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rene! Come here, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rene weaves across the room. Suddenly, he stops cold. He's staring at Jean's painting. He doesn't move.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go pee.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did this?  Who did this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIST #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I told you, this isn't my apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIST #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who did that. That's Jean Michel's. He's right here, man... He turns to look for Jean.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIST #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny looks around ineffectually and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck, man, where'd he go? Where's Jean?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fucking amazing. Motherfucker's got to put a crown on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naaaa. Poor thing has a little dick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIST #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just look at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIST #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rene grabs binoculars.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa - check it out. It's him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARTIST #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the same guy who did this painting.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the binoculars to Artist 3 and runs towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>I know that. Don't let him get away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Huffing and puffing, he catches up.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, wait up!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard of Albert Milo. I made that niggah. I'm Rene Ricard. Didn't you read "Not About Albert Milo?" I know who to hype. Baby, I'm gonna make you a star.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you put me in the ring with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can put you in the ring with him. Even book the dates.  But those big boys know how to fight. They</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>could make you look real sissy.  I was looking at that painting upstairs. It's the first time a picture made me embarrassed to own anything.  So what's your real name? 'Samo?'</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>Jean Michel Basquiat.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds famous already.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rene smiles. Jean finishes pounding the last piece into the wall. CAMERA pulls back to reveal several of Jean's paintings - found objects with paint on them.</context>
      <utterance>Oh child... You got no respect. Didn't anyone teach you how to mount paintings?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A crowd begins to gather around the work.</context>
      <utterance>This is a very important season in New York. One's public appearance is absolute.  Oh!!! Louise!!! I'd like you to meet Jean Michel Basquiat -  SAMO. This is Henry Geldzahler.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohh... SAMO. I've heard a lot about you. I love your graffiti.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was a kid then.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much are these?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You or the museum?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's five thousand dollars.  He's from the Metropolitan Museum of Art so suck my pussy, you star.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look fucking beautiful, beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNINA NOSEI, a sophisticated, well-groomed woman appears at Jean's side. She takes in his paintings. As Jean, Rene, and Annina talk, Gina is left out.</context>
      <utterance>Well thanks!</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Jean Michel, whose work I told you about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rene hasn't stopped talking about your paintings. Haven't I seen you in my gallery?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't been by lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't have the subway fare. My Medicare ran out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean sees Bruno and turns his back to her. Bruno looks at the paintings with a smile... He gives a cheerful nod to Annina.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Annina's impressed that Jean knows Bruno.</context>
      <utterance>You're doing well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd love to see some more of your work... Where's your studio?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You name it, I paint there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't want to get mugged on a Bowery street corner. Maybe I could find a place for you to work. Take my card.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He produces a pint bottle in a paper sack.</context>
      <utterance>You want a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks off.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks.  But I'd like one of these paintings.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kidding? That's Annina Nosei. Jean's been in her gallery a thousand times.  You slut. How do you know Bruno Bischofberger?  He's only the biggest art dealer in Europe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had lunch with him once.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which island of Hawaii do you want our house to be on? Maui? Kaui? Molokai?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hadn't thought about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oahu, Lanai, Niihau, Kahoolawee -</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean can't sleep. He stares at the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Staten Island would be ok. Beat. Silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gina's asleep.</context>
      <utterance>Do you wanna marry me? Beat. No reply.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean moves to add something. She stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Kind of a family portrait.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses.</context>
      <utterance>Think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... babies.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean babies with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a KNOCK at the door.</context>
      <utterance>You're your own baby. Jean paints out the image.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annina Nosei.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean jumps up and locks himself in the bathroom. Gina goes to the door, unlocks the chain, and looks out.</context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Oh. Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Jean Michel here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Closed in the bathroom, Jean smiles while eavesdropping.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annina starts noticing all the work around her. Gina hands her a stack of drawings.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here to see some work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are great.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much for these five?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annina contains her excitement.</context>
      <utterance>You should talk to him about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Jean in the bathroom looking at himself in the mirror with a bird's nest on his head.</context>
      <utterance>Um... Do Rene and Jean have a contract together?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm interested in showing Jean's work.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really think you should talk to him about this. Jean pops out of the bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unnoticed, Gina starts for the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>How about right now? She opens the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be ready in a minute!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DRIVER obliges. The back of the cab is loaded with all his belongings. Boxes piled with junk. Bags of new painting supplies. Benny emerges from his building and jumps into the cab.</context>
      <utterance>Honk the horn again, will you please?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're late.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cab pulls out. Jean lights a joint. and smokes it furiously. He doesn't pass it to Benny.</context>
      <utterance>One-fourteen Prince.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the rush, John Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't John Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny holds out his hand for the joint.</context>
      <utterance>What's your fuckin' problem, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't really have any problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. What do you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your fuckin' problem? You get a girlfriend and a little attention and then start acting all uppity with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Uppity?' Like as in 'uppity nigger?' He snaps his finger for the joint back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not how I meant it.  For all you know, you might just be a flash in the pan! You can never tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cab stops for a red light. Benny gets out. He doesn't say a word. Jean doesn't look at him. The cab sails off.</context>
      <utterance>Hey fuck you! I deserve this shit. You're just jealous 'cause it ain't happening to you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to find the switch.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT - BASEMENT, ANNINA'S - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annina flips on a light.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean looks around him. He's in a large, empty cement-floored room lit by fluorescent lights.</context>
      <utterance>Here it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In kangaroo court I want to be</context>
      <utterance>3rd night I called him 'boy' He sed "don't call me 'boy'" "Well Then don't call me 'Boss'" That Was the end for us and I've Been seeing him for 2 1/2 years.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean warms the plate 'til the coke crackles, and then "chases the dragon," sucking the smoke through a straw. He offers it to Rene, who refuses. He lights and hands Rene the joint. Rene takes a hit. Jean takes it back. Jean starts to work again. The PUPPY runs around, chasing after him, getting in his way, running across the paintings. Jean laughs, playing tag. The puppy gets a hold of Jean's sleeve. It unravels about ten feet. While Jean's playing, Rene spots a painting with the words "Famous Negro Athletes."</context>
      <utterance>Able to say I never kept a Slave. But he tricked me in To Tying him up and busting his Face. He'll jump up at my Trial Yelling 'He wupped me gud.'</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without hearing him, Jean walks towards the painting and with a swipe, paints out what Rene is pointing to.</context>
      <utterance>Oh man! That's one looks famous already.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The phone RINGS... Jean ignores it. Rene gets it -</context>
      <utterance>You are a willful boy. How'm I s'posed to write about you if you keep changing everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huhh... Band practice?  It's Benny. He wants to know why you're not at band practice...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rene hold the phone against his leg.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck...  I forgot about that. He sets his brush down.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck band practice... If you're gonna be a painter you're gonna have to break a few hearts - you don't wanna be like Tony Bennett..</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tony Bennett... What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Singing on stage and painting in your spare</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know Tony Bennett painted.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean picks up the phone... All he hears is a DIAL TONE.</context>
      <utterance>My point exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So keep painting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Boss.  If you're so smart, why are you here with me in this basement?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're news. I want the scoop. I write it down. When I speak, no one believes me. But when I write it down, people know it's true.  There's never been a black painter in art history that's been considered really important, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So shut up and keep painting..</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That one's for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks... I'll take it tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean continues painting. Rene slumps down onto the floor, happy - a parasite content to have a host, impressed with Jean's limitless energy. Rene closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I can't. After the show.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey - it's the big A.M..</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean continues to work, never wanting to appear impressed by anyone. He walks on top of the paintings.</context>
      <utterance>Rene's been telling me about your work. Milo takes his time looking at the paintings.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this finished yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's your show?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not sure. How was yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't decided yet.  Rene, you wanna come over to the studio tomorrow. I wanna make a painting of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rene shrugs to Jean. He prepares to leave.</context>
      <utterance>How about now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert and Rene begin to ascend the stairs. Jean continues painting. The dog leaves with Rene and Albert.</context>
      <utterance>See you at your opening. Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom and Cynthia Kruger.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context>We SEE that Jean continues to paint, looking down.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she speaks, Jean squirms. He grabs a banana from a fruit bowl. Without peeling it, he takes a big bite. And another. And another. Everyone looks uncomfortable. Annina starts showing them the paintings.</context>
      <utterance>This is Jean Michel Basquiat.  You've seen the SAMO graffiti everywhere. That's his. This is the true voice of the gutter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYNTHIA KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've seen the graffiti. I work on Wall Street. And I've heard wonderful things about the paintings. Everybody's talking about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at them, eating the banana.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's a very good example of his recent work that's not spoken for yet.  He's got to work in a basement. He's got so much energy that if he worked in a place with a window, he'd jump right through it. Most of these are reserved already. After this week, this work will not be available.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>KID #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, man, you're a damn lucky nigger selling this shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Krugers hem and haw in front of the painting next to Jean.</context>
      <utterance>Not bad. Yeah, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYNTHIA KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fascinated by his choice of crossing out words that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, well, they are more meaningful in their absence, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean paints the words "Rene 5:11" back into a painting. They ignore the kid..</context>
      <utterance>What does it mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYNTHIA KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, we see LEGS coming down the stairs. It's Gina. Everyone looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>I like this one, but that green...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'want me to make it a nice shit brown?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gina hadn't expected to find herself in the middle of this scene.</context>
      <utterance>Beg pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gina nods to the group.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. This is Gina. Annina nods to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYNTHIA KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gina tries to connect with Jean. He's cold.</context>
      <utterance>They're something like Dubuffet's... That... childlike quality.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYNTHIA KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't make up my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like this one. If it were just another color..</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get a fucking decorator. If you buy one, you'll have to change your whole lives - maybe even sell your kids!  These paintings aren't even done yet!!! He sets his brush down. As he leaves -</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we'll take the green one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take three big Macs, two chocolate shakes, two orders of fries, and an apple pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A line begins forming behind Jean.</context>
      <utterance>You want three Big Macs, two chocolate shakes, two orders of fries, and an apple pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it .I'll take six, no, seven chocolate shakes, an order of fries, a Big Mac, and two apple pies.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The people in line are beginning to get impatient.</context>
      <utterance>You only want one Big Mac?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... And make it three apple pies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BIG PINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I ever thank you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers her a Big Mac.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to squeeze your titties.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG PINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna Mac?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG PINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'd like the scarf.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a Mac.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG PINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't eat junk food.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. I didn't know. I'll take you to the best restaurant in town.  You'll miss a great meal and I'll keep the scarf, anyway. What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG PINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a fast mover.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A man sleeping on the ground with a beehive of paper bags on his head and three overcoats sticks out into the sidewalk. Jean leaves the McDonald's bag near his head as he walks down the street with the girl.</context>
      <utterance>No name? That's ok. I'll just call you Big Pink.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gina holds the scarf up and looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>A present I picked up for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she holds it up he puts it around her neck and kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look like an angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE UP PAINTING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We read the words:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean, man!!! Let's make a record!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You finally did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's so fulla shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #3</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jean walks up to Andy Warhol.</context>
      <utterance>How much is he getting for these?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, man, thanks for coming. I'd like to paint your jacket.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Your show looks great. Quite a turnout. You look great. You kids. You drink red wine with fish. You can do anything! Make paintings in the basement of your gallery? First time I've heard of that! They are approached by Mary Boone, a short woman in high heels and an Armani suit).</context>
      <utterance>My jacket? Gee, great...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I met her already.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the background, we see Annina watching.</context>
      <utterance>You should be pleased. It's a great show...I'm having a dinner later at Mr. Chow's for Albert. You should come.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annina walks over to Jean with a COUPLE.</context>
      <utterance>You'll like it. Everyone'll be there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean, your parents are here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Dad. Hi Nora.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rene appears out of the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNINA NOSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be very proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am!</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does it feel to have a genius in the family?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean notices Benny across the room. He slows down and waves. Jean sees Gina across the room wearing the scarf. Just beyond her, he sees Big Pink approaching. There must be ten people between them.</context>
      <utterance>It feels... good!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves towards her. Suddenly, directly in front of him are the Krugers.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We love our painting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which painting?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The green one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYNTHIA KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got a couch to match.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM KRUGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's only kidding!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean brushes past him.</context>
      <utterance>Willie Mays. A Toast.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny is left standing next to Andy holding the bottle. Jean manages to advance a few more feet through the crowd, then runs smack into Rockets, his drug dealer.</context>
      <utterance>Not now, ok?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCKETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nearby, Benny sees this meeting and walks off, disgusted, thinking this is why Jean gave him the brush off.</context>
      <utterance>Jean Michel, my man. Nice party. Should we step into my office?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean looks off and sees Big Pink fingering the scarf, saying something to Gina. Gina slaps her in the face. Jean tries to get around the dealer. Gina turns to leave. She catches Jean's eye. She walks out.</context>
      <utterance>That's alright. I'm cool now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCKETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dealer palms something to Jean.</context>
      <utterance>A gift! I was just trying to give you a gift!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean steps away from Rockets, but is trapped in the crowd. Rockets looks after him with disappointment. Rene arrives with, Andy, Bruno, and a PHOTOGRAPHER.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PHOTOGRAPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's not enough room. Rene accidentally gets pushed out of frame. Rene fumes. Albert Milo arrives with his parents (JACK AND ESTHER MILO). They are a nice Jewish couple in their 70's.</context>
      <utterance>Of the painters, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert crowds in. The photographer SNAPS a picture and the FLASH blinds everyone momentarily.</context>
      <utterance>He said 'of the painters!' Hey - Albert! Get in the picture!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean pulls out a joint and lights it as if it were a cigarette. He offers it to Albert, who takes a hit.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jean, I'd like you to meet my wife....and my parents. Mom, Dad, this is Jean Michel Basquiat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do that.  Hello, Jean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, John... Are your parents here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers the joint to Albert's mother.</context>
      <utterance>Well.  My dad's here with his wife. My mom couldn't make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to do a show with you.  I'm especially interested in that one. I'd like to buy it for myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around the room for Rene, but doesn't see him. Bruno remains smiling, waiting for an answer.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't gonna sell this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't have put it in the show. This is the one I absolutely have to have. I really love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean wants out. He feels compromised.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, ok..</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think I could borrow your limousine? I'll get it back to you in an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's OK. Just have him bring you to dinner at Mr. Chow's later. We'll be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean makes his way through the crowd, as we see images of the crowd and fragments of paintings. As he nears the door, he feels his arm pulled.</context>
      <utterance>Bye, Jean.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fucking little whore! You sold my painting! I'm gonna tell you something, brother - when you're climbing up the ladder of success, don't kick out the rungs! Believe that shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make you another one.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out a scrap of paper and starts writing.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rene shushes him... He hisses loudly, like a cat.</context>
      <utterance>Rene -</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean pauses. He turns around and surveys the room once more.</context>
      <utterance>SHHHHHH. Later.  "What is it about art, anyway......"</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone's eyes are shut.</context>
      <utterance>A blink. Silence. We see the crowd in SLOW MOTION.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.; CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Artist.</context>
      <utterance>... that we give it so much importance? Artists are respected by the poor because what they do is an honest way to get out of the slum using one's sheer self as the medium. The money earned is proof pure and simple of the value of that individual...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really... admire you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you check out my studio some time?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The limo pulls over.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. I'd be glad to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quickly, Jean gets out of the limo. He leaves the door open. The DRIVER watches as Jean talks to two DRUG DEALERS. Jean jumps back into the limo. The driver pulls away. In the rearview mirror, he sees Jean separate a bag from a bundle of ten. He rips it open and snorts directly from it. He lays his head back and takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>Here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They call me Steve, but I prefer Shenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you, Shenge. Want a job?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>MAITRE'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From behind the Maitre'd on the mezzanine we see Bruno waving to Jean. In the dining room on the lower level sit Annina and Rene. Nearby, at another, smaller table, are seated DAVID MCDERMOTT and PETER MCGOUGH, two artists dressed in Victorian attire. Annina beckons him. Rene looks away from him and talks to a WAITER. Jean waves to</context>
      <utterance>Good evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seated at a large table are Andy, Bruno, Albert Milo, his wife and parents, Henry Geldzahler, MELINA PORTOS (a young heiress) and FRANCESCO and ALBA CLEMENTE and Mary Boone. Dinner's already served. At the large table, everyone watches as Milo makes a portrait of Francesco in a beautiful leatherbound book. It belongs to Mr. Chow, who is nearby at the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Annina and continues towards Bruno's table.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to Mr. Chow to set a chair for Jean between Mary Boone and himself.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Jean.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Jean is seated, Andy and Jack Milo resume conversation -</context>
      <utterance>Jean, everyone loved your show.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nixon lives in Saddle River, New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saddle River's in New Jersey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saddle River, New York!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's in New Jersey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's in New Jersey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's in New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE UP: Jean smiles at Andy's diplomacy. Albert finishes drawing his portrait: it's Francesco with his arm around a headless torso.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I didn't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesco begins to draw.</context>
      <utterance>You finish it. He pushes the book across the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear your show was sold out already. There's a very important collector who's interested in some of your works.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annina watches from the other table as Jean talks to Mary. Francesco finishes his drawing. Albert takes the book and passes it to Jean.</context>
      <utterance>Bring him over sometime. I have some other stuff to show him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jean takes it. Mr. Chow watches his book change hands. Jean takes a bowl of moo-shoo pork in front of him and dumps it onto the book. Then he uses a piece of pork to draw a head. Suddenly, there's a shrill, familiar voice.</context>
      <utterance>Go on, take it..</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like a glass of your best champagne, please?  This is an enormously important season in New York, and to make a false step could have severe repercussions for years. We are no longer collecting art, we're buying individuals.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shut up, Rene.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over everyone and helps himself to some spears of asparagus.</context>
      <utterance>Everything's over your head, Andy. Even Mr. Chow's menu.  Thanks for not inviting me</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm starving. You can't buy advertising like this. This is the most glamorous dinner you'll have here this fall. How about some of that imitation crab?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. CHOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not paying for the drawing with crab. It's a present to my friends. It's my birthday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rips the page from the book.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't he great? Thanks, Jean.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Everyone's face drops. Mr. Chow grabs his book. He motions to a couple WAITERS -</context>
      <utterance>He owes me one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. CHOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're too much, Rene. Get this guy out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiters grab Rene's arms.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't eaten yet!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hands off me, you faggots! I'm going. I'm going...I've kept Diana Vreeland waiting too long, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow... That was a nice drawing, too, Jean. Maybe you should do another one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. CHOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spontaneously, David McDermott climbs onto the tabletop downstairs and sings "Paris Je T'aime." As he belts it out in a theatrical falsetto, he glides over glasses and plates, executing a leap to another table in mid- song. The restaurant staff and OTHER DINNER GUESTS watch, agape.</context>
      <utterance>Some other time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S, CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jean looks out the window, yawns and rubs his eyes. He now sports dreadlocks bundled into groups of spikes sticking out of his head. He wears a wrinkled Wesleyan College T-shirt, paint- splattered jeans, and no shoes; just out of bed, it would seem. An INTERVIEWER - a balding Brit with all the humor of a bank clerk - tries to buddy up with Jean on camera.</context>
      <utterance>... had over fifty articles written about you, switched galleries - how many times? - DJ'd in the hottest clubs -</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jean and the interviewer face each other in front of one of Jean's paintings. Jean stares at the interviewer, incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>... one of the youngest artists ever to be included in the Whitney Biennial, also produced a rap record. It's said you're quite the ladies man - even dated Madonna for a couple months!!!  All at the ripe old age of 24. One might ask: is there anything left for Jean Michel Basquiat to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it that gets you out of bed in the morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate this. Turn that off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SUPER: "GREAT JONES STREET, 1985"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A CAMERA CREW waits in the room. Jean returns.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He signals to the crew that he's beginning.</context>
      <utterance>We're running a little late.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He points to some scribbled words on the canvas.</context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Can you... decipher this for us?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Decipher?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. What do they... stand for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're just words.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I understand - but where do you take them from?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where? Do you ask Miles where he got that note from? Where do you take your words from?  Everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leeches. A long list of leeches.  It looks good like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. And 'Parasites.'  You seem to be a Primal Expressionist.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean like an ape?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A primate?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you said that.  You've got a lot of references from Leonardo da Vinci, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's a "Leonardo's Greatest Hits" painting. You like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but as a black painter -</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I use a lot of colors - not only black.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not black.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not what?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not black.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BUZZER sounds. He signals for Steve not to answer the door.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm Haitian-Puerto Rican.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes... Let's talk about that.... your roots... Your father is from Haiti, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmmm. Interesting. And when you grew up were there any primitives hanging in your home?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't hang them at home, y'know - just in the streets..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see..  And... How do you respond to being called - hmmm...  - yes, "the pickaninny of the art world."</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said that?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, that's from Time Magazine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he said I was the Eddie Murphy of the art world. He said the Eddie Murphy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean walks off camera like he just received a punch in the stomach. The filming of the interview becomes increasingly erratic.</context>
      <utterance>Is it true that your mother resides in a mental institution?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me... just... open something up here. You come from a nice, middle class, respectable home. Your father is an accountant. Why did you at one time live in a cardboard box in Tompkins Square? Jean walks back into frame.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or rather, do you think you're being exploited or are you yourself exploiting the white image of the black artist from the ghetto?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are those the only two possibilities?  You wanna French fry?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK. One last thing. Is there any anger in you? Any anger in your work?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should there be?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it. What are you angry about? Jean drifts off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Counterman selects a miniscule plastic spoon of caviar and begins to put it into a tiny glass jar.</context>
      <utterance>Can I have some caviar, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reluctantly the Counterman gives him a taste with a look like "what's a person who looks like you doing buying caviar?" Jean tastes the caviar and hands him back the spoon.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to taste it, first.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the best quality you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's the best one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take the whole tin.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's three thousand dollars!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands two one hundred dollar bills for the other items to the counterman, who checks them carefully.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it.  Andy, gimme three thousand dollars.  Just the caviar - I'll get the rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You check everyone's bills or just mine?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish they'd quit writing this shit about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good. At least they're interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody's paying top dollar for scraps of paper, refrigerator doors - anything with a SAMO tag on it.  The other day, I just wanted a pack of cigarettes, so I did a drawing and sold it for two bucks. A week later this gallery calls me up: "Somebody's offering us the drawing. Should we buy it for five thousand?"</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow... Stop giving them away.  I got an invitation to model for Comme de Garcons... You wanna do it with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah - I'd do that... You could teach me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean points to Andy's ankles - they have plastic flea collars on them.</context>
      <utterance>Gee. I don't need to. You're a natural. You should sign up with my modeling agent.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>My dog, Archie... I woke up with flea bites... Creepy. I ran out and bought flea collars. They work really well.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's leave this town and go someplace.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some island.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go to the Carnegie Museum. They have the world's most famous sculptures all in these giant plaster replicas. It's really great. It's in Pittsburg.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch..</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That girl looks just like my old girlfriend Gina.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you still love her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I really blew it. I still think about her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean shakes his head `no,' sorry that he didn't.</context>
      <utterance>Well, have you asked her to come back?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAITRE'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Basquiat - what a pleasure to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A huge table with NINE WHITE EXECUTIVES. WAITERS clear their lunch settings. As they spot Jean and Gina entering, they gawk and snicker.</context>
      <utterance>Hey George, what's up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are you really friends with Andy? He seems like such a weirdo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not. He's out of town and he calls me every day. What's weird about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think he's using you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why does everybody say that? He's the only person I know who doesn't need to use me. George reappears.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to see the wine list?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George disappears again.</context>
      <utterance>Chateau Latour '64, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. Are you ready? I start Columbia next fall. Of course, there's like, a year of pre-med stuff, but - whatever. I'm really excited.  And: Rene gave me a job as his secretary. His poems are getting published.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean's eyebrows go up.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty much the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Congratulations. I hate that asshole.  Thanks for coming. I guess I just wanted to find out how you're -</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is amazing. What year is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George hurries over.</context>
      <utterance>George?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Mr. Basquiat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See that table over there? I'd like to pay their bill. Long silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gina looks at Jean, confused.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, just put their bill on my tab.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves off towards the executives. George whispers to the HEAD EXECUTIVE, and nods towards Jean. The executives spread the words amongst themselves. They're horrified.</context>
      <utterance>Very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, I think about you a lot. I'm really sorry about everything. You have to believe me. I'm serious. I wish, y'know, that we were -</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A YOUNG EXECUTIVE, obviously the loser, takes a deep breath and heads towards them.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it, Jean - they're picking straws.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Executive reaches to shake Jean's hand. Jean puts a hundred dollar bill in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I wish you niggahs could get it togeth- ahhhhhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean turns back to Gina. The Executive leaves them. George smiles.</context>
      <utterance>The tip.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to be sorry. There's no one to blame. Jean, you're a real artist. I thought I was one. You made me realize I wasn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gina balks. Rather than face a disappointment -</context>
      <utterance>What's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go to the bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's always how you would do it. This is my version.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. It's your version. You should come over to the studio sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, so you could humiliate me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I wanted to make a painting of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with the wigs?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to send them to my friends for Christmas presents.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean makes a grimace. He walks up to the painting Frank's peeing on.</context>
      <utterance>You think those are good presents? Who wants an old wig?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Piss painting?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to make a few more of these. Frank's been drinking this Mexican beer. It makes a good green.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you're not peeing on them yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking down at the painting -</context>
      <utterance>I don't like beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you ever want me to shit on 'em, just ask. You could finger paint.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was my favorite part!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy watches as Jean lights a joint and continues working on his penguin.</context>
      <utterance>We can do better. It needed more white.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean, you make me feel worthless. You're so famous. Andy paints an Amoco logo next to the penguin.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even have any friends anymore besides you. And everyone says "Warhol?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's just using you."</context>
      <utterance>That death-warmed over person on drugs?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee. You shouldn't take it so seriously, Jean. That's why you can't stop taking drugs. You always think people don't like you. Everyone likes you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People are only interested in you because you're famous, not because they know a fuckin' thing about your work. Jean paints out part of Andy's logo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was poor, everybody doubted I could make it. When I got rich, everyone said, `yeah, but he'll never keep it up.' Now everyone says `he's killing himself.' So I clean up, and then they say `Look. His art's dead.' I don't take drugs, anyway. I'm healthy now. Jean obliterates Andy's logo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you say so. You sleep until 5:00 p.m. You call at four in the morning. You never show up anywhere on time - if you show up. You're painting out everything I do! Andy paints back in part of the horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's better. Jean adds some letters on top of Andy's logo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean Michel obliterates the rest of the logo with some white. Andy steps back and squints as he examines Jean's work.</context>
      <utterance>I can't even see what's good anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be a pity because you're a real painter. Frank arrives.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presents them with a yellow poster of Jean and Andy facing each other with boxing gloves.</context>
      <utterance>Here's the poster for the show.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elke.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>505-0236.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A BRUNETTE walks up -</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monica.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is really great. What a nice place. Jean is taken with Christine.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you met Christine?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's thrown off his rhythm.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TOXIC (seen with Rene at loft party earlier) spots Jean and steps in.</context>
      <utterance>Would you sign one of those for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOXIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YO! Jean, this is Ramellzee.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMMELLZEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo... You know why Rammellzee's here, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOXIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMMELLZEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here for an interrogation. You've been called a graffiti artist and I wanna know why. All I see are scribble scrabble abstractions!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boom.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMMELLZEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boom? As in ordnance? Are your letters</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMMELLZEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean likes Rammellzee enough to be patient... Toxic grins and rolls his eyes to Jean. Jean watches Christine as they go on.</context>
      <utterance>armed? What is the prime directive of graffiti culture? Do you know, black man?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOXIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, I was up on him years ago on the IRT.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMMELLZEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're selling and ending the culture. Not one bit of information. Only to get the money and growl with the power, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOXIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's ignorant.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't ignorant - that's just stupid.  Can I get you a bowl of gumbo? Rammellzee yells after him -</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMMELLZEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nearby are two WOMEN.</context>
      <utterance>This interrogation is not over! Jean escorts Christine to the kitchen. Bruno and Andy stand in the crowd.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Albert Milo? Ugh! He's just a pressmonger. That's all these people do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rene walks over to Jean.</context>
      <utterance>His early work? He's only twenty-six!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Rene.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks again for not inviting me. I'm only here on business. Rene heads back out into the party.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RENE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're asking me? Nigga, please. After the way you treated me? This is the first time I've heard from either of you in months! I had to crash this party! You treated me like a suede biscuit. Rene don't play that! I can't get him off drugs! I don't even talk to him any more!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a suede biscuit?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here... Pull over.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean exits.</context>
      <utterance>The limo pulls over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SET IT ON FIRE"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean arrives behind them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind your own fuckin' business.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KID#3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead. That's what I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ain't dead yet. He's gonna kill himself. That's why all those art fags in Soho are paying more every time we bring one of these in.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The panel is almost pried free without a scratch.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid SAMO... Hardly any of this shit left.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean shoves his way in front with a magic marker and adds a couple words; now it reads:</context>
      <utterance>This one's damn nice. I say we hang onto it if he's almost dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids are outraged, thinking Jean's ruined their find. They jump on him. They beat the shit out of him. They're done. Jean lies curled up on the ground, trying to talk.</context>
      <utterance>There you go. Now it's worth more.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm SAMO... I'm SAMO...</utterance>
   <speaker>KID #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kid 1 whacks him in the back once more for good measure.</context>
      <utterance>He says he's SAMO.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paint it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHENGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Maybe just his arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shenge picks up the phone, which has been RINGING for some time.</context>
      <utterance>Put some Cerulean Blue there. Jean points to the lower corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHENGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Andy again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHENGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- In this corner?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shenge changes the brush and dips it in the can.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah..</utterance>
   <speaker>SHENGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to put it here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shenge shrugs and starts to spread the blue. Jean looks at his work.</context>
      <utterance>Use your fucking instinct.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A woman's shout can be heard through the open window. Shenge looks out.</context>
      <utterance>Don't try to make art. Just paint like a housepainter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHENGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Maria Portos. What should we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you try letting her in, Steve - I mean Shenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHENGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up. She won't buy anything if she sees me working on it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARIA, a raven-haired, sharp-featured beauty in a Chanel suit jacket, blue jeans, and pearls walks into the room. She's with ELLEN - younger - a millionaire fake hippie from Texas. Maria carries a bag with clogs in it - a present for Jean. She takes them out.</context>
      <utterance>Wanna bet? If you show too much respect for people with money, they don't have respect for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean doesn't get up from the floor.</context>
      <utterance>These reminded me of you, the clogs. I found them in Amsterdam.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Basquiat points at the painting.</context>
      <utterance>You remember Ellen?  What are you working on?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean raises his hand and pumps five fingers three times in the air.</context>
      <utterance>How much is something like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen makes a snotty face.</context>
      <utterance>Fifteen. Reasonable.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shenge gives Jean a stupefied look.</context>
      <utterance>It's unfinished.  How 'bout some blue in the corner?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHENGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blue? Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shenge is embarrassed by Jean's remark in the company of the two women.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you today?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He points. Unsure, Shenge picks up the brush and paints one of the corners. Maria browses through a stack of paintings leaning against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Don't look at me like that. It hurts my feelings.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love these.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's better.  You can buy direct from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's not even worth a response. Jean looks around, numb.</context>
      <utterance>Look at these - silkscreens? What're you? Andy Warhol Junior? It's like - not even handmade anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean Michel... Crawling from the wreckage?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a dealer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a bunch of them, don't you? Albert Milo walks in from another room.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Jean!  It'll never fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be ok.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better take a look. Why's your door so small? The ceilings are sixteen feet and your door's the size of a mouse hole!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You doing anything right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naa..</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See ya in an hour.  So what do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bruno spoke to me already. We could talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK. I'll be at your studio Thursday three o'clock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is painted on a backdrop from the Kabuki theater in Japan. I painted it after Joseph Beuys died. A rebirth painting. I felt like he could've painted it, or maybe someone else was painting it instead of me. The Chinese calligraphers used to change their name mid-career so they could start over as someone else..</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you ever get sick of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whole thing - painting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's one of the few times I feel good. I used to have to go to work and cook every</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>day. That I got sick of.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the shit they write?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're asking me this because of the 'lapdog' remark. I read that. The person that wrote that has the compassion of a housefly. That's your enemy, not your audience. Your audience hasn't even been born yet. It's a lie that art is popular. The only thing popular about it is that it's written about in newspapers. I'm surprised when anybody comes to my openings. There're about ten people on the planet who know anything about painting, and Andy's one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't felt like talking to him since that thing came out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milo's daughter STELLA (12) calls out from over the balcony.</context>
      <utterance>As long as I've known Andy, he's never asked me for anything except to speak to you about getting off drugs. He's painted my picture, we've eaten dinner in God knows how many places together. But he doesn't care about me. He cares about you. You're the only person he cares about. He's your friend. Fuck that article. You want a toasted bagel with cream cheese?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stella comes downstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. I'll be right up. Albert leaves. Jean looks at some paintings.</utterance>
   <speaker>STELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>STELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen you before. I like your paintings a lot. Your hair was different.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws her.</context>
      <utterance>Stand still.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>STELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks to the door, leaving the drawing on the floor. Albert returns.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Jean?</utterance>
   <speaker>STELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert opens the door to the stairwell looking for Jean. He hears the sound of URINATING. He leans over the stairwell. He sees Jean Michel, taking a piss on the landing. He shuts the door quietly.</context>
      <utterance>He just left.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bruno pulls across the street because of the traffic. Jean drops one of the ducks in the street and walks off.</context>
      <utterance>You haven't heard? Andy's dead. The light changes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Gina?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean recognizes Benny's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He returns a moment later with a large SECURITY GUARD.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, come here! Please. Just for a second. Open the door. The janitor gets nervous. He leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard unlocks the door, hoping to settle Jean down.</context>
      <utterance>Open up! Open up!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother's inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back tomorrow. Visiting hours are over.  Don't cause any trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard gently ushers Jean out through the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not here to visit... I wanna take her home.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He locks the door and walks off with the janitor.</context>
      <utterance>Don't cause any trouble.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean stretches, kicking life back into his limbs.</context>
      <utterance>Willie Mays... Nice to see you. Benny looks at Jean's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Benny looks at him guiltily.</context>
      <utterance>How's Gina? You guys getting along?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it was a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, let's get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drugs??!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Medicine, man! Like health food. I'm taking care of my health!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean approaches and dumps some more stuff onto the counter. He's chewing something.</context>
      <utterance>You starting a hospital?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabouli spills onto Jean's shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Just ring it up. I don't need a bag.  Try this tabouli - it's great...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's definitely time to get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASQUIAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hawaii? Fuck Hawaii. Let's go to Ireland. We'll stop in every bar and have a drink.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
