<movie id="66" title="Batman">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nearby, STREET TYPES are beginning to snicker. DAD surveys them nervously, gestures toward the subway map.</context>
      <utterance>We're going the wrong way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO COPS lean on their patrol car outside an all-night souvlaki stand, sipping coffee and chatting with a HOOKER. The HOOKER smiles at JIMMY. JIMMY smiles back. MOM yanks him off down the street and glowers at DAD. DAD (cont.) We'll never get a cab here. Let's cut over to Seventh.</context>
      <utterance>Put that away. We'll look like tourists.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventh is</utterance>
   <speaker>DERELICT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister. How about it. One dollar?  One</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's beat it, man. I don't like being up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, scared of heights?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno, man. After what happened to Johnny Gobs --</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Johnny Gobs got ripped and walked off a roof, all right? No big loss.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't what I heard. That ain't what I heard at all.  I heard the bat got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme a break, will you? Shut up...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five stories, straight down. There was</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was no blood, man.  My brother says... all the bad things you done... they come back and</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now</context>
      <utterance>No wonder you're such a chickenshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want this money or</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACK NAPIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK NAPIER, 32, is right-hand man and chief enforcer to Boss Carl Grissom. His features are delicate, almost feminine, and he takes a vain, gangsterish pride in his appearance. He is also absolutely merciless. He trains a cold eye on DENT's televised image as ALICIA HUNT -- 26, beautiful, Carl Grissom's kept woman -- glides over in her negligee and snuggles up.</context>
      <utterance>Decent people shouldn't live here. They'd be much happier someplace else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything new?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALICIA finds JACK's necktie draped over a nearby chair. She begins knotting it playfully about his neck.</context>
      <utterance>The usual gas. If this clown could lay a hand on Grissom... I would've had to kill him by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Grissom knew about</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at himself before turning to the door.</context>
      <utterance>You look just fine, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I didn't ask.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEDIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That one there won't say a word. The other one's raving his head off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ECKHARDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the mouth of the alley, we find ALEXANDER KNOX -- thirty, hyperactive, a crime reporter for the Gotham</context>
      <utterance>Variety, huh? The spice of life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He was scared to come off the roof.</context>
      <utterance>They found him hugging a drainpipe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, but tell me: is this another you-know-what? 'Cause if so, it's the third one this week.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. What's "what"?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOX spots ECKHARDT and the MEDIC, waves cheerily, and saunters down the alley. ECKHARDT curses under his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Good answer. I'm gonna put you in for a commendation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ECKHARDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Christ, it's Knox.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, gents. This anything I should know about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ECKHARDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this exact moment two uniformed PATROLMEN drag a brain- fried NICK past the mouth of the alley.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing out of the routine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOX's tone is jokey, but only half-jokey. ECKHARDT snorts in disgust and turns away. KNOX shouts after him: KNOX (cont.) If so, is he on the police payroll? If so, what's he pulling down after taxes?</context>
      <utterance>Come on. One question. Is there a six-foot bat in Gotham City?</utterance>
   <speaker>ECKHARDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had another bat sighting.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ECKHARDT bristles. There's no love lost between these two.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure that was vitally important. Listen: things are heating up. Someone is leaking information to Harvey Dent.</utterance>
   <speaker>ECKHARDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm doing the best I can. If it's a problem --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eckhardt... our problems are your problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>ECKHARDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK reaches out and grabs ECKHARDT by the lapels of his topcoat -- an Italian job, obviously expensive. He rubs the material between his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>I'll work on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very nice, Lieutenant. But a little ostentatious on a cop's salary, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ECKHARDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I answer to Grissom, punk. Not to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ECKHARDT laughs in his face.</context>
      <utterance>You're a smart boy, Eckhardt. You should be thinking about the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>ECKHARDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ambition.  Forget it, Jack. You'll never run that organization.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ECKHARDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK lashes out and BACKHANDS ECKHARDT across the face. The fat cop, stunned, turns bright red and CHARGES JACK. JACK claps a hand on ECKHARDT's face and shoves him back full-force. The cop sprawls on his ass in the doorway of an all-night Cuban-Chinese restaurant. By now PATRONS are staring out of the restaurant windows. ECKHARDT is livid. His hand goes instinctively to his gun.</context>
      <utterance>You're a psycho, friend. You're an A-one crazy boy and Grissom knows it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK pulls an automatic from his pocket and tosses it in ECKHARDT's lap. He looks down and laughs, daring ECKHARDT to pick it up -- just as the two enormous GOONS from the stretch limo appear behind him for reinforcement. ECKHARDT wipes blood from his mouth as JACK -- an A-one crazy-boy grin on his face -- reaches down for the gun. JACK (cont.) It's all right, boys. Lt. Eckhardt here is a good cop. A real good cop. (pause; smiling) Inexpensive.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Use mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>COLLEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Knox, you got a visitor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm real busy, Clark. Be a pal and dust him, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Curiosity piqued, KNOX moves toward his desk... and stops in his tracks. Propped up on the desk are a PAIR OF LEGS. The legs -- exceptionally nice ones -- are attached to a WOMAN leaning back in KNOX's swivel chair, taking a nap, her face obscured by a big outrageous hat.</context>
      <utterance>This one you might want to dust yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hat tips back. VICKI VALE, her face framed by a shock of bright red hair, flashes a dazzling smile. She pulls KNOX over for a quick smooch and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>... Vicki Vale.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you know it was me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey -- I would know any randomly selected</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, a girl could get hurt doing this.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She unbuttons her sleeve, rolls it back to show KNOX a long fresh scar on the inside of her arm. He winces -- then points to the scar and adds, slyly:</context>
      <utterance>I do get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got any more of those?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing I'm at liberty to reveal here. What's new and hot in Gotham City?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too good, Vick. We got a six- foot bat that swoops out of the night and preys on evildoers.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evildoers, huh? Big or small?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Small so far. I mean -- they don't allow bats in boardrooms, do they.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speaking of which... I hear the notorious Bruce Wayne is throwing a big do for the Harvey Dent campaign.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOX suddenly freezes. It's just occurred to him that VICKI may have a purpose in all this. KNOX (cont.) Wa-a-it. Vicki. You're not saying -- She reaches back into her camera bag and hands over an INVITATION. KNOX is all but panting with excitement. KNOX (cont.) Aw, Vicki. Vicki! (apprehensively) Got a date? She flutters her great big eyelashes, shakes her head no. KNOX grabs her face and plants a kiss on her forehead, nearly knocking her out of the swivel chair. KNOX (cont.) Vicki, baby, I love you, I've always loved you. Will you marry me?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Hottest ticket in town. Every law'n'order freak in the city's gonna be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm starving. Will you at least buy me a hamburger?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but please -- be gentle. Overwhelmed with glee, he offers her his arm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can always pop him. -- Or pop someone close to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This suggestion draws CHUCKLES from several members of the crowd. GRISSOM is unamused.</context>
      <utterance>Let's feed him to the bat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRISSOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going after our front companies. Specifically Ace Chemical. Which would tie us in with Councilman Kane, Senator Miller... on up the line.  We have to clean out our files before the subpoena comes down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we go? The usual fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRISSOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking break-in. Trash the office, remove the relevant documents...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Industrial espionage."</utterance>
   <speaker>GRISSOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK has just turned up the third ace off the top of the deck. His hand freezes in midair.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. And Jack --  I'd like you to handle this operation personally.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you need</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ALFRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd say about thirty feet, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, if you cut your bathroom in half, you'd have my apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALFRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which bathroom is that, air?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOX takes a drink and ALFRED moves on. A moment later, VICKI detaches herself from her little circle of admirers and hooks up with KNOX. KNOX (cont.) Man, I feel like Robin Leach. You actually</context>
      <utterance>The small one.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knox, for the ninth time, and you can quote me --</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Dent. What's</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOX goes goggle-eyed as they enter the LIBRARY.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Likes to kill?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Women find him magnetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet they like him for his big charity balls.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That, and the sweet smell of two hundred million bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, A VOICE FROM BEHIND intrudes.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you know me. The more they've got, the less they're worth.  This guy must be the most worthless man in America.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOX turns. We get our first good look at the smiling face of BRUCE WAYNE: 32, tall, athletic, impeccably mannered... and</context>
      <utterance>You disappoint me. Why not the world?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I quite like it.</context>
      <utterance>Bruce Wayne. -- I've read your work.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Give me a grant.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOX blinks at VICKI. BRUCE already seems to know who she is. KNOX shrugs and forges bravely ahead:</context>
      <utterance>I might consider it if you introduce me to Miss Vale.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"This is Miss Vale." --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's intriguing. They haven't been</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some people think she has</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As far as I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly ALFRED, the butler, appears in the doorway behind them. He clears his throat. BRUCE turns.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Then with any luck we'll run into each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALFRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir. Commissioner Gordon was compelled to leave --</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know the rich are different, but that guy is</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yum, yum.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good Lord, it we could put our hands on Jack Napier... Why wasn't I told about this? Who's in charge of the --</utterance>
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lt. Eckhardt, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOOD I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like the file cabinets.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOD II</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK shakes his head. His boys are antsy, ready to mutiny. By now it's depressingly obvious: they've been set up. Then, as if they needed any proof -- a SIREN blares outside.</context>
      <utterance>I don't get it. If this place is cleaned out already, what do we need five men?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You men are dismissed. We'll take over from here.  Any man who opens fire on Jack Napier... will answer to me. ECKHARDT tries to slink off. GORDON grabs him roughly. GORDON  You. Stick around.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in charge here. Not Carl Grissom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't tell me some</context>
      <utterance>Commissioner. Do us both a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bruce Wayne? Date? He called you up and asked you for a date?...</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. "Mister One-Nighter."  Because that's the average length of his relationships with women.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The current record is almost two weeks. That cover girl -- what's her name? You must've shot her, Vicki --</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her about the peanuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peanuts?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Peanuts. Which is how he goes through</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plain or roasted?  Alex, I'm very flattered that you've gone out and done all this research.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- What'd you tell him?</context>
      <utterance>Why?  Aw, come on, Vicki, I'm a reporter. I'm curious. I do this for a living.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOX fumes. VICKI shakes her head and laughs. She takes KNOX's face in her hands, plants a kiss on his forehead. VICKI (cont.) You're awfully sweet to be concerned, but it's</context>
      <utterance>I told him yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miranda, I'm busy. Go be productive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALFRED has just appeared from belowdecks with a tray of drinks for BRUCE and VICKI. VICKI watches as BRUCE reaches for his glass. His forearm looks like a thin layer of skin over braided telephone cables.</context>
      <utterance>Too much work. I'm not really the physical type. -- Thank you, Alfred.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, slides the drink over toward her, gestures for her to try a sip. VICKI (cont.) ... Ginger ale?</context>
      <utterance>You do a very convincing imitation.  Mm, this is tasty. What's yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two drinks and I start swinging from the rooftops.  Tell me, Vicki. There's something I'm very curious about. What took you down to Corto Maltese?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I guess I needed a change.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone wanted you.</context>
      <utterance>You were one of the most successful magazine photographers in the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever been to Corto Maltese?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not since the shooting started.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We went there once when I was little. I played on the beach. And at nights -- they had a band -- I danced with my father on the hotel patio.  That was Corto Maltese. When the war broke out I had to go back. And I promised myself that this time... I wouldn't look away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The conversation is getting rather intense -- at both ends. VICKI seems to have hit some weird chord within BRUCE.</context>
      <utterance>... Terror.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's terror everywhere. Some types are just more --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VICKI is momentarily stuck for a reply. In some way she can't quite grasp, he seems to be challenging her.</context>
      <utterance>Insulation?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bruce, really, when I say these things I don't mean to criticize</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm happy to talk about something else. I don't want to be depressing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Bruce, I have to ask. Are you like this with the other women you know? -- Because I just can't seem to get a handle on this conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vicki, if I say anything cryptic, or... ambiguous, I think you should put the most flattering possible interpretation on it. Because even if it doesn't sound that way... that's how I'll mean it. Bingo. The guy's a chessplayer, but on the other hand he's also rather touchingly, almost childishly,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God. You</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... We could try that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me. "Sugar Bumps."</utterance>
   <speaker>GRISSOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I heard you'd been --</context>
      <utterance>Jack?  Thank God. I can't believe it's you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK gestures him over to the empty chair. GRISSOM doesn't move until he sees the GUN pointed at his belly. JACK (cont.)</context>
      <utterance>Is that what you "heard"?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've died once already. It wasn't so bad. -- In fact I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... The rent? Paid?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANG BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why don't we hear this from Grissom?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACKETEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How come you're wearing that stupid</context>
      <utterance>I got something I'd like to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTELLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what happens if we say no?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody wants a war, Carmine. If we can't do business, we shake hands and part friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTELLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE JOKER extends a hand. ROTELLI reaches out to shake it. He doesn't see the JOY BUZZER concealed in the JOKER's palm. 40,000 VOLTS course through ROTELLI's body. He drops back into his seat a blackened husk, SMOKE pouring out from his sleeves and shirt collar. The CRIMELORDS recoil in horror. Before they can make a move, a squad of ARMED THUGS burst into the room. JOKER (cont.) Looks like Carmine got a little hot under the collar.</context>
      <utterance>That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRIMELORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... You're</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said I'd call you the minute I got free. And I did. -- And here we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops in his tracks, takes her by the shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Hm hmm. Lunch. Not even dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All this, of course, is delivered with devastating sincerity. VICKI finds herself totally disarmed.</context>
      <utterance>Vicki. Do you want the whole truth? All coyness aside?  I wish I had more time to give you. Every day I don't see you, I miss you.  Now. Are you going to waste this lovely afternoon being all mad at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm a sucker. You sound so much like someone I used to...  Bruce? I know this is silly, but -- you're not</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Looks like a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for her. Involuntarily, she steps back. He sees her reaction and his face goes slack -- frightened, pleading. This time she lets him embrace her... but her face is full of bewilderment and doubt.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God... are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God... I've seen this picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess so. Pulitzer Prize, 1963.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT ON THE BOY'S contorted face, staring out in shock and disbelief, his features recognizable across all the years -- permanently, indelibly traumatized.</context>
      <utterance>His face. Allie, look at his face.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like this -- what do you suppose this could drive a guy to?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He walks out on his own party. Half an hour later, the Caped Crusader turns up in full bat-drag.  Sees an execution, freaks out in an alleyway. No place to</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VICKI wilts under the challenge. She holds her silence for a second, then changes the subject.</context>
      <utterance>Oh? Why is that, Vicki?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's best friends with Jim Gordon and Harvey Dent. They would</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your little chum is out of his mind.  Next time you call him up and he can't go</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm. How'd you find it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE ON PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The JOKER nods in satisfaction and resumes his place on the floor. Like a happy kindergartener, with paste pot and scissors, he's CLIPPING PHOTOS from a magazine -- horrible scenes of death, destruction, panic, mutilation. One by one, he's PASTING these shots on the blowup of Gotham city -- all along sidewalk level -- creating a massive photomontage of ANARCHY IN THE STREETS. We've seen these photos before. VICKI VALE took them... in Corto Maltese.</context>
      <utterance>Called her agent.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not to me. I need a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Vicki. Everyone</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PATSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind DAVE, on the bluescreen: a HUGE STATUE, covered in canvas -- not unlike New York's Statue of Liberty.</context>
      <utterance>The fashion world was stunned today by the sudden deaths of top models Kelly Brinkley and Christie Emberg. Cause of death has been attributed to a violent allergic reaction, although authorities have not yet ruled out the possibility of drug use. Dave?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A TECHNICIAN'S HAND passes a slip of paper into frame. DAVE (cont.) This bulletin just in. Nine more mysterious deaths at a beauty parlor in -- Off to the left, PATSY begins to LAUGH. DAVE FROWNS. DAVE (cont.) Patsy! This is hardly the -- (his eyes widen)</context>
      <utterance>In Gotham, plans continue for the city's 300th birthday celebration. The four-day event will conclude with the unveiling, in Gotham Harbor, of the newly restored 'Lady Gotham'...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANCHORWOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- The makeover counter at Bloomingdale's. SECURITY GUARDS rush to the scene as THREE MATRONLY CUSTOMERS go into simultaneous smiling fits. - An ANCHORMAN with a BIG UGLY ZIT on his nose:</context>
      <utterance>... sixteen new deaths, with no clues as to the Joker's identity or demands. The list at potentially lethal products now includes: perfume -- mascara -- cold cream --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- A SUBWAY CAR jammed with STRAPHANGERS. HUGE PATCHES OF SWEAT under every arm. The doors slide open; ONCOMING PASSENGERS RECOIL VISIBLY at the unendurable stench. - The original ANCHORWOMAN, whose look is now 100% natural. Her hair is frizzy. Her eyebrows are missing altogether. Every wrinkle on her face is plainly visible.</context>
      <utterance>Men's cologne toothpaste mouthwash -- underarm deodorant --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORWOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- A LARGE DRUGSTORE. CASHIERS sit idly by the registers. The store is utterly devoid of customers.</context>
      <utterance>Hair spray -- eyebrow pencil -- moisturizing cream --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get dressed. We're going out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but your table is ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAR V. VALE,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>PUT THIS ON</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops in front of an Ingres odalisque. Stands back a pace or two to get a better look. Then pulls out a STRAIGHT RAZOR and cuts a LONG DIAGONAL GASH in the canvas. He ambles up the ramp, stepping over collapsed patrons, pausing at every fourth or fifth painting. Monet water lilies, a Degas ballerina -- all get the razor treatment. Behind him his CRONIES work their way up the ramp, HEAVING BLACK PAINT on every canvas the JOKER has missed. He cocks an eyebrow at Edvard Munch's "THE SCREAM." JOKER (cont.) I kinda like this one. Leave it.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, boys, let's broaden our minds.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sets a couple of CANDLESTICKS on the table and reaches for his lighter. A LONG JET OF FLAME shoots out, Jerry Lewis-style, as he lights the candles. JOKER (cont.) You're Vicki Vale. I guess you know who</context>
      <utterance>Unfortunate, but I think we can work around it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A visual record, yes. A before-and- after kind of thing.  This could</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The JOKER turns. ALICIA steps out of a ROOFTOP ELEVATOR and moves toward them, drugged, wraithlike. She's still wearing the porcelain DOLL'S MASK we saw earlier.</context>
      <utterance>Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, it's my</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said I could look at the pictures before you -- before you --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(rolling his eyes at</context>
      <utterance>Shucks, honey, I forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in trouble</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALICIA sits down numbly and begins to undo the mask. JOKER (cont.) You see, Miss Vale, Alicia's beautiful. One in a million. A work of</context>
      <utterance>Alicia! Come here, have a seat. Show Miss Vale why you wear the mask.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode>cont.</mode>
      <context>As BATMAN sprints down the alley, a COMPUTER DISPLAY on the dashboard registers his unique voiceprint. A tinny, synthesized VOICE repeats the command:</context>
      <utterance>Ignition!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The engines are revving up even as BATMAN vaults into the cockpit alongside VICKI. Guns in hand, the JOKER'S GOONS Are stumbling out of the Fluegelheim, hacking, coughing, blinded by smoke. They DIVE FOR THEIR LIVES as the BATMOBILE comes barrelling out of the alley at ninety miles an hour. THE JOKER emerges just as the BATMOBILE careens off.</context>
      <utterance>Ignition.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called them.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A POLICE CAR whizzes past the BATMOBILE. TIRES SKID. The COP CAR does a quick 180 and sets out in hot pursuit of the BATMOBILE. BATMAN FLOORS THE ACCELERATOR in response.</context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't we --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about her? What about the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't we --</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(as she scrambles out)</context>
      <utterance>Too many people. Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a series or CLANGS, CHROME-STEEL PLATES slide into place -- across the cockpit, over the tires -- leaving the BATMOBILE an inert, impenetrable BLOCK OF BLACK METAL. BATMAN and VICKI sprint through the CONSTRUCTION SITE, vaulting over mounds of loose dirt and concrete rubble.</context>
      <utterance>Shields.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The VAN does a discreet U-turn and rumbles off sedately down the street.</context>
      <utterance>... I don't know. We'd better get out of here.  Westbound on 36th. DO YOU COPY??</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take 'em! I want his</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does some quick mental calculations. A beat. Then the CAR reappears -- backing up -- blocking their only avenue of escape. BATMAN unfurls a rope, HEAVES A BATARANG UPWARD, and grabs VICKI roughly about the waist.</context>
      <utterance>... A hundred and eight?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GOON III</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GOON III screws up his courage and crouches beside the body. He examines THE BATMAN'S TUNIC... and RIPS IT OPEN.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON IV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... What</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON II</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. You seen him before?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON III</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's got some kind of I.D.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON IV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea. Let's check his wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GOON II draws his automatic. And at that very instant... A</context>
      <utterance>We'll worry about it later. Plug him.  In the head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GOON I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn their attention to BRUCE. A GLOVED HAND snakes out with lightning speed -- GRABBING GOON I BY THE COATTAIL and pulling him DIRECTLY INTO THE LINE OF FIRE. GOON II bas pulled the trigger twice before he knows what's happened. In one fluid motion BRUCE HEAVES GOON I's lifeless body THROUGH THE AIR, knocking GOON II backward over a garbage can. GOON II falls and CRACKS HIS HEAD on the nearest wall. GOON III takes a rabbit punch to the throat. He's on the way down when he catches a STEEL-TOED BOOT in the gut. Four seconds after all this began, BRUCE is alone in the alleyway with GOON IV. GOON IV has his gun pointed right at BRUCE, but he's shaking too much to pull the trigger. BRUCE smiles. GOON IV SCREAMS and RUNS FOR HIS LIFE. Through all this, VICKI's telephoto camera has been poised on the ledge, snapping away. BRUCE looks up at the FLASH GUN and shakes his head. He bends to retrieve his cowl.</context>
      <utterance>Who cares? Wax that freak.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- I think you might consider thanking</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to distract them. I wasn't trying to get a picture of</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't let you have it. THE BATMAN is amused. He smiles menacingly. VICKI  I know you can break my neck and take it. But the Joker's on that same roll. I --</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Joker is a murderer. And</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, here's a compromise. I'll develop the photos. You keep the Jokers and I'll keep the rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I know you won't keep them all?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out, holds her gently by the shoulders. His voice is deep and soothing. True, VICKI is a little dizzy from all that's happened, but she's undeniably drawn to him. Still cautious, though. She reaches into her bag and hands over a roll of film. The</context>
      <utterance>Because I'll take you with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ignition.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stunned COPS gaze into the Batmobile's cockpit.</context>
      <utterance>Ignition.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's somebody</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite a while. I took the scenic route.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's just hit a BUTTON on the dashboard.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I've certainly enjoyed it. What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Garage door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better. It's not on the market yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't protect your head, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I wear a target on my</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VICKI'S HEAD jerks up abruptly. In the dim recesses overhead, BATS ARE SCREAMING. She shivers. BATMAN (cont.) They don't come down here. They're afraid of the lights.</context>
      <utterance>Stumbled across it when I was a boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like bats. Not that kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to a HIGH-SPEED PHOTO PROCESSING MACHINE -- the kind they have at Fotomat, only better -- and loads the roll. VICKI wanders over to the edge of a DEEP BLACK PIT. She kicks a pebble over. Long seconds pass; no sound. She looks up. Suspended over the bottomless pit are a pair of GYMNAST'S RINGS. This guy is</context>
      <utterance>They used to terrify me. But I forced myself to keep coming back, and --  -- I guess I became the thing I feared the most. I'll do your photos now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have sponsors.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The computers?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm running a check on the tainted products. There</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anywhere?</context>
      <utterance>Wait. You can just tap into any corporate database you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up a hand to VICKI: stand back. Then he checks out the pictures -- SMILING as he shuffles through the prints.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no. I let the FBI do that. Then I tap into the FBI. -- Your photos are ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You could have killed the Joker.</context>
      <utterance>You could've killed him, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to save</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns in seeming incomprehension. And shows her a SMILE... the same crooked, curious, childlike smile she saw on BRUCE's face that morning when she caught him singing. BATMAN (cont.) Maybe we've had enough for one night. I'll take you home. Almost in a trance now, she lets him lead her to the BATMOBILE. As she takes her seat he reaches into his utility belt for another KNOCKOUT CAPSULE. BATMAN (cont.) Do you want to do it this time? VICKI doesn't move. She looks at the capsule in her hand as he walks over to the driver's side and gets in. BATMAN (cont.) Don't be afraid. I'm here. She takes one last look at the familiar SMILE beneath the mask... then breaks the capsule and BREATHES DEEP. FLAME ERUPTS from the rear of the Batmobile as the after- burners kick in and BATMAN screeches off. A FIERY RED GLOW fills the screen, BURNING OUT THE IMAGE as we</context>
      <utterance>Are you talking to me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about the way things went between us. I'd very much like to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Bruce... I don't think... that would be possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you'd reconsider.  I didn't stand you up today. The museum was closed when I got there.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, uh...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The FBI. You know who's got the FBI computer contract? Wayne Technologies.  The guy's bats all right. He's</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOX slaps his forehead in frustration, sprawls back in his chair.</context>
      <utterance>He's not crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vicki. We got a wealthy millionaire here... who dresses up like a bat. He goes out at night and swings around -- in his cape -- on a</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, when he does you know my number.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STOCK MARKET CRASHES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Product Scare Drops Dow to 1100 Biggest One-Day Decline in History</utterance>
   <speaker>FINANCIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRUCE automatically claps a hand over the mouthpiece. His face goes slack as he hangs up -- with VICKI'S TINNY VOICE still squeaking on the other end of the line.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Bruce.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... We deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADVISER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>is to cut a deal with a</context>
      <utterance>Harvey, please. I mean --  If your first official act as D.A.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADVISER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COMMISSIONER GORDON reaches into his vest pocket for a cigar. He clips the end off, lights it, takes a long drag... and STARES GLUMLY at the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Harvey, the police are working round the clock, the feds are coming in. This thing could break any minute now.  Tell him, Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut the deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER II</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOX, who has recently taken up smoking, responds with a grunt. SUDDEN HUBBUB from the ONLOOKERS as a wave of VIDEO NOISE wipes half the screen away.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Knox, cheer up. It ain't the Batman but it's pretty choice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"While this administration remains vehemently opposed to terrorism in any form, we are prepared to negotiate any reasonable demands which will guarantee the safety of the populace."</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten million dollars. Ten million dollars.  Ten mi-- YOU CHEAPSKATES! I've just wiped out the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alexander Knox. Gotham</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOX starts cockily off down the driveway -- then STOPS. Behind him, the iron gates are SLIDING OPEN.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I wanted to talk to Batman. Pass that on to Mr. Wayne, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's how it is, chum. She tells me everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simple. You know the score. One column -- and I can bring all this tumbling down. I can take you off the streets once and for all.  I want you to hang up the suit. And I want you to stay away from Vicki.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that. Not while the Joker's still out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRUCE turns away, evading his gaze. KNOX fumbles in his jacket for a cigarette. KNOX (cont.) See, I don't know how it happened -- she's a smart girl and you are an extraordinarily screwed-up guy -- but she's in love with you.</context>
      <utterance>Then stay away from Vicki. That's all I want, man. I just want your word.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something I don't understand. If you've got the story, why haven't you printed it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Because she'd never speak to me again. KNOX is a bundle of nerves now. No longer cocky, he stubs out his newly-lit cigarette -- and begins to PLEAD OPENLY. KNOX (cont.) Come on, Bruce. Be straight. What have you got to offer? You gonna marry her? Batman and Mrs. Batman? (laughing bitterly) Gimme a break, huh? Who's gonna be Best Rodent? BRUCE sinks into a chair, exhales sharply. He can't even put up an argument. The two of them sit there, not looking at each other, as ALFRED appears in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Because I --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, a drink. "Civilized." Man-to- man, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Knox. -- I'll have one too.</context>
      <utterance>Alfred, bring something for Mr.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wouldn't matter much.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand it. You can do so much good for people.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're one man. You can't save everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VICKI is sick of watching BRUCE torment himself. She stands up, almost crying now, and ACCUSES HIM DIRECTLY:</context>
      <utterance>What it I could save a handful? -- What if I could save one?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bruce, at the rate you're going, you can't even save yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VICKI is totally drained. She heads for the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes... I don't know if there's enough of me left to save.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God. I've got to have some coffee or</utterance>
   <speaker>DELIVERY BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Package tor Miss Vale.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DELIVERY BOY sets the package down and wanders off, tipless, muttering something about "cheap shits." After a moment's interval, BRUCE opens the door and bends to pick up the mysterious package. Another brown-paper parcel... ADDRESSED IN CRAYON.</context>
      <utterance>Set it down by the door. On the left-hand side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As VICKI watches, he goes into the living-room and finds his ALLIGATOR ATTACHE CASE. He opens the case, removes a LAPTOP COMPUTER and a handful of business papers... then lifts out a false bottom to reveal his UTILITY BELT.</context>
      <utterance>Very thoughtful. Don't touch it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Bruce. Don't tell me you carry it</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... They're</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As VICKI struggles to keep the conversation alive, BRUCE rushes into the living room and crouches beside his LAPTOP COMPUTER. He plugs it in, flips open the screen, punches up a telecommunications program. A moment later VICKI enters from the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>... Where are you calling from?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, she hung up. What are --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finding out where she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you do that if she's already off the line?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had an automatic tracer on this number ever since he tracked you to the museum.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HE FREEZES. He's heard something in the hallway outside.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on. I have to leave a message.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VICKI nods yes. BRUCE -- all business now that he's in his element -- disappears into VICKI's bedroom. She peeks around the corner. He reemerges carrying a BLACK NYLON STOCKING, which he stuffs into his pocket. VICKI is full of question, but he shushes her before she can speak. BRUCE (cont.) I've got to take him out now. He stoops down beside the THUGS and pulls the elevator key off the key ring -- which he then tosses to VICKI. BRUCE (cont.) Pick an apartment and</context>
      <utterance>There's a garage in this building?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, boss, something's up. The elevator's working.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll be sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. How does he</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like your boyfriend. He's kinda</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gosh, I could kill you, but then you'd miss my</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Batman! Don't you even recognize your old pal Jack? After all...  You</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRUCE steps out just as ALFRED enters with a breakfast tray. DICK makes a puzzled face. What the hell is going on here?</context>
      <utterance>My name is Bruce Wayne. You're welcome to stay here as long as you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll be ready when you do. Remember what happened at the apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Bruce, what do you suggest?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suggest a nice big</utterance>
   <speaker>DENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I can't let you leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't keep me here, man. That's kidnapping.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(turning to go)</context>
      <utterance>If I let you leave, you'll do the same thing again. You'll go after the Joker... and you'll wind up dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right, Alfred. Everything's under control.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALFRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALFRED relaxes, musters his dignity, and turns to go.</context>
      <utterance>... Very good, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALFRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Upstairs. He's quite docile.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRUCE takes a moment to survey the Batcave as ALFRED looks on tremulously. BRUCE (cont.) He's a long way ahead of where I was at his age. (taking ALFRED's shoulders) I want you to treat him just as if he were me. Promise.</context>
      <utterance>I know that feeling. It won't last.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALFRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes lock for a long moment. ALFRED is unable to speak. Finally BRUCE turns and starts slowly up the long circular stairway which leads from the Batcave to Wayne Manor. On the third step he pauses: BRUCE (cont.) Alfred? -- Thank you. As BRUCE disappears up the stairs, a shaken ALFRED steadies himself against a lab table, fighting back tears.</context>
      <utterance>He'll be taken care of financially. Beyond that... you know what to do. Don't let all this go to waste.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yeah. Little winded. DID YOU</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it. Relax.  ... He's</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well now, you're not exactly the picture of mental health, are you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Murderer...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SPOTLIGHT cuts through the night sky. The JOKER hears his helicopter approaching in the distance. BRUCE reaches down furtively. Finds the timer on his utility belt. FLICKS A SWITCH... and the countdown begins. The JOKER pulls a straight razor from his pocket and opens it gingerly. JOKER (cont.) I have to do it now, Bruce, but it won't even hurt. Now relax. The bat's in his belfry, all's right with the world... He has the razor almost up to BRUCE's throat when BRUCE reaches out and GRABS HIS LAPELS in a death grip. The JOKER is momentarily amused by this seeming display of affection. JOKER (cont.) Why,</context>
      <utterance>Bruce, we're both murderers. Think how many people you've killed by letting me live.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohhhh... you don't mean that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't, but... I</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment he stares deeply into her eyes. Then he pulls her over, takes her in a tight embrace.</context>
      <utterance>I guess you did it, didn't you. You saved everyone.  Almost.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how to explain this so it makes sense... but</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
