<movie id="69" title="Being Human">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector takes a few steps. The Boy follows.</context>
      <utterance>No... stay here... stay!</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector walks on again, taking big, angry father strides. The Boy stubbornly tags along at a safe distance. Hector walks on for some time before turning on him.</context>
      <utterance>No... go back... go away...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is real anger in his voice. The Boy wisely retreats to the cave. As Hector turns to continue his walk alone he see Deirdre looking at him accusingly from the entrance. She holds out her arms ready to comfort the Boy rejected by his father. Hector is in the classic, timeless, no-win situation and he knows it. With a sigh of frustration he heads for the beach.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone! Stay here... Stay!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up the hill!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, down onto the other beach. The little ones can't take the hill. Neither can I.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up the hill! They're down there already. I saw them!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs off down the slope. Hector has no choice but to follow her, herding the children in front of him. Deirdre runs on, heading for the lower slope and the cover of some trees. Then from these same trees she sees the figures of the RAIDERS coming toward her. She turns, running back up the hill. Hector and the children also turn and run back the way they have come, by now dropping precious bits of food and other possessions. The Raiders are running strongly, five or six of them.</context>
      <utterance>You're wrong!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector moves off, looking back to his children in the tree. They too gaze anxiously at him. They don't wave. Maybe waving hasn't been invented yet. Hector heads off alone, higher into the hills.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move from here. I'll come for you in the morning. There's no food. Try and sleep in the branches. Don't cry. Don't make a noise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAIDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no response from the tree. The Raider coaxes again.</context>
      <utterance>It's too cold to spend all night up there. We've got a fire at the beach. Food, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAIDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His friendly tone of voice has an effect. There is movement in the branches. Hector can see the dark shapes of his two children clambering down. The Raider stretches out his arms and helps the Boy to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Your mother's down there. She's happy... she's warm, too... and full... she wants to see you... she sent me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Leader moves closer to Hector and talks to him in a friendly, reasoning tone.</context>
      <utterance>I told you! I knew they did it around here! Ask him...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector doesn't understand. He looks at him blankly.</context>
      <utterance>What do we do? Do we throw you over, is that the idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Leader tries to help Hector understand by miming the act of throwing him off the cliff. Hector doesn't know how to respond.</context>
      <utterance>He wants me to throw you over. What does it do? Does it help the sun? Should I throw you over?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Leader is unsure. He walks around the pile of stones, checking it out from all sides as if it was some infernal machine that he didn't know the workings of. He squats down and squints through it to the watery sun emerging from the clouds far out to sea. He looks across to Hector, now sitting on the grass. The Leader sits down beside him. They sit together like friends. The ageless intimacy of sacrificer and victim.</context>
      <utterance>I tell you, it's one man, one stone. It'll help the voyage.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it got to do with the sun?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Leader looks at Hector. Then he makes up his mind.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, he stands up. The Priest, with some sense of ceremony, looks around for a large stone, picks one up and places it on top of the pile. He waits for a moment, almost as if he expects some consequence of his action.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's too much of a risk. Just add a stone to the pile. Let him go. That's the best we can do. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Leader strides off back toward the beach. The others follow him, giving a final look or smile to Hector, apart from the Priest, who looks him up and down, regretting that he is not by now a corpse in the ocean. Hector watches them go, too shocked still to react in any mean- ingful way. He stands alone, trying to unpick the rope that binds his hands. When they are some distance from him, Hector starts to follow them, at first running to catch up and then simply trotting after them. The Raiders are aware of him behind them. The Leader eventually stops and calls to Hector.</context>
      <utterance>It's meaningless, without him going over the cliff.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns from Hector and moves on. Hector persists in following them. They are his only connection now with anything that thinks or feels in the world. His link with them is all that is left. Again and again the Leader stops to shoo Hector away, but Hector dumbly tags along behind.</context>
      <utterance>Off you go. We don't want you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad omens, Hector. Bad omens. Get me something to eat. Just a mouse or two.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector places the stool at Lucinnius's feet and moves off. Lucinnius sits down, still absorbed in his problems. Hector keeps an eye on Lucinnius as he orders the food.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two mice... and some bread...</utterance>
   <speaker>STALLHOLDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No mice.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Hector is given the food and pays for it, he sees another man, JULIAN, approach Lucinnius, trailed by TWO SLAVES. One of them is carrying a folding chair much more substantial than Lucinnius's. Julian and Lucinnius greet one another and sit down to talk, Lucinnius at something of a height disadvantage. The Two Slaves move off to one side. Lucinnius's mood has brightened since the arrival of his friend. Their conversation seems open and friendly. Hector gives his master his food, and then moves to join the Two Slaves, hearing a snatch of the conversation as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>Two chicken legs, then, cold, and the bread.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector offers to share his bread with the other Two Slaves. They easily fall into conversation, inevitably, about their masters.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you're free to call at my house at anytime, but I was receiving Nepos... how could I admit you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>he's been avoiding him all week.</context>
      <utterance>Spoiled his day, meeting your man...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His ships have gone too, we heard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last night. Nepos knew. Pirates. They're sunk, he reckons. That could finish him, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the worst it's been.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This makes them laugh, Hector less so than the other two.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be up for sale before you know it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other two nod their heads.</context>
      <utterance>He's finished... you reckon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... at the baths... I could tell... they smelled blood...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... if he'd pulled it off he'd be in Rome by now...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector nods his head thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>And you with him...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius and his friend stand and exchange their final words, unaware of the scrutiny they have been under, or so used to it that they are oblivious to it. Hector and the Slaves hurry to gather up the seats and take their positions behind their masters. The casualness of their conversation has gone, and they resume the formality of their roles.</context>
      <utterance>And me with him... half way home...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector obligingly trots a step or two closer to Lucinnius to aid their conversation.</context>
      <utterance>He's a true friend, probably the only one I have left.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will he lend you the money?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was honest about it. He said so, plain and simple. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius unburdens himself.</context>
      <utterance>That's a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the ships have gone... did I tell you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have they?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can see the concentration on Hector's face as he concocts appropriate responses. He has a tough occupation, being the alter ego to an ambitious loser in one of the most competitive and dangerous societies ever to exist. And he has to carry the stool and the towel as well.</context>
      <utterance>Cyprian knows already. He'll want his money back too...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we get home I want you to get some chickens... and fetch Hermas, the diviner.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hermas tetchily stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Are my ships from Sicily still afloat...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius obeys.</context>
      <utterance>No, no... offer the grain first... sprinkle it on the altar...</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cuts into the chicken liver and prods around the in- side. The other two wait in silence.</context>
      <utterance>... and we can't ask the Gods specific questions like that... it's a gentle, probing enquiry... general questions... but let's see.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General answer... no...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius objects.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, no. The liver says no...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it again... I want you to do it again... Is it the Gods' will... that Cyprian... be well disposed towards me... in the future?</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks a Lucinnius, who nods reluctantly. Hector opens his purse and counts out the coins for Hermas.</context>
      <utterance>If you want to do it again, you need another chicken and another fifteen sesterces... and I'd like the first fifteen now please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector smiles ruefully.</context>
      <utterance>Cyprian loaned me half a million to fit out these ships... I'm finished. Just when things were going well... I had plans for you too, Hector... in four or five years I was going to make you a free man... and then in ten years you'd be a citizen... you... you could've found your family... brought them here... everything...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius misses the irony in Hector's voice and enthuses about his own future generosity.</context>
      <utterance>It sounds good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius is silent for a while as Hector continues to rub his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>It does, doesn't it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shouldn't give up. I can't... I'll visit Cyprian, first thing tomorrow... before the others can get to him... he's got to see reason... I can pay him back... sometime. It's the only chance we have, Hector. Should I do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This burst of resolve has relaxed Lucinnius. His tense muscles yield more to Hector's fingers. THALIA enters the room. She is a household slave, a Nubian from Africa. She carries a lighted torch and moves around the room lighting the wall lamps. Lucinnius watches her.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. I must.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector does as he is told. He takes the torch from Thalia and discreetly leaves the room, hearing Lucinnius as he closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>Thalia, I think I need one of your massages. Hector, you can finish the lamps.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lower, Thalia.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is Thalia. We can tell that they are close. Hector sits down beside her.</context>
      <utterance>I missed you last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He kept me working until morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>and he's not very clever.</context>
      <utterance>He has no money and a lot of enemies. If he's very clever he'll survive... but the omens are bad...</utterance>
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She doesn't like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thalia looks out towards the sea.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody does. He's unfortunate. You get people like that. Clumsy and sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector puts an arm around Thalia. At first it feels strange, their physical intimacy alongside their matter- of-fact conversation, but gradually we understand it, the giving and taking of comfort where it can be found, and the realness of their friendship. Their stroking and touching and holding becomes good to watch. We get a feeling for what they have given one another, in stolen hours and half hours, up here on the roof, the only place where they can be themselves.</context>
      <utterance>Why does the thunder always stay out on the ocean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. Far away some street DOGS BARK.</context>
      <utterance>It's the Gods arguing. They're working out what to do with Lucinnius... he'll be lying awake down there... wondering what they're saying about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he goes down I'll ask for my freedom... he owes it to me... he said as much... you too... we could be free...</utterance>
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now he is kissing her.</context>
      <utterance>What we talk about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We talk about going home. Yours is that way and mine is that way... your family is that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just made that up... I don't know which way they are... anyway ... you can't think like that. Not after so many years...</utterance>
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what you talk about.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We talk about it because it can never happen. What we do is you and me...</utterance>
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. I think you'll leave. You're going to leave me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's all.</context>
      <utterance>Never. It's you and me now.</utterance>
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is silent, still kissing her. He yawns as he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Well. We stay here. He'll survive.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm tired.</context>
      <utterance>Then I can see you every night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector smiles. He isn't surprised to see them. They are only doing what he and Thalia do on the roof. The Slaves have their meeting places scattered all over the house.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you find a woman, Hector...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man shakes his head with a smile. Hector leaves, the sleepy chicken going to meet her fate in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry to trouble you... just fetching a chicken... good night ... the roof's free...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, miss, you can tell Lucinnius his future.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look happier.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius strides out of the courtyard with Hector following after him.</context>
      <utterance>Relieved anyway... relieved that it's over at last.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will he help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is shocked.</context>
      <utterance>I have to kill myself by tomorrow morning. He has all my letters to Titinius, none of them got through. He says it's like treason... and he says I should want to die for owing him half a million anyway...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if you don't...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius shivers to think of them.</context>
      <utterance>Then he will... and that wouldn't be pleasant... he would drag me to Rome... those letters...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm done for, Hector... but it's strange... I feel kind of good about it... the struggle is over ... we've seen it through together, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius quickens his pace.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get home. We have a lot to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius is obviously in a state of shock.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight... peace at last...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two of us, to the end...</context>
      <utterance>We'll do it with a knife, Hector. When everyone has gone to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. What do you want me to do... I don't think I can help you...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll help each other, Hector. We must. We've been through this whole mess together... we must die together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you mean. What mess?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't understand do you? I'm asking you to die with me... you're my closest, my dearest slave... what would they say about me if you refused to die with me? This is honor... we're choosing death... we're not going to submit to the humiliations that Cyprian can heap on us, are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius changes his tone, becomes more, in his own mind, frank, man-to-man.</context>
      <utterance>You say we... I don't know... what is we? I've done nothing... I know nothing...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hector... at Cyprian's this morning ... I had to sign certain papers ... tell a bit of a story...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of story?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is stunned with shock...</context>
      <utterance>A confession. That we were plotting against Cyprian and the provincial senate... we were short of names... most of the people I know were in the room... people I thought were my friends... so I mentioned you... I had to...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'm a conspirator?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector manages to speak.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. So you see, I don't want you to die with me just because of my honor... it's more complicated... I'm sorry, Hector. I would be honored... if you would die with me... I mean it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I sit down?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the worst it's been.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector has picked up a large metal plate to help him make his point.</context>
      <utterance>But even if it's round you can still fall off the edge.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gallus sees his playball. He picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>No... it's not round like that... it's round like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gallus ignores this tease, intent on the ball.</context>
      <utterance>Do you believe everything that Greek tells you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector becomes more interested.</context>
      <utterance>Rome must be right in the middle... here... and we must be out here somewhere...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, where is my home?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many months did they march you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gallus walks out the distance from Rome with his fingers, as if there is serious calculation.</context>
      <utterance>Seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His fingers stop on the other side of the ball.</context>
      <utterance>It must be about here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But then you'd be upside down...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gallus is stumped for answers.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't upside down... and how could you see the sun round there ... I saw the sun at home... every day...</utterance>
   <speaker>GALLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector remembers that he and the boy's father are supposed to die that night. He looks on Gallus with a new tenderness.</context>
      <utterance>I'll ask him tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, tell me tomorrow... I'd like to know... because my children are round there and I want to know that they're getting the sun... ask him something else, too... where are the gods if the whole thing is round?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I know that... they're out here, and all around... that's how they can look down and see everything...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scatters some grain on the table. The chicken at once begins to peck them up.</context>
      <utterance>If he eats the grain it means yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's saying yes... there's a way...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's saying yes, we should die.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you asked it if we had to die, or if there was another way... it's saying yes, there is...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bird is certainly enjoying his food.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's saying yes, we should die.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chicken is inscrutable, as they are prone to be.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's just hungry...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DALMIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kitchen slave quickly appears.</context>
      <utterance>Solus!</utterance>
   <speaker>DALMIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Solus... I'm eating chicken again. I ate chicken yesterday and the day before... will I be eating chicken again tomorrow? Why am I always eating chicken?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks again at Lucinnius and Hector. They look at each other. Thalia looks at Hector. Dalmia looks at them all looking at each other, more intrigued than she was before. A SLAVE interrupts them.</context>
      <utterance>It's what we have to hand in the kitchen, ma'am... I always try to use the fresh stuff... the chickens have just been turning up...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius and Hector look at each other and share a moment of hope. They might be coming with good news, perhaps a softening of Cyprian's heart.</context>
      <utterance>Two men have come to see you. From Cyprian.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VISITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius sighs, as his last hope expires.</context>
      <utterance>Good evening, Lucinnius. Cyprian asked us if we could be of any assistance... in the business that you have to conduct tonight... to make that business as... comfortable... as you could wish...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The heavies metaphorically keep their foot in the door.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, gentlemen... But I feel that I will be capable of taking care of my affairs tonight without your help... Thank Cyprian for his kind thought...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VISITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're spending the night at the house of Nepos, not far from here. Don't hesitate to send your man for us... at any time... We're anxious that things should go well for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>VISITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll call in the morning at any rate... just to make sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is closing the door when one of the Visitors talks roughly to him.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VISITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector instinctively looks to his master. Lucinnius doesn't protest, but retreats into the house. Hector is left alone with the Visitors.</context>
      <utterance>You. Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VISITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks like the kind that'll want some help. Have you ever killed before?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only chickens.</utterance>
   <speaker>VISITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He prods at Hector's body freely, showing him what to do. If it is ticklish, Hector doesn't let on.</context>
      <utterance>He's not much different. Use a thin blade, but long. Get it in deep... the heart... feel for a space between the ribs...</utterance>
   <speaker>VISITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We leave Hector nodding obediently as this weirdest of coaching lessons continues.</context>
      <utterance>... or go in from the back... any place he'll let you...</utterance>
   <speaker>VISITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting it out's not as easy as you might think... you have to twist a bit... to get over the stickiness...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius places the money in a box on his table. He is quite drunk, resigned now to his fate. Hector however is cold sober, grim-faced. Lucinnius looks up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Eight hundred sesterces... cash ... that's all that's left... what a failure... my father left me three farms and forty thousand...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing else to be done. Don't you want some wine?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... but I want something...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius looks at him grimly and manages a smile. He clears his throat and attempts to put a note of ceremony into his voice.</context>
      <utterance>I want to die a free man... I don't want to die a slave...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hector, by this proclamation, I make you a freed man... I don't know the exact words... I've never done it before... But you're free, Hector.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius looks at him for a moment, then reaches out for his paper and pen.</context>
      <utterance>In writing... so that when they find me... they know I died a free man... please...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scratches out a few words on the paper, Hector looking over his shoulder, keenly watching what he writes. Lucinnius finishes writing and lays down the pen.</context>
      <utterance>Very well...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll find it in the morning. It's a nice thought, Hector... you were right to ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius picks up a large kitchen knife which lies on the table. He fingers its blade.</context>
      <utterance>Well... freed man, let's do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing... I mean, not to me... I have to do it first... you understand that... and then you... if I don't succeed... then you must help me...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius stands and leaves the room. Hector follows with the oil lamp.</context>
      <utterance>No point in messing up the room. Let's go downstairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius sits back on the step of the washing pool, holding his stomach. Hector sits down beside him. They both look down at the blade, still in Lucinnius' body.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that hurts, that stings!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit absurdly like this for a long moment, neither of them knowing what do do next. It's awkward, like in a waiting room. Then Lucinnius speaks.</context>
      <utterance>This is hopeless.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help me, Hector...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector speaks gently, like coaxing a frightened animal. He helps Lucinnius lie out on the marble floor.</context>
      <utterance>You've done it... you've done it ... lie down...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close your eyes... you did it...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The movement has increased the spread of blood over Lucinnius' clothing. He raises his head.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do it now, Hector... hurry...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lie still... lie still...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It looks as if Hector is playing for time.</context>
      <utterance>Do it Hector... do it... you promised...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shush... I'll need the knife...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinnius' voice is fading now. Hector waits, then reaches down for the knife in Lucinnius' stomach. We see on his face the effort as he pulls at it, and do we detect a subtle twisting of the blade to speed Lucinnius on his way? Lucinnius sighs and twitches a little. It's as if the life flows out of him as the knife is released from the wound. His voice is even more faint.</context>
      <utterance>Take it... do it...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector has the knife in his hand, but still he waits, looking at Lucinnius, willing the last dregs of life from him.</context>
      <utterance>Do it, Hector... do it... do it...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINNIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whispers fade to a croak. Lucinnius lies still. Hector has won this final battle of wills. He stands up, suddenly repulsed by what has happened. But quickly he gathers his wits. He makes his decision. He throws the knife down. It clatters along the hard shiny floor. Hector has run out of the room before it has come to rest against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Do it... do it... do it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have some mail for Tyre... where are the east-bound ships?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATCHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With an authoritative nod, Hector strides off in the direction of the noise and lights, Thalia at his heels. Hector talks when the Watchman is out of earshot.</context>
      <utterance>Ask at the harbor.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We want a timber ship... they go west... straight to Rome...</utterance>
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector hurries on, noncommittal in his reply.</context>
      <utterance>And then? Then you go home?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can go to anywhere from Rome.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CREWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He indicates a man standing on the rear deck. Hector and Thalia climb up the gangplank and approach him.</context>
      <utterance>He's on the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Captain... I'm looking for passage to Rome, for both of us...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who might you be?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the steward of Lucinnius the merchant... we have business in Rome... I need an immediate passage...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's five or six days... to Brundisium... you can walk or ride from there... you have money?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>what were you thinking of offering?</context>
      <utterance>Well, let's see... passage for two... food for two... six days...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do you leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anxious to leave, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keen to start, yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been on a ship before?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can tell he is lying.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points down into the lower depths of the hold. Then she gets even more excited.</context>
      <utterance>Me, too, but they kept us down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>THALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other and then all around them. The freshness of the day and on an overwhelming feeling of freedom, exhilarate them. Their senses and their feelings, are in new territory. They are like children in a brand-new world. The Captain on the other side of the ship, beckons them.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight... we'll be where the thunder is!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to three shapes in the mid-distance, ships heading for the port they have left. There is a thrill in their glamor, their fine progress under full sail.</context>
      <utterance>Thought you would like to see them.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your master's ships... going home...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... they can't be... they're lost...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector and Thalia look at each other. The Captain smiles at them and looks back to the ships, coursing healthily on their way.</context>
      <utterance>No they're not... I know these ships... my brother-in-law's the master of the big one with the brown sail...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody been putting the wind up Lucinnius? That's an old one... didn't think anybody'd fall for that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girl is sobbing through all of this.</context>
      <utterance>We want to praise God because we live in this ultimate age, when all things are done, all is known, all the wonders of his creation revealed to us... nothing more for man to see or do... all that is left is the hope of salvation... even for our humbler sisters...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an Irish lilt to his voice which colors what he is saying with a tinge of mischief. He is a difficult fellow to pin down. Hector looks at him amusedly, still sharing his thoughts silently with the woman, BEATRICE. The Nun interrupts the Priest cheerfully.</context>
      <utterance>Yes weep, child, weep for joy... you are a glorious example to us all... already a child of God's... blessed to spend your earthly days within his church as Christ's servant... what generous parents you have... giving you to the sisters... What a sacrifice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The child sobs more noisily.</context>
      <utterance>She's already received the last rites, before she left her family. She belongs to God now... Don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fortunate child, destined for paradise. Untouched by the abiding curse of carnal lust. I struggle against it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks accusingly at Beatrice.</context>
      <utterance>I will not join myself carnally with any woman...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Hector is getting the hard looks from the Priest.</context>
      <utterance>... I will carry my unspilt seed from this world to the next... as should every man...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DRIVER of the wagon turns his head briefly to the Priest.</context>
      <utterance>... If all men forsook forever the fleshy temptations... and held womankind to barrenness... think how much the sooner would come the day of judgement... all God's chosen gathered in paradise... I've written a small treatise in favor of virginity, sister. We could discuss it later if you like...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector gestures to Beatrice that he is leaving the wagon to walk for a while and asks her to join him. She shakes her head with a smile. Hector smiles, too, then jumps down from the wagon and, walking slowly, allows it to gain ground in front of him. The ramblings of the Priest fade away.</context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's simple, brother... if we cease carnal union entirely then in fifty or so years we'll all be rid of our earthly lives and God can proceed with His reign over His heavenly kingdom... that same paradise that God gave to man before, but which man was so unfit to inhabit that within seven hours Eve was already tempting her master and mate, and within nine hours the Lord had to expel the both of them! Just think, they messed it up in nine hours!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at him. He sits opposite her in the wagon, and allows his foot to touch hers. She doesn't move away. Hector calls to the Driver.</context>
      <utterance>A bit cold... walking...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long to get there?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks at Beatrice.</context>
      <utterance>When it gets dark, we'll be there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beatrice replies, but in a language that Hector doesn't understand.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I heard fighting... back there...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector talks back to her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're saying... I haven't understood anything you've said all day...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both smile. It doesn't seem to disturb them too much that they don't share a language. They repeat their incomprehensible statements, just for the fun of it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're saying...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beside Hector the Girl has stopped sobbing but she is still troubled. She turns to him and speaks quietly but with determination.</context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector doesn't know how to respond. He can do nothing to help her, and anyway, is more interested in Beatrice.</context>
      <utterance>I want to go home to my mother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He indicates the large pot containing the remains of the stew.</context>
      <utterance>God, I'm starving. Do you think I dare heat that up on the fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours some wine into the cup and slides it across the table to Hector.</context>
      <utterance>No... I'll eat it cold... I deserve to suffer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector takes a drink.</context>
      <utterance>Have some wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw some fighting today... back up the road...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, the mad knights are at it again... what were they, Swiss or English?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. They all look the same to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Priest changes his tone of voice, mocking his own holy act.</context>
      <utterance>It might help us get through... if there's a bit of confusion... we'll still travel separately though, for now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is smiling.</context>
      <utterance>But, Hector, you must keep out of the way of temptation... I saw the way you were eyeing up that widow... now stay away from that... although she is beautiful, is she not... but we're going home, remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know she's a widow?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He changes his tone yet again. He talks straight.</context>
      <utterance>Look at her eyes... hungry eyes... she could lead you into trouble... she smells like paradise, though.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>stirred thoughts that he had intended to dampen entirely.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Hector, let's get this clear... if anyone's going to dally with that widow it'll be me... you couldn't handle her... she'd bewitch you... at any rate, you're not a sinning kind of fellow, are you... why don't you get off up the road tomorrow, and I'll catch you up, in five or so days... Hector doesn't answer, but smiles. The Priest has</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector still remains silent. The Priest is worried.</context>
      <utterance>You're not a sinning fellow, remember... another month and we'll be at the channel, then home... the little ones you only talk about when you're drunk... don't forget them...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector obeys the Priest without thought. The Priest is happier now that he is in control again.</context>
      <utterance>Why do I always talk so much... you weren't even thinking of her 'til I opened my mouth... but I trust you... don't worry. I know you wouldn't do anything to anger your God, or me. Get me some bread.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who saved your neck in Venice?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector approaches the Priest with the bread.</context>
      <utterance>You did, Ronald.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his cup to Hector.</context>
      <utterance>And don't you forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May the Lord forgive us our sins, those we have committed and those we as yet only dream of. She's a glory of a woman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PEDLAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to the forlorn Girl.</context>
      <utterance>Hostages, too, they've got... they only take the rich ones...</utterance>
   <speaker>PEDLAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector talks to the company, but means his words for the Priest.</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever seen so many fine, rich men, my girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Priest looks him straight in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>I won't be travelling today.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector shakes his head, catching Beatrice's eye.</context>
      <utterance>The fighting's behind us, brother ... you'll be safe enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Nun puts an arm around the Girl.</context>
      <utterance>You should go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the door is thrown open and four SOLDIERS man- handle an inert body, dressed in full armor, into the room. They scatter the food from the table and lay out the MOANING suit of armor on it. A young SQUIRE follows them in and kneels by the knight in the suit. The MOANS are MUFFLED because the knight's helmet has been battered out of shape in the battle and can't be removed. The ugly dent suggests an equally ugly wound inflicted on the head inside. The Soldiers gingerly try to remove the helmet. Their efforts are useless. Blood oozes from the joints of the helmet. The MOANING suit of armor seems inhuman, robot-like.</context>
      <utterance>We're going. God will protect his ewe lambs.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Squire looks at him and nods his head. Hector looks with sympathy at the boy.</context>
      <utterance>Must be sore in there. Is it your dada?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An OFFICER comes into the room.</context>
      <utterance>If he's got a little head it might be alright. Has your dada got a big head?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where's the smith?</context>
      <utterance>Is there a blacksmith here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FARM WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer looks at the moaning suit of armor, then at the astonished group of Travellers. He picks on the Priest.</context>
      <utterance>In the village, sir, half a day away.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Priest obediently goes up to the knight and starts to pray earnestly. The Officer turns to the Soldiers.</context>
      <utterance>You, Priest, come here... get to work on him... he's not ready for heaven yet... there's a hundred thousand livres on his head if I get him to Paris alive... Start praying... there's fifteen livres in it for you if he lives...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't, I don't understand a word.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you don't speak like anyone else? Are you far from home? Home? Where you sleep and live?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>home.</context>
      <utterance>I think I know what you mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm far from home, too... way, way over there... then across the sea...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're losing me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector smiles, pleased with himself. Beatrice laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever seen the sea? Water everywhere... right to the end of the world... I come from the other side of the little water, then there's the big, big water... I had a friend who sailed on that... went too far... fell right over the edge... into nothing. They never came back... they fell off the world...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think that's funny? It's true... it's a sad story... you shouldn't laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk about home again... remember you said home?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not making sense, am I? Well, let's go back to homes. That's where I'm going... I've been away for too long... Some people locked me up... I had to run away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>home...</context>
      <utterance>We have to learn to talk the same... try it like me, say it...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you're saying... you're saying home... say something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Home... home... try it... home...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want the word for home? It's home... say it... home... home...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>home...</context>
      <utterance>I don't want your word for home, I want you to say mine... home...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beatrice has her way, turning the tables on Hector. He says it in her language.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, you can do it... home... home...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beatrice smiles. In this tiny victory the dynamic of their relationship is set.</context>
      <utterance>Home... home...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They fall silent, suddenly shy. Beatrice breaks this moment by reaching out to Hector's neck, very delicately, like a caress. Hector smiles. There first touch. Then it changes. Beatrice completes her movement with a sharp grab at Hector's hair, and pinches her fingers on something. Triumphantly she shows him the flea she has caught.</context>
      <utterance>That's it... clever boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tick... it's a tick.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beatrice looks at him directly now, their intimacy well under way.</context>
      <utterance>Flea... a flea... thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She ruffles his hair, in a motherly but then again sex- ually provocative way. He understands her well now.</context>
      <utterance>Bet there's more in there. You need a good going over... nobody's been looking after you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They understand each other perfectly now. They look around for a more private spot.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we go somewhere and have a good session... I could do you... I'd like to give you a good grooming...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sleeping now... at peace, for the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer leaves. Ronald quickly follows him outside.</context>
      <utterance>Leave him for a while. There are a few souls out here you can help on their way to heaven. Ten sous a soul to you... come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When they have gone the Squire gives his father a nudge, but there is no response from the knight, just the impression of lifeless bulk.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty sous is normal. How many are there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's four.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives his scalp a final delicious rub, and then stops.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it does feel good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beatrice loosens her clothing to bare her neck and shoulders. Hector begins to probe her hair and scalp. She arches her back under the first touch of his fingers. Hector laps it up, inspired to caress ever more tenderly her scalp and neck, still with the outward purpose of looking for fleas.</context>
      <utterance>You can do me now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To Hector even her fleas are a delight. He seems to want to keep it as a pet. There is no hope for this man. Beatrice moans softly, happily. Hector still kneading her scalp.</context>
      <utterance>Got one... a tiny little one... yours are so small... and fair...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beatrice replies with a hint of breathlessness.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know your name. I'm Hector... who are you? I'm Hector.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hector... yes... I'm Beatrice...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beatrice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Hector... I think you'll have to do under my arms... I'm a little itchy there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I think Beatrice is a good name. Beatrice is sighing contentedly now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In between parting the hairs on her scalp Hector is kiss- ing her on the neck now. At first it is small, snatched kisses amongst the grooming, but soon the kisses become longer and the grooming less.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should find the river, and have a proper wash...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still itchy lots of places, Hector.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He talks to the Nun as they move off.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, little girl... the Lord will bless you, I know, in his house.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long for you on the road?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three or four days.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not killing nuns, yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Saxon, won't he go with you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald is mumbling his prayers.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Peter... don't forget ... tell everybody that was my name... Peter...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lie still, Peter...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald stays with the boy as he struggles against his own annihilation.</context>
      <utterance>That's it, Peter... tell everybody ... write it... don't forget it... Peter... tell them Peter died here ... my name is Peter... Peter... say it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald behaves well with the dying boy.</context>
      <utterance>Peter...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a busy man, what with all these souls departing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing wrong with helping someone to die in peace. They want me to go with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you staying here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll wait for you at the channel.</context>
      <utterance>Moving on, as you told me to... we'll meet up, like you said.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll do you harm. I told you. She might be a witch. Wait for me. I still have the money from Venice. We can be home in a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both of them are unhappy now, confusing one another, spoiling their friendship.</context>
      <utterance>Witch my arse. Stop giving me orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Priest is silent. They are saved from hurting each other more. A Soldier shouts down to them from the farm.</context>
      <utterance>You're a strange fellow. Are you a priest? Are you jealous?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're moving soon, Father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you're leaving?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Priest walks back up to the farm. Hector calls out what might be an attempt at an apology or simply another taunt.</context>
      <utterance>You have work to do here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Priest looks back at him briefly, then walks on.</context>
      <utterance>I don't understand you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad we're going the same way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The damp greyness of the early morning has lifted and the sun is shining as they step out onto the higher hills.</context>
      <utterance>We'll have to sleep in the hills tonight. Will you keep me warm?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector seems to know what she is saying. He throws down his knife and cheese, lying down with her on the grass. He kisses her breasts and her body eagerly. He lifts her skirts and caresses and kisses her naked legs and thighs. She stretches herself out happily, arms spread wide on the grass. Hector talks through his kisses.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry up and finish your wine and then we can make love.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts his head to let her see him sniffing.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you smell so wonderful?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector kisses her more. She smiles and turns her head to the sky. Then she starts to giggle.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you like my smell, do you? I make it from the flowers. I put it here, and there, and there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector doesn't understand, and keeps on with his kissing. Only her persistent giggling makes him stop and look up. Hector sees him too. Down by the stream a head peering over the top of a rock, not even attempting to hide.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it... someone's watching us, the dirty devil... don't look... he's down by the water, by the rocks...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheeky devil.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not moving. He must've seen us, though.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beatrice doesn't understand. Hector stands up, still looking at the figure.</context>
      <utterance>It's a dead man.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move cautiously. When they are closer to it, and can see it for what is is, they walk straight for the dead body.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, we're going that way at any rate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sign of a battle... only a few horses... or just one. He wasn't killed in a fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a sadness about this young death in such a lonely place. Hector and Beatrice are open to this sad- ness, but in their age sentiment was of a tougher strain.</context>
      <utterance>Poor boy. Isn't he fine-looking. Look at his shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is already gathering stones. Hector sees what Beatrice is doing.</context>
      <utterance>We'll cover his eyes at least... so the crows don't get him. Look at these shoes, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he lays him down Hector sees a small, dry wound on the boy's side. Beatrice brings her armful of stones and starts to build a mound around the squire's head.</context>
      <utterance>That's good of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beatrice is still taken by the boy's shoes.</context>
      <utterance>It's all we can do. It won't keep the wolves away though.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at Hector.</context>
      <utterance>His feet are like mine, you know. I'll give you mine, poor boy, and I'll have yours. I have more walking to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector watches as Beatrice exchanges her old shoes for the squire's. They fit her well, and she proudly shows them off to Hector. He smiles at her.</context>
      <utterance>It's not stealing if I give him mine, is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're eager today, Hector, aren't you? Is it all this death?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're saying but I like you when you talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That should help him a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should go now. We've been here too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder if his mama will ever know what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said mama. I know what that is... mama... We can talk the same...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama... that's right... mama...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to keep the sun on my back, that's what Ronald said... the sun on my back all the way home... I'll stay on this side of the river...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course... we stay on this side of the river, all the way down... until tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stay on this side...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move off, each thinking that they have reached agreement. Beatrice starts to sing as they make a gentle descent into the forests below.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... On this side. Then the other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector stands looking around the small dark room. Beatrice suddenly seems shy and awkward.</context>
      <utterance>Here we are... home... you want some food... and then I'll show you everything. We have a spring ... you can wash...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks at her in silence.</context>
      <utterance>This is when I wish you could understand me. You'll have to learn, you know... I want you to stay here. You want to, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses the room to a wooden chest under the window.</context>
      <utterance>I look after the hens, and I make dyes from the plants, and perfumes too. I'm good at that. But I'm no good with the sheep and the goats. I wish you could understand... Arnaud's been dead two years...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds the jacket up against Hector to measure it. Hector's reaction to a dead man's clothing is predictable.</context>
      <utterance>I still have his clothes. I'll make them fit you...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he die of?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is beginning to understand what she means, but he keeps his feelings to himself. Beatrice talks on. Now that she has started, she wants to say it all.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting shy. Imagine me being shy with you... I made this for him... tonight we'll try them on. You're the same height as Arnaud, but a little thinner. I'll make them fit. I'm a good sewer. And we have a big bed upstairs for you and me, in the rafters... You and me... sleep...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beatrice falls silent, overtaken by her shyness. Hector understands fully what she means now, but his mind is a confusion. He can't respond. She tries to direct his thoughts to the one area she is sure about.</context>
      <utterance>I like you. You like me too, don't you? We were lucky to meet the way we did. All the men around here are old.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She climbs a ladder nearby and lifts open a trapdoor on the wooden ceiling. Hector climbs up to join her and together they stand on the ladder with their heads poking into the tiny space above.</context>
      <utterance>Come up and I'll show you the bed...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs. Hector's expression lightens a little too. It occurs to him to take up her offer immediately. She catches his thought, and the moment tingles happily. Then from outside they hear voices. Firstly a young Boy calling.</context>
      <utterance>A good bed, eh? For you and me. We can have fun up here... better than a ditch...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama, are you home?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girl eyes Hector up and down.</context>
      <utterance>You were gone a long time. Who's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beatrice pronounces his name with care. She stands proudly by her children.</context>
      <utterance>This is Hector.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CREAK of a door makes Hector turn his head.</context>
      <utterance>These are my children...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An OLD WOMAN stands in the main doorway, smiling at Hector and nodding her head. She speaks to her daughter.</context>
      <utterance>... and this is my mother....</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>OLD WOMAN</mode>
      <context>Hector stands, surrounded by instant family, and doesn't know what to do. Eventually he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>So... you found one, eh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He mimes with his hands. Beatrice understands that he wants some breathing space. She talks to her son.</context>
      <utterance>Is there water... to drink... to wash?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEATRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off the dead Squire's shoes and puts them on the Boy's bare feet. He is delighted. He does a little dance in them before leaving with Hector.</context>
      <utterance>Take Hector to the well... but come here first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector gently pacifies her.</context>
      <utterance>We can't have this... this was Arnaud's seat... it's yours now... I can sit on the box...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old woman allows herself a shy smile. Whether in innocence or mischief, she has secured the best seat in the house for herself. If he stays, Hector will never dare rest his bones in it.</context>
      <utterance>You must sit there... look... you need the light from the window... it's your seat... I don't want it... it's yours... I can sit on the box.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boy says something and points towards his sister. She stands by her cauldron, stirring the bubbling liquid. Hector goes to watch her work. He looks in the cauldron.</context>
      <utterance>Ah...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without thinking, Hector leans over the cauldron to sniff. A hideous odor assaults him. He backs off.</context>
      <utterance>Good color... for cloth?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girl says something to him, and points to a bucket of liquid at her feet. Hector makes out something like the word "peepee."</context>
      <utterance>Ugh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girl nods enthusiastically. The Boy is sniggering.</context>
      <utterance>Peepee?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to leave soon. I can't stay... it would be wrong to stay for just a while...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector fumbles awkwardly with his bag and then walks off down the track. He turns to look at Beatrice. She stands outside her house for a long time, watching him until he turns onto the main road and OUT OF SIGHT. The pain and the awkwardness in Beatrice and Hector are specific, but the scene of parting is timeless. Is this the ten millionth such parting, or the billionth? It is one of them at any rate, and a sad one.</context>
      <utterance>I have to go... have to keep the sun on my back... I have to get home... I have a family, just like you... I like you... you smell good... wonderful...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a wonderful dream. I was lying under a tree, beside a river. I was dozing. I heard the water... beautiful clear water. I got up and drank some. I think I ate some raspberries too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks around him at the squalid mass of distressed humanity.</context>
      <utterance>I would like some water.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some figures rise and an argument takes place, like a domestic squabble. We can hear some of their exchanges.</context>
      <utterance>God, this is the worst, the worst.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me keep him... they said we'll find land in a day or so... you're evil...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a flurry of movement amongst the figures, then a splash, then a cry of a Woman. The noise has awakened others. All over the raft figures are coming awake, sitting up, taking in the new day, and the dreadful reality of their situation. Andre speaks to Hector.</context>
      <utterance>When they're dead they go over the side... The place stinks enough as it is...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think I'll still see Europe?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think there's more chance of me eating you, Andre.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone speaks from under a crude canvas shelter.</context>
      <utterance>I think today will be the day, my friends. We've been in the inshore currents since yesterday. Three crowns to the first one to sight the coast. God preserve us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo strides off to his station by the makeshift rudder.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind the three crowns... a side of beef would do... or a drink of clean water.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, there'll be food for all ashore. Africa's full of meat and drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's full of Africans too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many made it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighty men. Ten women. Eighteen children and forty-five slaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer leaves to carry out his orders. Dom Paulo addresses another of his men, Da Cunha.</context>
      <utterance>Two parties of ten men each... one to the north and one to the south... bring back what you can... game, fruit, anything... and send someone back as soon as you find fresh water. Any trouble, discharge three shots.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco barely stops his work to reply.</context>
      <utterance>I have a carpet and some cloth... I thought if we worked together we could make a better shelter...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's a joke it's a poor one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least ask Dona Ursula...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His stubborn rejection of Hector reveals just how strong their friendship once was.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have to ask her... I know she would agree with me... leave us alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... would you take my cloth, at least?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it and build your own hovel somewhere else... leave us alone...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They ran off with the dry bread... about eight of them, sir... Dom Paulo looks at the two prisoners.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He speaks again to the Sailor.</context>
      <utterance>You men are deserters. You will die tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco steps forward, outraged.</context>
      <utterance>Chain them on the raft for tonight, and watch them...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo's authoritative manner vanishes in an instant. He becomes hesitant, unsure of himself. As always, his Son watches every detail of the exchange.</context>
      <utterance>I must object... these sentences can't be lawful...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course... we can't allow ourselves to fall into terror and violence...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right... but then how can we punish them? We can't lock them up...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SALGADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The captured Deserters look on helplessly as their lives are argued over.</context>
      <utterance>You were right the first time, sir... they must hang... they were stealing the bread from our mouths...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG DESERTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't steal any bread... Gomes had the bread... he's off, in the forest...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo turns to the Priest.</context>
      <utterance>Oh dear...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Priest throws open his arms noncommittally.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think, Father?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll comfort them whether they live or die, now or later, any of you, all of you... I'll comfort you all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALGADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo is deeply confused.</context>
      <utterance>Hang them... you have to set an example...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco confuses him even more.</context>
      <utterance>So I was right the first time?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir... there must be proper justice...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's proper justice?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESERTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't steal any bread...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SALGADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to make a decision, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESERTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was Gomes... he told us to run.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A lot of hands go up. Hector hesitates, his instincts are not for killing. But the force of the majority weighs on him. He starts to raise his hand. At that moment, as he scans the crowd, he meets the eyes of the Deserter whose death they are voting on. For a moment they communicate. Hector is thrown. He drops his hand, only to find in the next instant the stern gaze of Salgado on him. He hesitates again, then starts to raise his hand. Then the eyes of the Deserter find him once more. This comic pantomime goes on while a solid majority of the crowd firmly raise their hands.</context>
      <utterance>I'll decide... no I won't... we'll all decide... most of the people that matter are here... we'll have a vote... who agrees with Salgado... and me... that they should die?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the Deserters raises his own hand meekly.</context>
      <utterance>... and those against death...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he looks to Salgado.</context>
      <utterance>You can't vote...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALGADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the other Deserter raises his hand too.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALGADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo thinks.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think this is working, Dom Paulo... we need authority... you must decide...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well... Da Cunha?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to the Sailors holding the Deserters.</context>
      <utterance>The cross the carpenter is working on... tell him to turn it into a scaffold... have it erected along the beach, away from the women... the executions will be at sunrise tomorrow. Tell Father Diogo.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dazed Deserters are led off. Dom Paulo's face clouds in doubt again.</context>
      <utterance>Take them to the raft.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone in agreement with hanging? Or should we shoot them... or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DA CUNHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hanging is fine, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo looks over the faces of the men. He stops at Hector.</context>
      <utterance>Very well... now... who's going to conduct the executions... should we pick someone, or have a volunteer...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector doesn't have the will to accept or the courage to refuse. He is saved by another young man, ALVAREZ, eager to prove himself.</context>
      <utterance>Hector?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVAREZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do it, Dom Paulo.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can sense the feeling of relief in Hector. Dom Paulo's son has been a silent witness to everything that has happened, but his blank face reveals nothing of his feelings.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Alvarez. Sunrise tomorrow. Send the Priest to them tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks across to the well-made shelter of Ursula and Francisco. Ursula herself works at the fire.</context>
      <utterance>Good work, Andre.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hector turns to Andre.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre leaves.</context>
      <utterance>You go and sleep by the big fire, Andre. Keep warm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector quickly stows his food back into his sack, and with a grunt of irritation sticks his head out of the shelter. Nuno is holding four fruits, about the size of large apples, but green and thick-skinned.</context>
      <utterance>Senor Hector?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was all they found in the forest. Four for each of us. They taste kind of milky, but sour.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Nuno.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother ate three and she was sick. So try two... but she's sick anyway... maybe you can try three...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nuno makes to leave, but then hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>I'll start with two.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nuno is looking down the beach to the remains of the raft on the shoreline. The shapes of the two Deserters chained there can just be seen.</context>
      <utterance>Hector, will you help me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the fruit he has just given Hector.</context>
      <utterance>Lopo... the boy they're going to hang tomorrow... he was cook's cabin boy... I was going to take him something to eat... I thought, perhaps, one of yours and one of mine...</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you might just eat two...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nuno looks disappointed. His eyes turn again to his playmate tied to the raft.</context>
      <utterance>But there's tomorrow, Nuno... we must eat tomorrow too...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nuno is silent, unconvinced.</context>
      <utterance>Dom Paulo would call it a waste. You must keep yourself strong, Nuno, that's what he'd say... so that you can help the others... God knows what we have ahead of us... we'll need strong people like you...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nuno stomps away in silence. Hector shouts after him cheerily.</context>
      <utterance>Try not to think about Lopo any more... The guards wouldn't let you near him anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DA CUNHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some gunpowder would scatter them, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they might want to be friendly... they'll have food too... get one of our African slaves... we must try and talk to them... If they think we're timid we're dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate it when people have to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's foolishness. Killing our own men when we have the whole of Africa to face.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco looks at him for the meaning in what he is saying. Hector shrugs. He takes a small bundle from his jacket and gives it to Francisco.</context>
      <utterance>It's foolish squabbling at all. We should be friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some bread and raisins.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought everything was shared out on the raft...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco looks Hector straight in the eye, looking for his angle. But this time there is none. Hector is simply a lonely man seeking to retrieve lost friendship. There is a glimmer of sympathy in Francisco's face.</context>
      <utterance>Well this wasn't. It's for her... and you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must speak to her!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo and the others laugh.</context>
      <utterance>They want to make a visit here... with their King... he will bring gifts, and will receive gifts. They said not to sacrifice anymore men for them... they don't like that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turtles' eggs, sir... Doctor Correa was shipping them to the Royal Zoo... I think they hoped some of them would hatch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... it's eggs for supper tonight... for everyone...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector cracks one of his eggs into a copper pan. Inside is a brown smudge of dried yoke and some dust. Hector grunts in annoyance and cracks another egg. The yoke is discolored and the smell is rank. Hector looks at Andre, rapidly finishing his omelette before Hector can demand it.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yours were fine?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector picks up a third egg and shakes itclose to his ear. It seems as empty as the other two. He picks up a fourth egg and cracks it open. A small dried-up, half- formed baby turtle RATTLES into the pan. Andre is quietly enjoying Hector's frustration. He stands up to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you any eggs left?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The slaves only got three. I want to ask you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were lucky. What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want my real name back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't like Andre anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think of my home all the time. I want to hear the name they call me. We should die with our real names.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector smiles at his own insensitivity.</context>
      <utterance>We're not going to die, Andre...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've forgotten your name...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ketabomago Pululo.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre looks at him expectantly.</context>
      <utterance>Now I remember why we called you Andre.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre is satisfied, and leaves. Hector calls to him.</context>
      <utterance>I will, Andre... I promise... I'll call you that... when I remember...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night... Keta...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ketabomago Pululo...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... good night...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many are sick?</utterance>
   <speaker>DA CUNHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About fifty, sir, some of them very sick indeed. It's the eggs. A couple of the crates were full of rotten ones, but eaten just the same. Others just ate too many. It would have been better to ration them, I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How wise of you to think of that now. Any deaths?</utterance>
   <speaker>DA CUNHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many eggs did you have?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DA CUNHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three. I had them boiled.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had four. I don't feel well now...</utterance>
   <speaker>DA CUNHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four's all right... the really ill ones had eaten eight, ten...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salgado comes forward with a handful of the broken remains of a kettle. Copper is a useful currency.</context>
      <utterance>Let's not think about it... what have you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALGADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salgado shows a handful of nails from a small sack in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>It worked well... they'll go for this... and nails... Luis cleaned up a sackful from the crates...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo rummages in a box of cheap rosaries, selects a couple, and then retires to his tent. The others work on at the table. Hector drifts off down to the beach.</context>
      <utterance>Organize some men to gather all the nails they can find. We have to keep control of that particular currency.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boy is standing now and fixing his clothing. He walks off back to the camp. The Girl remains sitting in the sand, buttoning her dress, too embarrassed even to raise her head to Hector. Then Hector is touched by something, perhaps the sad stoop in the Boy's shoulder or the Girl's lowered head. Hector realizes he has broken something precious and in their circumstances infinitely fragile and irretrievable. He feels like an oaf. He calls after the Boy.</context>
      <utterance>Stop that... leave her alone... get back to the camp... or I'll tell your mother... how can you play like this when there are people needing your help back there...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back... I didn't mean it... it was a joke... you come back... she's still here... I won't say anything...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SLAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points repeatedly at his navel.</context>
      <utterance>He was excited when he heard you had come, but he wants to know if you are real people... he didn't think you would be such a strange color... so he wants to see your...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... so that he will know that you were born like real people...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to open up his coat and shirt. The four Officers do the same. The King and a few of his atten- dants take a step or two forward and peer at the exposed white European bellies. They look at one another and mumble solemnly. Then they step back. Dom Paulo and the Officers fix their clothing and re-muster their dignity. The King is enjoying himself. He speaks again to the Slave, who then translates.</context>
      <utterance>Right... you four as well...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King takes a deep breath, then nods to Dom Paulo. Dom Paulo and the Officers do as they are told. The King joins them, and for a few moments there is a kind of communion between them. Then everyone joins in. It is a strange, poignant moment, all the Natives and all the Europeans united in the simple act of breathing. Dom Paulo regains his composure. He speaks to the Slave.</context>
      <utterance>He wants to see you breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Slave speaks to the King. The King listens and talks back for a long time. Then the Slave translates again.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him that we want to trade with him, to buy food... and we want him to guide us out of here... we have a long way to travel... to where the white men have their big ships...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>twenty big rivers...</context>
      <utterance>He has heard of white men very, very far away... this way... but you have to cross many rivers...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo steps forward to the King. An Officer brings a wrapped cloth. Dom Paulo opens it, letting the King see the pieces of broken copper inside.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him I want to give him these...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Various Officers raise their eyebrows at this.</context>
      <utterance>... and tell him that I want to make him a very special gift as one King to another...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo solemnly and without a blush removes the cheap rosary from around his neck and offers it to the King.</context>
      <utterance>Of these precious things, which my fathers and forefathers have worn for many long years before...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is translated. The King refuses to accept the rosary. Instead he is pointing to a couple of chunky and valuable-looking rings on Dom Paulo's fingers which he has forgotten to remove.</context>
      <utterance>I shouldn't do this, but it is such a special occasion, and he is such a great and worthy King...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is impossible to know if the King is being naively polite or hugely clever. Dom Paulo's Officers enjoy a muted titter as he peels off his precious rings and gives them to the King, replacing the worthless baubles around his own neck. The King begins talking again. The Slave translates.</context>
      <utterance>He says he could not accept such a treasured gift, something of such value to your family... instead he would be happy to take one or two of the old rings you have on your fingers... but please do not insist that he take your necklace...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will give you guides to help you across the first of the big rivers... it is ten days from here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Slave continues.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo looks shocked.</context>
      <utterance>... and he asks you to be ready to leave the beach in two days time... he cannot permit you to stay longer...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mention of turtles' eggs almost turns the stomachs of most of the survivors, even the fit ones. The King and his followers walk back into the forest. Soon the survivors are alone again, with the lost- looking cow the Natives have left. A doomed cow if ever there was.</context>
      <utterance>Because with the new moon the turtles will arrive and lay their eggs... you may frighten them... you must be gone...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nuno follows Hector's example. Hector allows him to feel the benefit of his gift before he starts to talk.</context>
      <utterance>Suck out the marrow... it's the best bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about today...</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I wasn't really angry at you...</context>
      <utterance>But it does... it was mean of me... I was upset at something...</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nuno is taking it rather well. Hector regains his natural self-confidence.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think too badly of me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nuno shyly nods his head.</context>
      <utterance>You still like me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is satisfied now.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are silent for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that makes me feel better... we all have to like each other... and respect each other... that's important too.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't respect me, just say so...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This doesn't produce much of a response. Hector tries again. He starts to chuckle to himself and nudges Nuno in the ribs.</context>
      <utterance>I have a boy like you... maybe you could meet him when we get home...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nuno shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>You can take her back there tomorrow, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... she's sick now...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector comes to the meeting. He sits down on a box near the table and watches and listens, his expression changing with the shifts in mood of the others. This is Hector the social animal, our Hector with his pockets full of stolen nails and his tent full of stashes of food.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you be more accurate?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I be accurate without instruments? As it is I'm sighting the sun with two pieces of wood... Call it five hundred and be done with it... he said twenty rivers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just want you to be as accurate as we know you can be, Dias. After all, the ship did manage to find that rock with admirable precision.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dias pounds his fist on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Confound you, Dom Paulo, that's an insult... she hit that rock because she was taking water and unsteerable... She was overloaded before she left India and you know it....</utterance>
   <speaker>DIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've told you... we vote for a leader or you can walk into the jungle on your own... it should have been done days ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>DA CUNHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are mock groans and laughter at the thought of it. The tension for the moment is broken.</context>
      <utterance>Calm down, Dias... you can't stay here forever, living on turtles' eggs...</utterance>
   <speaker>DA CUNHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dom Paulo lets out a heavy sigh.</context>
      <utterance>What about the sick and the injured, Dom Paulo...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've discussed it with Father Diogo... I don't see how a hundred of us can carry seventy sick...</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER DIOGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to search the scriptures tonight. I'm sure that God has an answer to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An excuse, you mean... we'll be leaving them here to die...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALGADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so you're coming with us now, Dias!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After the vote...</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER DIOGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It might be the best we can offer them now... the chance to die a good Christian death here, and set an example to the heathens...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be glad when we're on the move... the sound of the sea is driving me mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector lingers.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Hector...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Ursula? Sleeping?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sick. She hasn't been able to rise since yesterday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This offer has found a chink in Francisco's armor.</context>
      <utterance>Will you share a bottle of wine with me? I've had it since we left the ship... I want to drink it tonight, with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a bottle of wine?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, fetch it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco sips the wine with the relish of long abstinence.</context>
      <utterance>You should hang for this. Some people on the raft might have lived with a glass of this in their stomach...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector pulls a cotton bag from under his coat.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I feel very guilty. I brought this too...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco can't believe such food still exits. He smiles in anticipation.</context>
      <utterance>Honeyed fruit. The last I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco grabs at the bag and stuffs two or three sweets into his mouth, not so much the gentleman now.</context>
      <utterance>You rogue... give it here...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco talks through his munching.</context>
      <utterance>I brought it for Ursula...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Much too rich for her... do you want to kill her?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surely... some fruit couldn't...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't argue with me, old friend... you're the guilty one around here, and don't you forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is it always me? Why am I always guilty, always sorry... am I so bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is silent.</context>
      <utterance>With Ursula you weren't bad, you were stupid... you did the one thing you can't do to a strong woman... you took away her pride... what else can she do but hate you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>what a fool...</context>
      <utterance>And then you get on the same ship...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to get home... just like you...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when the ship went down... why did you have to get on the same raft... it was as if you were trying to torment her...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... the other raft was sinking...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco's face breaks into a smile. They drink the rest of the bottle in silence, the complexity of their friendship having gone beyond words.</context>
      <utterance>Francisco... please...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SLAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... they will look after the sick... but the King would like one thing... the machine that makes music...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need food as well... ten cows... to take with us... then the King can have the music.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must come with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>do you understand that?</context>
      <utterance>Your mother might not get well...</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I have to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And afterwards... what will you do then?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Follow you and the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nuno remains silent.</context>
      <utterance>Alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FATHER DIOGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll comfort them as best as I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father Diogo hastens to correct this misunderstanding.</context>
      <utterance>You're staying with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER DIOGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two sailors, like stagehands, enter and remove the table, leaving Dom Paulo and Father Diogo propless on the beach.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, I'll comfort them before we leave. I think my place is with you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Francisco... I have to see her before we leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco goes into the hut. Hector waits outside, watching the small human dramas all around him. Soon Francisco emerges from the hut.</context>
      <utterance>I'll ask her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector goes into the hut, stooping low at the small entrance.</context>
      <utterance>In you go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns her eyes to him but doesn't speak.</context>
      <utterance>Ursula... it's Hector.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice is a whisper.</context>
      <utterance>We're leaving soon. I've come to say goodbye...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>URSULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't forget you... I won't forget India... I can't forget how I hurt you... She looks at him but doesn't or cannot speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She manages a whispered word.</context>
      <utterance>We should have talked... I could have explained... many things...</utterance>
   <speaker>URSULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lisbon...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lies still. Hector lingers for a moment. Then he speaks again.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... I'll pray for you in Lisbon... at the Cathedral...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector has blown it. Ursula pulls herself up on an elbow, finding wells of energy from sheer indignation. Hector is astonished, almost jumping out of his skin.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I hurt your pride...</utterance>
   <speaker>URSULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What did you say? What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ursula speaks one word, and then falls back into a dead faint.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing, nothing...</utterance>
   <speaker>URSULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lies still. Hector leans over her to make sure she is still breathing. He whispers nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Idiot!</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ursula?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won't forget you, or what you are doing for these poor people...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not staying here with the intention of dying, Dom Paulo... we'll be following you... when we are fit and well...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They make what they both know is their final parting.</context>
      <utterance>... and good luck to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>God protect you... it breaks my heart to leave you all here, but I don't know what else I can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're leaving the cross with you...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOM   PAULO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector comes out of the hut, solemn-faced.</context>
      <utterance>It's too heavy to carry... and who knows... it might make some impression on the heathens.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Francisco, I must talk to you alone...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I think so...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank, God... Well, goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there anything that I can do for you? A letter... a message? Francisco laughs softly.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector smiles uncertainly, unsure if Francisco is making a joke. Then he becomes more serious.</context>
      <utterance>No... if you were carrying something for me I would have to worry about you... if you go empty-handed I can put you out of my mind!</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to ask you something. There's no easy way to do it...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on, Hector...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco looks down at his boots.</context>
      <utterance>Your boots...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about them?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector lifts a foot to show Francisco his boot. Francisco is stunned into silence. But then a smile comes to his face.</context>
      <utterance>Can I have them? You can have mine... they'll be fine for here... but I have to walk six hundred miles...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you're right... I daresay my boots would take you six hundred miles... I look after them... Hector becomes almost poetic in his pleading.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll walk all the way home, Francisco... I'll pray for your soul in the Cathedral in Lisbon...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... In my boots...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco starts to laugh out loud.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco starts to take off his boots. Hector does the same. He can't believe his luck. At this moment, he loves Francisco. He makes nonsensical small talk, hopping around on one foot.</context>
      <utterance>Hector, you have surpassed yourself... sit down and take my boots!</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco is giggling now.</context>
      <utterance>They were made by Da Fosca, weren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco is laughing, but Hector doesn't get the joke.</context>
      <utterance>The best bootmaker in Goa... pray for my soul in Lisbon, Hector... and pray for your own...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've been gone a week, at least.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn them...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other. They are in trouble, and now they know it.</context>
      <utterance>We're ten days late...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll start on a fire...</context>
      <utterance>Cheer up. Have a look around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Sandy's... whiskey...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector walks to the fire, pleased with himself. Bobby unfolds his fist and looks at what he has found, an Indian arrowhead with a few inches of broken shaft. He folds his hand over it again, keeping his secret. Behind them, nailed to a tree, is a plaque their companions have left. It reads, "Pennsylvania Boundary Expedition 1761, Marker 152." Also on the plaque someone has written, "We left here, 20th October."</context>
      <utterance>Well done, my lad!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if we lose their track, we'll still hit the river... we can't miss that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too high for Indians?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Much too high. You won't find an Indian up here. We just have to keep our heads... no panic.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you did find an Indian, what would he be?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't... but he might be a Delaware if you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We keep working?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their forced tone of matter-of-factness only serves to heighten the growing feeling of doom.</context>
      <utterance>Why not. We can log the peaks on the far side, just a couple of sightings a day... keep us busy...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think we'll get out?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we keep our heads. I wish I had some tobacco.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector writes it in the log book. Bobby goes to the horse and takes a brass chronometer from a box strapped to the saddle. Hector takes out a smaller chronometer from his own pack. They compare readings. There is a difference of some four or five minutes in the time.</context>
      <utterance>Barometer... twenty-eight and three-eighths... temperature... low... thirty-four... high... forty-two and a half... time...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's getting worse... you're nearly five minutes fast now...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not fast... you're slowing down. They obviously have this tiff every morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the point of having two chronometers when you don't take the average?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly... you should throw yours away.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector writes in the book. He speaks pointedly.</context>
      <utterance>You're unscientific, Bobby... at heart...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby mocks him with a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Seven twenty-five...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice rings sharply around the forest. Hector far ahead turns around, taken by surprise. Bobby has frightened himself too. He eyes the forest all around as the echo of his voice fades. Chastened, he begins to sing again, quietly this time, under his breath.</context>
      <utterance>I see her in the dewy flowers I see her sweet and fair...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's not a bonny bird that sings But minds me o' my Jean...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure this is a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hastily dismantle the equipment and load up the horse, in an atmosphere of controlled panic.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Indian backs off from them, holding his hands up and smiling crazily, as if to say, "Don't mind me, boys, I'm just leaving..." Hector and Bobby are equally silly in their response.</context>
      <utterance>Hi! Hello!</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>goodbye...</context>
      <utterance>Hey, come back... we're just moving through... don't apologize... we all got a fright...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was stupid...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I saw him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was he a Delaware?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the fuck should I know? He was an Indian... and Indians don't come in ones...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I think he was an Indian too... What about the horse?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going back down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't panic, Bobby...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs off into the forest. Then he turns and shouts to Hector.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector follows him, a mad race through the forest.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same as you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An Indian... with long hair...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it... kind of short...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... he was't tall...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector scans the hills above them.</context>
      <utterance>That's the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move off. Bobby looks at Hector's backpack.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get a bit further up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What've you got in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some food, the logbooks, my letters, a candle...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won't have a fire tonight. We should make a shelter though, in case it snows.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby laughs quietly.</context>
      <utterance>What about bears, without a fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't even think about bears, Hector.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at Hector, and allows himself a small smile.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's lost too... on his own... must be Delaware... they were chased up here years ago... everybody thought they'd cleared off west... the other side of Ohio... they were an angry lot... no wonder... they used to farm on the coast.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Go on, read it out...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No... not tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector gives in. He holds a scrap of paper close to the candle and reads.</context>
      <utterance>I've had to listen to it every night since April... why not now?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks up at Bobby.</context>
      <utterance>Dear, Father, I miss you. Three frogs are dead. Everybody misses you. Bring me a bear's head and claws and a gun. School is good. Miss White has married a fireman. Come back soon. Do not worry about the frogs, they did not have names. Nathaniel.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not so funny now as it was.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't funny then.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you knew him... if you could picture him saying it... it would be funnier.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a father like you... nine months on a whaler and then three weeks at home telling us all how much he missed us...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby doesn't pursue his argument. He tenses, then sniffs the air vigorously.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going home, for the winter...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smell it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector sniffs some more.</context>
      <utterance>Goddam it... smell it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Tobacco?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his head out of the shelter.</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell is it coming from?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He huddles back inside the shelter.</context>
      <utterance>I can't tell... a night like this it could carry for miles...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I had a smoke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a wedge of tobacco. Bobby takes it.</context>
      <utterance>I was saving it... you have it...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, you were saving it? You know the rules... no hoarding, tobacco or food... you've listened to me for a month, day and night... wanting a smoke...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>take it...</context>
      <utterance>Well have it now... I don't smoke...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've kept it from me, and you don't even use it...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I was going to give it to you then...</context>
      <utterance>I was saving it for my birthday...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to wait until your birthday for a smoke? Who are you... the fucking king?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on, smoke it... have it now...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a brooding silence.</context>
      <utterance>I bloody won't... I'm not smoking on your command... I bloody won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, your poor children... what do they have to do for a piece of candy in your house? It's very hard to like you sometimes... d'you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>come on... smoke your pipe...</context>
      <utterance>I know, Bobby... but that's how I feel about you, too... that's why we're friends... we try hard...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I'll have it in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby does, and then breaks into a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Come on... tell me... who would you rather be sitting here with... have a think...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector smiles, too.</context>
      <utterance>Daniel Boone?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. He would be a help... but after Daniel Boone...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Bobby grows shy of their growing intimacy.</context>
      <utterance>I can't think of anyone else... but you're impossible to like sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Hector has other plans. He is in control of their friendship now.</context>
      <utterance>We should sleep. We've got a lot of running to do in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby yields to this with the softest, most vulnerable smile we have yet seen on his face.</context>
      <utterance>No we're not... we're going to talk... all night...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby is silent, but still smiles his acquiescent smile. Hector reads the silence well.</context>
      <utterance>So... where do you want to start?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby is still silent.</context>
      <utterance>I know where you want to start...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alicia...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... what about Alicia?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby is mischievous now.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, you're sorry... I'm the one that has to apologize...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It will be a worthwhile night for both of them.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no you're not...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector finishes his writing, tears out the page from his book. He offers it to Bobby.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't it a beautiful day?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've said who we are and where we're headed. Want to sign it, write anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The peak we logged yesterday... I've named it Nathanial Mountain. After my boy... is that fine with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was going to call it Tobacco Mountain... or Mount Alicia... but Nathaniel's fine...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get away from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>North?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby walks off with great clouds of tobacco smoke billowing defiantly around him, as if to challenge their night-time tormentor. Hector takes a last look at their shelter and its little memorial cairn and then runs to catch up with Bobby.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Keep the sun on our backs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector ducks lower, hugging the ground. Bobby is already sliding up the slope to look over the rise. Hector follows him.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet. They're on the other side...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're right in the middle of them...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it have to be bad? They might be friendly...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby turns to Hector to make his point. That is when he sees the first of the figures, just the ghost of a shadow moving from tree to rock. His eyes flick across the forest behind them. He sees another figure caught in the act of seeking cover, looking absurdly embarrassed for the fleeting moment that we see it. Then Bobby sees another. Are they teasing them? It looks so much like a game children would play.</context>
      <utterance>They were chased here... They should be on the coast growing corn...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks and sees nothing. Fifty Indians hold their breath. The forest seems empty. But Hector looks at Bobby. He is grey-faced, a man who is looking at death. Hector knows they are doomed.</context>
      <utterance>They're behind us. They must think we're stalking the women...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to run?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do what you do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When they catch up... fight... it'll be quicker... fight like hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector stretches out an arm to Bobby.</context>
      <utterance>They're not going to catch us. We're going home.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hold hands and run.</context>
      <utterance>Hold my hand, Bobby...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know the lady, Mr. Troup?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think you'll go to jail again?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look here for a second, will you, Mr. Troup?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you talk to us when you come out?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The paramedics turn around and head back down the stairs. Hector looks at the Policeman curiously.</context>
      <utterance>You guys are downstairs... third floor... thirty-eight...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue climbing.</context>
      <utterance>You're forty-eight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A DETECTIVE is with another man who looks like a city official.</context>
      <utterance>This is Troup!</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector joins them.</context>
      <utterance>Come here, Troup. I'm Cobb.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bring everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Building warrant, license, fire certificate, sanitation certificate... I want them all... This is Mr. Santiago, from the city... insurance...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't really my building... it's my partner's... I just took the call and came right over... I have to leave town in an hour or so anyway...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Slow down, Troup... so it's 3:15 on a Friday... you're staying here 'til Mr. Santiago gets the paperwork... get your partner over here, with everything... this is serious...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might have to close the place down.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Detective and Hector walk down the hall. They stop at the door of the bathroom. Hector looks inside. There is a large ragged hole in the floor. At the far side of it the toilet unit dangles at a dangerous angle into the hole, held only by its plumbing. Firemen are working to secure it and what is left of the floor with metal props and hydraulic jacks. Lying on the floor below, surrounded by rubble, and being attended by the paramedics, is an old lady, MRS. PHILIPPOPOLIS. She tries to sit up when she sees Hector peering at her over the rim of the hole. She looks angry.</context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PHILIPPOPOLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I phoned you Monday... I told you the floor was making noises...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Detective and Mr. Santiago. The Detecitve is unimpressed.</context>
      <utterance>Not me, Mrs. Philippopolis... my ex-partner... I think you spoke to him... How are you feeling? Hector says this clearly, for the benefit of the</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back from there, Troup, the floor's still moving...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why don't they move her?</context>
      <utterance>I'll make a couple of calls... I'll straighten it out... is she bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They waited for a portable X-Ray machine... they can move her now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if in response, Mrs. Philippopolis shouts up to Hector as she sees him leaving the bathroom above her.</context>
      <utterance>She seems in good spirits...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PHILIPPOPOLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait 'til my son sees his mother lying here like this... he's gonna sue you... you're a lousy landlord... you should be ashamed... to let old people live like this... I phoned you Monday... I have a witness! I was dancing with a prince on my eighteenth birthday, and now look at me... you have me falling down a toilet!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finishes the call just as Santiago approaches, waving his notebook now full of incriminating notes.</context>
      <utterance>Anna... thank God... you have to help me... I'm still in Queens... I've got cops here and everything ... I need your car... I don't have time to pick up the rental now... they won't let me leave the building... you come down here... and put my bag in the car... no.. I have to pick the kids up by six, otherwise I fuck up her weekend too... she'll kill me... this is an emergency... what can I say? Please... right... okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like water rotted the floor... You have any plumbing maintenance records?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santiago is talking almost to himself now, absorbed in the mundane mechanics of Hector's building.</context>
      <utterance>At the office... I might have some bills... it's not my building.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector shakes his head wearily.</context>
      <utterance>It's a weird one... I don't know how water could sit in there for so long without somebody noticing ... you didn't use water-resistent paint on the ceilings did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't really know...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to have to check out the whole building... you know that, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I do it Monday?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good joke... it'll take you a month.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment's pause.</context>
      <utterance>Can I speak with Leonard, please... Mr. Deutsch? My name is Hector Troup, Borlonski and Troup, Real Estate...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the call Hector has walked down the hall and back to the hole in the floor. He sees Mrs. Philippopolis, now strapped in a stretcher, being carried out of the room below. At the sight of him, she tries to sit up, straining on her straps.</context>
      <utterance>Leonard... it's Hector... Borlonski and Troup... yes... listen, we've had a domestic accident at our Eighth Street building... a floor ... and an old lady... she did mention the word sue, but it might have been hysterics... what I need to know is what certificates you have on file for the building... I know it's Friday... just do one thing... let me know if the insurance is current... I need to know that... I'm on my mobile... anything you have... before five ... thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PHILIPPOPOLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son's downstairs... when he sees me like this he'll kill you... go on... jump through the hole... see what it feels like! Break both legs! Hector is almost tempted to do what she says.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Troup, I'm George Philippopolis.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about your mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... it's happened... you want to travel with us, or do you have a car?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the hospital...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I wasn't planning to...</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not making a visit to the hospital?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Son addresses the Policeman.</context>
      <utterance>I've talked to your mother, given her my best wishes... she wants her family with her now... Any other Friday but this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Policeman looks at Hector.</context>
      <utterance>He's not coming to the hospital...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop is enjoying his role as straight man to these two. Hector takes out his diary.</context>
      <utterance>That could look bad...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>lots...</context>
      <utterance>Look, George... here's what I can do... I'll visit her on Tuesday, I'll organize some flowers...</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screw the flowers... who's gonna check her into the hospital... who's gonna pay? It's your building that fell down...</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He nods his head to the Policeman.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Policeman this time backs him up.</context>
      <utterance>They won't let me leave here...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Son backs off to the waiting ambulance reluctantly.</context>
      <utterance>That's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait 'til they hear this in court ... he wouldn't even make a trip to the hospital... Can't you even give me a credit card number?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's never been this bad, Boris. Deutsch is checking the insurance... did you bring the rest?</utterance>
   <speaker>BORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... we're covered for most things... the license is current, the inspection certificate is okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with the we... it's your problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>why did you do this to me?</context>
      <utterance>She's a witch... her bones must be made of steel... she didn't break a thing... it might help if you make a visit to the hospital...</utterance>
   <speaker>BORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector doesn't let up on his anger.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Hector... I just put your name on the lousy forms... I didn't plan this... I just borrowed your name on the titles.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boris is conciliatory.</context>
      <utterance>I told you to stop doing that... why does this keep happening to me... my name is mine... use your own name, Boris Borlonski... will you remember that? Boris Borlonski!</utterance>
   <speaker>BORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is calm now. We can sense real depth in their relationship, despite Boris's pranks.</context>
      <utterance>Hector... forgive me... I'll take care of it... don't let it spoil your weekend... four years, huh? You make the most of it... and don't worry, you'll walk away from this... I'm sorry...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm sorry too... you have to get out of this business... I thought I had...</utterance>
   <speaker>BORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on... have a great weekend... I'll talk to you on Monday... we'll straighten everything out...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the worst it's been.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Hector's girl friend ANNA arrives in her car. It is a bright pink station wagon, highly decorated with flower motifs and slogans like "ANNA'S ARRANGEMENTS," and "FRESH OR DRY, WE'LL PLEASE THE EYE." Anna is a florist. Hector brightens when he sees her. Everything is falling into place. All he has to do now is cross two rivers and Manhatan Island in under an hour, in Anna's pink car. He runs to meet her.</context>
      <utterance>Everything can be fixed... always.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector gets into the car, smiling broadly.</context>
      <utterance>Get in... you can dropp me at the shop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bring my bag?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Your camera's in there too. Take some photographs of the kids...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nervous?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much... just like I'm being executed...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our Hectors have been hearing this for centuries, but at least Anna smiles when she says it.</context>
      <utterance>Well you deserve to suffer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry... this is the beginning of something... not the end... you can start being a father again.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you talked me into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't do much... you were ready...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna is looking at him amusedly, nodding her head with every earnest pronouncement that he makes.</context>
      <utterance>You're right... you're absolutely right... I was ready... I am ready, for everything... I'm fixing all that shit with Boris... I told him... it can't go on... I want my freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and the kids... that'll work out... we can have them over sometimes... Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure... that was the plan... when we have the space...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>together...</context>
      <utterance>Right, when we have the space... when we get the bigger apartment...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is pleased with himself.</context>
      <utterance>There you go... you said it... the bigger apartment together...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I said it, didn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is high on his optimism now, and cheeky with it.</context>
      <utterance>You're a man of decision, Hector...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna pulls into the curb. Hector leans over to embrace her before she has stopped the car.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I am... Together... I said it ... and get out of my car at the corner here... I don't have the time to go 'round the block.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>everything...</context>
      <utterance>Thanks... for the car...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She indicates a massive bouquet of flowers wrapped in cellophane, taking up the whole of the luggage space in the car.</context>
      <utterance>Do the best you can with them, Hector... and one more thing... deliver these...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Anna, I can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks him straight in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Here's the address... just two blocks before the bridge... a five minute detour. It's a golden wedding... you have to...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector accepts this.</context>
      <utterance>We have to help each other...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him quickly, but lovingly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you'll need gas too... Go to it, Hector...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts loading up the car. Janet talks to Hector.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Hector.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You made it. The kids are just coming. They're not over the moon about going to the beach house. I ought to warn you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you say? I could have fixed up something else. I thought it would be a good place to get to know them again...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shouts into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I figured you should be allowed to make your own mistakes. It's only for a couple of nights, they can take it... and you'll learn... Check into a hotel if it gets too much... they like hotels.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands Hector a piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, you two... your father's ready to go...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector gets a little scared about what he has taken on.</context>
      <utterance>This is where we'll be, if anything crops up... thanks for the break...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet doesn't let him off the hook.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe this is a bit sudden for them... Maybe I should have come over a couple of nights and got to know them...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the children come out of the house, BETSY, who is about thirteen, and TOM, who is eleven.</context>
      <utterance>By Monday, you'll know them...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to Hector.</context>
      <utterance>Here he is, the invisible dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is daunted by how grown up they are, not any more the little kids in the photograph in his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>That's what they call you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hardly lift their heads to him.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet takes control of the farewells.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector nods his head obediently. He always did with Janet. The children let their mother pat them and follow Hector to his car, eyes to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>You three have a good weekend. If it's too miserable at the house your father said he'll take you to a hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donald shouts from behind the wheel of his car, where he has been hiding.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Hector.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids load themselves into the back of Hector's car. Betsy notices the huge arrangement of flowers, wrapped in cellophane and red ribbon. It seems to have grown even larger than before.</context>
      <utterance>See you Monday, Hector.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks at the flowers. His face contorts in guilt and anxiety.</context>
      <utterance>Are those for mom?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no... Jesus save me... what have I done...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up his mobile phone and is about to dial Anna's number, then he stops.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the kids.</context>
      <utterance>No... I can't face it, not just now...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets connected.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, kids... I have to consult the oracle...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy and Tom are listening in the back seat, eager for clues about this virtual stranger in front of them.</context>
      <utterance>Hello... God? No, Leonard, it's Hector... just a joke... sorry to phone you at home, did Boris call you? The insurance is fine? Good ... but she could claim negligence ... oh, she's got a lawyer already? That's a bad omen...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>'bye...</context>
      <utterance>Is there anything we can do right now... make her an offer... Sure, with the insurance company... sure... you're right... me, too... I have the kids in the car with me right now... sorry to bother you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They return his look with blank expressions. He picks up the phone and offers it to them.</context>
      <utterance>That's it! The last call... the weekend starts right now... we have things to do... look out for a Safeway... we need some supplies... and gas... oh my God, gas... soon...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Want to make any calls? Betsy?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... and it's Thomas...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we called you Tom... that's what it says on your birth certificate...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode>TOM</mode>
      <context>Hector wisely lets it go.</context>
      <utterance>I changed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right... it's your name... you can do that... Safeway... keep your eyes skinned... and I could murder a Chicken McNugget.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy is defiant.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with that? It's a kitchen roll... why can't I pick a kitchen roll?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up a more friendly brand of kitchen towel from the shelf and throws it into the cart. Hector has the sense to back down.</context>
      <utterance>It's bleached... and it isn't recycled... you don't care... you just buy junk...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy keeps on the attack.</context>
      <utterance>Good point, Betsy...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She prods a packet of frozen hamburgers.</context>
      <utterance>Everything you buy is junk... I don't eat steak... and what's this...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A trace of girlish common sense has crept into her voice. Hector warms to her.</context>
      <utterance>Ugh! Why don't you ask us what we like... it'll save you money... you buy junk, we won't eat it...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector pushes the cart to her.</context>
      <utterance>You're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy moves off with the cart.</context>
      <utterance>Well, get to it... I'll just tag along...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do it every week anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector follows them up the aisle.</context>
      <utterance>She does. She tells us what to eat. We let her.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I just keep a couple of those steaks? We can't live on chicken.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to bring the flowers in?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mention the flowers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="169" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TV MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is good, Tony, the stones are talking to me already... now here's something... travel... movement... Tony, are you planning a move... travel... anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I am... I've been thinking about a move to California...</utterance>
   <speaker>TV MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The big one, eh, Tony? These stones are really talking here... what are you planning for yourself in California?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hoping for an acting career, Mel...</utterance>
   <speaker>TV MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Perhaps this might have enthralled one of our earlier Hectors, but our modern one is simply restless. He stands up and leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Tony, these stones really like what you're planning... there is no doubt in my mind about that... now listen... you have to be specific... these stones really want to tell you something, be it love, money or the purpose of your life... but I want a specific question from you... think about it... what do you want to know... love... or your income level next year? Be as specific as you can, Tony...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="170" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She changes in an instant from a bossy adolescent to a tearful, crumpled little girl. She sobs pitifully.</context>
      <utterance>Get me the books... all the books... all of the books... no, no, no... not the pancakes... not the pancakes... no...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is a confusion of feelings: frightened, fascinated, impotent. How can he help her? How could he possibly unravel the secret of the pancakes, what comfort could he offer his stranger daughter if he did? It is a spooky, mystical moment for Hector, more mystical than the mumbo-jumbo still issuing from the TV next door.</context>
      <utterance>... not the pancakes...</utterance>
   <speaker>TV WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Hector moves quietly out of the room, Betsy's sobs having subsided. Just as he is closing the door he gets another surprise, this time from the sleeping Thomas.</context>
      <utterance>... find your true cosmic partner first time around... every weekday morning at three here on the Psychic Network... Lucinda's Horoscope Dating Show... remember there is an answer, and there is a special partner out there for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector closes the bedroom door. He is one spooked, moved human being.</context>
      <utterance>... don't let the oil run out... yes you did... watch the oil... why... why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="171" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't eat eggs?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many have you got in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three. Is that all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector does a little probing.</context>
      <utterance>For a week, maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about pancakes, Betsy... d'you like pancakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much... why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wondered. Pancakes don't mean much to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't mean a thing. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mystery of Betsy's pancake dream is evidently lost in infinity. Hector changes the subject.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we could walk into town this morning. I saw the Funfair when we came through last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't go to Funfairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's take the walk anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is determined to make it work.</context>
      <utterance>I brought some books. I want to stay home and read.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. We're taking a walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="172" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going to rain... we should stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's an umbrella... and there must be some old coats in here... and shoes... I only have these I'm wearing...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas is already in the cupboard under the stairs. He emerges with a pair of sturdy walking shoes.</context>
      <utterance>Donald has some shoes...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I want to wear Donald's shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector declines to explain the complex reasons that he might have for not wanting to wear the shoes of his children's replacement father. He sits down on the stairs to put them on. Then something on the wall catches his eye.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids' heights have been marked on the wall on some long-ago holiday. The dates are beside them.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. Look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to a mark and a date lower down on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Six years ago. Look at that... What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was the flood. The sea came right up. Donald says it's the icecap melting. It's going to get worse. That's why Mom's selling the place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="173" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It comes up every year?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The last two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="174" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the birds? Is it the wrong time of year?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't come over so much. The shellfish have gone... that's what...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what Donald says?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks at the sky. He speaks quietly to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... and it happens to be true.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't rain... please...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="175" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has stopped at some dated space rockets.</context>
      <utterance>Let's have a ride...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector triumphs. He pulls a wad of kitchen roll from his pocket and starts to wipe the seats.</context>
      <utterance>The seats are wet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="176" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>re-cycled, biodegradable... dry seats... Betsy has the grace to smile as the three of them climb aboard the rockets. As the attendant releases the brakes and cranks them up into the drizzle, 'round and 'round, Hector knows that he has to do something to break the awful distance between him and his kids. He looks at them. They sit grimly in their rockets, one in front of him and one behind. Their faces are set in expressions of what? Boredom? Resignation? Patience? Expectancy? Then he realizes what is going on. They are waiting for him to open up to them, talk to them seriously, explain himself. He looks at Betsy's face and sees in it the years of his absence, her stoicism, her patience, her courage. It moves him. He leans over to her.</context>
      <utterance>Kitchen roll, unbleached,</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy smiles her small patient smile.</context>
      <utterance>This is ridiculous. Let's go somewhere and talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks to Thomas. Thomas vigorously nods his agreement. Hector is happier. He looks down on the decrepit fairground.</context>
      <utterance>All right, if you want to...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we land these things?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="177" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you won't have a pancake, Betsy? Betsy gets impatient.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="178" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids are ready for this. There is no coyness now.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, first question?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector begins like a story-teller embarking on a long saga.</context>
      <utterance>What he means is why did you stay away?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>she must have told you all that?</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's a fair question... your mother and I got divorced... you're big enough to remember...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure she has... but lots of people get divorced... that doesn't mean they disappear...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right... what can I tell you... I went kind of crazy after that, for a good while... I came around a few times... remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it wasn't easy... everything with her and Donald happened pretty quickly. I missed you both really badly... but for a while I thought I should stay away, until your mother got settled... no, that's not really true... I missed you... but I was kind of crazy at the same time... your mother and I married young... I wasn't used to the freedom... it went to my head ... then you moved to New Jersey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="179" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's forty minutes away on a slow bus...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right, you're right. I don't have too many excuses for the first year... the second year is easier... I was in jail. Hector is pleased with this. A solid excuse.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector thinks about this, remembering the pain. For us there is the echo of the real killing that was done long ago.</context>
      <utterance>We were doing government work, big contracts... there were some temptations... my boss asked me to shuffle a few papers... there was a lot of money in it... I had to testify against him... it was like killing somebody.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thomas wanted to visit you in jail, but Mom wouldn't let him. Hector looks at Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas nods proudly.</context>
      <utterance>You did?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I appreciate that... but I'm glad your mother didn't let you. I'll tell you all about it some day. It was no fun. One year and eight months.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't even know when you got out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="180" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids look shocked at this.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't in great shape... I sure didn't want you to see me then... so I got back to work... in real estate... found a partner, we met in jail...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He's a good man, a good man. I like him. I mean it. He's my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what you do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy shrugs her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. We rent apartments... but we want to get into commercial property... people are a nuisance... does that sound bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector carries on with his story.</context>
      <utterance>How should I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>so here we are...</context>
      <utterance>Just recently I've been feeling good, things have been going well... and I missed you two...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about your girl friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you about her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids smile.</context>
      <utterance>Anna... she's nice... she wants to meet you, real soon... she sells flowers... well, you know that... and on Monday she's probably going to kill me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="181" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betsy thinks that was her at the gas station...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector has to think to remember.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Tom...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... heck... no... did you think she was following us?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's always thinking up stories like that... she never stops...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if people don't tell you things...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's right, Thomas... people should talk more.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you haven't been staying away because of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have almost exhausted themselves in this first bout of talking. Hector looks out at the sea.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? Is that what you thought? I was avoiding you two? No... you mustn't think that... that's terrible...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rain's off. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="182" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to ask you something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="183" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is moved by the depth of her memory, her pain.</context>
      <utterance>Why did you leave just two days before my swimming test?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't leave because it was two days before your test... it was just what your mother and I decided... I taught you how to swim... we went to the pool twice a week... why would I leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks at Betsy. She is beginning to cry silently. He puts a tentative arm around her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I know... that's what I mean... why did you leave just then?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy is still crying.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, Betsy. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you do, in the test?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector leaves his limp arm on her shoulder. It is too soon for gestures of emotion. After a long moment she speaks.</context>
      <utterance>I passed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector doesn't make the obvious comment. His emotions are full. He hides his feelings in a gruff call to Thomas.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a life-saver now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Thomas! We're going home... we're having a barbecue... Betsy said she'll even let me eat a steak!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up, Tom!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="184" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't call him Tom, he doesn't like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somehow Hector is touched by this.</context>
      <utterance>I'm allowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mother said it, when we split up... don't lose the children... didn't mean much at the time. But she was right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a silence. Then Hector speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Who said I'd let you eat a steak?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betsy. On Monday will you come with me when I take the flowers back to Anna? I can't face her alone. She wants to meet you anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be there, right beside me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd have to take the morning off school.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy and Hector are quite close now.</context>
      <utterance>No, that could be good...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell them you were with your invisible dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="185" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she like? How did you meet her?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy looks at him kindly.</context>
      <utterance>The funny thing is I fell in love with her before I ever saw her... I smelled her... It was the day I got out of jail... I was on the train and she was sitting behind me... it was just this incredible perfume... remember I'd been inside for nearly two years with four hundred sweating males... She got off the train and I followed her... I couldn't help it... that's how good she is... she listened to a bum who followed her off a train...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share a laugh. Betsy looks out to the ocean.</context>
      <utterance>... but she's still going to kill me on Monday...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll paint the sunset tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy doesn't take the bait. There is a silence.</context>
      <utterance>It's just like a big pancake up there, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember when you two were tiny.. I used to watch you sleeping... it was like now... I felt close to you, could touch you... but you weren't there... you were gone... dreamland ... just when I was closest to you, you weren't there... I felt it last night, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what it's like... you should know that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="186" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not smart about things like that, usually.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be so tough on yourself. You seem to want to be... you don't have to...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. Hector is out of his depth with this daughter of his.</context>
      <utterance>No... we can do that...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector looks at her in wonderment. One of those moments when another human being stands before you and is an utter mystery.</context>
      <utterance>No, I mean it... look out for yourself...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you? Who's inside there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Future generations of women are going to be just as unknowable to our Hectors as past ones were. Betsy moves off briskly along the beach. Hector trails after her, hooked.</context>
      <utterance>You'll never know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="187" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's been a while... you're bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose so. He's getting fat, too. I bet I could beat him at the breast-stroke now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="188" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They call back to him.</context>
      <utterance>Come on in, kids... that boat doesn't look too safe...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector tries to relax, but he doesn't have the confidence yet, or something. He is edgy.</context>
      <utterance>We're fine!</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks down to the water. The kids reluctantly pull on the oars and bring the little boat in. A few feet from the beach they hit some sand. The boat sticks. Hector wades out in his shoes so far. Then he calls to Thomas.</context>
      <utterance>I've just found you... I don't want to lose you. What would I tell your mother... come on in...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas throws the mooring rope to Hector. It isn't attached to the boat. Hector ends up with all of the rope in his hands. He stands there, and they all laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Throw me the rope, Thomas, I'll pull you in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just for a moment we have the image of our Hector standing on the shoreline with a length of rope. An image with an echo from six thousand years ago. But this time Hector is laughing, and his kids are safe.</context>
      <utterance>This is one useless piece of rope, Thomas...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="189" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas is laughing at her. He has seen her attempt this before. Hector has other concerns. He is trying to light his barbecue. Match after match disappears into his elaborate stone structure, only to fizzle out. The sun finally vanishes, and Betsy goes limp at her easel. The sun has won the race again. She and Thomas watch Hector trying to light the fire. After a while he is conscious of their amused attention on him, then he becomes a little self-conscious.</context>
      <utterance>Why does it always go so fast...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh a little.</context>
      <utterance>I used to know how to do this...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wafts and blows ineffectually at a flicker of flame. There's not much of the caveman about him now.</context>
      <utterance>I did... I used to be really good at this...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="190" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector serves the chicken onto their plates. He sits down beside them with his steak, and a glass of wine. He watches Thomas attack his chicken, and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Ah... smell it... the smell of civilization... scorched meat...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd forgotten that... how you eat... dedicated... like it's your religion!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things I like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="191" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas tries it out, eating and humming. It feels good to him. His head nods with the chewing and the tune.</context>
      <utterance>You used to hum to yourself too, when you ate... like everything was fine with the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The early stars are appearing in the sky. Hector lifts his eyes to a bright point low on the horizon.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, so I did... I'd forgotten about that...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There she is... old Mercury...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is impressed by his son.</context>
      <utterance>No... Mercury doesn't rise 'til after midnight... that's Jupiter...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd forgotten... we used to watch the stars... you could tell me the names of all the planets... you could recite them like a poem... remember... at the tiny window upstairs in the old house?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh well, not to worry. I'm glad you still like astronomy though.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not into star-gazing so much ... we're working on computer modelling... we're trying to make a biosphere...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A self-sustaining life system... for inter-stellar travel. But we always get a methane build up, it doesn't matter what we do...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="192" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is at school?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We're making such a mess of the world, one day we're going to have to take off for somewhere else...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector realizes how far his kids have travelled from him. He looks at them.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds like Donald said that...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy chimes in.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm glad you two are thinking about the old planet. I'm proud of you. Look how beautiful everything is. Sometimes I think it's people that make it all wrong... we walk around with all our problems...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector stands to fetch another baked potato from the fire. We see the three of them in a WIDE SHOT, the evening sky now pulsing with more and more points of light. Hector's voice and laughter carry to us.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. If it wasn't for us there'd be nobody around to see it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector has come to rest, and found peace at last, however temporary, here on the beach, beneath the same stars that our first Hector wailed at six thousand years ago. On Monday he will face the music. The kids will go back home, Mrs. Philippopolis will have to be dealt with, and the wilting three hundred dollar bouquet of flowers. In general, life will take over, on Monday. But at this moment of calm on the beach, let's leave him while he's ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, you two... I'll tell you... it's just a big, black sheet up there with holes in it so the light comes through... that's the truth... the very latest...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="193" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute... I know... the whole universe is inside a speck of dust that's lying in a ball of fluff in the cuff of a pair of pants hanging over the back of a chair...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three of them are laughing now.</context>
      <utterance>No... I'll tell you... the whole thing... stars and everything... is sitting on the skin of a bubble of milk in a bowl of cornflakes... and somebody's just about to eat it...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skimmed milk...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't get bubbles in skimmed milk...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perhaps that's just about as close as Hector and his tribe of humans will ever come to working it all out. But they try.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... it's half-and-half...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a better one... we're all inside a speck of pollen that's stuck to the wing of a bee while it sits on a flower...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then, after a long, long pause.</context>
      <utterance>Don't mention flowers, Betsy... please, not tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have an idea, Betsy... we're inside a pancake... what d'you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="194" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you always talking about pancakes... what's wrong with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got pancakes on the brain.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
