<movie id="72" title="Beloved">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>The boys look up the stairs and see their baby sister, nine year old DENVER.</context>
      <utterance>Bul?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The brothers are brokenhearted at the sight of her. They love their sister. But there are stronger forces here. A MIRROR on a wall beside Howard cracks down the middle.</context>
      <utterance>Where you goin?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bulgar looks up to Denver. They exchange a look of deep affection and pained longing. He wants to take her.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta go!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye, Denver. You take care.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bulgar is starting to cry. He rushes up the steps and hugs his sister. He kisses her hard then breaks away. Denver's outstretched hand misses his shirt and hangs mid-air.</context>
      <utterance>Bye? Bul?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bulgar flies down the steps and disappears out of the house holding Howard's hand once more. Denver sits alone at the top of the stairs. She sadly looks up and weeps, as if to the house itself:</context>
      <utterance>No..Bul...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what you go and do that for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe is placing folded laundry into a dresser. She stops and checks her pockets for rags or swatches...She looks around the room..</context>
      <utterance>Ya know what I'd love to see? I loved to see me some lavender. You got any lavender? Or even pink - pink'll do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suggs goes back to contemplating her green until;</context>
      <utterance>Ah, winter in Ohio is especially rough if you've got an appetite for color.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Suggs looks up to see Sethe sticking her pink tongue out at her. Suggs smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Oh wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe lets out a small laugh. She walks toward the window, stretching her body. Her expression changes as she thinks of her boys. Baby Suggs reads her like a book.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's fine. Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll be all right. I'm surprised they lasted here this long.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Maybe we should have moved.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd be the point? Not a house in the country ain't packed to the rafters with some dead Negro's grief. We lucky our ghost is a baby. My husband spirit come back? Or yours? Don't talk to me! Ha..You lucky. You got one child left, still pullin at your skirts. Be thankful. I had eight. Eight with six fathers. Every one of them gone from me. Four taken, four chased and all, I expect, worrying somebody's house into evil. My first born - alls I can remember of her now is how she loved the burned bottom of bread. Her little hands..I wouldn't know'em if they slapped me. Can you beat that? Eight children and that's all I remember.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember Halle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I remember bits and pieces of all of'em I guess..Halle, of course..I had Halle a lifetime. Almost twenty years... My two girls, sold and gone before I could even a heard about it, and them without their grown up teeth yet. My third child, my son after Halle...I let that straw boss have me for four months so's I could keep that boy. Next year, he had him traded for lumber anyway and me pregnant with his child. I couldn't love that child. I wouldn't. Not any of the rest either. God take what He would....and He did...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boys wouldn't have left if Halle were here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe's mixed feelings show all over her face. Although she loved Halle, there is clearly something unresolved in her.</context>
      <utterance>Those boys didn't even know him. You had six whole years of marriage to my Halle Fathered every one of your children. A blessing. I learned hard that a man's just a man, but a son like that...like Halle..now that's somebody.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe exits.</context>
      <utterance>Just got a few more things to do, then I'll start supper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think maybe when daddy comes, he could talk to the baby ghost. Maybe make her behave and then people won't be scared of here no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why won't she ever settle?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's mad like a baby gets mad. You forgetting how little it is. She wasn't even two years old when she died. Too little to understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a baby she throws a powerful spell.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more powerful than the way I loved her. Hearing her mother say this, moves Denver.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you pray for Mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't really pray anymore. I just talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, about time. How some things go. Pass on. Some things just stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What things?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like, the place I was at before here - Sweet Home. Even if that whole farm and every tree and blade of grass on it died - it'll still be there. Waiting. And if you go and stand in the place where it was, what happened there once, will happen again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's still there, waiting, that mean nothing ever dies?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's why you can never go there.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing ever does. That's why I had to get my children out. No matter what.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never tell me all what happened. Just that they whipped you and you run off pregnant with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't need to know nothing else.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw a white dress kneeling next to you when you was praying.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Describe it to me.</context>
      <utterance>White? Maybe it was my bedding dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had a high neck. Whole mess of buttons coming down the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What else?</context>
      <utterance>Buttons. Well, that's not my bedding dress. I never had a button on nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bunch at the back. On the sit down part.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bustle?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what it's called.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say it was holding on to me. How?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kneeling next to you while you were praying. I mean, talking. It looked just like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll be.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it was a sign. I think maybe baby's got plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What plans?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but that dress holding onto you got to mean something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe smiles sympathetically for her lonely child. They hear a sound in the house - floor boards creaking.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Maybe it does.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe nods and holds her daughter's hand as they listen.</context>
      <utterance>She's crawling again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul? Paul D.? Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How you been girl, besides barefoot? Sethe jams her balled up stockings into her pocket. She smiles like a little girl, not able to believe her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What's left.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You looking good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Devil's confusion. He lets me look good long as I feel bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long has it been?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Bout eighteen years, I figure.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighteen years.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins taking off his shoes.</context>
      <utterance>And I swear I been walking every one of them. Mind if I join you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to soak them? Let me get you some water.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, uh, uh. Can't baby feet. A whole more tramping they got to do yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You stay awhile.</context>
      <utterance>You're not leaving right away, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, long enough to see Baby Suggs, you..Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw no. When?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight years now. Almost nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it hard? I hope she didn't die hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soft as cream. Being alive was the hard part. Sorry you missed her though. Is that what you came by for?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe doesn't know what to do with her eyes when he says this..she looks away instinctively. Paul realizes that may have sounded too intimate so he leans back and sighs:</context>
      <utterance>That's some of what I came for. The rest is you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truth be known, I go anywhere these days. Anywhere they let me sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like a nervous little girl, Sethe takes a sit beside a man for the first time in years, folding her sweat stained skirt beneath her.</context>
      <utterance>Porch is fine. Cool out here. Sit with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Baby Suggs is gone. Somehow never thought death would find her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It finds everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We managed well enough without meeting it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Awkward pause. Sethe tries to find the words to a difficult question - but one that is foremost in her mind;</context>
      <utterance>I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul knows instantly she is asking about Halle.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't have to ask about him, would I?...You'd tell me if there was anything to tell, wouldn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something about Paul's expression might suggest he's keeping something from her. He turns his gaze outward as he says;</context>
      <utterance>You know I would. But I don't know any more about what happened to Halle now than I did then.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must think he's still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I think he's dead. It's just not being sure that keeps him alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did Baby Suggs think?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same. Ha, listen to her, all her children dead and she felt each one go the very day and hour it happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When she say Halle went?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1855. Same day my baby was born.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had that baby, did you? Damn, never thought you'd make it. Running off pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had to. Couldn't be no waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All by yourself too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost. A white girl helped me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Awkward silence.</context>
      <utterance>Then she helped herself, God bless her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got spare rooms. You could stay the night, if you had a mind to.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't sound too steady in the offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul smiles a warm, touched smile that after all that they've survived, Sethe is worried about what he'll think of her home.</context>
      <utterance>Oh it's..it's truly meant. I just hope you'll pardon my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe smiles, then rises to escort him in.</context>
      <utterance>My house. I like the sound of that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got company?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The light undulates faster and faster, extending all the way to the kitchen at the end of the hall. Frightened, Paul steps back out the door.</context>
      <utterance>On and off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good God! What kind of evil you got in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe reaches out her hand. Paul tentatively takes it and is lead through the red light of the hallway, through to the kitchen where it ends. As he walks through, we can see Paul affected by the light. It is sad. A sadness that touches him, welling up inside until tears are brimming in his eyes. He reaches the normal light of the kitchen and steps out of it.</context>
      <utterance>It's not evil..It's just..just sad. Come on. Just step through.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you said she died soft as cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh that's not Baby Suggs. That's my daughter. The one I sent ahead with the boys before I run off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't live?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boys too?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still affected by the light, Paul eases himself down at the table, finding something to say.</context>
      <utterance>No, they alive - they run off before Baby Suggs died. The one I was carrying when I left Sweet Home is all I got left.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, probably best..If a Negro boy got legs he ought to use them. Sit down too long, somebody figure out a way to tie them up.......  You by yourself then?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me and Denver... my daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No man?  And that's all right by you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She places a bottle and a glass on the table before him. The light jarred him. He snatches the bottle to drink and calm himself down. She jokes.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right by me...I cook at a restaurant in town. Sew a little on the sly....</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look more done in by a walk through my front hall than all those eighteen years of walking put together.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got that right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="60">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs down the white staircase.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Denver appears expectantly, down the white staircase that leads from the second floor. She looks at Paul wide eyed. They turn to her with gentle smiles;</context>
      <utterance>Won't you stay a little while? Can't nobody catch up on eighteen years in a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, this here's Paul D. Garner...Paul, this is my Denver...Paul's the last of the Sweet Home men. Denver's heart sinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning Miss Denver. It's a pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Mr. D.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Garner, baby. Paul D. Garner.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad to get a look at you. Last time I saw your mama, you were pushing out the front of her dress. She's a fine looking young lady, Sethe. Fine looking. Got her daddy's sweet face.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew my father?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knew him. Knew him well.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Denver reacts with surprise and dismay. Paul is not her friend. Paul, right now, is more of an intruder.</context>
      <utterance>Of course he did. I told you, he's from Sweet Home. Paul may stay with us a while. Won't that be nice, having an old friend stay a spell?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's all right with you, that is?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a ghost here, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We met. But sad, your mama said. Not evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir, not evil. But not sad either.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What then?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lonely.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see how it could be lonely spending every minute with us like it does.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my sister. She was just a baby when she died in this house.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Used to roam them woods regular.</context>
      <utterance>Reminds me of that headless bride back behind Sweet Home. Remember that Sethe?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama doesn't like talk about Sweet Home. Says it was never sweet and it sure wasn't home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girl, mind yourself!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, now, she got it right there, Sethe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's where we were. All together. It's where I met your father. And it comes back on us whether we want it to or not....</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe pauses - unnerved and irritated by Denver's challenge.</context>
      <utterance>Then why don't you ever tell me about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Denver, start up the stove. Paul must be hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go to no trouble on my account.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bread's no trouble. The rest I brought back from where I work. Least I can do, cooking dawn to noon, is bring dinner home. You got any objections to pike?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He addresses his humor to Denver who offers no response. She crosses to the stove and works on lighting it. She's mad.</context>
      <utterance>If he don't object to me I don't object to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's he going to sleep? Baby Sugg's room got no sheets or nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll figure it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should stay with mama, Mr. Garner. Then you two can talk about Sweet Home all night long.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you! I never knew you to behave like this!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave her be, Sethe. I'm a stranger to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver collapses where she stands, sobbing out loud. Sethe moves to her.</context>
      <utterance>That's just it. She got no cause to act up with a stranger.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver moves away. Sethe registers this rejection.</context>
      <utterance>Baby, what is it? Did something happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't no more! I can't no more!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't what? What can't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't live here! I don't know where to go or what to do but I can't live here. Nobody speaks to us. Nobody comes by. Nobody even knows I'm alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What she talking about 'nobody speaks to you'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the house. People don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's you!</context>
      <utterance>It's not! It's not the house! It's us!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Denver!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave off, Sethe. It's hard for a young girl living in a haunted place. That can't be easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver allows herself to be held.</context>
      <utterance>It's easier than some other things. Come here, baby..</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a grown man with nothing new left to see or do and I'm telling you it' ain't easy. Maybe you oughta move.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sethe!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No moving. No leaving. It's all right the way it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to tell me it's all right with this child half out of her mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What tree, Sethe?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What tree on your back? I don't see nothing growing on your back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's there all the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>White girl. That's what she called it. I never seen it and never will. But she said that's what it looked like. A chokecherry tree. Leaves, branches. That was 18 years ago. Could have cherries by now for all I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe pauses. Something in her decides to tell Paul D, although she keeps working on the bread to stay in control;</context>
      <utterance>I don't follow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul listens, half dreading where he thinks this story's going.</context>
      <utterance>I had milk, see. I was pregnant with Denver but I had milk for my baby girl that I sent ahead with the boys. I hadn't stopped nursing her when I sent her and the boys ahead of me. Anybody could smell me long before they saw me. Nothing I could do about it. All I knew is I had to get my milk to my little girl. Nobody was going to nurse her like me. Nobody was going to get it to her fast enough or take it away when she had enough..nobody knew she couldn't pass her air if you held her up on your shoulder, only if she was lying on your knee..Nobody knew that but me...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe works faster. It is the work, taking an action - any action - that allows her tell the story numbly, without the pain of reliving it...without the images attacking</context>
      <utterance>We was talking about a tree, Sethe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT: FLASHES OF MEMORY attack as SETHE TELLS HER</context>
      <utterance>Schoolteacher's boys drag me into the barn and took my milk... ....yet, the images come anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>IN KITCHEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..Held me down in that barn and took it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>IN KITCHEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were like boulders on me. Their hands over my mouth and on my shoulders and my legs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told Mrs. Garner on them. She had that lump on her neck and couldn't speak but her eyes rolled out tears, I remember. Them boys found out I told on 'em and Schoolteacher made one open up my back, and when it closed it made a tree.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They used cowhide on you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they took my milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They beat you and you was pregnant?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe has separated the dough into biscuits which she slips into the stove. As she rises, Paul steps gently behind her. He slowly caresses her breasts from behind, pressing his cheek against her back.. He rubs his cheek against it, feeling the scars beneath the dress. Raising his fingers to the hooks, as Sethe cries silently, he undoes her dress which slips down to her hips, exposing the sculpture her back has become.</context>
      <utterance>And they took my milk!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grateful to have her body be someone else's responsibility for the moment, Sethe closes her eyes as Paul touches every ridge and leaf of her tree with his mouth. The tenderness is almost unbearable. Suddenly, PAUL'S LEGS BEGIN TREMBLING. He pauses and looks down...He realizes it is not his legs that tremble, but rather;</context>
      <utterance>Aw Lord, girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A table rushes at him but Paul grabs it's leg. Managing to stand at an angle as the house continues to pitch, he holds the table by two legs and bashes it about, wrecking everything, screaming at the house;</context>
      <utterance>GOD DAMN IT! HUSH UP! Leave this place alone! Get the hell outta here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you...take a rest..I'll call you when we're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you don't want me to help clean up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand in silence, looking at each other for a moment. The awkwardness they both feel strike them suddenly as funny. Paul starts smiling. Sethe covers her mouth to conceal it. And then, just as quickly, the urge to laugh subsides - and the fear they feel takes it's place. Paul slowly closes the door and places his shoes on the floor. Sethe watches him. Paul crosses to her. He moves in to kiss her. They approach each other's lips like two burn victims, trying desperately not to hurt the other with their touch.</context>
      <utterance>No..you'd just get in my way. Denver and me'll do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here?! out in the open?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe looks and can see nothing through the corn stalks. She shakes her head no.</context>
      <utterance>Look around - can you see anybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off his shirt. Seethe giggles as she gets on the ground, keeping her ankles crossed. Halle lays her back and gently separates her legs. She giggles. Halle pauses before laying on top of her.</context>
      <utterance>Then nothing can see us neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are a beautiful sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sings the word "life", so that Sethe laughs. Then, Halle lowers himself slowly to her and they begin to make love. As camera pans up to a HILL above the field, we hear Sethe ask;</context>
      <utterance>You're my wife now! I can talk as stupid as I like about you!  I ain't never loved nothing like you before, Sethe.  And after I get mama out...then I get us out too. And you'll see, baby girl...  we're gonna have us a liiife..</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We hear Halle grunt "uh-huh" as we arrive on the hill where a GREAT TREE sits.</context>
      <utterance>You sure nobody can see?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAUL A</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't see nothing so special about Halle.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL F</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about what he's doing for his mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL A</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fool thing, if you ask me. By the time he buys it, freedom won't mean a thing to somebody that old and worn.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men watch the corn stalks swaying to the lovemaking. A YOUNG PAUL D., in particular, watches with tender yearning.</context>
      <utterance>Freedom mean something anytime it come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. GARNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men looks to each other, suppressing a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Raccoon must've got into my corn. Damaged a few so, no use throwing them out...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GARNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks at each other as they thank No. Garner and begin to smear butter on their corn and eat. A NEIGHBORING FARMER visiting the Garner's cautions him;</context>
      <utterance>Sethe, get the butter there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBORING FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You spoil these nigger boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bought 'em thataway, raised'em thataway.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you got boys on your farm. My nigger's are men. Not a boy among'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBORING FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beg to differ Garner. Ain't no nigger men.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if you scared. But if you a man yourself, you'll want your niggers to be men too.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBORING FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't have no nigger men around my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe hides a smile as she hands a piece of corn to Halle. Paul A and Paul F hesitate as they think of eating the corn which the lovers consummated. But Sixo digs right in. Paul D eats slowly, his eyes never leaving Sethe as she moves Around the kitchen, her eyes never leaving Halle...Paul's Attraction and love for her are apparent.</context>
      <utterance>Neither would I..Neither would I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sethe.  I was thinking of looking for work around here. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't much. River mostly. And hogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul moves to where Sethe is sitting.</context>
      <utterance>Hogs is fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe realizes what he is asking and tentatively responds:</context>
      <utterance>I don't need much, Sethe. Eat, sleep, sing a little when it strikes me. I don't ask for more to..to live somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. It's...it's fine with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your girl Denver. Seems she's of a different mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about her. She's a charmed child. Nothing ever touch her too bad. From the beginning. Everybody I knew dead or gone, but not her.  You got to know something, though - this here ain't no better life. It's just not that other one. What I do here - all I ever do - is keep Denver from that other..So if you stay, there's no more talk about Sweet Home or anything else. I won't let the past in my yard again. Getting me and Denver through this here life is all that matters. You understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dangerous to love anything that much, Sethe. Best thing is to love everything just a little bit..that way, when it breaks or runs off or gets taken, well maybe you'd have a little love left over for the next one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There ain't no choice here.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be asking me to choose, Paul D.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Sethe is frightened by the prospect of feeling for him.</context>
      <utterance>That's the whole point. I'm not asking you to choose. Just want to know if there's some space for me. Want to know if it's more than "you can stay", "it's fine"..more like, "I want you here Paul".</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe rises to enter the house when Paul's words stop her:</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should leave things the way they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We get along.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't go inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sethe, if I'm here with you, with Denver, you can go anywhere you want. Jump, if you want to, 'cause I'll catch you. Go as far inside as you need - I'll hold your ankles. Make sure you get back out. I'm not saying this because I need a place to stay. I told you, I'm a walking man, but I been heading in this direction for seven years. When I got here and sat out there on the porch, waiting for you, well, I knew it wasn't the place I was heading toward. It was you. We can make a life girl. A life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe's heart is twisted. She wants to cry...because she feels hope...and because she feels fear.</context>
      <utterance>Leave it to me. See how it goes. No promises, if you don't want to make any. Just see how it goes, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. We'll see how it goes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You willing to leave it to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well..some of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe manages a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Some?...Well okay...some.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Nothing's wrong. Lay back down. Denver obeys, unsure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think baby ghost's really gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe lets out a small laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I miss her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hear Paul singing out on the porch. Denver grimaces.</context>
      <utterance>I do. Baby Suggs told me baby ghost would never hurt me. She was my sister. When I was little, after the boys left, I used to think that she and me both were waiting for daddy to come. And once he did, she wouldn't be mad no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish he'd shut-up...He's ruined everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver's eyes light up with excitement then caution.</context>
      <utterance>No, he hasn't. He won't.  He..he wants to takes us to the carnival next Thursday...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean, go out where they'll be other people?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you think?</context>
      <utterance>Dress up a little bit. Wear our hats.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe....</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(she stops)</context>
      <utterance>Maybe...All right...all right.  Can I ask you something?  I was wondrin'..What you think about us...maybe... maybe thinking we could start...if we got an idea to, thinking we could start.. countin' on...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe can barely bring herself to say. To hope. To imagine. Paul? But, for Denver, she forces herself and whispers;</context>
      <utterance>On what mama? Countin' on what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver heart almost weeps with joy. Sethe walks cautiously. Overdressed for the occasion, it is her first outing among neighborhood folk in many years. She catches the eyes of some of the women she knows...ELLA and LADY JONES..good Christian women who nod in their acknowledgement yet are holding back something. A judgement? A repulsion? Paul doesn't notice them and for this Sethe is glad. MONTAGE of SCENES...the various carnival acts, all performed by a WHITE TROUPE; magic, clowning, fire swallowing, spitting ribbons, acrobats forming pyramids... Our trio take it all in like water to the thirsty. At one point, A WHITE CARNIVAL BARKER shouts to the children;</context>
      <utterance>Hey Denver!...Hi there Denver!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARNIVAL BARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phrase stabs Sethe and Paul a bit. But Paul whispers;</context>
      <utterance>All Pickaninnies free!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe can't help but let out a small laugh - and with that laugh, a sudden sensation of relief... Paul buys Denver some licorice, peppermint and lemonade. Holding the lemonade for her, Paul asks;</context>
      <utterance>Two pennies and an insult well spent in my opinion to see the spectacle of whitefolks making a spectacle of themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver agrees. Paul takes some lemonade then wipes the rim where he sipped with a small napkin and gently hands it back to her. Denver, in spite of herself, is starting to like him.</context>
      <utterance>Mind if I take a sip?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young Woman shakes her head NO. She reaches down and takes off her shoes, which Sethe notices as new. Sethe bends down to pick them up. The Young Woman never lets her eyes leave Sethe.</context>
      <utterance>You from around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those shoes look brand new.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What might your name be? The Young Woman speaks in a low, rough voice;</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe drops the shoes. Denver sits down. Paul smiles;</context>
      <utterance>Beloved.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beloved. You use a last name, Beloved?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(she spells it)</context>
      <utterance>Last. No..just Beloved..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Beloved has fallen asleep upright in the chair.</context>
      <utterance>That's a pretty name Beloved. Take off your hat and I'll make us something. We just got back from the carnival over near Cincinnati-</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes open to slits. Paul is about to help her when Denver rises;</context>
      <utterance>Miss...Miss, you want to lay down?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take her up. She can sleep in baby Suggs room - that all right Mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver eases Beloved onto her feet, which Sethe and Paul notice do not have a line or sore on them.</context>
      <utterance>Course.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like the croup.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she feverish, Denver?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. She's cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then she is. Fever goes from hot to cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could have the cholera.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver helps her up the stairs. Sethe and Paul register Denver's defensive reaction.</context>
      <utterance>She's not sick!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beloved? Beloved I'm here...what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heavy..this place is heavy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved shakes her head no. She takes hold of Denver's arm and wraps it around her own body. Denver sits up against the pillow as Beloved snuggles her body into Denver's arms and falls back asleep. Denver holds her, lovingly.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to sit up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..then you fold it over like this see. This here used to be where my brothers and me slept. I was always at the top.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you get so smart?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't so smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I used to go to Lady Jones. She'd teach us with songs how to spell and count.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't go no more?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I...I had to stop going.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You so smart. Tell me about your brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Denver continues, Beloved steps towards her and begins to touch her face - examining her lips, her nose, her skin as if it were a rose to admire. Denver drinks in the attention, her heart expanding with love with every touch from this strange creature.</context>
      <utterance>Well..they're names were Howard and..</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..and....and Bulgar...At night, we used to..crawl into bed together..I'd lay down on Bul's lap and Howard would tell us die- witch stories. He said they would protect us...And if I learned them, they would protect me if ever they were gone...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna just feed her, from now on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Denver likes her. She's no real trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But don't she have a home? Some place to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't mention one. I thought we'd wait until her breathing got better. She still sounds a little lumbar.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She breathe like she can eat, she could blow this whole house down. And all those sweets.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes the body needs that sugar for strength when it's trying to recover after an illness.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's just it. She don't seem sick. Something funny about her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny? How?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Acts sick, sounds sick but she don't look sick. Good skin, bright hands and strong as a bull.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can hardly walk without holding onto something.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I mean. Can't walk but I passed by Baby Sugg's room this morning and saw her lifting the rocker with one hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, Denver passes by on her way to the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me. Ask Denver. She was right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver enters the keeping room.</context>
      <utterance>Denver. Come in here a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver looks at Paul with a hard gaze;</context>
      <utterance>Paul says you saw Beloved pick up the rocking chair in Baby Suggs room with one hand. That so?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From Paul's expression we can tell Denver is lying...and whatever fragile connection they were building, is swiftly destroyed.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't see no such thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen her? I can't find her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe shakes her head. Denver exits anxiously. The mentions of Beloved's name stir a MEMORY in Sethe:</context>
      <utterance>Beloved.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Engraver eyes her body.</context>
      <utterance>She need a marker. Somethin' to tell me where she is. But I ain't got no money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGRAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe is embarrassed by his lascivious tone, especially in front of the young boy. The Engraver rises, takes a step toward Sethe and touches her hip, curling his hand around to her back.</context>
      <utterance>What you got then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGRAVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you want it to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking what the preacher say at the funeral. Dearly Beloved.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!...I didn't know you were there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved kneels before her on the floor and finishes buttoning up Sethe's night dress.</context>
      <utterance>Help what, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you go in the morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Work. I work in a restaurant.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved nods, absorbing the information.</context>
      <utterance>Little after the sun come up. I like to make a loaf of bread before I go. How you feelin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember your mother at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe, nods, understanding such things. She cautiously reaches out to stroke Beloved's face. Beloved responds like a puppy, pressing her cheek against Sethe's hand. Sethe is moved.</context>
      <utterance>I remember a woman who was mine and I remember bein snatched away from her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The question surprises Sethe...and startles Denver.</context>
      <utterance>Where your diamonds?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Diamonds? What would I be doing with diamonds?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On your ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish I did.  Hmm..come to think of it, I had some crystal once. A present from Mrs. Garner - woman I worked for at Sweet Home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never saw you with no earrings.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gone. Long gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me...Tell me about your diamonds... Sethe hesitates. Beloved kneels at her feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma'am don't talk about Sweet Home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver is both interested and slightly hurt at her mother's willingness to tell Beloved what she'd never tell her:</context>
      <utterance>Well..this lady I worked for in Kentucky gave them to me when I got married..</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..What they called married back then. I remember going up to her in the kitchen to tell her. I'd help her make ink for Mr. Garner in the kitchen. I was fool enough to think I was going have some kind of ceremony...maybe even a new dress..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best unbraid that hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today's always here. Tomorrow never.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comb it everyday, it won't..</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All three look to Beloved, puzzled by her question, which is clearly intended for Sethe. Paul's getting more annoyed.</context>
      <utterance>Your woman never fixed up your hair?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved nods. Paul and Denver exchange a curious look.</context>
      <utterance>My woman?..You mean my mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she did I don't remember. I don't think I saw her but a few times.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul and Denver look to Sethe, waiting to see if she'll answer.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me 'bout her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is disturbed by Sethe's carefree storytelling - how it contradicts her words to him that first day and worried it will lead to no good... Once again, Denver is surprised to hear what she's never heard before. She looks to Paul and knows what he is thinking. Paul looks back and knows Denver realizes it. But Denver returns his glance with a defensive dismissal of the eyes.</context>
      <utterance>..I remember once, she picked me up and carried me behind the smokehouse... The only thing I do remember in fact...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...She opened up her dress and right on her rib, right here, was a circle and a cross burnt right into the skin....</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sethe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul doesn't want her to continue but doesn't want to say so.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe rises to get him more food and she continues:</context>
      <utterance>Any more beans?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...anyway, she points to this mark and says to me "This is your ma'am. I am the only one whose got this mark now. The rest all dead. If something happens to me and you can't tell me by my face, you can know me by this mark"..Scared me so... I couldn't think of anything to say so I said "Yes Ma'am..but how will you know us? Mark me too. Mark the mark on me too."</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is disturbed. He can see Sethe getting upset. He is mad at Beloved for her damn questions..</context>
      <utterance>No. She slapped my face. I didn't understand it then. Not until I had a mark of my own...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something inside of Sethe stops, a wall erected. Something unwanted is coming into her consciousness. Paul notices it. She rises;</context>
      <utterance>What happened to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe collects a few dishes and crosses to the sink as Paul asks:</context>
      <utterance>Don't know. Everybody done?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera follows Sethe as she arrives at the sink, placing the dish inside. We hear the others O.S.:</context>
      <utterance>Well, as long as we're all asking questions, getting to know each other..  Why don't you tell us a little bit about yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She don't remember nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You be surprised what you start remembering once you start talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Camera stays on Sethe as we drown out the voices at the kitchen table. She is staring out the window above the sink as if watching the MEMORY BEING RELIVED IN HER YARD;</context>
      <utterance>Can I have some more pudding?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little Sethe looks up and sees her mother - her face a mask of courage and rage and tears. She looks straight ahead - not at anyone in particular, especially not her daughter.</context>
      <utterance>That's your mama - right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The child Sethe listens, watching her mother move further down the line. END of MEMORY as WE CUT BACK TO:</context>
      <utterance>..I'm telling you, small girl Sethe...Me and your Mama was taken by the men many times..She threw them other babies away..the others from the whites, without names, she threw them away..But you she gave the name of the black man. She had her arms around him, child. The others, she did not put her arms around. Never...Never...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't you got no brothers or sisters?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She finds Paul interrogating Beloved who eats a second pudding. Denver tries to interfere.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has us now!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been here five weeks, we still don't know nothing bout you..</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, Stop it. Denver bring those dishes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was you looking for when you came here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place. I was looking for this place I could be in.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the sink, both Sethe and Denver pause, obviously interested.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody tell you about this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul looks quizzically at Sethe, who shrugs;</context>
      <utterance>She told me. When I was at the bridge, she told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be somebody from the old days.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you come? Who brought you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I walked here. A long, long, long, long way. Nobody bring me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had new shoes. If you walked so long why don't your shoes show it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul D. stop picking on her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to know! Where'd you get them shoes and that dress you had on?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, she begins to CHOKE on a raisin from the pudding and falls backward, off the chair. Denver and Sethe rush towards her. Beloved thrashes around until they help her turn over and spit up the raisin. She breathes in Sethe's arms as Denver wipes up the mess, glaring at Paul.</context>
      <utterance>I take the shoes!  I take the dress!  The shoe strings don't fit! I...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to go to sleep now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe gets Beloved to her feet. Denver takes her up the staircase to her room - glaring at Paul. When the girls have gone, Sethe turns on Paul as she cleans up.</context>
      <utterance>Come to my room. I can watch out for you up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand what the hold is. It's clear why she holds onto you, but I just can't see why you holding on to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you care who's holding on to who? Feeding her is no trouble. And she's nice company for Denver.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We was just starting to feel a little like a family ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what's got your teeth on edge?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't place it. It's a feeling in me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna feel somethin!? ... Feel how it is to have a bed to sleep in and somebody there not worrying you to death about what you got to do each day to deserve it. And if that don't get it, feel how it feels to be a colored woman roaming the roads with anything God made liable to jump on you. Feel that!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know every bit of that, Sethe. I wasn't born yesterday and I never mistreated a woman in my life!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that makes one of you in this world.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One? Not two.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not two!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Halle ever do to you? Halle stood by you. He never left you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha, what'd he leave then if not me, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know but it wasn't you. That's a fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then he did worse - he left his children.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>HE WASN'T THERE! He wasn't where he said he would be! I had to pack my babies off ahead of me, on their own, so I could stay behind to look for him...Underground agent said by Sunday we had to leave.. Sunday came and he wasn't there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He couldn't get out of the loft, I expect. Forgetting himself, Paul let that slip out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loft? What loft?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MEMORY TAKES OVER:</context>
      <utterance>The one over your head... The one in the barn. Sethe stops dead cold. It's no use...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He saw? He told you he saw?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me. The day I came here. You said they stole your milk. I never knew what messed Halle up. That was it, I guess. I seen him the day after you left. Says where you been Halle? All he says to me was "the loft". I asked him what he meant not going with you but he never answers me. But I knew was something broke him. Not one of them years of Saturdays, Sundays and nighttime extra never touched him. But whatever he saw go on in the barn that day broke him like a twig.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He saw them boys do that to me and let them keep on breathing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man ain't a Goddamn ax, Sethe. Chopping, hacking, busting every Goddamn minute of the day. Things get to him. Things he can't chop down cause they inside him. The last time I saw him, I knew he was broken for good...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say? Didn't you say anything to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>C.U. on PAUL who doesn't want to explain - or even remember - as we cut to:</context>
      <utterance>Couldn't?! Why the hell not?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Schoolteacher sold me to. Don't know what possessed me...Me and about 45 other prisoners were being walked from Kentucky to Virginia...then on to Georgia. Two places I don't ever want to see again. He is lead past the milk shed, when he sees: HALLE, alone with a crazed faraway look in his eyes, sitting by the butter churn. HALLE'S FACE IS COVERED WITH BUTTER AND CLABBER. He sticks his hands in the churn and continues to cover his face with the sticky, slippery, white substance covering his face and head, squeezing it through his hands. The White Men laugh. Paul is aching to scream out to him but the iron bit holds down his tongue. As Paul is lead past Halle, A ROOSTER named MISTER is SITTING ON A TUB in the sun shrieks with an almost arrogant glee.</context>
      <utterance>I tried to kill Brandywine - man</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears of rage and humiliation stream down Paul's face. He struggles to keep a view of Halle, until he is out of sight.</context>
      <utterance>Look at Mister there...  You go tell these niggers where to go there Mister! Crow'em right outta here! Mister crows and the white men laugh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to tell you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't plan on hearing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe, instead of collapsing from the information, she seems hardened.</context>
      <utterance>I can't take it back but I can leave it alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do that..let's leave it alone now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let it alone. Just sit down and leave it be! Yeah that would be nice. Would be even nicer to lose it altogether - if I had my choice. Halle did. Other people's brains stopped, went crazy. How sweet that would have been. Me and Halle squatting by that churn, smashing cold lumpy butter in our faces, not a care in the world..</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sethe, don't do this..</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe exits O.S. Paul is left alone on the porch until Beloved runs out of the house giggling with Denver in pursuit. As Denver passes, Paul sarcastically remarks;</context>
      <utterance>What a relief to just stop it all right there, huh?!! Close it shut! Squeeze that butter...But I had three children on their way to Ohio and nothing would have changed that! And you tell me he didn't leave me!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver gives him a quick, disdainful look, then continues after Beloved. The two girls run towards the woods.</context>
      <utterance>Guess she's feeling better, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you learn to dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her fists on her hips and skips.</context>
      <utterance>Nowhere. Look at me do this!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes Denver's hand and places another on her shoulder. As they dance, Denver laughs harder and harder - a giddiness from the dizziness and the gratitude she feels for Beloved's attention. They spin and fall to the ground, like two lovers nestled. Beloved catches her breath as Denver asks;</context>
      <utterance>Now you! Come on! Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you call yourself Beloved?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the dark my name is Beloved.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it like where you were before?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dark. I'm small in that place. I'm like this here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you cold?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hot. Nothing to breathe there. No room to move.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wait; then I got on the bridge. I stay there in the dark, in the daytime, in the dark in the daytime. Long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All this time you were on the bridge?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. After. When I got out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you come here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To see her face.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma'am's? Sethe's?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Denver takes a breath of courage to ask the question she's been longing to ask:</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Sethe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved looks at her and smiles. They are so close she leans in curiously and - touching Denver's face - kisses her on the lips.</context>
      <utterance>You my sister, ain't you? You really are.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't leave us, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Never. This is where I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiling, Beloved moves to touch Denver's cheek when suddenly, Denver sits up cross legged and urges Beloved;</context>
      <utterance>I knew it. I knew. First time I saw you and you said your name. And when you touched me - real gentle. And familiar. Like I'd felt that touch before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Beloved's face turns to rage as she rises up as well;</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell mama. You musn't tell her who you really are. I don't know what she'd do! Please, you hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me what to do? Don't never tell me what to do!?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But..but I'm on your side. I want to protect you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Beloved please! Don't go! I didn't do nothing! We were dancing! Don't go!....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..God lead you home... So now, lay'em down, child. Sword and shield..Don't study war no more. Lay all that mess down. Sword and shield...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe weeps...She slides to the ground and holds her head to weep. She covers her head from God and cries AS SHE LETS THE MEMORIES COME..memories she can no longer fight from coming;</context>
      <utterance>Lay'em down...sword and shield.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look there. A nigger. If that don't beat all... Sethe can not speak for fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe manages to control her breath and push out the word;</context>
      <utterance>Man, you 'bout the scariest looking something I ever seen. What you doing back up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy looks at Sethe's swollen, bloody flesh at the end of her legs.</context>
      <utterance>Running.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Them the feet you running on? My Jesus my...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I in Ohio?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohio! Fool girl - you in Kentucky. You 'bout a thousand miles from Ohio.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still in Kentucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got anything on you, gal, pass for food?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like to die I'm so hungry. Thought there might be huckleberries. That's why I come up here. You having a baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy doesn't know what to do with that information. So..</context>
      <utterance>I expect this baby ma'am is gonna die in these wild onions.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Any stands and looks as if she's about to leave when Sethe, feeling the girl is safe, stops her with a question.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I got to eat something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you on your way to, miss?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boston. Get me some velvet. It's a store called Wilson. I seen pictures and they have the prettiest velvet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boston - is that far?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Farther than Ohio.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be velvet closer by.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You ever touch velvet? Or even seen it?</context>
      <utterance>Not like in Boston. Be so pretty on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe desperately wants her to stay - to not be alone. Amy kneels back down to her, curious now;</context>
      <utterance>If I did, I didn't know it. What's it like?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What they call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lu.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you gonna do, just lay there and foal?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get up. Amy wipes her nose and looks up beyond Sethe.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a house back yonder. Well, not a house with people in it - more like a lean-to near the river.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make a difference, does it? You stay here, snake might get you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he may come but I can't stand up, let alone walk...and God help me, I can't crawl.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy helps Sethe turn over onto all fours.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you can Lu..come on..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She eases Sethe onto the leaves then lifts her feet onto the rocks.</context>
      <utterance>Never know it to look at me but I used to be a good size. Nice arms, everything. That was before they put me in the root cellar...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy props Sethe up from behind when she notices</context>
      <utterance>...Mama worked for these people here to pay for her passage but then she had me and died right after so I had to work for'em.. I was fishing off the Beaver once and a nigger floated right by me. I don't like drowned people, do you? Your feet remind me of him. All swole like.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe makes a tremendous effort just to turn to her side as Amy undoes her dress;</context>
      <utterance>You all bloody back here. Gal you a mess. Undo your dress - let me see.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy sees Sethe's back and, for a moment, is speechless. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Lord, I ain't never seen a poorer excuse for a-</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus...It's a tree Lu..A chokecherry tree. I had me some whippings but I don't remember nothing like this. Glad I ain't you.. what God have in mind I wonder. ...You thank your Maker I come along. Spiderwebs all I can do for you. What's in here ain't enough. I'll look outside...Maybe I ought to break them blossoms open and let the pus run..   That you ain't dead yet Lu's a miracle. Make you a bet..You make it through the night, you make it all the way...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUTTON EYES..."</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't up and die on me in the night, you hear me Lu? I don't want to see your ugly face hankering over me. If you do die, just go on off somewhere where I can't see you, hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy continues singing.....</context>
      <utterance>I'll do what I can, miss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause of me, you up and walking. See, Jesus - Lu made it through..I'm good at sick things, ain't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you good...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that all over your dress?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Milk..Got to get my milk to my baby girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got another baby waiting for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy doesn't know what to say, so she says:</context>
      <utterance>I think this one is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe keeps trying to walk;</context>
      <utterance>You hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't nothing but in a hurry, miss. Got to meet someone...help bring me and my milk to my baby girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say what?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured how...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe can't believe her eyes. She walks right into the water when suddenly, her own water breaks and her labor begins... She doubles up in pain;</context>
      <utterance>Jesus looking at you, girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe, on her knees, crawls into the boat and props her feet up. Water leaks in wherever it can, rising up as high as her waist. Amy takes her position to assist.</context>
      <utterance>What you doing that for!? Ain't you got a brain in your head? Stop that right now! I said stop it, Lu. You the dumbest thing on this here earth, LU!..LU!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe screams in agony as the child pushes through. Amy curses;</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus, I'm awful sorry 'bout the braggin...I need you here now..Come on Jesus...don't be getting lost on me now.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn daddies never around 'cept for the fun part. Biggest joke God made on woman was giving men the planters 'stead of the soil...!! PUSH!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Lord...She's never gonna know who I am. You gonna tell her? Who brought her into this world. You better tell her, you hear! You say MISS AMY DENVER. Of Boston.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's pretty. Denver. Real pretty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Headin cross?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody know you coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamp Paid raises his hand to stop her. He looks around to see that no one else is in sight, then motions for her to sit on a rock. As she does, he gets a water jug and hands it to her - she drinks like a madman in the desert. The Boys watch in fascination. Stamp Paid turns to one of them and says:</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir. My mother-in-law over in...</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take off that coat?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me? The Boy slips out of his jacket, complaining.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I gonna wear?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unties the baby from Sethe and wraps it in the coat.</context>
      <utterance>You want it back...</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..then you go head and take it off this baby. And if you can do that, then go 'way somewhere and don't come back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't move. They'll find you.</context>
      <utterance>Wait here. Somebody be here directly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. What's your name - so I can remember you right.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods as he and the boys exit.</context>
      <utterance>Name's Stamp. Stamp Paid. Watch out for that baby, you hear?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELLLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saw the sign a while ago but I couldn't get here no quicker.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What sign?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ella empties a sack with a wool blanket, cotton cloth, two baked sweet potatoes and a pair of men's shoes.</context>
      <utterance>Stamp always leave the old sty open when there's a crossing. Knots a white rag on the post if it's a child too.  My name's Ella..Where you headed?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother-in-law's. Name's Baby Suggs. She got my other three children I sent ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was this one born?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesterday. I hope she makes it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard to say.  Let's try to get these on your feet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Suggs welcomes Sethe into the house, kissing her hard on the lips....Sethe can't believe she's in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my Lord...My sweet Lord thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe looks at her with confusion and exhaustion.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Halle?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A flash of fear is quickly transformed into pragmatism.</context>
      <utterance>He wasn't there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he be along presently, I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the children?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now. You too ugly looking to wake 'em up in the night. First we get you well..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feel this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Suggs notices roses of blood on Sethe's back...She looks and covers her mouth when she sees the remnants of the whipping.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing..</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girl...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe picks her up and the tears flow. She can't stop kissing them - their necks, their heads, their hands...The Boys inspect her strange looking feet and ask;</context>
      <utterance>Already crawling - ain't that somethin? ..Come on, baby girl..right this way..Mama's waiting..</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pappie come?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Suggs seems doubtful but appreciates the lie for the children.</context>
      <utterance>Soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe hugs and kisses them as if for the last time - as if she still doesn't believe she can just get out of bed, walk downstairs and be with them. The Boys leave as Sethe cradles the Little Girl. Sethe anxiously undoes her dress and carefully guides her breast to the Little Girl. She winces with pain and smiles - she got her milk to her baby girl. Baby Suggs gathers the rags Sethe wore when she first arrived.</context>
      <utterance>All right boys - mama's home now, you be seeing her all the time..Go downstairs and get your supper...Go on...</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing worth saving here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Suggs finds TWO CRYSTAL EARRINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Oh wait..Look and see if there's something knotted up in the petticoat. Wedding present. From Mrs. Garner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be nice if there was a groom to go with it. What do you think happened to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. He wasn't where he said to meet him at. I had to get out. I had to. He'll make it. if I made it, Halle sure can.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe surrenders herself to Baby Suggs firm, safe hands - letting go of the "diamonds", one of which lands in the hands of the Little Girl...who plays with them in fascination...</context>
      <utterance>Whatever happens now...God lead you home. So now lay'em down Sethe...Sword and shield..Don't study war no more. Lay all that mess down. Sword and shield...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul sits in a tub under the white staircase. He smiles. Sethe is relieved...grateful to find him there, for her.</context>
      <utterance>Paul? Paul, you home?...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe smiles, almost in tears.</context>
      <utterance>Where else would I be on a Sunday off?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you come on in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul D. What if the girls came in?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't hear nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul D. stands up in the tub and holds Sethe against his wet, naked body.</context>
      <utterance>I have to cook.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you gonna cook?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I'd make some snap beans.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fry up a little corn?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her - and that's exactly what she wanted.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Paul...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm right here baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera slowly moves out of the kitchen as Sethe and Paul begin to make love, revealing; Beloved watching from the doorway, unknown to Sethe or Paul. She is disgusted, envious...and runs out..</context>
      <utterance>Thank you Lord.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caught off guard, Paul looks to Sethe - whose expression asks him to be nice.</context>
      <utterance>You have brothers or sisters?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>We don't talk about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is about to get mad when he looks to Sethe again, reels it back in and answers curtly, but politely;</context>
      <utterance>Sethe told us you been walking for eighteen years. Where you been all that time?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lots of places. I don't remember them all. Don't remember much about anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing his own words echoed back to him, annoys him.</context>
      <utterance>You be surprised what you start remembering once you start talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Paul focuses on his dinner, suddenly ill at ease. He can't help looking, covertly, at Beloved and finds Beloved staring right back at him...It makes him shiver.</context>
      <utterance>Well not me. What's gone is gone. No good come from bringing it back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul?..Paul?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmm. What?...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called you two or three times but I gave up round midnight. I thought maybe you went out somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn. I'm sorry honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe begins to make breakfast as Beloved enters the kitchen and sees Paul has slept in the rocker. She looks at him with a smile, as if she knows more than she's letting on. Paul registers the look.</context>
      <utterance>I'll make some breakfast - you get yourself washed up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WHITE GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Breakfast? Want some breakfast nigger?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hungry nigger?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The White Guard unzips his fly and undoes his pants and moves a step closer to the Black Man's mouth. Paul D. looks ahead, trembling...He vomits...The Guard steps away as another Guard steps in and hits Paul on the shoulder with a rifle..</context>
      <utterance>Here you go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved enters the cold room.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hoists up her skirt and turns her head away.. Paul stares at a silver lard can so as not to look.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to touch me on the inside part and call me my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When good people take you in and treat you good, you ought to try to be good back. You don't....Sethe loves you. Much as her own daughter. You know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She don't love me like I love her. I don't love nobody but her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what you come in here for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to touch me on the inside part.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever since you come here - feel like I got a new devil to face.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to touch me. On the inside part. And you have to call me my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul continues to stare at the lard can - like Lot's wife, he's fearful what turning to look will do.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't no chains on me no more. I don't have to do nothing...Now, go back in that house and go to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved moves closer, right up behind him, entwining her arms around his body, like chains..</context>
      <utterance>Call me my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Ain't no chains on me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Ain't no chains on me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears well up in his eyes. Paul can feel her warmth. He surrenders.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go if you say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved presses her body against his. He turns and grabs her, kissing her with a passion bordering on hatred.</context>
      <utterance>Beloved.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe appears, exiting the back door of the restaurant with a scrap pan in the crook of her arm. To her surprise. she finds Paul waiting for her.</context>
      <utterance>Look here Sethe..You ain't gonna like what I got to say but I got to say it...See, it's not the..a man can't...what I mean is, it ain't really me..see, it ain't weakness, the kind of weakness I can fight, that girl is doing it. I know you think I never liked her nohow, still don't, but she is doing it to me anyway. Fixing me, Sethe, she's fixed me and I can't break it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tosses the bones and skins from the scrap pan into a heap before four dogs who wait there as if by appointment.</context>
      <utterance>Man, you make me feel like a young girl, you coming by to pick me up after work. Nobody ever did that before. Better watch out, I might start looking forward to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She enters the restaurant. Paul watches the dogs eat - watching them getting what they wanted. Sethe re-appears with a cloth over her head.</context>
      <utterance>Got to rinse this out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get off early or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took off early.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a way of speaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not cut back?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe steps forward to hear what Paul came to tell her. There is no apprehension or anger in her look. Instead, a calm resolve - as if she were already able to accept whatever he had to tell her without it being anyone's fault. As if she already knew he cane to say he was leaving her. She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>No, no. They got plenty of work with them pigs..More they can handle. I just..  You ain't gonna like what I'm about to say, Sethe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul knows what she's expecting. And when he sees her diminished expectation, the melancholy without blame in her eyes....he can't tell her about Beloved. He is filled with respect and admiration for her in that moment. Something pops into his head and out of his mouth that wasn't planned;</context>
      <utterance>Well say it, Paul D...whether I like it or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you pregnant, Sethe. Would you do that for me? Sethe breaks up with laughter. Paul joins in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came by here to ask me that!? You are one crazy-headed man. You right; I don't like it!...Don't you think I'm a little too old to start that all over again? She slips her fingers into his.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul lifts them, putting the tips of her fingers on his cheek. He smiles broadly; She laughs, shaking her head. A burden transformed into a gift, so suddenly. They begin walking. Sethe and Paul catch and snatch each other's fingers, stealing quick pats on the behind, joyfully. Paul throws his arm around Sethe and squeezes. She lets her head touch his chest. They stop and stay that way for a moment - not breathing. Sethe closes her eyes. Paul looks up to the trees lining the roadside like defending arms against attack. Softly, suddenly, it begins to snow. Sethe opens her eyes:</context>
      <utterance>Think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mercy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been on my feet all day, Paul D.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where I been? Sitting down!?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They slow to a walk.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! I don't have the legs for this!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before she can stop him, Paul hoists Sethe up over his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Then give'em to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need some babies..somebody to play with in the snow.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sure would like to give it a try. Need a willing partner though.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue laughing and moving down Bluestone Road when they are jolted by the appearance of; Beloved. Waiting in her usual place for Sethe. Her hands wrapped in a long shawl, waiting to be given to Sethe. Her eyes only on Sethe, not even acknowledging Paul's presence. Sethe gets herself down from Paul.</context>
      <utterance>I'll say..Very, very willing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the shawl from Beloved's hands and wraps it around her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Crazy girl. You out here with nothing on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks on ahead with Beloved. Paul, suddenly icy cold and filled with anger, walks behind.</context>
      <utterance>You got to learn more sense than that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe and Beloved enter the house. As Paul approaches, he stops before Denver. Their eyes meet. Paul stares at her, as if to ask - "Who's ally are you?"...Denver, unnerved by his look, runs into the house. Paul waits on the porch until, a moment later, Sethe re-appears.</context>
      <utterance>Evening, girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if healed by her strength, Paul's face melts into relief.</context>
      <utterance>Now I know you not sleeping out there tonight, are you Paul D.?  You come upstairs tonight. Where you belong...and stay there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She likes him here...  Make him go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved didn't consider that. Her fingers move violently in her mouth as if something were bothering her...until, finally, she pulls out a back tooth...her lips slightly bloody.</context>
      <utterance>She'd be mad if he leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OOoo..didn't that hurt you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like my dreams...I get two dreams, see..One, I exploding...BUUOOGGG...The other I being swallowed. Sometimes it's hard to keep my head on my neck, or these legs connected to my hips...One day I think I might wake up and I'll be in pieces..  Maybe it's starting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh stop. It's just a tooth. Probably wisdom. Does it hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why don't you cry?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved, eases herself into Denver's arms, and cries...</context>
      <utterance>If it hurts, why don't you cry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you think about Schoolteacher?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He white, ain't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, is he different like Mr. Garner was?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was he different?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Garner too.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he and Mrs. Garner - they ain't like other whites I seen before. Mr. Garner always spoke soft, for one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't matter. Loud or soft, what they say is the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Garner let you buy out your mother. Found that house for her to live in from those friends of his in Ohio...</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. He did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he hadn't, she would have dropped in his cooking stove.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still, he did it. Let you work off her fee, lending yourself out on Sundays. He could of said no. He didn't tell you no.</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he didn't tell me no. She worked here ten years. If she worked another ten, ya think she would have made it? I pay him for her last years and in return he got you, me and three more coming..</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He always treated you fair. Called you all men - said he never wanted niggers on his farm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just it. We was men because he said so. We was men because we was on his land. You think he be calling us men if we ever walked off his land?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we walk, don't matter what they call you. You'll be free.</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sethe..baby girl, that ain't gonna happen. Not by walking, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That phrase "..while the boys is small"..causes Sethe to look at her sleeping boys..</context>
      <utterance>Schoolteacher in there told me to quit lending myself out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Halle raises himself up to face her, to give her the final blow.</context>
      <utterance>But..then..how you gonna buy yourself out? Or them?  Or me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe understands, looks to her sleeping children and is frightened.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't gonna be no buying us out, like I did with mama. Or them. As far as Schoolteacher concerned, ain't no other life ahead for any of us but this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Halle....what we going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixo, ya know he creeps out at night..he says the way they took my ma'am..he says freedom is that way. He and Paul A. got a plan. They heard of this man, what they call an underground agent...if we do what he says, don't need no buy out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What'd they do to us? To the children?</context>
      <utterance>You mean...? But what if we caught?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same thing they're doing now, honey - only quicker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCHOOLTEACHER</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Hearing her name, Sethe stops and peeks through the window. Schoolteacher is standing over the student, who has been writing in a notebook. Schoolteacher licks his finger and thumbs a couple of pages before saying;</context>
      <utterance>Sethe?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHOOLTEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Although Sethe doesn't entirely understand, something about the words disturb her. She looks to her children.</context>
      <utterance>No, no. That's not the way. I told you to put her human characteristics on the left; her animal ones on the right. And don't forget to line them up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MRS. GARNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Too thick. I'm sure it's too thick.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think I can swallow that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want me to loosen it up with a little water?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GARNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Take it away. Bring me some cool water, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe helps her drink a glass of cold water.</context>
      <utterance>Yes ma'am...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GARNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you can have quite a few.  Mmmm. Thank you Sethe. Now tell me, I know Halle's no trouble but the others, the Pauls and Sixo - how's my brother-in- law handling them? All right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes Ma'am. Look like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GARNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They do what he tells them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't need telling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GARNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Sethe fills Mrs. Garner's basin with fresh water, she looks out the window and sees: SCHOOLTEACHER outside with his students, we notice HE WEARS A VERY DISTINCTIVE HAT as Mrs. Garners description continues;</context>
      <utterance>Good. That's a mercy. I know he's no Mr. Garner. But after he died, I had no else to turn to. I would've had to sell one. It wasn't even enough selling Paul F. And in my condition. I needed help. People said I shouldn't be alone here with nothing but Negroes. And he is a learned man being a schoolteacher...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GARNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I know his ways might be a little more strict but as long as the men do as they're told I'm sure it'll be fine. All right, I'm through.. Talking makes me tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes ma'am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up. You're late.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But ma'am...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe carefully hands her baby girl to the woman.</context>
      <utterance>Just go with her! Do what I tell ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put sugar water on that cloth for her to suck so she won't forget me til I come.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Halle wasn't there. I gotta go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You crazy..</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses her baby girl, a little too hard perhaps, waking her...along with the boys...</context>
      <utterance>Take em out. Now! I'll get there myself. I got her milk...I'll get there...Don't worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe disappears back into the corn field leaving the Woman holding the baby girl... as Bulgar cries out.</context>
      <utterance>Go..Go! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>BULGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CO-WORKER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men laugh. Paul smiles and brushes it off.</context>
      <utterance>Hey - you like this work so much maybe you best get in the chute with the others. You ain't got much more sense than they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't just a job reason to sing. Other things a man's got to look forward to that a job just a way to spend your day til the good times arrive.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO-WORKER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good times? Ain't no such day.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, now...it's all a state a mind, right Paul D. If you can think it, it can happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than that. When a man can make plans then a man can make good times happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO-WORKER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh the man's got plans! You saving up for a gold mine, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamp Paid's face registers sudden concern.</context>
      <utterance>Better then gold, my friend. Me and my woman's planning on starting a family.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New life. Born free, hear! Now if that don't define a good tine, I don't know what does.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO-WORKER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing born free ever again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you talkin? Nobody owns us no more. Nobody gonna own my children neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO-WORKER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>continue working. Stamp Paid looks at Paul, confused by what he should do.</context>
      <utterance>Children inherit what come before'em. Just cause you can't see no chains, don't mean they not there. We're not free men. We're somewhere between freedom and chains. And as long as the world is white, that's where we're stayin. The truth of this causes the men to be silent as they</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Free country. No matter what anybody says.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like the way you think, boy. Good. Good to think that way. Friend of mine, Baby Suggs was her name...sort of became a preacher in these parts..that was her way of thinking too. When she was at her best, that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew Baby Suggs?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes...You're not one of her Sweet Home men, now are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir...Me and my brothers and her son.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I see now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sethe told me she died soft as cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...maybe on the outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamp Paid looks at him with sympathetic, sudden understanding.</context>
      <utterance>Why is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know, son, do you? See I had to figure that out first.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamp Paid pulls out AN OLD NEWSPAPER CLIPPING from a bag he carries with him all the time. He hands it to Paul who looks to see: A DRAWING OF A YOUNG BLACK WOMAN beneath a HEADLINE; MURDER!</context>
      <utterance>Know what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That there's a picture of Sethe.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sethe?  Nah, that ain't her mouth. I can see where you might think it around the eyes but that there ain't her mouth. Besides, why would some black woman's picture be in the paper?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul senses something terribly wrong...and doesn't know whether to say yes or no.</context>
      <utterance>You don't read son, do you?  You want me to read to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul doesn't answer. Instead, he steps up to her as he removes the clipping from his pocket and hands it to her. Sethe's heart stops beating for a moment - not having seen this image for many years. But she's survived worse than the telling so she faces him.</context>
      <utterance>Already fed the girls. You eat?  Want something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best you come inside. She rises and enters the house. Paul follows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks for a response but expects none.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have to tell you about Sweet Home. What it was. But maybe you don't know what it was like for me to get away from there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rises and begins to move about the room, circling Paul as she tries to find a way to explain it all;</context>
      <utterance>I did it. I got us all out. Without Halle too. Up til then it was the only thing I ever did on my own. Decided. And it came off right like it was supposed to..</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We was here. Each and every one of my babies and me too. I birthed them and I got 'em out and it wasn't no accident. I did that! I had help, of course, lots of that, but still it was me doing it; me saying, "Go on" and "Now!". Me having to look out. Me using my own head. But it was more than that. It was a kind of ...'thinking-about-myself' I never knew nothing about before. It felt good. Good and right. I was big, Paul, and deep and wide and when I stretched out my arms all my children could get in between. I was that wide. Look like I loved them more after I got them here. Or maybe I couldn't love'em proper in Sweet Home 'cause they wasn't mine to love. But when I got here, when I jumped off that wagon - there wasn't nobody in the world I couldn't love if I wanted to....</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had 28 days...28 good days of free life.....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>She sits on the bed, watching the sun rise.</context>
      <utterance>...of getting up like I always did, getting dressed before the sun came out, and then realizing I had to decide myself what to do with the day...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Denver is asleep in a bassinet. Sethe reaches in and picks her up. She sits by a window and breast feeds her as she hums A MELODY. (This is the same melody we heard Sethe humming in the beginning of the film). Sethe's melody carries itself over the following images;</context>
      <utterance>...Days of watching my children sleep away the morning...And taking care of my baby like it was the most important thing I had to do...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Alone for a moment, Sethe looks around at the crowd of faces; Sethe's Melody stops as Baby Suggs stands on her rock and calls to the crowd:</context>
      <utterance>...And when everyone would gather to hear Baby Suggs, I saw something I ain't never seen before in my whole life...</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let the children come!</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let the grown men come!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera follows those women who are not singing as one by one, they remember and weep... Sethe watches...and weeps.</context>
      <utterance>Now...you women...I want you to cry. For the living. For the dead....Just cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>....Something in me knew Halle was never gonna knock on our door. He was never gonna see what I saw that day. I saw what men look like...and I saw mothers, for the first time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>He places the baskets on the porch in front of Baby Suggs, Sethe who is holding Denver..and the Little Girl (Beloved).</context>
      <utterance>I think it was Stamp Paid who started it. He walked six miles to the riverbank, slid into a ravine, reached through blood drawing thorns, suffered mosquitoes, wasps and the meanest lady spiders in the State just to bring us those berries.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a sight you are, Stamp.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts one into Denver's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Worth it though. Just one bite of these berries and you feel down right anointed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's too little for that, Stamp. Her bowels be soup.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll sickify her stomach..Now go wash up round back...crazy fool.. Stamp exits.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was real nice of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a good one, no doubt of that. I can get three, maybe four pies out of this. Seems a shame just for us though. I'm gonna invite Ella and John over...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout if I make a couple of chickens to back it up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's how it began...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>- Older men sitting and talking as they eat... - Younger men playing with the children. Chasing them with sheets on their backs, scaring them into laughter.. - A Man with a guitar playing a blues song and singing. While Sethe enjoys her free life and, most of all, her children - the boys running around her..Denver in her arms..Her Little Girl (Beloved) by her side.. Baby Sugg's visits with various guests, serving up the food...</context>
      <utterance>...and Ella and John turned into almost ninety others... - Women serving up the food...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>INTERCUT; Images of whispers exchanged between some of the women:</context>
      <utterance>... Everybody ate so well and laughed so much...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Women head to head with a remark or an eye of disapproval towards Baby Suggs as she continues cooking and feeding....</context>
      <utterance>...it made them angry...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Over the above speech, we see in Sethe's expression a death of soul - an instantaneous loss of hope for possibilities of joy and life. And with it, an insane rage. Sethe grabs Denver out of the basket, then scrambles after the crawling Little Girl (Beloved), scooping her under her free arm...</context>
      <utterance>...There's a Look whitefolks get..a Look every Negro learns to recognize along with his ma'am's tit..That righteous Look that's like a flag going up the pole..the righteousness that announces the whip, the fist, the burning, the lie...long before it happens in the open...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tone of her voice cause the boys to freeze. She runs towards them, grabbing one by the hand and ordering the other to run in front of them. She moves and speaks with efficient clarity.</context>
      <utterance>Howard!...Bulgar!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Suggs and Stamp Paid watch helplessly -</context>
      <utterance>The shed!...Get in the shed!...Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NEPHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Suggs walks in. Whatever amount of God's grace she could imagine and will into being, vanishes with one look into that shed.</context>
      <utterance>What she go and do that for?...What she go and do that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing here to claim, I guess. Look like your business is over. Mine's started. Schoolteacher beats his hat against his thigh and spits in the shed before exiting, followed by the catcher and the nephew. The Sheriff speaks to Sethe.</context>
      <utterance>You all better go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have to take you in. No trouble now. You've done enough to last you.... Sethe doesn't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, Baby Suggs notices who breathes and who does not and moves straight to the boys.... Stamp Paid extends his arm to Sethe.</context>
      <utterance>You come quiet, here, and I won't have to tie you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe turns to him, the first time she's looked into anyone's eyes and sees Denver in his arms...A sound escapes from her throat as though she'd made a mistake.</context>
      <utterance>Sethe. You take my arm and gimme yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits. Baby Suggs rubs the boys' hands, tries to raise their eyelids, spits on her dress and wipes away the blood as they slowly regain a dazed consciousness..She whispers;</context>
      <utterance>I'm going out here and send for a wagon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg you pardon..I beg your pardon..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me..but the child needs nursin..needs the mother's milk..</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Suggs approaches Sethe who sees Denver crying and reaches for her without letting the baby go. Baby Suggs resists;</context>
      <utterance>Then she's best come too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Sethe only wants her living child. The two women struggle as Stamp Paid does what he can..Finally, Sethe wins and takes Denver with her free hand, undoes her dress and nurse's her with a bloody breast.. Baby Suggs breaks inside. Breaks right in two, although from outwards appearances, she looks merely numbed by shock. A WHITE BOY makes his way through the crowd with a pair of shoes and hands them to her..</context>
      <utterance>One at a time!...And you gotta clean yourself up!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama says Wednesday. She says you got to have them fixed by Wednesday. Baby Suggs looks at him not understanding..</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hear, Baby? She says Wednesday.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon..Lord, I beg your pardon..I sure do....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your love is too thick, Sethe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love is or it isn't. Thin love ain't love at all...I did stop him. I took and put my babies where they'd be safe...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't work though, did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It worked.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How? Your boys gone, you don't know where. One girl dead, the other can't go farther than the yard. How did it work?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They ain't at Sweet Home! Schoolteacher ain't got'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe there's worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't my job to know what's worse. It's my job to know what is and keep them away from what I know is terrible. I did that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you did was wrong, Sethe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have gone back there? Taken my babies back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There could have been a way. Some other way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What way?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That jumped out before he had a chance to choose saying it. Sethe has no response...The distance between these two people in this small room is suddenly vast. Paul rises, playing with his hat...not knowing how to leave. But desperately needing to. He moves to the exit and stops..</context>
      <utterance>You got two feet, Sethe. Not four!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unable to look at her, he turns to exit. When Sethe speaks in a soft, forgiving tone, he stops to listen;</context>
      <utterance>You can set aside supper for me... Might be late getting back...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul turns to look at her and realizes she saw right through him...</context>
      <utterance>After all I told you, Paul D. and after telling me how many feet I have, you think saying goodbye is gonna break me into pieces?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unable to bear it, Paul turns and leaves... Sethe stands still, fighting tears, and whispers...</context>
      <utterance>You're a sweet man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So long, Paul D.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe and Beloved look up. Sethe smiles;</context>
      <utterance>What do these do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Lord...where'd you dig up those?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There for skating on the ice. We have another pair and half of another, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe takes the skates and looks at them with a curious lightness:</context>
      <utterance>Can we try them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ice skating? Ha...  Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver and Beloved register hopefulness in the light of Sethe's attitude. Sethe speaks to Denver;</context>
      <utterance>Strikes me that after your man leaves, it might just be the wrong time to be scrubbing floors... might just be the perfect time to go ice skating.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls get excited. Sethe tosses the scrub brush into the pail.</context>
      <utterance>Go get the shawls..and find me an old shoe for that half a pair...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe steps onto the ice and takes a few strides and promptly falls on her rear. The girls scream with laughter. Sethe tries to get up and falls, their laughter infecting her as well. The girls try to help her and fall over each other in the trying. Denver rises and tries an independent glide. The tip of her skate hits a bump and she falls, flapping her arms wildly. All three laugh so hard, they start coughing. Beloved goes to Denver's aid. Sethe rises up on her hands and knees, her laughter shaking her chest and causing her eyes to tear in the cold air. Beloved helps Denver, and falls as well. The two girls see Sethe laughing and play it up even more, a few more times... Until, Denver notices something and motions Beloved to stop and look. The two glide back to Sethe. Her laughter has stopped, but her tears have not... They gently, comfortingly, touch her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, ma'am...try!</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...All I remember is how she loved the bottom of burned bread. Her little hands...I wouldn't know 'em if they slapped me".</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Beloved lifts her head towards the fire at the same time she leans back to rest on a propped-up pillow. In the flickering of the firelight, Sethe can see:</context>
      <utterance>..."Here. Look here. See this mark? If you can't tell me by my face, look here."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver lifts her head from her mother's lap to look at Sethe, knowing what is happening....</context>
      <utterance>I made that song up. I made it up and sang it to my children...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved turns to Sethe;</context>
      <utterance>...Nobody knows that song but me and my children.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A click. Sethe looks at her daughter, returned. "There is no gasp of astonishment - no exclaim for the miraculous. For what is truly miraculous is so, because the magic lies in the fact that you knew it was there for you all along."</context>
      <utterance>I know it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back stiff?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OOh, yeah...Don't know if it's the floor or the skating.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be that fall you took.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved snores lightly beside her;</context>
      <utterance>That was fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I wake her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, let her rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She likes to see you off in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make sure she does. But first I'm going make up a nice, big breakfast against that cold outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't you be late for work?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver smiles - but it is a cautious smile. Something about her mother's statement both elates and disturbs her.</context>
      <utterance>Don't matter. First time I'll be late in nine years. No great trouble..Whatever goes on out there goes on with or without me showing up on time... don't matter...  The world is in this room, baby. This is all there is and all there needs to be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Suggs turns to her old friend - but there is no sign of welcome or recognition. There is a noticeable change in her demeanor. She continues walking. He follows;</context>
      <utterance>You missed the Clearing meeting three Saturdays running.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Folks came.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Folks come. Folks go.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for the carpetbag but Baby Suggs pulls it away.</context>
      <utterance>Here, let me carry that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a delivery around here. Name of Tucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk a bit, until;</context>
      <utterance>Yonder. Twin chestnuts in the yard.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well what?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Saturday - you coming to Call or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I call them, and they come what on earth am I going to say to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two whitemen raking leaves look up at the sound of Stamp Paid's voice, which was too loud. So he whispers;</context>
      <utterance>Say the Word!</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Word. What you was put here to speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the last thing they took from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you got to do it. You got to. Can't nobody Call like you. You have to be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I have to do is get in my bed and lay down. I want to fix on something harmless in this world.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What world are you talking about? Ain't nothing harmless down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blue. That doesn't hurt nobody. Yellow neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You getting into bed to think about yellow?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I likes yellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what? When you get through with blue and yellow, then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't say. It's something can't be planned.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You blaming God. That what you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Stamp. I ain't.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saying whitefolks won. That what you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those white things have taken all I had or dreamed. I'm saying ain't no bad luck in this world 'cept for white folks..They just don't know when to stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saying nothing counts?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm saying they came into my yard.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saying God give up? Nothing left for us but pour out our own blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm saying they came into my yard.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You punishing Him, ain't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not like He punished me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do that, Baby. It ain't right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was a time I knew what was.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I know is what I see: a nigger woman hauling shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops her, before the Twin Chestnuts of the Tucker house.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, Baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to be steady. "These things too will pass". What you looking for? A miracle?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exchange a look of silence and finality. She turns and walks to the back door of the house and knocks. A moment later a White Woman appears, takes the carpetbag and keeps Baby waiting on the back steps while she goes in for a dime. Baby rests on the railing until the whitewoman returns.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm looking for what I was put here to look for: the back door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strolling in here this late?</context>
      <utterance>What the hell you thinking, girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to me, Mr. Sawyer. Don't say nothing to me this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What? You talking back to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe begins organizing her counter to make pies.</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you don't say nothing to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe ignores him as she begins. Sawyer is at a loss.</context>
      <utterance>You better get them pies made!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not too sweet! You make it too sweet they don't eat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it the way I always do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he exits)</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Too sweet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="43">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you been keeping yourself? I told John must be cold if Stamp stay inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamp takes off his hat and follows Ella, who is doing laundry in the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Oh I been out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out where?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was over to Baby Suggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you want there? Somebody invite you in?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ella shrugs and continues folding wet laundry on a line behind the stove. Stamp sits.</context>
      <utterance>That's Baby's kin. I don't need no invite to look after her people.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody new there. A woman. Thought you might know who she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't no new Negroes in this town I don't know about. What she look like? You sure that wasn't Denver?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know Denver.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might see anything at all at 124.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better ask Paul D.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't locate him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's sleeping in the church.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The church!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Asked Rev. Pike if he could stay in the cellar.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cold as charity in there! What he do that for? Any number'll take him in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All he have to do is ask somebody.</context>
      <utterance>Can't nobody read minds long distance.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Why he have to ask? Can't nobody offer? What's going on? Since when a black man come to town have to sleep in the cellar like a dog?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unrile yourself, Stamp. It's only a few days he been there.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NO! Shouldn't be no days! You know all about it and don't give him a hand? That don't sound like you, Ella. Me and you been pulling colored folk out the water more'n twenty years! Now you tell me you can't offer a man a bed?! A working man who can pay his own way?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ask, I give him anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's that necessary all of a sudden?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know him that well.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know he's colored? What else there to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stamp, don't tear me up this morning! I don't feel like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's her, ain't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her who?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sethe. He took up with her and stayed in there and you don't want nothing to-</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on! Don't jump if you can't see bottom!</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Ella knows he's right. She surrenders the truth.</context>
      <utterance>Girl, give it up! We been friends too long to act like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, who can tell what went on in there? I never even knew who Sethe was or none of her people.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know she married Baby Suggs' boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't sure I know that. Baby never laid eyes on her till she showed up here. And how'd she make it and her husband didn't? And where is he? And how she have that baby in the woods by herself? Said a whitewoman help her. Shoot. You believe that? Well, I know what kind of white that was.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, no, Ella.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything white floating around in the woods - if it don't got a shotgun, it's something the Lord tells me I don't want no part of.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You was friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Till she showed herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ella.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't got no friends take a handsaw to their own children.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's any of that got to do with Paul</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What run him off? Tell me that!</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I run him off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told him...Showed him the newspaper. About Sethe. Read it to him. He left that very day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't tell me that. I thought he already knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't know nothing. And nobody. Except her, from when they was at that place Baby Suggs was at.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knew Baby Suggs?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure he knew her. Her boy Halle, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he left when he found out what Sethe did?  What you say casts a different light on it, I guess...I thought- Stamp knows what she thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you didn't come here talking 'bout Paul. You came asking about a new girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Paul D. must know who she is. Or what she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mind loaded with spirits. Everywhere you look you see one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamp can not deny this.</context>
      <utterance>You know as well as I do, Stamp, that people who die bad don't stay in the ground.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="48">
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamp has his hands in his pockets, moving about.</context>
      <utterance>Howdy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got any more newspaper in that pocket for me, just a waste of time. Ain't interested. Stamp sits beside him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is hard for me. But I got to do it. Two things I got to say to you. I'm a take the easy one first.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he drinks)</context>
      <utterance>If it's hard for you, might kill me dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I come looking for you to ask your pardon. Apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You pick any house, any house where colored live. Pick any one and you welcome to stay there. I'm apologizing 'cause they didn't offer to tell you. But you welcome anywhere you want to be. My house. John and Ella. Miss Lady Jones..anybody. You choose. You ain't got to sleep in no cellar and I apologize for each and every night.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I...I did get offered one place but I just wanted to be off by myself a spell.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Oh that's load off. I thought everybody gone crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You planning to do anything about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drinks from the bottle like an angry, broken man. It stabs at Stamp's heart to see him like this. A WHITE MAN in a horse and wagon drives up the path leading to the church. He leans stops before them and leans forward;</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. I got big plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!!</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for a gal name of Judy. Works over by the slaughterhouse. Said she lived on Plank Road.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mile, maybe.</context>
      <utterance>Plank Road. Yes sir. That's up a ways.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know her? Judy? Works in the slaughterhouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul drinks from the bottle. The White Man addresses him.</context>
      <utterance>No sir, I don't, but I know Plank Road. 'Bout a mile up thataway.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look here..There's a cross up there, so I guess this here's a church or used to be. Seems to me like you ought to show it some respect, you follow me?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul offers no response. The White Man clicks his tongue and drives off. Stamp breathes a sigh of relief.</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir..You right about that. That's just what I come over to talk to him about. Just that..</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember your price, Stamp?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never found out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. Down to the cent.$900. Always wondered though what Mrs. Garner got for my brother Paul F. Must of been more than nine hundred dollars cause she use that money for Sweet Home for almost two years. But then they hung my other brother Paul A. up on a tree so I guess he wasn't worth the same..I wonder what was Baby Suggs worth? And Halle? I wasn't surprised when I found out they tracked down Sethe all the way to Cincinatti. Her price must have been higher than all of us - her being property that reproduced itself without cost. A breeder.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No use thinking these things now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh but we got to. How we gonna know our price in the future? How are children's children's children gonna know what they cost? Who's gonna tell them? What are they gonna pay for us, if we free?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Children ain't gonna need to know that kind of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll know. They'll know as soon as they born. Cause it's inside us,Stamp. It'll be inside them. We'll pass it down. Schoolteacher didn't just change the outside, he changed the mind..and the blood..and what it carries...and what it's worth..</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe that. I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a rooster named Mister down at Sweet Home. Last time I saw Halle, with that butter all over his face and me with an iron bit in my mouth, I saw Mister - sitting on a tub. He loved that tub. Like king on a throne. He was a hateful thing. Bloody and evil..But he was better than me. Mister was allowed to be and stay what he was. Even if you cooked him you'd be cooking a rooster named Mister. But wasn't no way I'd ever be Paul D. again..Schoolteacher changed me. Was never no beating under Mr. Garner. Schoolteacher changed that. Why wouldn't a man run from that? Why wouldn't a man not work, kill, starve, pull out his own heart to stop feeling 'stead of feeling that? And it strikes me, it's got to be cause we were something else. And that something was less than a chicken sitting in the sun on a tub. He drinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said I had two things to say to you. I only told you one. I have to tell you the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When she did it.</context>
      <utterance>I was there Paul D...There in the yard.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What yard? When who- And then Paul realizes he's talking of Sethe.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't what you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know what I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She ain't crazy. She love those children. She was trying to outhurt the hurter's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave off..</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was only-</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stamp, leave off I said! I knew her when she was a girl. She scares me and I knew her when she was a girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't scared of Sethe. I don't believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She scares me. I scare me. And that girl in her house scares me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is she? Where she come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know. Just shot up one day from a stump.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul thinks a moment. Then, tears brimming in his eyes:</context>
      <utterance>She what run you off? Not what I told you 'bout Sethe?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me something, Stamp. Tell me this one thing. How much is a nigger supposed to take?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP PAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All he can. All he can.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Why? Why? Why? Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved jolts her head up to Denver. She doesn't like being looked at unawares...</context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't be in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know about it? I sleep where I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beloved looks at Denver, then at the quilt - then abruptly tears the hole apart with one strong pull. Triumphant, she gets out of bed and exits, passing Denver;</context>
      <utterance>You best leave that quilt alone. That was grandma's quilt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Breakfast ready? I'm hungry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe turns, not realizing Denver was there as well. Their eyes meet. Sethe wonders if her daughter saw her eating the pan crumbs. She smiles;</context>
      <utterance>Morning, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Knowing there must be nothing left, Denver answers;</context>
      <utterance>You hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe looks relieved.</context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver crosses to the dishes, taking the pan from her mother. Sethe nods and crosses to the table, to sit down. But as she sinks into the chair, Beloved kicks it away;</context>
      <utterance>I'll finish those. Why don't you sit down?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't sit with me!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, don't be like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't sit with me!! I don't sit with people who leave me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk like that. Your mama loves you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had another dream last night.  The dead man laying on top of me and I had nothing to eat. And the ghosts without skin stuck their fingers in me and said Beloved in the dark and bitch in the light..</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say those things. You forget about those dreams..</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gave me the bad dreams. You left me behind...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama told you - I'd give up my own life, every minute, every hour of it to take back one of your tears baby...My children my best thing. You my best thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're weren't nice to me..you didn't smile at me..</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true. I told you, I had to get you out, make you safe...so's you and me could be together on the other side, forever..</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one pays attention to Denver.</context>
      <utterance>Ma'am...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold back Denver - I'm fine..You..you go on upstairs. I'll do the cleaning up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But mama..</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe's harsh tone is only for Denver. Denver exits the kitchen, afraid to leave them alone... As she moves from the kitchen, she hears;</context>
      <utterance>Go upstairs I said!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want somethin' sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have nothing sweet no more, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for me, you don't! You don't let me eat the pies...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Denver walks up the white stairs...</context>
      <utterance>No. Since mama lost her job, we don't have no more pies..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A NINE YEAR OLD DENVER shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>You mean I never told you about your daddy? About the Bodwins who let me rent this here house while I do my shoe repairing? About your mother's feet, not to mention her back? I never told you all that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why you can't walk down the steps and out yonder by yourself? Denver can't answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you never go back to Lady Jone's and learn your letters? You liked going there I remember. Seeing the other children. Then all a sudden, you stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Suggs face registers the pain of her granddaughter, hurt by hurtful words.</context>
      <utterance>There was a boy there...said mama was a jailbird...said he could prove it..</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Jesus my...What people won't say. Why didn't you come and ask me?  'Fraid I'll tell ya, huh?  Come here, child.. Denver crawls into her arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got to go sometime. You got to go out there by yourself sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you said...you said out there, there ain't no...what was that word?..no..de- fense. No de-fense.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There ain't.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY SUGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know it, and go on out the yard. Go on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe turns, startled, to reveal - it is BELOVED in Sethe's best clothes...When Beloved sees Denver, she smiles tauntingly and strikes a pose...</context>
      <utterance>Mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELOVED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disgusted, Denver exits.</context>
      <utterance>I look just like her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama let me help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe continues her work, without even looking at Denver. Denver pauses a moment, realizing she is of no use here - but knowing she needs to help her mother somehow. She looks up to the kitchen, where every cupboard door is open revealing empty shelves...SHE EXITS - HEADING FOR THE</context>
      <utterance>NO!...She wanted me to do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LADY JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver manages to smile.</context>
      <utterance>Why Denver..Look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unfortunately, Denver can't manage anything beyond the smile.</context>
      <utterance>It's been so long. It's so nice of you to come see me. What brings you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lady Jones takes her by the hand and leads her inside.</context>
      <utterance>Well, never mind - nobody needs a reason to visit. Let me make us some tea. Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LADY JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver swallows a bite of something with some tea, then;</context>
      <utterance>How's your family, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to work, Miss Lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Work? Start learnin your letters again?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I mean work work.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what can you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do anything but I would learn it for you if you have a little extra.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Extra?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Food. My mama, she doesn't feel well. I couldn't stay away from her too long, cause of her condition but I could do chores in the mornings.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh baby...I don't know anyone could pay anybody anything for work they did themselves...But if you all need to eat until your mother's well, all you have to do is say so...We have a church committee invented so nobody had to go hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lady Jones can sense something far more serious is going on.</context>
      <utterance>No..No that won't do...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody..no sir..that's right..nobody's going be doing that..nobody going be writing my daughter's characteristics on the animal side..no sir..I don't care..ain't laying that down..no sir. I refuse..that's right..that's right...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama...Mama she's asleep. Why don't you eat something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She likes this dress...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe considers this. She rises cautiously, then sits at the table. Denver rises and gets her some food, placing it before her.</context>
      <utterance>But you'll hurt your eyes doin it there. Come sit at the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe nods...Denver is getting more and more frightened of losing her mother completely...Instead of protecting Beloved from Sethe, she must protect her mother from Beloved.</context>
      <utterance>Please mama, eat something...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to see Mr. and Mrs. Bodwin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Bodwin. They brother and sister, darlin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you want'em for?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for work. I was thinking they might know of some.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You Baby Sugg's kin, ain't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard your mother took sick, that so?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes ma'am..</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, come on in. You letting in flies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what? I've been here since I was fourteen and I remember like yesterday when Baby Suggs, holy, came here and sat right where you are. Whiteman name of Garner brought her. He and Mr. Bodwin were good friends. That's how she got that house you all live in. Other things too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Never be another like her.</context>
      <utterance>I never went to those woodland services but she was always nice to me. Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bet you do. Everybody miss her. That was a good woman...Well, I don't know whether the Bodwins think it or not but they sure could use some extra help.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They getting older now and I can't take care of 'em like I used to. More and more they keep asking me to sleep over night. Now, I don't want to quit these people but they can't have all my days and nights too. I got my own family needs me. It'll take some convincing but maybe you could come after supper - take care of your mama during the day, then earn a little something at night, how's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. But what would I do at night?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be here. In case.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In case of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During Janey's lines, Denver looks about the house imagining herself here at night...her eyes happen upon A STATUE OF A BLACK BOY on his knees, his head thrown back farther than a head could go, his mouth wide open like a cup and filled with money for delivery tips. On the pedestal are the words' AT YO</context>
      <utterance>In case the house burn down or bad weather slops the roads so bad I can't get here on time or late guests needed cleaning up after. Anything.  Don't ask me what whitefolks need at night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They good whitefolks?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver nods, beaming gratefully - so gratefully that no words come, only tears... Janey reaches for Denver's hand and holds it warmly;</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. They good. Can't say they ain't good. I wouldn't trade them for another pair, tell you that. But you come back in a few days - give me a chance to lead'em to it. All right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver looks at her and we know she needs to tell someone.</context>
      <utterance>What is it, child? What's the trouble with Sethe?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But is it really the daughter, Janey? The killed one?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That what she say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WILLIAMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How they know it's her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's sitting there. Sleeps, eats and raises hell. Whipping Sethe every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be. A baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Grown now. The age it would have been had it lived.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the flesh. And whipping her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLIAMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess she had it coming a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody got that coming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILLIAMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Ella- you can't just up and kill your children.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women agree.</context>
      <utterance>No, and the children can't just up and kill the mama. What's fair ain't necessarily right...  Now you all know how I felt about the whole thing. I know the rage Sethe felt in that shed that day. We all do. But what I could not understand, and still don't, was her reaction to it. Prideful. Too damn complicated for a black woman in her position before God. But whatever she done, I don't like the idea of past errors taking possession of the present. I don't cotton to sin moving in on a house, unleashed and sassy. Every day life takes enough, takes all a woman has. "Sufficient unto the day is evil thereof" and nobody needs more. Nobody needs a grown up evil sitting at a table with a grudge. As long as that ghost showed itself from a ghostly place, I respected it. But once it take on flesh and come into this world, well, the shoe's on the other foot now. I don't mind a little communication between worlds. But this here's an invasion.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we pray?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. First. Then we got to get down to business.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama?....Mama I'm going out..  Mama, I got a job. Working over at the Bodwins at night. Mr. Bodwin coming over now to pick me up on his way back from town. I'll be staying there nights and coming back here for the daytime. We'll have some money, mama..Mama? Sethe continues her action as if hypnotized. Denver approaches her from behind and whispers softly;</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denver touches her gently, but Sethe acts as if she hears and feels nothing. Denver exits.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going help you, mama. Don't you give up yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She releases Beloved's hand and moves forward...</context>
      <utterance>No...No, he's not coming into my yard. He not taking my best thing...No..</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...no...no..</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She passes Denver, feeling for the ICE PICK IN HER APRON.</context>
      <utterance>Mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mr. Bodwin reaches the thirty women who separate him from</context>
      <utterance>No...NO..NO..NOOOOOOOOOOOO!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is clearly impressed by the sight of her.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Paul D.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, is it now? How you getting along?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't pay to complain.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You on your way home?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Got me an afternoon job at the shirt factory. Figure between that and my night work at the Bodwins I might be able to put something away for me and mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They treating you right over at the Bodwins?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul smiles - wanting to warn her but deciding not to spoil the possibilities that lay before her.</context>
      <utterance>More than all right. Miss Bodwin, she teach me stuff..Book stuff. She says I might go to Oberlin. She's experimenting on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mother all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not a bit all right. Hasn't gotten out of bed since that day.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I should stop by? Think she'd welcome it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I think I've lost my mother, Paul D.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That girl...You know, Beloved...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She gone like they say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't seen her since that day. Ella thinks she might be waiting in the woods for another chance but..I don't think so. Mama thinks she's gone for good. Says she can feel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think she sure 'nough your sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She levels her eyes at him and he knows what she means.</context>
      <utterance>At times. At other times I think she was...more. But who would know that better than you. I mean, you sure 'nough you her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you want my opinion...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't. I have my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You grown.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, good luck with the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. They pass each other until Denver turns back;</utterance>
   <speaker>DENVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Paul D...you don't have to stay 'way, but be careful how you talk to my mama, hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul watches her walk away. He watches as a YOUNG BLACK MAN runs towards her shouting;</context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches as the two young people, the future, walk together.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Miss Denver..Wait up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sethe?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks like she's dying.</context>
      <utterance>Paul D.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches her.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, Sethe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shaved.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Look bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, You looking good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Devil's confusion. What's this I hear about you not getting out of bed?  I saw Denver. She tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She comes in the daytime. She still with me, my Denver.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got to get up from here, girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm tired, Paul. So tired. I have to rest a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you die on me!! This is Baby Suggs quilt. Is that what you planning!?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't have no plans. No plans at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe looks at him - a long look - and sees in him that thing, that blessedness, "that makes him the kind of man who can walk into a house and make women cry, make women tell him things they could only tell each other".</context>
      <utterance>Look - Denver be here in the day. I be here in the night. I'm a take care of you, you hear? Starting now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She left me. She's gone again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, girl. Don't cry...Me and you, we got more yesterday than anybody. We need some kind of tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul leans down and takes her hand, entwining his fingers into hers...</context>
      <utterance>She was my best thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sethe smiles, with tears in her eyes, looking almost surprised;</context>
      <utterance>You your best thing, Sethe. You are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?...Me?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
