<movie id="74" title="Big Fish">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Beast's journey takes it past a dangling fish hook, baited with worms. Past a tempting lure, sparkling in the sun. Past a swiping bear claw. The Beast isn't worried.</context>
      <utterance>There are some fish that cannot be caught. It's not that they're faster or stronger than other fish. They're just touched by something extra. Call it luck. Call it grace. One such fish was The Beast.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the time I was born, he was already a legend. He'd taken more hundred- dollar lures than any fish in Alabama. Some said that fish was the ghost of Henry Walls, a thief who'd drowned in that river 60 years before. Others claimed he was a lesser dinosaur, left over from the Cretaceous period.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward points to his wedding band, glinting in the firelight.</context>
      <utterance>Now, I'd tried everything on it: worms, lures, peanut butter, peanut butter-and-cheese. But on that day I had a revelation: if that fish was the ghost of a thief, the usual bait wasn't going to work. I would have to use something he truly desired.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE BRAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward slips his ring off.</context>
      <utterance>Your finger?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While the other boys are rapt with attention, Will looks bored. He's heard this story before.</context>
      <utterance>Gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tied my ring to the strongest line they made -- strong enough to hold up a bridge, they said, if just for a few minutes -- and I cast upriver.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>WILL, now 17 with braces, is fuming and ready to leave. His mother SANDRA -- from whom he gets his good looks and practicality -- stands with him at the door.</context>
      <utterance>The Beast jumped up and grabbed it before the ring even hit the water. And just as fast, he snapped clean through that line.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can see my predicament. My wedding ring, the symbol of fidelity to my wife, soon to be the mother of my child, was now lost in the gut of an uncatchable fish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His mother pats him sympathetically, then adjusts his tie.</context>
      <utterance>Make him stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL'S DATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will regards his father with exasperated contempt.</context>
      <utterance>I followed that fish up-river and down-river for three days and three nights, until I finally had him boxed in.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With these two hands, I reached in and snatched that fish out of the river. I looked him straight in the eye. And I made a remarkable discovery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over near the doorway, we spot Sandra, just returned from the restrooms. She looks gorgeous. She couldn't be any happier if this were her own wedding.</context>
      <utterance>This fish, the Beast. The whole time we were calling it a him, when in fact it was a her. It was fat with eggs, and was going to lay them any day.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will can't take any more. Josephine tries to hold him back, but he gets up and leaves. Edward doesn't even notice.</context>
      <utterance>Now, I was in a situation. I could gut that fish and get my ring back, but doing so I would be killing the smartest catfish in the Ashton River, soon to be mother of a hundred others.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he leaves, Will mutters in perfect unison with his father --</context>
      <utterance>Did I want to deprive my soon-to-be- born son the chance to catch a fish like this of his own? This lady fish and I, well, we had the same destiny.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD AND WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will reaches the door, where his mother intercepts him.</context>
      <utterance>We were part of the same equation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will can't articulate his anger. He just leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, it's still your night.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He focuses his words on Sandra. This story is -- and has always been -- about her more than anyone.</context>
      <utterance>Now, you may well ask, since this lady fish wasn't the ghost of a thief, why did it strike so quick on gold when nothing else would attract it?  That was the lesson I learned that day, the day my son was born.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward motions for Sandra to get up here with him. As she crosses, we can see that thirty years of marriage has not lessened their affection for each other. As they kiss, Edward tweaks her chin a special little way. The crowd APPLAUDS. Edward toasts the happy couple. Josephine covers well for her absent husband, a smile as warm as summer. Edward downs his champagne in a gulp.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes, the only way to catch an uncatchable woman is to offer her a wedding ring. A LAUGH from the crowd.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, a father's not allowed to talk about his son?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am a footnote in that story. I am the context for your great adventure. Which never happened! Incidentally! You were selling novelty products in Wichita the day I was born.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friend of yours? Did you help him out of a bind?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Will. Everyone likes that story.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat, then...</context>
      <utterance>No Dad, they don't. I do not like the story. Not anymore, not after a thousand times. I know all the punchlines, Dad. I can tell them as well as you can.  For one night, one night in your entire life, the universe does not revolve around Edward Bloom. It revolves around me and my wife. How can you not understand that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will won't let him get the last word.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry to embarrass you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON Edward. Fine. A hand to wave, enough of you. He walks away. ANGLE ON Will, still fuming with righteous anger. It's then we FREEZE FRAME.</context>
      <utterance>You're embarrassing yourself, Dad. You just don't see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After that night, I didn't speak to my father again for three years.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Edward takes a seat, starting to eat his sandwich.</context>
      <utterance>When I'd call, Mom would say that Dad was out driving. Or swimming in the pool.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True to form, we never talked about our not talking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We LOOK DOWN at the river, where Edward's reflection is caught in the dark water. As the water ripples past, something changes. Sure enough, as we LOOK UP again, it's a younger EDWARD BLOOM, 20's, staring into the water. He's not just handsome, not just charming. It's as if all the forces of the natural world had conspired to create him.</context>
      <utterance>In telling the story of my father's life, it's impossible to separate the fact from the fiction, the man from the myth. The best I can do is to tell it the way he told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, this Edward thrusts both hands into the water, grabbing hold of</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't always make sense, and most of it never happened.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YOUNG DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, we hear a POP as a slimy mass of human being rockets into the doctor's unprepared hands. Bennett tries to hold tight, but the infant is slippery like a fish. It shoots up into air. The NURSES and the Husband try to grab the baby, but no one can hold it. As the newborn sails upward TOWARDS CAMERA, we can see a GIGGLING SMILE on its face. As it falls, the newborn knocks over a tray, which provides it a ramp to slide right out of the room. Everyone races after it.</context>
      <utterance>Now, Mrs. Bloom, I'll need you to give me one good push. On three. One...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A NURSE finally scoops up the slippery baby. Everyone lets out a collective sigh of relief.</context>
      <utterance>Grab that baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father's birth would set the pace for his unlikely life. No longer than most men's, but larger. And as strange as his stories got, the endings were always the most surprising of all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will begins stripping out of his wet clothes, each layer unleashing a new drizzle. He plays it up, trying to get a reaction out of Josephine.</context>
      <utterance>Allo oui?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands the phone to Will, concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Half-stripped, Will takes the phone. This won't be good news.</context>
      <utterance>It's your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Josephine takes off her rain coat, we see she is very, very pregnant. She listens carefully to Will's side of the conversation, trying to gauge how bad the news is.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. Uh-huh. Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He covers the mouthpiece. Looks over to Josephine.</context>
      <utterance>What does Dr. Bennett say? Okay. No, sure, let me talk to him. I'll wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's more than they thought. They're going to stop chemo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Probably tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one about the witch.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mom says I can't tell you that one anymore. You get nightmares.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward looks around for a beat, seeing if his wife is in earshot. He then leans in, complicitous.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will smiles, excited to hear the forbidden story.</context>
      <utterance>Neither was I. At first.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward holds up his hand, counting the names on his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>This all happened in the swamp outside of Ashton. Kids weren't supposed to go out in the swamp, on account of the snakes and spiders and quicksand that would swallow you up before you could even scream. But there were five of us out there that night: Me, Ruthie, Wilbur Freely, and the Price Brothers, Don and Zacky.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As his hand moves past the light, we</context>
      <utterance>Not a one of us knew what was in store.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zacky, turn your flashlight on!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZACKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Red-headed ZACKY PRICE is 10. His brother DON PRICE is 12, and a lot bigger than the others.</context>
      <utterance>I don't got any batteries!</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why'd you bring it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZACKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WILBUR FREELY, also 10, is the black asthmatic son of a sharecropper. Redheaded RUTHIE MACKLIN, 8, is happy just to be there.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be in the swamp with a witch and no flashlight.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true she got a glass eye?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILBUR FREELY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard she got it from Gypsies.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a Gypsy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZACKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your momma's a Gypsy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your momma's a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't swear. There's ladies present.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZACKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILBUR FREELY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screw.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ADULT EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We PULL BACK, and BACK, revealing more of the Gothically creepy house: its broken windows, strangling vines, and eerie gargoyles half-buried in the dirt. Even bats are afraid to fly over it. In the moonlight, the house is especially sinister. Who knows what is lurking in the shadows?</context>
      <utterance>Now, it's common knowledge that most towns of a certain size have a witch, if only to eat misbehaving children and the occasional puppy who wanders into her yard. Witches use those bones to cast spells and curses that make the land infertile.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADULT EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We finally come to the kids, staring in through the gate.</context>
      <utterance>Yet of the all the witches in Alabama, there was one who was the most feared. For she had one glass eye, which was said to contain mystical powers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILBUR FREELY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear if you look right at it, you can see how you're gonna die.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's bull-s-h-i-t, that is. She's not even a real witch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward looks back at the spooky house.</context>
      <utterance>You're so sure, why don't you go in and get that eye? I heard she keeps it in a box on her nighttable.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or are you too scared?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go in right now and get that eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, you do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Zacky his flashlight, then starts climbing the gate.</context>
      <utterance>Fine, I'm doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Edward, don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILBUR FREELY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward drops down on the far side of the gate. Truth be told, Edward is scared, but he forges ahead anyway. Wilbur looks to Ruthie, and they're in complete agreement. They get the hell out of there. Zacky would run too, but Don holds him by the collar.</context>
      <utterance>She'll make soap out of you!  That's what she does, she makes soap out of people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get the eye?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brought it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Woman steps out of the shadows behind Edward, flipping up her eye patch. When their flashlight beam hits her left eye, it shines with a hellish glow. We RUSH IN on Zacky, who is paralyzed by what he sees.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZACKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw how I was gonna die. I was old, and I fell.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The brothers suddenly bolt. Still standing next to the Old Woman, Edward smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't old at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Woman turns to him slightly, still not facing him.</context>
      <utterance>I was thinking about death and all. About seeing how you're gonna die.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Woman smiles a little, a crooked grin of broken teeth.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, on one hand, if dying was all you thought about, it could kind of screw you up. But it could kind of help you, couldn't it? Because you'd know that everything else you can survive.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Woman turns leaning her face right in front of his. And on a silent count of one, two, three -- Edward looks into The Eye. This time we don't cut. Instead, we HOLD ON Edward as he witnesses his death. He stares transfixed, perplexed and amused. Whatever he sees, it's not as dire as the other boys. His future has something strange in store.</context>
      <utterance>I guess I'm saying, I'd like to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Woman nods. Still a little overwhelmed, Edward turns and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Huh. That's how I go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADULT EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As Edward leaves, the door swings SHUT on its own.</context>
      <utterance>From that moment on, I no longer feared death. And for that, I was as good as immortal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We swam. The Atlantic, it's not that big really.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ruth McHibbon offered to pick you up at the airport.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We rented a car.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Starting over...</context>
      <utterance>You didn't need to do that. You just didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans in and hugs her. She surrenders, squeezing her son tight. Will and his mother are cut from the same cloth -- strong-willed but practical. They've always been close.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That hug finished, Sandra pushes past her son to her daughter- in-law. Seeing the size of her belly --</context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hug.</context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't have flown. But...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's not flattery. It's the truth.</context>
      <utterance>It's good to see you. You look beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I'll bet you need to --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Josephine squeezes past, a smile to her husband -- be nice. Will heads back to the rental car to retrieve luggage. Sandra follows him. Coming down the driveway, we get to see the house for the first time: an older suburban home, three bedrooms, big for the neighborhood, and nicely grown into the lot. KIDS are playing on the street.</context>
      <utterance>Down the hall on the right. The door sticks. You have to really pull it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Dr. Bennett's car?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heading back to the house...</context>
      <utterance>He's up with your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's impossible. He won't eat. And because he won't eat, he gets weaker. And because he's weaker, he doesn't want to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much time does he have left?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't talk about those things. Not yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Bennett. It's good to see you.  My wife, Josephine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He judges her belly.</context>
      <utterance>A pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're seven months.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans close to her, whispering in her ear...</context>
      <utterance>To the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, surprised but not doubting. Will looks over -- what did he say? Josephine shakes her head. Back to the main subject...</context>
      <utterance>It's a boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think he looks any worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And in the silence that follows, a lot is said. It wasn't the upbeat reply Sandra was hoping for.</context>
      <utterance>No. I would say he's the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I see him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of awkwardness -- everyone here knows they haven't spoken in years. Sandra hands Will a squat can of Ensure from the case on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. Be good for you to talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get him to drink one of these. He won't, but tell him he has to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward cracks open an eye, a beat before he focuses. He tries to say something, but no words come out. He looks over at a pitcher on the nightstand. Will pours him a glass of water, helping him hold it to his parched lips. Finished, Edward sets down the glass by himself. A very long, tense beat. Will almost speaks again to fill the silence. Finally...</context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You --  -- are in for a surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Having a kid changes everything. I mean, there's the diapers and the burping and the midnight feedings...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you do any of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I hear it's terrible. Then you spend years trying to corrupt and mislead this child, fill its head with nonsense and still it turns out perfectly fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm up for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will doesn't rise to the challenge. A beat, then he remembers the can of Ensure. Holds it up. Edward recoils.</context>
      <utterance>You learned from the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, then Edward rolls his eyes. Fine. Will cracks open the can, finding a straw on the nightstand.</context>
      <utterance>Just drink half the can. I'll tell her you drank the whole thing. Everyone wins.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People needn't worry so much. It's not my time yet. This isn't how I go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truly. I saw it in The Eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Old Lady by the swamp.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was a witch.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, she was old and probably senile. Maybe schizophrenic.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw my death in that eye. And this is not how it happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how does it happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward slurps down as much of the Ensure as he can stand, then pushes the can away. He swallows with difficulty.</context>
      <utterance>Surprise ending. Wouldn't want to ruin it for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was this panhandler who used to stop me every morning when I came out of this coffee shop near the office.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And every day I gave him a quarter. Every day. Then I got sick and was out for a couple of weeks. And when I went back there, you know what he said?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You owe me three-fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>True story.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you ever work in an office?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a lot you don't know about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward gives a wry smile. He walked into that.</context>
      <utterance>You're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will won't commit to Edward's assessment.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother was worried we wouldn't talk again. And look at us. We're talking fine. We're storytellers, both of us. I speak mine out, you write yours down. Same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, I'm hoping we can talk about some things while I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean, while I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward LAUGHS a little, which becomes a COUGH. The HACKING escalates until another drink of water gets it under control. It's not clear whether any of this was an act to keep from talking.</context>
      <utterance>I'd just like to know the true versions of things. Events. Stories. You.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mother hasn't been keeping up the pool. If you wanted to you could...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know where the chemicals are?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He didn't mean for that to sound so pointed. Taking the half- empty Ensure, Will gets up to go. He's at the door when...</context>
      <utterance>I used to do it when you were gone, remember? I used to do it a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at his joke.</context>
      <utterance>I was never much for being at home, Will. It's too confining. And this, here. Being stuck in bed. Dying is the worst thing that ever happened to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you weren't dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said this isn't how I go. The last part is much more unusual. Trust me on that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>YOUNG WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Bennett says I'm going to have to be home for a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nothing. I once had to stay in bed for three years.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you have chicken pox?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>INSERT: The encyclopedia article, complete with drawings.</context>
      <utterance>My muscles couldn't keep up with my bones, and my bones couldn't keep up with my body's ambition. So I spent the better part of three years confined to my bed, with the World Book Encyclopedia being my only means of exploration. I had made it all the way to the "G's," hoping to find an answer to my gigantificationism, when I uncovered an article about the common goldfish.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Kept in a small bowl, the goldfish will remain small. With more space, the fish can grow double, triple, or quadruple its size." Young Edward thinks this through.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It occurred to me then, that perhaps the reason for my growth was that I was intended for larger things. After all, a giant man can't have an ordinary-sized life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHARECROPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ate an entire cornfield!</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ate my dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOT-BLOODED SHOTGUN TOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you ain't gonna stop him Mayor, we will!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't have mob violence in this town. Now, has someone tried talking to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOME FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't reason with 'im!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPHARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agreement from the crowd. And then...</context>
      <utterance>He's a monster!</utterance>
   <speaker>A VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Everyone turns to see who said that. The crowd parts to reveal none other than Edward Bloom. Don Price glowers.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll talk to him. See if I can get him to move on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, that creature could crush you without trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, he'll have to try.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's no answer.</context>
      <utterance>Hello!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From deep in a cave, a thunderous voice:</context>
      <utterance>My name is Edward Bloom! I want to talk to you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, then we hear a RUMBLE, like a train coming. Edward braces himself, fists ready for a fight, if that's what it's going to take. As the RUMBLE gets louder, the ground starts to shake. Even Edward starts to worry. Just how big is this guy?</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going anywhere until you show yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Edward picks up a stone, ready to play David to Goliath. Then suddenly, the giant bursts forth. Hunched over, he slams into a stunned Edward, knocking him halfway down the hill. KARL THE GIANT is bigger than any man you've ever seen. Not just tall, but massive. He's completely feral, with a beard to his elbow and skin scratched and blistered. What remains of his clothes are ragged and muddy. God knows what's living in his matted hair. Karl leans over Edward, blocking the sun. Edward throws his rock, but it just bounces off. The giant didn't even notice it.</context>
      <utterance>Armed with the foreknowledge of my own death, I knew the giant couldn't kill me. All the same, I preferred to keep my bones unbroken.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward ponders the best response, settling on...</context>
      <utterance>Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karl's eyes narrow, confused. Edward stands up.</context>
      <utterance>So you can eat me. The town decided to send a human sacrifice, and I volunteered.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward closes his eyes, hands at his side, ready to be eaten. Karl just stares at him, not sure what to do. After a beat, Edward opens his eyes a tiny bit, just to see what the giant is doing. Relieved to see he's not licking his chops --</context>
      <utterance>My arms are a little stringy, but there's some good eating on my legs. I mean, I'd be tempted to eat them myself.  So I guess, just, if you could get it over with quick. Because I'm not much for pain, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karl sits down with a BOOM, dejected.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I can't go back. I'm a human sacrifice. If I go back, everyone will think I'm a coward. And I'd rather be dinner than a coward.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reaching up, Edward shoves his hand into Karl's mouth. But the giant spits it back out.</context>
      <utterance>Here, start with my hand. It'll be an appetizer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's the sad truth. Karl is less a monster than a freak -- a giant man, but in the end, just a man. Edward takes a seat beside him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to eat you. I don't want to eat anybody. It's just I get so hungry. I'm too big.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Circling behind them, we look down at Ashton -- a tiny town in a tiny valley.</context>
      <utterance>Did you ever think maybe you're not too big? Maybe this town's just too small. I mean, look at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hardly two stories in the whole place. Now I've heard in real cities, they've got buildings so tall you can't even see the tops of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't lie to you. And they've got all-you-can-eat buffets. You can eat a lot, can't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karl smiles, but then it fades. A certain sad suspicion --</context>
      <utterance>So why are you wasting your time in a small town? You're a big man. You should be in the big city.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just trying to get me to leave, aren't you? That's why they sent you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name, Giant?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karl.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine's Edward. And truthfully, I do want you to leave, Karl. But I want to leave with you.  You think this town is too small for you, well, it's too small for a man of my ambition. I can't see staying here a day longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karl thinks a moment. Then --</context>
      <utterance>I love every square inch of it. But I can feel the edges closing in on me. A man's life can only grow to a certain size in a place like this.  So what do you say? Join me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake on it.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now first, we gotta get you ready for the city.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That afternoon as I left Ashton, everyone seemed to have advice.</utterance>
   <speaker>VARIOUS TOWNFOLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find yourself a nice girl! Don't trust anyone in Kentucky! Watch your pride, Edward Bloom!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As the crowd parts, he finds himself face to face with</context>
      <utterance>But there was one person whose counsel I held above all others.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said that the biggest fish in the river gets that way by never being caught. The advice only succeeds in confusing Edward.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward and Karl keep walking. The Old Woman shuffles off, somehow knowing her advice will go unheeded.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did she say?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beats me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Edward and Karl come to a bend, where the paved road veers left and an overgrown dirt road runs straight. The old road is blocked with signs and warnings of danger.</context>
      <utterance>There were two roads out of Ashton, a new one which was paved, and an older one that wasn't. People didn't use the old road anymore, and it had developed the reputation of being haunted.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Karl looks at the dirt road, wary.</context>
      <utterance>Since I had no intention of ever returning to Ashton, this seemed as good a time as any to find out what lay down that old road.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know anyone's who's taken it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little paranoid...</context>
      <utterance>That poet, Norther Winslow did. He was going to Paris, France. He must have liked it, because no one ever heard from him again.  Tell you what. You take the other way and I'll cut through here. Meet you on the far side.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not trying to run away?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karl perks up, even though it means more for him to carry.</context>
      <utterance>Just to be sure, you can take my pack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Edward tosses the sign and forges ahead, into the spiderwebs.</context>
      <utterance>There comes a point where a reasonable man will swallow his pride and admit he's made a terrible mistake. The truth is, I was never a reasonable man.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what I recalled of Sunday School was that the more difficult something became, the more rewarding it was in the end.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A forty-year old man named BEAMEN comes out of the seed store to greet Edward. Friendly but a little drunk, he's the closest thing the town has to a mayor. He's carrying a clipboard.</context>
      <utterance>Friend!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to ya. What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beamen checks the clipboard. Not finding the name, he flips forward a few pages. Still looking...</context>
      <utterance>Edward Bloom.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bloom like a flower?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still confused...</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Here! Right here. Edward Bloom. We weren't expecting you yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were expecting me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A helpful woman named MILDRED chimes in:</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must have taken a shortcut.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. It nearly killed me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm-hmm. Life'll do that to you. And truthfully, the long way is easier, but it's longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Much longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beamen's daughter JENNY (8) hides behind her father, peering around to look at the handsome stranger.</context>
      <utterance>And you're here now, and that's what matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The town of Spectre. Best kept secret in Alabama. Says here you're from Ashton, right? Last person we had from Ashton was Norther Winslow.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The poet? What ever happened to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's still here. Let me buy you a drink. I'll tell you all about it. Hell, I'll have him tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He didn't mean it as a joke, but for some reason, everyone's laughing.</context>
      <utterance>No. I've gotta meet somebody. I'm already running late.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, I already told you. You're early.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now tell me if that isn't the best pie you ever ate.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It truly is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Jenny YANKS OFF Edward's shoes. She races for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Everything here tastes better. Even the water is sweet. Never gets too hot, too cold, too humid. At night the wind goes through the trees and you'd swear there was a whole symphony out there, playing just for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He chases after her.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! I need those!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no softer ground than town.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That rhymes!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The townsfolk continue to congratulate Edward...</context>
      <utterance>He is our poet laureate.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes in a dream, you'll visit places that seem instantly familiar, filled with friends you've never met.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Norther hands him his noteboook.</context>
      <utterance>A man might travel his entire life and never find a place so inviting. My journey had scarcely begun, and I had arrived.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been working on this poem for 12 years.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>There's a lot of expectation. I don't want to disappoint my fans.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norther grabs his notebook back.</context>
      <utterance>It's only three lines long.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is why you don't show work in progress.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norther, do you ever regret not making it to Paris?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't imagine any place better than here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norther doesn't answer. Just goes back to his notebook.</context>
      <utterance>You're a poet. You oughta be able to. And maybe if you'd seen more, you could.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRABBING THE SNAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman dives back underwater, understandably terrified that a man is coming at her.</context>
      <utterance>just as it's about to strike.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the splashing subsides, Edward looks at what he holds in his hands. Which isn't a snake at all, but rather a common stick. And a non-threatening one at that. While Edward ponders his mistake, he looks around to discover that the Girl in the River is gone. He never even saw her face.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's okay! I got it. I got the snake.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward keeps expecting her to surface, somewhere, but she never does. He stands alone in the river, wondering what tricks his eyes are playing on him.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! I'm sorry. Hello?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>A GIRL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Edward looks to the bank, where young Jenny Hill is watching him.</context>
      <utterance>There's leeches in there!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see that woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did she look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she... uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Embarrassed to admit it...</context>
      <utterance>Was she nekkid?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Given the day he's had so far, Edward isn't inclined to follow up on the issue. He starts to wade back to the bank.</context>
      <utterance>It's not a woman, it's a fish. No one ever catches her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Edward climbs up onto the shore, completely drenched. He pulls up his pant legs to reveal three shiny leeches clinging to his skin.</context>
      <utterance>Fish looks diff'rent to diff'rent people. My daddy said it looked like the coon dog he had when he was kid, back from the dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to work pulling them off.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm eight. That means when I'm eighteen, you'll be 28. And when I'm 28, you'll only be 38.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're pretty good at arithmetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eager to get off this subject...</context>
      <utterance>And when I'm 38, you'll be 48. And that's not much difference at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure is a lot now, though, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MILDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jenny thinks you're quite a catch. We all do.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward stops dancing. A beat, then he heads for the edge of the crowd. Beamen is there, with Jenny on his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>I said you're quite a catch!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to leave. Tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This town is everything a man could ask for. And if I were to end up here, I'd consider myself lucky. But the fact is, I'm not ready to end up anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's ever left.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you gonna make it without your shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Edward walks down Main Street. The townspeople stop dancing, disbelieving, some shaking their heads. Poor Edward Bloom's gone crazy.</context>
      <utterance>I suspect it will hurt a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't find a better place!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jenny runs to him. She'd tackle him if she could.</context>
      <utterance>I don't expect to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise me you'll come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's not good enough, but it will have to do. Edward keeps walking.</context>
      <utterance>I promise. Someday. When I'm really supposed to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As he ducks under branches, the chain holding the Key to the City gets caught. He's almost strangled, but the chain finally breaks. The silver key disappears into the mud. Scrambling forward, he looks for a way out. But the trees have encircled him, their spiky crowns bending down to crush him. He SCREAMS up at the night, until his breath is gone.</context>
      <utterance>As difficult as it was to reach Spectre, I was fated to get there eventually. After all, no man can avoid reaching the end of his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a sudden calm...</context>
      <utterance>And then I realized, this wasn't the end of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another lightning FLASH, and suddenly the trees are back where they've always been. Edward is lying shoeless and torn in a muddy puddle, staring up at the rain. And LAUGHING.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't how I die.</utterance>
   <speaker>A DEEP VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward turns to see</context>
      <utterance>Friend!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward looks down at his muddy, bloody feet.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to your shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, the men start walking down the larger road.</context>
      <utterance>They got ahead of me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if you've seen it, but Josephine has some photos in the most recent Newsweek.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really! That's wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I spent a week in Morocco for the story. It was incredible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. As Will scoops out another serving of potatoes, Edward suddenly speaks:</context>
      <utterance>We'll have to pick up a copy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All three stop to listen.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know if you're aware of this, Josephine, but African parrots, in their native home of the Congo -- they speak only French.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking the bait...</context>
      <utterance>You're lucky to get four words out of them in English. But if you were to walk through the jungle, you'd hear them speaking the most elaborate French. Those parrots talk about everything: politics, movies, fashion -- everything but religion.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not religion, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>It's rude to talk about religion. You never know who you're going to offend.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Josephine actually went to the Congo last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so you know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, would you say you understand Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I mean is, do you really know what's going on in his head?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is that possible? I mean, you try to ask him a question and suddenly it's another one of his stories.  You can't honestly say you know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's more amused than annoyed, but Will is entering dangerous territory.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Will, I do. And don't presume things you don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you say you understand Josephine?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. But that's a different...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves on to the carrots.</context>
      <utterance>No it's not. It's exactly the same. Your father and I met, we dated, and we married -- we chose each other -- because we understood each other on some fundamental level. Just the same as you two.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Josephine and I have a lot in common.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you both think William Bloom is a very smart man.  The problem is, you only see me as your mother, and not as someone's wife. And I've been his wife longer than I've been your mother. You can't discount that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a look, Sandra acknowledges the stakes.</context>
      <utterance>True. But I've known him my whole life, and I don't feel like I know him at all. Or ever will.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it's not easy. Just remember, he didn't choose to be your father and you didn't choose to be his son. You just ended up together. You could pick numbers out of a dark bag and it'd be just the same. If you ask me, it's a wonder parents and children can stand each other at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I understand you, Mom. I always have.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, clearly you don't. But I'm not the mystery you're trying to solve right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before I forget, your father has papers in the basement I'd like you to go through. I wouldn't know what's important.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was she one of your teachers?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But it's weird. She seemed to recognize me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cashier turns to look. He can only get a profile as the woman leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know who that is?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never seen her before. Pretty, though.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. How are you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was dreaming.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to recollect, but it's already gone. Josephine motions, is it okay for her to sit on the bed? He nods.</context>
      <utterance>What were you dreaming about?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>I don't usually remember unless they're especially portentous. You know what that word means, portentous?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Means when you dream about something that's going to happen.  Like one night, I had a dream where this crow came and told me, "Your Aunt is going to die." I was so scared I woke up my parents. They told me it was just a dream, to go back to bed. But the next morning, my Aunt Stacy was dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits up a bit in bed, his strength returning.</context>
      <utterance>Terrible for her, but think about me, young boy with that kind of power. Wasn't three weeks later that the crow came back to me in a dream and said, "Your Grampa is going to die." Well, I ran right back to my parents. My father said, no, Gramps is fine, but I could see there was trepidation. And true enough, that next morning my Grampa was dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat. Then, deadpan...</context>
      <utterance>For the next couple weeks, I didn't have another dream. Until one night the crow came back and said, "Your Daddy is going to die."  Well, I didn't know what to do. But finally I told my father. And he said not to worry, but I could tell he was rattled. That next day, he wasn't himself, always looking around, waiting for something to drop on his head. Because the crow didn't tell how it was going to happen, just those words: your Daddy is going to die. Well, he went into town early and was gone for a long time. And when he finally came back, he looked terrible, like he was waiting for the axe to fall all day. He said to my mother, "Good God. I just had the worst day of my life."  "You think you've had a bad day," she said. "This morning the milkman dropped dead on the porch!" Josephine smiles, a half-laugh, which gets him smiling too.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because see, my mother was banging the milkman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, a bit more of a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>He was slipping her a little extra cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Edward continues, she can't help but laugh harder, especially as the metaphors get more vulgar.</context>
      <utterance>He was filling her basket. He was making deliveries around back.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was buttering her rolls. Pumping her churn. Splashing milk in her box.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's starting to cry from laughing.</context>
      <utterance>They were squeezing the cheese. Clanking the bottles. Licking the popsicle.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, he stops. She regains her composure.</context>
      <utterance>Cracking the eggs and making an omelet.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spooning the sherbet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I take your picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't need a picture. Just look up handsome in the dictionary.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Josephine leaves, heading down the hall to get her camera. We STAY WITH Edward in bed.</context>
      <utterance>Please? He rolls his eyes, why not.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Edward grimaces, a flash of pain. Around others, he's hiding how much it hurts, but alone we can see how bad it is. He controls his breathing, trying to push through it.</context>
      <utterance>I have photos from the wedding to show you. There's a great one of you and my father. I had an extra print made.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She returns with her camera. Edward smiles, doing a good job masking the pain.</context>
      <utterance>I want to see pictures of your wedding. I've never seen any.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because we didn't have a wedding. Your mother-in-law was never supposed to marry me. She was engaged to somebody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will never told you that?  Probably just as well. He would have told it all wrong anyway. All the facts and none of the flavor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so this is a tall tale?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A devilish smile. Pushing past Edward, we settle on the whirling fan.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not a short one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From behind Amos, CARNIES start rolling a massive ball towards the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentlemen, you may think you've seen the unusual. You may think you've seen the bizarre. But I've travelled to the five corners of the world, and let me tell you, I've never seen anything like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amos comes up to a MIDDLE-AGED WOMAN in the first row, a quieter moment.</context>
      <utterance>When I found this man, he was picking oranges in Florida. His fellow workers called him El Penumbra -- The Shadow -- because when you were working beside him, he blocked out the daylight. He could take a whole tree in his hands and shake off the fruit. I had to pay his crew boss $10,000 just so I could take him with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The carnies back away from the ball as a deep DRUM ROLL begins. A moment, then the ball starts to bulge from inside. A foot suddenly bursts out from within. GASPS from the crowd. That foot is massive. In the stands, Edward looks closer. Intrigued. As the drum beat intensifies, a second foot breaks out. Followed by hands. Shoulders. Finally, the head. This is</context>
      <utterance>Not to alarm you, Ma'am. But if this man wanted to, he could crush your head between his toes.  But he won't.  He's not going to hurt her, folks, because he's our own Gentle Giant. Ladies and Gentlemen, I give you Colossus!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his name? Does he talk? It's not important.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karl.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me Karl, have you ever heard of the term "involuntary servitude?" Karl shakes his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Unconscionable contract?" Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, great. That's fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was on that night Karl met his destiny. And I met mine. Almost.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey kid! Your friend just made himself a star.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amos hands off the contract to a CLOWN.</context>
      <utterance>That's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>INTRODUCING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My attorney, Mr. Soggybottom.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Soggybottom HONKS his horn, then waddles off.</context>
      <utterance>Good to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you, kid? I haven't seen a customer so depressed since the elephant sat on that farmer's wife.  Get it? "Depressed?" Karl chuckles.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See! The big guy likes it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just saw the woman I'm going to marry, I know it. But then I lost her.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tough break. Most men have to get married before they lose their wives.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to spend the rest of my life looking for her. That or die alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, kid.  Let me guess. Real pretty, blonde hair, blue hat?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know her uncle. Friends of the family.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is she? Where does she live?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Amos starts to walk away, Edward hurries to catch up with him. Karl follows as well.</context>
      <utterance>Kid. Don't waste your time. She's out of your league.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? You don't even know me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I do. You were hot shit back in Hickville, but here in the real world, you got squat. You don't have a plan. You don't have a job. You don't have anything but the clothes on your back.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the bleachers, where no backpack is to be found.</context>
      <utterance>I've got a whole backpack full of clothes!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone stole my backpack.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Getting in front of Amos, Edward stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Kid, you were a big fish in a small pond. This here is the ocean, and you're drowning. Take my advice and go back to Puddleville. You'll be happy there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amos smiles, amused.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. You said I don't have a plan. I do. I'm going to find that girl and marry her and spend the rest of my life with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a job, but I would have a job if you gave me one. And I may not have much, but I have more determination than any man you're ever going to meet.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, kid. I don't do charity.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amos takes a long look at him. Ultimately, there's no way he can say no. He shrugs. What the hell.</context>
      <utterance>I'll work night and day, and you won't have to pay me. You just have to tell me who she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward shakes Amos's hand before he can retract the offer. We move into a MONTAGE:</context>
      <utterance>Every month you work for me, I'll tell you one thing about her. That's my final offer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amos stops, looks at the young man. Finally...</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Calloway! It's been a month today.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks away. We PUSH IN on Edward, enraptured by the concept.</context>
      <utterance>This girl, the love of your life. Her favorite flower is daffodils.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daffodils.  Daffodils!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wonder of it. He goes back to shoveling, a smile on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Daffodils!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True to his word, every month Amos would tell me something new about the woman of my dreams.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sudden EXPLOSION as Edward is shot...</context>
      <utterance>College! She's going to college!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Music! She likes music. I like music too!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>That time had come. I couldn't wait any longer.</context>
      <utterance>Over the months, I learned a lot about the woman I was going to marry, but not her name, and not where to find her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the rocking and moaning stop. A beat, then the door handle begins to RATTLE. It seems to be stuck. Edward turns the knob. Suddenly, the door BURSTS OPEN. Edward is knocked down by a massive black dog, biggest you've ever seen. It has green glowing eyes and a lick of fire for a tongue. Edward wrestles with the beast, its mouth snapping at his throat. Blocking with an arm, Edward tries to push himself free, but the creature's hands -- it has hands instead of paws -- hold on tight. Entwined, they roll across the dirt. The other nearby CARNIES scatter for cover. Mr. Soggybottom pulls a revolver out of his clown suit. Loads a silver bullet. Edward finally succeeds in throwing the beast off. He rolls to his feet. The hell hound squares back on its haunches, GROWLING, ready for another leap. Mr. Soggybottom sheds a clown tear, aiming the revolver at the dog. At the last moment...</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Calloway! It's Edward Bloom. I need to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward moves just as Mr. Soggybottom FIRES. The bullet catches Edward in the shoulder, knocking him down. The carnies GASP. Licking its chops, the dog approaches the helpless Edward, who feels the ground around him, looking for some kind of weapon. He finds only a small stick. He waves it at the dog, ready to strike it. Like magic, the dog's whole demeanor changes. It bounces excitedly, ready to play fetch. Seeing an opportunity, Edward throws the stick as far as he can. The dog bounds after it,</context>
      <utterance>No, wait!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't kill anything, did I?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few rabbits, but I think one of them was already dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward tosses him his jacket to cover his privates.</context>
      <utterance>That would explain the indigestion.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wrong about you kid. You may not have much, but what you got, you got a lot of. You could get any girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>There's only one I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her name is Sandra Templeton. She's going to Auburn. The semester's almost over, so you better hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward walks away. Then starts running. He has to get there as soon as possible. Amos sits down and scratches his ear with his foot.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After saying my goodbyes, I hopped three trains to get to Auburn that afternoon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SANDRA, overwhelmed. All she can finally think of to say is...</context>
      <utterance>You don't know me, but my name is Edward Bloom and I am in love with you. I've spent the last three years working to find out who you are. I've been shot and stabbed and trampled a few times, had my ribs broken twice, but it's all worth it to see you here, now, and to finally get to talk to you. Because I am destined to marry you. I knew that from the first moment I saw you at the circus. And I know it now more than ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her hand on the door frame. On her left ring finger, we see a diamond.</context>
      <utterance>Don't need to apologize to me. I mean, I'm the luckiest person you're going to find today...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON EDWARD as his heart falls 20 floors. He tries to suppress the reaction, put on a brave front.</context>
      <utterance>No I'm sorry, I... I'm engaged to be married.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're wrong. I do know you, at least by reputation. Edward Bloom from Ashton. See, I'm actually engaged to a boy from Ashton. Don Price. He was a few years older than you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stays in the doorway for a few beats, feeling genuinely horrible for what's happened. But eventually she goes back inside. We hear GIGGLES from inside as her sorority sisters get to the bottom of this.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Congratulations. I'm sorry to have bothered you. He turns and walks down the front steps.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We LEAD Edward as he walks away, tears just starting to form.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it. It's not funny. That poor boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He EXITS FRAME, leaving only the sorority house in the background.</context>
      <utterance>Fate has a cruel way of circling around on you. After all this work to leave Ashton, the girl I loved was now engaged to one of its biggest jerks.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A beat. Edward steps back INTO FRAME, looking at the sorority house.</context>
      <utterance>There's a time when a man needs to fight, and a time when he needs to accept that his destiny is lost, that the ship has sailed, and that only a fool would continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We CIRCLE as he shouts:</context>
      <utterance>The truth is, I've always been a fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sandra Templeton! I love you! And I am going to marry you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daffodils?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're your favorite flower.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get so many?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of nowhere, a tear drops down Sandra's cheek. She wipes it off.</context>
      <utterance>I called everywhere in five states and explained this was the only way I could get my wife to marry me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't even know me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From down the street...</context>
      <utterance>I have the rest of my life to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sandra!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Don. Promise me you won't hurt him.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The adult DON PRICE arrives. He's 230 pounds of football- playing, Skynyrd-loving, fraternity-proud muscle. And he's pissed. A gang of his BROTHERS walk behind him.</context>
      <utterance>If that's what you want, I swear to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bloom!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing? This is my girl. Mine!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don Price decks him, knocking him down. Edward gets right back up, but makes no move to defend himself. Unfazed, Don slugs him again.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't know she belonged to anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the matter, Bloom? Too scared to fight back?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Don shrugs, fine. Then proceeds to kick Edward's ass nine ways to Sunday.</context>
      <utterance>I promised I wouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As the ass-whupping continues, we</context>
      <utterance>While I took the beating of a lifetime, it was Don Price who was ultimately defeated.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don is about to slug Edward again when he turns. Sandra pulls off her engagement ring. There's an audible AHH! from her sisters, and an OHH! from Don's brothers.</context>
      <utterance>Don!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Don stands stunned, his mind reeling. Edward, whose eyes are swollen almost shut, keeps waiting for the next punch. Where is it? What's going on?</context>
      <utterance>I will never marry you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What. You love this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him the ring. Another beat, then Don storms off. But not before decking Edward one last time. Sandra leans over Edward's broken body. His head lies on the daffodils.</context>
      <utterance>He's almost a stranger and I prefer him to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I convince you to stop?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, his teeth bloody.</context>
      <utterance>Go out with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the crowd of students APPLAUDS and CHEERS, we CRANE UP above the flowered battlefield.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As the MUSIC reaches a crescendo, we suddenly...</context>
      <utterance>As it turned out, Sandra was able to keep her same date at the chapel. Only the groom had changed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you said you didn't have a church wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for his glass of water, but Josephine already has it for him. She watches him while he slowly drinks the entire glass, thirstier than he imagined. While he's drinking, we...</context>
      <utterance>Well, we were all set to, but there was a complication.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it the medicine that's making you thirsty?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Will quietly approaches the door, not exactly sneaking, but not exactly announcing his presence. The door is open a few inches, letting him look in on his father and his wife.</context>
      <utterance>Truth is, I've been thirsty my whole life. Never really known why.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was one time when I was eleven...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were talking about your wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't forget. I was just working on a tangent. See, most men, they'll tell a story straight through, and it won't be complicated, but it won't be interesting either.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like your stories.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't let the moment linger with undue sentimentality. There's a story to be told.</context>
      <utterance>And I like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the hallway, Will shifts to a new position, letting himself listen to the story one more time.</context>
      <utterance>Now. The thing about working for a circus is you don't have a regular address, and after three years I had a lot of undelivered mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>During the four weeks I was in the hospital, the postmaster finally caught up with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still fighting, Edward jumps for a pole on the far side of the catwalk, sliding down it to end up</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes a girl can feel so alone Without a lover to call her own. Sometimes it's so bad, she wants to explode. Wants to grab the first man she sees and tear off his clothes. A ROAR from the soldiers. She knows what they want.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACKSTAGE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His determined opponent follows him down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she won't. No, she can't. She needs a special special different unusual man. Because that girl, Who looks like me, She has wants, but she has needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>PING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers ROAR LOUDER, STOMPING on the bleachers. Backstage, the two men are still fighting.</context>
      <utterance>Any of you got needs?</utterance>
   <speaker>PING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had twice the adventure, Cried double the tears. Two times the bad times in half the years. I need a strong man, because I've got Twice the love to give. For the first time, Ping turns, and now we see why she was standing in profile. Ping is one-half of</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say hello, Jing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Jing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could you miss your cue? You make me look like a fool, out there alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ping HUFFS, turning her back on her sister. Jing reaches deeper into the closet to find a new dress, exposing Edward's hiding place. She GASPS. Ping turns to look.</context>
      <utterance>You weren't alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(yelling)</context>
      <utterance>Damn right you're not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard obeys. Ping shakes her sister off. Desperately flipping through his Asian phrasebook, he finds...</context>
      <utterance>Tell your men not to bother us! And lock that door!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, I need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>PING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward pulls a photo out of his flak jacket. It's Sandra.</context>
      <utterance>What makes you think we'll help you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Hearing the story, Jing wipes away a tear. Even Ping is a little affected.</context>
      <utterance>Over the next hour, I described my love for Sandra Kay Templeton, and the ordeal that brought me before them. As it had always been, this love was my salvation. It was destined to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Still subtitled:</context>
      <utterance>We put together an elaborate plan for escape, involving a whaling ship to Russia, a barge to Cuba and a small, dirty canoe to Miami. We all knew it would be dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>PING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what are we supposed to do when we get to America?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can get you bookings. I know the biggest man in show business.</utterance>
   <speaker>JING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob Hope?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bigger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A black car pulls up. Two ARMY OFFICERS get out.</context>
      <utterance>And so the twins and I began our arduous journey halfway around the world. Unfortunately, there was no way to send a message back to America.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Hearing the news, Sandra CRIES OUT. The pain of her shout makes church bells RING.</context>
      <utterance>And so it was no surprise that the Army believed I was dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I talked with your father last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look to say, should I be worried?</context>
      <utterance>Did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never told me how your parents met.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They met at Auburn.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the details? How they fell in love. The Circus. The War. You never told me any of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because most of it never happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>But it's romantic.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves his head out from under the sheet. She follows him to the "outside."</context>
      <utterance>Mmm, what. I know better than to argue romance with a French woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you love your father?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone loves my father. He's a very likeable guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will doesn't want to answer yes or no.</context>
      <utterance>Do you love him?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to understand. When I was growing up, he was gone more than he was here. And I started thinking -- maybe he has a second life somewhere else. With another house, another family. He leaves us, he goes to them. Or maybe there is no family. Maybe he never wanted a family. But whatever it is, maybe he likes that second life better. And the reason he tells all those stories is because he can't stand this boring place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off her silence...</context>
      <utterance>What is "true?" I've never heard my father say a single true thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I know why you like him. I know why everyone likes him. But I need you to tell me I'm not crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you on my side.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am always on your side. And I think you should talk to him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I ever tell you about how...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward is startled.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The maple tree and the Buick. We heard it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think someone hasn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>The tree fell on the car, spilling the syrup, which attracted the flies, which got stuck to it and flew off with the whole car.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the real story is how I got the car. You see...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra SNAPS the cap back on the syrup.</context>
      <utterance>Can we talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to get started on dishes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both women quickly gather plates. Will and Edward both smile. The women clearly want this to happen. It settles for a beat after they leave.</context>
      <utterance>I'll help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know much about icebergs, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I? I saw an iceberg once. They were hauling it down to Texas for drinking water, only they didn't count on an elephant being frozen inside. The woolly kind. A mammoth.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to make a metaphor here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you shouldn't have started with a question. Because people want to answer questions. You should have started with, "The thing about icebergs is..."</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The thing about icebergs is you only see 10 percent of them. The other 90 percent is below the water where you can't see it. And that's what it is with you Dad. I'm only seeing this little bit that sticks above the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you're seeing down to my nose? My chin?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea who you are because you have never told me a single fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've told you a thousand facts. That's all I do, Will. I tell stories.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell lies, Dad. You tell amusing lies. Stories are what you tell a five-year old at bedtime. They're not elaborate mythologies you maintain when your son is ten and fifteen and twenty and thirty. And the thing is, I believed you. I believed your stories so much longer than I should have. And then when I realized that everything you said was impossible -- everything! -- I felt like such a fool to have trusted you. You were like Santa Claus and the Easter Bunny combined. Just as charming and just as fake.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm fake.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward looks away, angry and disbelieving.</context>
      <utterance>Only on the surface. But that's all I've ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, I'm about to have a kid of my own here. It would kill me if he went through his whole life never understanding me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally --</context>
      <utterance>It would kill you, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want, Will? Who do you want me to be?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yourself. Good, bad, everything. Just show me who you are for once.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have been nothing but myself since the day I was born. And if you can't see that, it's your failing, not mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra hands Will a yellowed telegram. He shares it with Josephine.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will can't believe what he's reading.</context>
      <utterance>It was during the war. Your father went missing. They thought he was dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That really happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, then Sandra stands.</context>
      <utterance>Not everything your father says is a complete fabrication.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to check on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to lie down for a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Josephine kisses him, then follows Sandra. Will re-reads the telegram, still bewildered. Looking for a place to put it, he tucks it into a strange mechanical hand on the desk. It clamps down automatically. Will smiles, a memory. He hasn't thought about this device in years. We slowly PUSH IN on the telegram, held in the hand. Edward's VOICE begins as a memory...</context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After the war, the sons of Alabama returned home, looking for work. Each had an advantage over me. They were alive, while I was -- officially -- deceased.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward sets down a contraption, which looks something like a metal lava lamp. Like a flower, it unfolds to reveal five fingers and a thumb. This is the Hand Around the House.(TM)</context>
      <utterance>I've travelled from Tennessee to Timbuktu, and if there's one thing people have in common, is we could all use a hand around the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>QUICK MONTAGE as he demonstrates:</context>
      <utterance>Why, with this product you can...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indeed, a remarkably agile Edward is able to support his entire weight on it. The crowd APPLAUDS.</context>
      <utterance>Open a jar. Open a letter. Scratch yourself while wearing mittens. Hold a book. Hold a baby. Hold the dog away from kittens. It's strong enough, you can do a handstand with no hands at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hand points a finger at an HEAVYSET MAN IN OVERALLS.</context>
      <utterance>You can use it to point out important information. Or dangers. Or beautiful women.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd LAUGHS.</context>
      <utterance>We're still working on that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon I added other products, and other cities, until my territory stretched from the coast to western Texas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man is none other than...</context>
      <utterance>Edward? Edward Bloom?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me. Norther Winslow.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The men shake, disbelieving this lucky coincidence.</context>
      <utterance>I was astonished to see the greatest poet of both Ashton and Spectre all the way out in Texas.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to know, when you left Spectre it opened my eyes. There was a whole life out there that I was not living. So I travelled. I saw France, and Africa, half of South America. Every day a new adventure, that's my motto.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's genuinely proud.</context>
      <utterance>That's great, Norther. I'm happy for you. I can't believe I helped.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you up to now?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reaching the front of the line, Norther pulls two pistols out of his coat, FIRING both into the ceiling. SCREAMS all around. The skinny SECURITY GUARD makes a halfhearted reach for his gun, but Norther waves him off. The guard takes out his gun and slides it over.</context>
      <utterance>I'm robbing this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He decides he better go.</context>
      <utterance>Now, I want all of you to lie down. I'm gonna be cleaning out the cash drawers, and my associate here is going to handle the vault.  You help my friend, okay? The TELLER WOMAN nods. ANGLE ON Edward, not sure what to do. He has a gun, but he truly doesn't want to shoot Norther. The Teller Woman is already waving him to the back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm really sorry. I just don't want anybody to get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>TELLER WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls open the vault door.</context>
      <utterance>It's not that, it's just...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TELLER WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...there's no money. We're completely bankrupt.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It turned out the savings and loan had already been robbed -- not by armed bandits, but by speculators in Texas real estate.</utterance>
   <speaker>TELLER WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta promise you won't tell anybody.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward winces, but doesn't say anything yet. Digging through the vault bag, Norther is surprised to find only a single deposit envelope. He rips it open, revealing just a little cash inside. Even some dimes and pennies.</context>
      <utterance>Sixty. Eighty. Four hundred dollars! Not bad for just the drawers. Let's see what you got from the vault.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is it? The whole vault.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Fraid so.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caught, Edward has to confess...</context>
      <utterance>Edward, it's got your deposit slip on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward continues his narration...</context>
      <utterance>Look, I just didn't want you to go empty-handed. There's something you should know, Norther. You see, the reason why...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Hearing this news, Norther was left with one conclusion:</context>
      <utterance>I told Norther about the vagaries of Texas oil money and its effect on real estate prices, and how lax enforcement of fiduciary process had made savings and loans particularly vulnerable.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward looks over at Norther, the reality sinking in.</context>
      <utterance>I should go to Wall Street. That's where all the money is.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The two men wave at each other as Edward drives off. At the last moment, Norther calls out:</context>
      <utterance>I knew then that while my days as a criminal were over, Norther's were just beginning.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTHER WINSLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's talking about his Hand Around the House. We HOLD ON Norther for a beat, dreaming of his future.</context>
      <utterance>Edward, thank you for the hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When Norther made his first million dollars, he sent me a check for ten thousand. I protested, but he said it was my fee as his career advisor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We reveal the Bloom house, the nicest one in the neighborhood. Edward kisses his wife.</context>
      <utterance>Ten thousand dollars is no fortune to most men. But it was enough to buy my wife a proper house with a white picket fence.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Sandra drops the hose, letting it run on the lawn.</context>
      <utterance>And for that, it was all the riches a man could ever want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was drying out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, then pulls his knees up, making room for her in the tub. A beat while she considers. Sandra steps out of her sandals and climbs into the tub, facing him. Her dress is soaked, but she doesn't mind. He leans forward and kisses her. When they separate, she has tears hanging in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I see. We need to get you one of those plant misters. We can spray you like a fern.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wipes them away.</context>
      <utterance>Come now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I'll ever dry out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he awake?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She passes him. He turns.</context>
      <utterance>He just fell asleep. Josephine's with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will quickly debates whether or not to ask her...</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you and Dad have any other property?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose your grandmother's house when she passed on. But we sold that right away. Your cousin Shirley bought it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you never bought any land.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will nods, just curious. He continues heading up.</context>
      <utterance>Heavens no. We had a hard enough time keeping the mortgage on this place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The door opens to reveal a blonde woman in her 50's -- the woman from the grocery store. Her name is Jenny Hill. She and Will are startled to see each other.</context>
      <utterance>Go back to the start. Right hand only. The piano starts again. FOOTSTEPS.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Confused, Will checks the name on the form.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't expecting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you Jenny Hill?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PIANO STUDENT, a black boy of eight, has stopped. He's watching the conversation at the door. Speaking of awkward...</context>
      <utterance>I am. And you're Will. I've seen your picture, that's how I recognize you. I almost said something at the store, but it would have been awkward.  Like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him five dollars out of her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Kenny. Why don't we skip the lesson today? We can go again next week.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have to give it back to my Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You don't have to tell him twice. He's out the door in a flash.</context>
      <utterance>I won't tell her if you won't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know my father?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Not flinching...</context>
      <utterance>This was on his sales route, so he was through here all the time. Everyone in town knew him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you and my father having an affair?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Wow, you just said it. I was expecting to dance around this for another half hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves, trying to get out of the corner he's boxed her into. Once she's finally free...</context>
      <utterance>I've seen him with women. He flirts. He always has. On some level, I presumed he was cheating on my mother. I just never had proof.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you a question? Why did you come here today? If you found this deed, why didn't you just ask Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat. Jenny is taken back by the suddenness of it. She's a tangle of conflicting emotions.</context>
      <utterance>Because he's dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't know how much you want to know about any of this. You have one image of your father and it would be wrong for me to go and change it. Especially this late in the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fair enough. Jenny takes a seat across from him at the table.</context>
      <utterance>My father talked about a lot of things he never did, and I'm sure he did a lot of things he never talked about. I'm just trying to reconcile the two.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first thing you have to understand, is that your father never meant to end up here. And yet he did, twice. The first time, he was early. The second time, he was late.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The first raindrops hit the windshield. Edward turns on the wipers.</context>
      <utterance>Those days, your father was working for himself. If there was one thing you could say about Edward Bloom, it's that he was a social person, and people took a liking to him. One night he was returning from three weeks on the road, when he hit a thunderstorm unlike any in his life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Edward raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Two different corporations were looking at buying the town, if they could get the price low enough. One wanted to open a chicken processing plant. The other, a municipal dump. Either way, Spectre would be destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone turns to look at this new bidder.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty-thousand!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And so Edward Bloom decided to buy the town, in order to save it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was never a wealthy man, but he had made other men rich, and now he asked for their favors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most of them had never seen Spectre -- they only had Edward's words to describe it. That's all they needed. He sold them on the dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>JING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Edward takes notes...</context>
      <utterance>You can structure it as a historical trust. But you'll need every contiguous piece of property. It's all or nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So first he bought the farms. Then he bought the houses. Then he bought the stores.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever he bought, the people were not asked to leave or pay rent or anything. They were just asked to keep doing as they were doing. In that way, he could make sure the town would never die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be Edward Bloom.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She keeps PLAYING.</context>
      <utterance>How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one would come out here unless they had business. And no one would have business with me except for you. You're buying the town.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apparently I've overlooked this one piece of it, and I'd like to remedy that. You see, in order for the town to be preserved, the trust must own it in its entirety.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I've heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jenny stops playing, her piece not quite finished. She turns to face him. Edward still doesn't recognize her.</context>
      <utterance>I'll offer you more than it's worth. And you know you won't have to move. Nothing will change except the name on the deed, you have my word.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strange to hear it put that way, but --</context>
      <utterance>Now let me get this straight. You'll buy the swamp from me, but I'll stay in it. You'll own the house, but it'll still be mine. I'll be here, and you'll come and go as you please to one place or another. Do I have that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In so many words, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I don't think so Mr. Bloom. If nothing is going to change, I'd just as soon it not change in the way it hasn't been changing all this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat.</context>
      <utterance>It's not like you're going to lose anything. You can ask anyone in town. I've been nothing if not generous. I want the best for everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, puzzled and surprised. No one has really asked before.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bloom, why are you buying this land? Some sort of midlife crisis? Instead of buying a convertible, you buy a town?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helping people makes me happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not convinced you should be happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finally turns to face him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Have I offended you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you did exactly what you promised. You came back. I was just expecting you sooner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Beamen's daughter. Your last name is different.  You married.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can say anything more...</context>
      <utterance>I was 18. He was 28. Turns out that was a big difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't be selling you this house, Mr. Bloom.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bit bewildered, Edward tips his hat to her as he leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I see. I thank you for your time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to lean the door against the frame, but it keeps slipping.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, just leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans the door a different way. It holds for a beat then falls in, SMASHING a small table.</context>
      <utterance>I can get it. I can just...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord, I'm sorry I...</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Go. Just go.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll...</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's dead serious. Weighing the scales of chivalry, he finally backs away. Turns and heads back towards his car. We STAY ON Jenny, watching him go. She's furious, but there's something more in her feelings for him. Something softer.</context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most men in that situation would accept their failure and move on. But Edward was not like most men.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finished with his work, he takes his hat off the chair and hangs it on the rack. Perfect. A beat. A look between them. With that last job done, there's no reason for him to be staying any longer.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, the best part was creating new material. By the time the twins and I got to Havana, we had a whole new routine worked out for them, with just a ukulele and a harmonica.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his hat off the rack.</context>
      <utterance>I suppose I should...</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes closer. Edward holds his ground. She takes his hand, lifting his hat up to the peg. She's very close -- just a half-inch from kissing him when -- -- Edward gently holds her back.</context>
      <utterance>You can leave it there. A beat. Does she really mean it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She freezes, stunned and humiliated. She pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't. Don't be embarrassed. I should never have let you think that...  I am in love with my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And from the moment I saw her until the moment I die, she's the only one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucky girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, he begins to leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Jenny. I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finds a pen and hastily signs the deed to the house. Hands it to him. With a look, he thanks her. Then goes.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Edward!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We REVERSE to find FOUR KIDS looking in through the rusty iron gate with flashlights. A beat, then they run away.</context>
      <utterance>As for the girl, the common belief was that she'd become a witch, and crazy at that. She became something of a legend herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the story ended where it began.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Logically, you couldn't be the Witch, because she was old back when he was young.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's logical if you think like your father. See, to him, there's only two women: your mother and everyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't become crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will smiles to hear it called that.</context>
      <utterance>Well, therapy. And one day I realized I was in love with a man who could never love me back. I was living in a fairy tale.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her composure is starting to break.</context>
      <utterance>People aren't like they are in stories. They hurt each other without meaning to. They are kind and unbelievably cruel at the same moment. Like me, now. I'm not sure I should have told you any of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat, both staring at their iced tea. Jenny is working herself into more of a state by not talking.</context>
      <utterance>No, I wanted to know. I'm glad I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's fighting tears, not the first ones she's shed over this.</context>
      <utterance>I wanted to meet you for the longest time. I did.  I envied you so much. The way Eddie would talk about you when you were at Missouri, that award you won. Congratulations, incidentally. And when you got the job at the A.P., everything, he was so proud of you. I mean, that's the thing. Every moment he loved you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON Will, sorting through his swirling thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>And as brightly as the sun would shine when he was with me, every time he left it disappeared. I wanted to be as important to him as you were, and I was never going to be. I was make-believe and his other life, you, were real.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew that, didn't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He turns to see his wife at a payphone. She hangs up. She was calling him.</context>
      <utterance>Will!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father had a stroke. He's upstairs with your mom and Dr. Bennett.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He half-smiles, realizing the idiocy of his question. Of course his father's not going to be okay.</context>
      <utterance>Is he going to be okay? A beat. How can she answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cuts him off --</context>
      <utterance>What I mean is, will he get back to the way he was when...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And like that, it's done. We HOLD ON Will, reeling from the news.</context>
      <utterance>No. He won't. I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't suppose one of us could stay with him. In case he...  In case he wakes up, one of us should be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll stay. Why don't you go home with Josephine and I'll stay tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll call if...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>I will. I'll call.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, do you want some time with Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nod, then Will holds the door for Dr. Bennett and Josephine as they leave. Sandra is alone in the room with her husband. She neatens his hair. Holds his hand. As she kisses his fingers, she tweaks her chin with them -- his signature move.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. It seems every hour I have to...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two women start to walk, no hurry.</context>
      <utterance>I know. It was the same when I was carrying Will. Like clockwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like it, being pregnant?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra has accidentally evoked a storm of emotion. She struggles to keep it in check. Almost a whisper...</context>
      <utterance>I loved it. It sounds peculiar, but I loved every minute of it. I did. Eddie was travelling a lot, so he was gone, but I felt like I always had a piece of him with me. A little part of his soul inside me. I could feel it. It was alive and kicking.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a few breaths, Sandra tries to hold on. Hold back.</context>
      <utterance>I really miss that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, then Sandra finally melts. Josephine holds her. The two women stand together in the hallway, letting the moment be.</context>
      <utterance>Don't stop. Don't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad to see you're not trying to have a heartfelt talk. It's one of my greatest annoyances, when people talk to those who can't hear them.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Bennett smiles as he checks Edward's chart.</context>
      <utterance>My father and I have an advantage. We never talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you known my father?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty years. Maybe more.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would you describe him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did your father ever tell you about the day you were born?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A thousand times. He caught an uncatchable fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that one. The real story. Did he ever tell you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long silence, just the sounds of the hospital, doctors being paged.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother came in about three in the afternoon. Her neighbor drove her, on account of your father was on business in Wichita. You were born a week early, but there were no complications. It was a perfect delivery. Now, your father was sorry to miss it, but it wasn't the custom for the men to be in the room for deliveries then, so I can't see as it would have been much different had he been there. And that's the real story of how you were born.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patting Will's shoulder, Dr. Bennett leaves. We STAY ON Will and his father for a long time, then Will takes his pen and starts making a list.</context>
      <utterance>Not very exciting, is it? And I suppose if I had to choose between the true version and an elaborate one involving a fish and a wedding ring, I might choose the fancy version. But that's just me. Will half-smiles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His father is awake, silently GASPING for breath. His eyes are open, scared and confused.</context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward shakes his head unambiguously. Will already has his finger on the orange "nurse call" button, but doesn't push it.</context>
      <utterance>Dad! Do you want me to get a nurse?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward nods. Will pours a glass from the pitcher on the nightstand. He holds it to his father's lips, but Edward won't drink. He pushes it away. He wanted something else.</context>
      <utterance>What can I do? Can I help? Can I get you something? Water?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The river.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes Edward all his strength to put together each thought. It's like he's only half-there, fighting to hang on to this world.</context>
      <utterance>The river?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me how it happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How what happens?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON WILL, realizing...</context>
      <utterance>How I go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward nods. Yes, that's what he was trying to say. A long beat.</context>
      <utterance>You mean what you saw in The Eye?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will pushes his fingers under his father's heavy hand, and holds it. There's nothing else to do. Edward looks around, confused and increasingly scared. He sees the end approaching, but doesn't know exactly what's coming. Without the story, he's lost. Fighting the urge to panic --</context>
      <utterance>I don't know that story, Dad. You never told me that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can try, Dad. If you help. Just tell me how it starts.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will looks around the room, increasingly desperate. He looks to the nurse call button. He really wants to press it. ON EDWARD, waiting for Will to begin.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. It's morning, and you and I are in the hospital. I'd fallen asleep in the chair. I wake up and I see you, and...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's dawn, and the first golden glow is shining through the vertical blinds.</context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We LOOK OVER to find a nimble Edward sitting up in bed, combing his hair.</context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somehow, you're better. Different. You're getting ready to go. And I say...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Edward throws back the covers.</context>
      <utterance>Dad, you're in no condition to...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will heads for the bathroom. Sure enough, the wheelchair is there.</context>
      <utterance>There's a fold-up wheelchair in the bathroom. Wrap a blanket around me. As soon as we get off this floor, we'll be in the clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry! We don't have much time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass a HEAVYSET NURSE, who turns to look. Rounding a corner, they nearly crash into Dr. Bennett.</context>
      <utterance>Faster!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BENNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can answer, Will spots Edward rolling the chair himself, pumping both arms. Will dashes to catch up with him. The Heavyset Nurse leans out of Edward's hospital room.</context>
      <utterance>Will! I... What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Security! Stop them!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Will sets him in the passenger seat.</context>
      <utterance>I pick you up and you hardly weigh anything. I can't explain it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scrambling in back, Will finds a liter of Arrowhead. Hands it off. Edward unscrews the cap, but instead of drinking it, he douses himself. Soaks the blanket. Will pops the trunk. Starts to fold up the wheelchair.</context>
      <utterance>Water. I need water.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIRES SMOKE as the car peals out.</context>
      <utterance>Leave it! We won't need it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT ON Edward, enjoying that detail. He's focused completely on Will's story.</context>
      <utterance>And we have to take Glenville to avoid all the church traffic, because those damn church people drive too slow.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ask...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we headed?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Amos Calloway is here with the circus folk, including Mr. Soggybottom. We also find Edward's Mother and Father, the Mayor, and many others from along the way. No one has aged a day since we saw them last. While Ping scans the horizon, Jing nuzzles with her boyfriend, Norther Winslow. It's Ping who first spots the Chevrolet.</context>
      <utterance>As we get closer to the river, we see everybody's already there. And I mean everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>PING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd CHEERS. The Ashton marching band PLAYS. Jenny Hill smiles. So does the Old Woman. We PUSH IN on the Old Woman's glass eye, where we see...</context>
      <utterance>He's here!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>reflected. This is what he saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's unbelievable.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Story of my life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Will walks into the river, up to his knees. He turns back so his father can face the crowd. Edward waves.</context>
      <utterance>And the strange thing is, there's not a sad face to be found. Everyone's just so glad to see you, and send you off right.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye everybody! Farewell! Adieu!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CROWD</speaker>
      <mode>VARIOUS</mode>
      <context>But one face is missing from the crowd -- Sandra. Will turns to see she's already standing in the river beside them. The reflection of the light off the water gives Sandra an unearthly glow. She's more tranquil and more beautiful than we've ever seen her.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye Edward! / See ya! / We'll miss you!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him. He tweaks her chin. The crowd HOLLERS in approval, but their moment remains strangely private. Only Will is there to witness. As the kiss ends, Edward tries to pull off his wedding ring. But it's stuck. Finally, he sucks on it, pulling it free with his teeth. A look to Will, a smile with a glint of gold. Will takes the ring out of his mouth. Edward suddenly drops out of Will's arms with a SPLASH. For he's no longer a man, but rather</context>
      <utterance>My girl in the river.</utterance>
   <speaker>A FAT CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We watch as the catfish circles, then heads for deeper water, disappearing. Will and his mother stand knee-deep in the water, watching Edward Bloom swim away into the sunlight. Josephine is back on the shore, along with the entire crowd. MUSIC BUILDS to a climax, then... Down the river, a GIANT FISH suddenly jumps out of the water, cutting a beautiful arc across the sunset. It then dives back under with a SPLASH.</context>
      <utterance>swimming at his feet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You become what you always were. A very big fish.  And that's the way it happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward smiles, proud of both of them. His eyes are so pale and so open, we can almost see his soul. In every atom of his body, in every thought, Edward Bloom is entirely happy. And this is how he goes.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Exactly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So he said he'd fight the giant who was fifteen feet tall.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, that's right, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will smiles as his son continues the tale, which FADES. Sandra takes Will's hand in hers, just listening.</context>
      <utterance>See. So he was a giant but my grampa was going to fight him because he wasn't afraid of anything because he'd seen how he was going to die in this old lady's glass eye...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was my father's final joke I guess. A man tells his stories so many times he becomes the stories. They live on after him.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
