<movie id="77" title="Birthday Girl">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand adjusts a microphone on his lapel.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shifts in his chair. Coughs. He looks straight at us.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, hello. Hello...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes the microphone. He sits there, thinking very hard.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe in perfect love. You know, love that comes out of the sky like a thunderbolt and uh... This is ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands, turns and stretches.</context>
      <utterance>No. No no no. Nope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>We all have someone in our past who uh... one skeleton, if you like. We've all got at least one person, as it were, under the patio. Not literally of course. I suppose I only say this because I always thought people who did this sort of thing were... I had an image that they were losers. Not losers. A bit sad. But I think this is the modern world. And I think really it's quite a brave move. Quite a brave, reasonable thing to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry can we start again?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods.</context>
      <utterance>Nadia?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>I'm John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well. Look I didn't have a speech but... A distorted passenger announcement breaks above us. It's too loud to talk. It ends and they stand there in silence. He points to her luggage.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand there.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Okay. Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about forty miles from here. I don't know if you've looked at a map, it's close to London but it's a city in itself. A Roman city. It's a nice house. I'm having a problem with ants. I uh... It's the warmer weather. I can't seem to find the nest. Sorry, do you understand "ants"?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just can't find a nest. The root of the problem. I've looked everywhere. What's the Russian for ant? Sorry that's a stupid... Sorry. This is strange isn't it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pretty nervous. Are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean... "Ants." "I've got a problem with ants." He shakes his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls a sign from his jacket which says "Nadia!"</context>
      <utterance>I had this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drive. He sees Nadia looking at England.</context>
      <utterance>As a joke but uh... He tosses it onto the back seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. Is it different to how you imagined it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet.  What about me? Am I how you imagined?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He double-takes, changes lanes.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how was the flight. Sorry, am I speaking too fast for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John looks across.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do uh... Sorry. Can you follow me? Do you understand what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Or should I speak slower?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you follow or should I speak slower?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks across. Back at the road. He changes gear.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... Are you a giraffe?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John turns to face the road ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drives in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly she winds the window down and vomits out of the speeding car. John panics and swerves onto the hard shoulder amidst loud horn blasts.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She peers round him and looks inside. He leads her down towards the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Lounge.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances around it. Then back at John. He nods to himself, looking tense and pale.</context>
      <utterance>Kitchen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes it.</context>
      <utterance>Bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There it is. The Double Bed. John frowns gravely. Without warning, he marches out. She comes out onto the landing to catch John plus suitcase kicking open another door and vanishing inside.</context>
      <utterance>Bedroom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at it, then up at John. She turns and walks out. Now she's back, with her camouflaged hold-all, dumps it onto the floor, heaves the suitcase onto the bed and smoking no- hands, starts unpacking. John plugs in the lamp by the bed. To show Nadia how it works he switches it on, off, on, off, and then feels stupid.</context>
      <utterance>The uh... the other bedroom...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With John gone, Nadia stops unpacking. She walks to the window and stares out over the rooftops of the estate.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get an ashtray.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANSWER MACHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have reached From Russia with Love. Our office reopens on Monday. If you are interested in our services...  Thank You.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is John Buckingham from St Albans. I need to speak to you urgently. There's a critical problem. It's... Call me back as soon as possible. It's critical.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia reaches down into her bag and pulls out a small box wrapped in brown paper. She places it in front of him. He warily unwraps a little wooden box. He opens the lid and fishes out a simple gold ring. He holds it in his palm.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to say. Your letters were in English. Good English. You said you'd studied English.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts it back in the box, hoping it will disappear. She fishes it out again and holds it on her palm for him to take.</context>
      <utterance>I can't take this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his hand. He automatically yanks it away like he's been burned. She takes his hand again and to stop it becoming unbearable, he allows Nadia to push the ring onto his ring finger. It goes on easily.</context>
      <utterance>I can't take it. I'm not really a ring guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. No big deal. Thank you. Yes thanks. Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the ring off and holds it out to her. She doesn't take it. He puts it on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Nadia. This isn't going to work. I'm sorry. It's been a terrible mistake. You must go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John and Nadia on her bed, Nadia tearing off his tee shirt. She gets on top.</context>
      <utterance>I'm booking a flight for tomorrow. I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Problem solving. John identifies most problems within appropriate time frames...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We move fast through the banking hall to the furthest counter. The blind snaps up to reveal John, wearing a smart suit.</context>
      <utterance>Most of the time he develops several alternative solutions to problems...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He usually resolves or minimises most problems before they grow into larger problems...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good weekend?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. Yeah. Pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do anything special?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Communications. John listens and comprehends well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Across the desk the Branch Manager reads a report out loud in an impersonal, flat manner.</context>
      <utterance>When communicating he is good at selecting the most efficient methods and displays effective verbal communication skills...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On one occasion John showed first class communication skills in a delicate customer situation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bluffers guide to the Internet. She opens an old copy of The Lion, The Witch and The Wardrobe. Inside is written 'John Buckingham Class 3F'.</context>
      <utterance>He is adequate at resolving difficult or emotional customer situations...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He usually fulfills commitments made to customers within expected time frames.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>One of John as a little boy, holding a football, flanked by his parents. On the back someone has written "Summer 1973".</context>
      <utterance>Customer Service. John shows a high degree of respect for customers...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>There is a photo of John, about three years ago, arm in arm with a plain, thin-looking girl, with small eyes. Another of him kissing her on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>John still has some reluctance to / or has problems in, carving out new relationships face to face.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judgment -- John makes able decisions in most areas of his job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRAINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stands again and closes his eyes. After a short wait he falls back and again his colleague catches him just before he hits the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good. How does that feel John?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It feels good. Weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John nods.</context>
      <utterance>It's called Trust and Letting Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A simple guitar theme begins, and plays over the following sequence: Kids playing cricket in John's Close. A boy hits the ball and others chase it as it bounces off cars. John at dusk tied to the bed with his two bank ties. Nadia is on top. They are having sex. Hands stacking bank notes into the back of a cash machine. Fast, mechanical. At the bank, John walks to his desk. His phone rings. He answers it. Silence. Then soft breathing. John listens intently and looks around. "Nadia...?" -- John sits there, surrounded by his colleagues, listening to Nadia breathe. Close up on a man's hands tying a tie tight a-round a woman's wrist. Pull back to a close up of Nadia's face, her eyes fixed on John. John running by the river. John watches Nadia rise from his bed after sex and leave the room. He stares out the window. Nadia's fingers, knitting skillfully. Nadia sits on her bed alone, pulling on black stockings and attaching them to suspenders. The street cricketers run for cover as a thunder storm breaks over the close. Rain coming down in John's garden. The pair sit under the shelter of the back porch. John has his hands out as Nadia is winding red wool it into a ball. The jumper is half finished. The rabbits shelter from the rain under broad leaves. John in a pub with a four colleagues from the bank. He sips his half, half listening to the conversation. It all seems so dull. He finishes his drink and looks at his watch. They ask him if he's staying for another. A knitting needle is drawn from a row of red stitches on the nearly-finished jumper. Nadia kneels over John holding the knitting needles. She presses one to his skin and we watch it drawn across his chest in close up, up to his neck. His eyes are fixed on hers. Close up on Nadia's face. Her mouth is gagged and she's lying on her front, head half-buried in a pillow. We can just make out John behind, on top of her. Both are lying still and breathing hard, covered in sweat. Catching her breath Nadia yanks the gag off and wriggles out from underneath him. She snatches up a towel and covering herself hurries to the bathroom. The guitar theme ends.</context>
      <utterance>Trust and Letting Go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, then down at her tome. She speaks slowly, in a heavy accent:</context>
      <utterance>Are you O.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today is bath day.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She studies her book. Looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Today is bath day.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods.</context>
      <utterance>Bath day?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The penny drops.</context>
      <utterance>Happy bath day.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She frowns. John leafs through the dictionary.</context>
      <utterance>Today?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Syevodnya?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Syevodnya</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his hand on her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday. Happy Birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John nods, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Party.  Party. Syevodnya.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lights a cigarette from the butt of her last. Blows smoke. She holds the jumper up to John, as if to try it for size, and the theme returns.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Party. Party syevodnya.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...It might just be a twenty-four hour bug...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you just get better. I'll tell Beaky. You just get some rest, ok?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="56">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In Russian, the first man introduces Nadia to the other man, who is relighting the candles with a Zippo. It seems they haven't met before. The first man, Yuri, pulls out a bottle of vodka and hands it to John.</context>
      <utterance>You must be John. You seem very nice. Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that? We can't drink our piss can we?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang on hang on, sorry, but like, who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must find some glasses, small, for the toast, and some plates.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri stops.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. You've lost me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm asking what you're here for.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri speaks to Nadia in fast Russian.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Frenzy".</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Yuri.  Alexei. Alexei and Yuri.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia talks fast to Yuri.</context>
      <utterance>He says he feels safe here.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei turns off the light again. Nadia blows out her candles. They are plunged back into darkness. John turns the light on again. Yuri is already sitting down.</context>
      <utterance>She says she wanted to tell you but her English is shit. And no one speaks Russian, it's very hard for her. The light please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to know who you are first please.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.  We are Russian.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he sits down)</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And...</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands John another bottle of vodka.</context>
      <utterance>And what? You mean from the beginning? Jesus. Can I uh okay, as we say in Russia can I cut a long story short. Okay. Nadia is my little cousin. Except she's not. But we say cousin. This is for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vodka is splashed into their glasses. Yuri raises his glass and shouts a toast in Russian: "Vashe Zdarovye!". They down their vodka, John sips at his, then realises he must finish it. Yuri makes as if to throw his in the fireplace.</context>
      <utterance>Toast first then we talk seriously, I can see you are serious about us.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sausages, cheese, bread and pickle bottles rain onto the table from Yuri's rucksack.</context>
      <utterance>Just kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So hang on. You're both Nadia's cousins?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not. Alexei, he's is my problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We better watch him. He's crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri mimes giving a blow-job.</context>
      <utterance>I am actor, he is actor, although he is an actor stroke musician. I just noodle along, I'm not so good. He makes me look like a retard -- He smokes me. I don't mean he smokes me.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He mimes the blowjob again.</context>
      <utterance>I mean he smokes me. Do you say "smoke" in U.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Right. So I can say he smokes me. So.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri speaks to Nadia in Russian, she replies looking at John.</context>
      <utterance>So I come to England with other actors to make shows, I meet this freak from Novgorod I tell him of you and Chicken and the birthday here we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked her if you were happy to see us. I find it hard to tell with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia lights a cigarette. John notices that on both wrists she has bold red marks from the ties. He freezes.</context>
      <utterance>Yes it's okay. Thank you for the food.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John is thrown, panicking that one of them will notice the marks.</context>
      <utterance>She says you are a little shy. I think I know this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how long will you be in England?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plans are for the architects, politicians and so forth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must have a visa or something...</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're asking for my documents?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri laughs, translates for Alexei and they both get a big laugh out of this. Yuri gets his passport out and makes a big show of presenting it to John. But John keeps glancing at the marks on Nadia's wrists. We see a close up of her neck. There is the tiniest blood mark. John sees it and starts to sweat.</context>
      <utterance>No, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri raises his glass and they all drink to Tony Blair and Margaret Thatcher. John drinks his vodka in two hot gulps.</context>
      <utterance>We are all Europeans here. Europe, Tony Blair and Maggie Thatcher!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John looks glazed. The room falls silent.</context>
      <utterance>So. You have nothing to say to your Fiancee? Maybe to wife of forty years it's understandable. Come on. You speak and I will translate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri translates -- She replies.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She says 'Hello' to you. Go for it John!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. Do you like England?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John nods. He watches Nadia tap ash. The wrist again.</context>
      <utterance>Classic!  Thank God. She says 'Yes!'</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all wait. Yuri nods encouragingly.</context>
      <utterance>Uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia speaks in Russian to Yuri.</context>
      <utterance>I can't think of anything. Hang on.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She says she has a secret to tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia speaks. John waits uncomfortably. Silence.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stops.</context>
      <utterance>She says she watched you at the airport.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I saw you waiting there, by the gate."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see John's face.</context>
      <utterance>"I have these uh..." She explains to you... "When I was a little girl my father had these beautiful old glasses." Like... I don't know the word. Like for watching uh... for watching the birds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Binoculars.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Binoculars. He had these Binoculars he has kept from the war.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>butterflies, birds, a rabbit. She stops running and aims the binoculars up, up, into the sun</context>
      <utterance>I would run around with them taking pictures of things I liked with my mind. If I saw something beautiful I would take a picture. With the binoculars pressed to her face, she spies</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia looks at the table.</context>
      <utterance>The day before I left Russia my father gave me the old binoculars. He said that when I saw you I was to stand far away and look at you with these, and to examine your face closely. And if you were a bad person I could run away.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John watches Nadia looking at the table. She glances up once and catches his eye. Alexei suddenly slams his hand down on the table. He raises his palm. There is an ant squashed there. He shows Yuri.</context>
      <utterance>She says she took a picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nasyekski.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It is too judgmental.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me what he said.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. John suddenly looks sick.</context>
      <utterance>He says why did you send to Russia for a wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not ashamed of it? It's no surprise to want to love.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's not that.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe in love?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose it's... I mean define your terms.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a plate and starts reaching for the food.</context>
      <utterance>It's very strange. How many people are truly themselves with their love? It is the greatest human disaster and it is never in the newspapers. There are no Marches Against Heartache, no Ministries Against Loneliness, no Concerts Against Disappointment. We look away. And still we know in secret that nothing is more important to us. The one thing we all share but don't say. Look John I will show you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John accepts the plate.</context>
      <utterance>Here look, something beautiful from Russia. Here is Life, there, take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John eats.</context>
      <utterance>Here is bread. Khylep. This is work. We all need this, here eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John bites the sausage.</context>
      <utterance>Good. But we cannot survive with just work, so here is meat and blood. Myasa. This is family and country, flesh, strength, eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John nibbles some pickled garlic.</context>
      <utterance>But again this is not life. Here is joy and pain. Chyesnok. Without these life has no flavour, is too serious. Eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is love. Only this magic changes you inside. The moon and the stars and the sun. Yuri offers John the glass. He looks at Nadia, takes it and swigs it down in one. He looks across at Nadia, wiping his mouth, his eyes watering. She looks back at him. Alexei begins softly singing a song. As he sings:</context>
      <utterance>But this vodka.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They listen to the beautiful, sad voice. For the second verse Yuri joins in, a slow stirring lament. For the end Nadia joins in too and the three of them begin harmonising beautifully. John watches in the candlelight. John, Nadia and Alexei pose with the cake. Nadia puts her arm round John and Alexei. With a FLASH! Yuri takes a Polaroid. The guitar theme returns as we see the Polaroid on the table in close up, developing speeded up. John comes into focus, beaming.</context>
      <utterance>This is a love song, a soldier's song to his beloved -- Alexei, he's Afghanstya, a veteran of Afghanistan. He saw terrible things.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Quick word John?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is sensitive. Your car. Lovely car. Doesn't necessarily give the right impression.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ch...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To customers approaching the bank from the rear</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can see why it's sensitive?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The manager smiles and taps the desk twice.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John is left alone.</context>
      <utterance>I'll leave it on your desk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is bank?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. I thought you were leaving today.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia stops knitting and takes her shirt off and stretches back to sunbathe in her black bra. Alexei takes the knife he has just finished cleaning and holds the cold wide blade flat above Nadia's bare stomach. Just before pressing it down he looks across at John. Nadia yelps and sits up. They laugh, and Yuri joins in. John laughs uneasily. Alexei notices marks on Nadia's midriff. He asks her about them in Russian. John goes white, unable to understand Nadia's explanation. He has no idea what she told him.</context>
      <utterance>To be indoors on such a day. It's crime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John begins to swim toward Alexei. Just as he gets near, Alexei lets Nadia surface, coughing and spluttering -- she shouts at Alexei in Russian, angry. Alexei makes for her again but she pushes him away, twice, almost slapping him. She is very uncomfortable. She swims away. Yuri admonishes his friend in Russian. Alexei stares at John, then swims off powerfully back towards the shore.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John watches Nadia walk out of the lake towards her clothes.</context>
      <utterance>He's just having fun. He's maybe too strong you know...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They go. John. They go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. They go. Yes. Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They go.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. I'm so sorry</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can stay tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have brought you trouble. Maybe I should have come alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei stares at John as he backs out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei shouts at Yuri in Russian.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei shouts again. Nadia is frozen with terror.</context>
      <utterance>John, I'm sorry. It's my fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei addresses John.</context>
      <utterance>What's he doing? What the fuck are you doing? Leave her alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei and Yuri shout at each other. Nadia begins crying.</context>
      <utterance>He says sit down. Or he'll cut her.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John sits across the table from Nadia.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kettle boils. Alexei takes the kettle and holds it over Nadia's head. John springs up.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him to stop and let her go, and we'll talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put the fucking kettle down.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri translates -- Alexei replies.</context>
      <utterance>Put the fucking kettle down. Tell, Yuri, tell him put it down or I'm going to make him.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says you scare him so much he must go to the toilet in his trousers. John, he is a soldier. A trained killer. We must do what he says.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei speaks.</context>
      <utterance>What? What does he want?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say? Tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says you are very sad ridiculous man. I don't agree of course. And that you must pay someone to have sex like a prostitute. Nadia is a prostitute. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he want. The Russian shithead. What do you want ?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri translates this for Alexei. Alexei has a reply.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him to put the kettle down and I'll give him money.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants a lot of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give him money. Tell him to put the...</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants the money from your bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll fuckin' give it to him! We'll go down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't understand. He wants all the money that is in your bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The penny drops.</context>
      <utterance>I've got eight hundred pounds. Oh Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is sure you can do this. Of course you can not.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei doesn't need the translation he tilts the kettle, and a small amount of boiling water trickles onto Nadia's hair. She screams through the gag. John tries to reach across to her but Alexei draws the knife and holds it to his face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus. Of course I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just leave her alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE UP On Nadia's terrified eyes, imploring John to help her.</context>
      <utterance>Leave her alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah John. This is Robert Moseley, Head of South East New Business. Robert, this is John Buckingham.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you could give us the tour this morning. Sort of be our Indian Guide.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you play?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's John. He's always surprising you with hidden talents.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>I used to be in a band. Keyboards. Sort of like very loud, uh -- very loud Marillion.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Maestro, give us a tune.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Branch Manager takes John to one side and stage-whispers.</context>
      <utterance>I'll give you a tune later.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the ball and run with it John.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A colleague passes carrying a file.</context>
      <utterance>This is uh... This is the uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSING COLLEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning John. Give us a tune.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you a tune later.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is where we're doing Trust and uh... Trust and Letting Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not doing this till the fourth quarter -- Has it, uh -- any results, has it been been beneficial?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's weird at first. Sort of exciting and frightening at the same time. Wouldn't you say John?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANCH MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They say hello to each other and MOSELEY asks her a couple of questions.</context>
      <utterance>We're starting to see results. This is Karen, who's uh... taking uh... it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLLEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning John. Hey, Moseley's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you a tune later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei says "SSShhh" He is counting in his head. He stops.</context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You first.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty thousand. Almost exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty four thousand, eight hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other, absorbing the moment.</context>
      <utterance>There's over eighty thousand here.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lies back on the bed and chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Sweet Jesus...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put it in the cases. Split it up. And don't forget you owe me 150.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what for.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got you those trousers from Paul Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been buying you stuff all week. I've been buying him stuff all week.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia is smiling at them as they squabble.</context>
      <utterance>Such as?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we went to the Hard Rock Cafe. Who paid? When we went to see 'Cats'. Who paid?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those aren't presents. That's normal friendship stuff</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I paid for those guitar cases.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was 'Cats' like?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah it was okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It was quite good actually. Some bits I really liked.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sets were good.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri goes into the bathroom, leaving Nadia and Alexei alone on the bed. Alexei runs his hand across Nadia's cheek.</context>
      <utterance>The sets were excellent. Everything was big, you know, all the rubbish, coke cans, sweet wrappers, dustbins, so when you were watching it you felt cat size. It was really clever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. How many times did you have to fuck him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John refuses to meet his eye. Yuri flushes and wipes his hands.</context>
      <utterance>How you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From his back pocket, Yuri takes out an old envelope. He opens it and removes a dozen or so Polaroids. John looks down at the first Polaroid. Nadia, Alexei and a man John doesn't recognise at a birthday party. There is a cake with candles and everyone is smiling. The next picture is the same. And the next. Sometimes Germany, sometimes France, but otherwise the pictures are the same, each 'fiancee' beaming with his arm round Nadia, Alexei looking on. John studies the faces of his fellow dupes and at last comes to his own picture. Despite himself tears come to his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'll show you something. It should make all this easier I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri takes John's left hand and pulls off Nadia's ring. He puts it in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Not all these bastards were like you, believe me. You should not too feel bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's enough isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I mean babe, It's enough. We can stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to stop?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss. He takes her hand, and notices the tie marks on her wrists.</context>
      <utterance>We'll stop then.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothing. I burnt myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not a burn.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit there looking at each other.</context>
      <utterance>It is. I did it cooking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia looks back at him. The seconds pass.</context>
      <utterance>On both wrists?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei studies her face. She pulls a face. He keeps staring.</context>
      <utterance>What? I did it cooking.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit there in silence. Alexei is so big, and she is so small.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia leans over the bed, and searches in her bag. Alexei watches her closely. She comes back up with the jumper she has knitted.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I made you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the jumper, then back at her.</context>
      <utterance>Put it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts pulling at his shirt. Eventually he pulls the jumper on. It fits perfectly.</context>
      <utterance>It's taken me weeks. I want to see you in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is still staring at her.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his hands. He is still looking at her. He strokes his hair. He places his big hand around her throat and holds it there, holding her at arms length. She doesn't react, but just looks levelly back at him. They sit like this for about ten seconds, looking at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei seems not to relax. He keeps his hand there.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to have a baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei removes his hand. Now he seems shocked. He lights a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>You heard what I said. I'm pregnant. I've been throwing up for weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>We're having a baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A baby? What are we supposed to do with a baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes to him and holds him. He is still absorbing the news. We see Alexei's face over her shoulder, behind her back, unreadable. Behind his back she rubs her wrists.</context>
      <utterance>Name it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning. What can I get you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have an espresso, with a small pastry, a croissant or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We only do a croissant with the Continental breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just get me a coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>One coffee. And for you Sir ?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress leaves them. Nadia lights a cigarette and they sit in tense silence, the pain of betrayal, and recent violence, thick in the air.</context>
      <utterance>He'll have a coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia ignores him. John bellows</context>
      <utterance>You can't smoke in here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It seems as if John has no intention of replying. He sips his coffee, and puts it down. He begins speaking very calmly.</context>
      <utterance>I don't expect you to understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know. In my job as Deputy Assistant of New Business at the bank would have to listen to the problems of a great many individuals. This took a lot of understanding and sympathy, to try to work out solutions to their problems. But, you see, I'm not in that line of work anymore. Nowadays I'm a bank robber.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't understand anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sips his coffee.</context>
      <utterance>I think that about covers it. I think I have grasped the part about you being dumped though. That's got to hurt, I imagine. That's got to smart a bit. I mean strictly in my observer's capacity it seemed you two were getting on Pretty Fucking Famously.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless. Unless this is part of the routine. You get tied up, stick around, distract me, they both bust in and Steal My Cup Of Coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's makes it easier. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It makes it faster. If I don't speak to the men, they fall faster. It's pretty obvious why.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>That's a relief. It's nice to know I'm a regular guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to drink my coffee. Then, we're going to the police station. Where there will be lawyers, loss of job, house, humiliation, gutter press, and probably prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't blame you. When a bank employee does this they understand. You get your life back. Anyway I bet you hated that bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even so I always felt the decision to burst in and rob it very much remained with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why else would you send off for me? If you just wanted sex just go to a prostitute.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slaps his face. He slaps hers back. The waitress comes over.</context>
      <utterance>Well as it turns out I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes please.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pours for John.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Splendid. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and leaves them. John watches her walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This really tickles John. He has to put his coffee down.</context>
      <utterance>John, I need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must think... I'm the biggest pillock... In the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you just want to punish me --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do. I want to very badly.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're just going to be vindictive</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In every sense. If at all possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't hurt me more than I'm hurt already.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Nadia, It it's all the same to you, I'd like to give it a bash.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stares back at her.</context>
      <utterance>My name isn't Nadia.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the restroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to be sick. Where's the...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No you're not..</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going... I am... I'm going to be sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia stands and addresses the Duty Sergeant.</context>
      <utterance>No you're not. How... Nice one. How dumb do you think I am ?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the restroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The what, love?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The toilet. Where's...</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads off. John springs up. He seizes her arm as casually as possible.</context>
      <utterance>Down there on the left.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John looks at the Policeman, then at Nadia. The seconds pass.</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John is still looking at Nadia -- He closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Sir? Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John looks sick. He speaks very quietly.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets inside. Nadia is left standing there. She gets in too.</context>
      <utterance>Get in the car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John ignores her.</context>
      <utterance>Plenty of women have babies in prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to do this. I can look after myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you got your passport?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up. Have you got your passport?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drive along.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to get off this motor-way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me some money.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stops squeezing petrol.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have any money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stares at Nadia. He eyes the CCTV.</context>
      <utterance>I said I don't have any.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia passes them and John puts them on,trying to look casual. He gives the pump a couple more squirts, hangs it up, nonchalantly sidles up to his door. In one move he opens it, dives in, turns the key in the ignition. The Rover coughs. He tries it again. It howls, barks and sneezes. The attendant comes out onto the forecourt and starts approaching the yellow Rover. Miraculously it roars throatily to life, he floors it and the Rover tears away from the station and off down the road</context>
      <utterance>Give me your sunglasses.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="67">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, uh, Alexei, which I know isn't his name...</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to talk about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's none of your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia ignores him.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Absolutely. Must be disappointing though. Must come as a hell of a shock.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, if you want to know is he better in bed than you then yes he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If what you want to know is does he have a bigger cock than you, then yes he does.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Of course. Of course he does. Of course. Thank you. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drive.</context>
      <utterance>But, you know, so what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>It's his baby I take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the kids type then is he? Not that broody. You must be pretty miffed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He left me my passport and ticket. It's pretty clear he wants to see me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I tend to tie up and abandon women I really want to see again too.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John freezes. He looks across. Nadia gives nothing back.</context>
      <utterance>No. But you tend to tie them up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia is just looking at him.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is just looking at him.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck off. You started it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up. I'm not listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia looks out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Okay we won't talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll pretend it never happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. What's it like having to fuck men you hate?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't hate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's... Okay. Okay. You have had sex with people you don't like haven't you? For money. To make money.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And? What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And. It's wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who says what is wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that would be Morals. That would be one's own moral sense of decency.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a moral orgasm John? Tell me how it feels exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. What then? You just detach sex from everything..</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whereas "Wet 'n' Wild" is an emotional journey. "Tied and Tethered". It's pretty moving huh? Like Anna Karenina.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John remembers he did. Nadia looks across knowingly.</context>
      <utterance>Listen. I didn't go rooting around in your private stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Funny. Usually it's the first thing they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what? Do you just switch off in your head or do you imagine you're with him, or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes which?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some... What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing wrong in liking sex, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like sex. I don't think I'll be having sex ever again.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's just that the thought trying to charm up an erection in front of a woman, or alone for that matter, makes me want to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now you hate all women?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's my safest bet, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John looks across.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. I think you will recover okay. I think you got what you paid for.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got what I paid for.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't mind too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't what I wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what did you want? I think we understand each other, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't understand me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>You don't understand you either.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stops the car.</context>
      <utterance>It's no big thing. You are the same as most men. You are a man so you are a savage. Not a monster, but half animal. You put on a tie and you go to the bank, but really you are a beast. But also you are from woman so you have a soul. Half beast, half soul. But you hide your beast in the bottom of the wardrobe. It's not so healthy. It's fucked you up, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits there.</context>
      <utterance>Get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are throwing me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She collects her bag from the back seat, her cigarettes, gathers up her belongings, clicks open the door and gets out, leaving the shot. John sits there staring ahead. We hear her voice offscreen.</context>
      <utterance>Get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>John turns the key in the ignition. The engine bellows and screams. Silence. He tries again. The engine shrieks and wails like a soul in torment. A terrible, mournful grinding noise. Silence.</context>
      <utterance>You prefer your women mute.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>John tries to start it. It lets out a whimper, a crying, a few juddering moving sobs, and dies. John sits in his dead car. He shakes his head. He rubs his face. He sits there.</context>
      <utterance>Car trouble?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets her holdall from inside the car and stuffs the map inside.</context>
      <utterance>It's another twenty miles. It's going dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia scans the horizon with her binoculars. John watches her.</context>
      <utterance>What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia lowers her binoculars and looks at John.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. You weren't even on the plane.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="54">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, in Russia, there's no work for women. It's a different world.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to say anything</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I... I wasn't saying...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, there's no... Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't saying anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Then okay.  So how old were you when you met him?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen. You don't know him. He was very kind and strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. He's a smashing bloke.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rest of the world, John, it's not all like St. Albans.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank Christ for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are pretty naive if you think it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pretty naive? Look at you. You have to do all this, and what have you got to show for it? Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Well what have you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit there in the lapping firelight.</context>
      <utterance>I have my baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know if it's a boy or a girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you had any before?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you scared?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A fox cries out in the night.</context>
      <utterance>Not really. Maybe a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She listens. It cries out again. She gets out her binoculars.</context>
      <utterance>Listen. I think it's a fox.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks through them and searches the brush. John watches Nadia with her binoculars. He looks suddenly very sad.</context>
      <utterance>It sounds close.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts them back in her bag. John watches her. He sees her wrist again. She lights a cigarette, and blows the smoke into the air.</context>
      <utterance>I can't see anything. It's too dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened between you and the blonde?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The thin... the girl with small eyes. The one in your cupboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's none of your business. She didn't have small eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she leave you? Come on. It's nothing to be ashamed of. Who did she leave you for? Your best friend? Her boss? A woman? Did she leave you for a woman, John?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>She's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I didn't mean to hurt you. I'm sorry. That's awful. Forgive me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia looks at John.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know why I said that. She's not dead at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why I said it. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia starts to laugh. Long and loud. We have never seen her laugh before.</context>
      <utterance>She's alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's alive!! She is not dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to cough. She gets on her hands and knees and coughs like fury.</context>
      <utterance>Laugh it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should stop smoking. You're pregnant. You smoke like a fucking lab dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got news for you. It's not working.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I smoke more these days. I smoke more when I'm unhappy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's that unhappy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I want to die. Don't you want me to die?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want anyone to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except for Small Eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs again.</context>
      <utterance>Except for Small Eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John thinks. It looks as if he's going to tell the whole story. In the end he shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>So why did it end?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was her name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fox cries out again.</context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They listen to the fox crying in the night.</context>
      <utterance>Listen. It's definitely a fox. Now I'm scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you can come under the blanket.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene from bird's eye view. John lies back and stares at the stars. Nadia curls up on the other side of the fire, and hugs herself. We push down closer and closer until we are on John's face. The theme returns. The cricket boys from John's Close stand in a line in the middle of the street, bathed in flashing blue light. We pan round and end on John's house. It is surrounded with Police. Police cars, Police Vans, plastic police tape "POLICE LINE.</context>
      <utterance>It's alright.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got an hour. Can I buy you a coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I think I better just go.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia hesitates. There's just a touch of regret in this goodbye.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him the binoculars case.</context>
      <utterance>John. These are for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Because it was a lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John shrugs. He takes them.</context>
      <utterance>No it wasn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John nods and turns. Nadia watches him walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia looks at the floor.</context>
      <utterance>I love you. I don't need to tell you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't leave my child would I? You know that. I was confused. That's all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his shirt off -- Nadia glances up -- With horror, she sees John in the doorway. Alexei turns to see John stand by the door, holding a little silver gun.</context>
      <utterance>You still love me? Eh? Of course you do. Come here. Yuri won't be here for a while. Come on babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John and Nadia look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the little gun.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is he doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei stands. John takes a step back. Alexei walks calmly towards John and throws a punch. It catches John right on the chin and he hits the wall and goes down very fast.</context>
      <utterance>That's that cigarette lighter I gave you isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei turns round to see Nadia holding the knife. He is dumbstruck.</context>
      <utterance>Stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei kicks John in the ribs.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Nadia, the girl he came back for, angrily pointing the knife at him. He suddenly looks completely punctured. John has struggled up again and stands behind him. They are both looking at Nadia.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What. You're what? You're with this creep now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have. You've actually fallen for this prick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexei looks dumbstruck. He laughs emptily</context>
      <utterance>No I haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia stares back at him. The seconds pass. She speaks in a whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Babe it's me. I won't let you get away.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the impasse, John picks up a lamp and hurls it at Alexei's head. It is going to hit him, but reaches the length of its cord and stops six inches short. In the confusion. Alexei grabs Nadia's wrist and forces her to the ground. He grabs the knife, just as John brains him with one of the guitars. It emits a fruity final chord.</context>
      <utterance>I'll kill you if you try.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John finishes tying up Yuri, and removes his passport from his jacket. Behind Nadia another plane arcs up into the night sky. He takes Alexei's passport from his pocket, but Alexei is only watching Nadia.</context>
      <utterance>Get their passports.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She carefully places tape across his mouth. Almost as if having second thoughts she bends down to kiss his cheek. The 'kiss' suddenly makes Alexei's eyes widen in pain. As she stands her lips are bloody. She's bitten him on the cheek. A single streak of blood runs from the gash.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John collects the cases and they head for the door. Nadia stops to look back at Alexei. A final look.</context>
      <utterance>Get your money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadia shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>What will you do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand around. She takes the last cigarette from a pack.</context>
      <utterance>Promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can probably buy them on the flight.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm quitting. This will be my last one. So. Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't deserve me John Buckingham.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seems about to say something more when the tannoy interrupts.</context>
      <utterance>You prefer your women...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCEMENT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She leans forward and kisses him. As they kiss, John puts a guitar case in her hand. Nadia looks down at the case.</context>
      <utterance>Gate closing for Flight 1311 to Moscow. Please have your tickets ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not mine either.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John frowns and looks a little embarrassed. She speaks to him in Russian and we see the subtitles.</context>
      <utterance>It's what you came back for.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>You're a big surprise, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans forwards and whispers in his ear. John looks at her. He looks to the four corners of the airport. And back at her.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you see when I said I didn't speak Russian I wasn't actually just making it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not asking you to marry me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. What? No. I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's more like a date.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a long way to go for a date.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. She speaks softly in Russian. We see the subtitle:</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John frowns.</context>
      <utterance>All that matters is to try...</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John repeats the phrase in Russian.</context>
      <utterance>We can only try. Say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Nadia kneels and opens the guitar case. She stealthily removes about five hundred.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you will find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry. I'll wait for you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the flight full?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Sir. I believe the flight is closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please check. Is it full? Please could you check.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have excellent English.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you want to pay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John collects his ticket, turns and heads back to where he left Nadia with the guitar cases. He suddenly stops. She's gone. He looks all around. People swirl about. She's nowhere to be seen. John hangs his head. He turns, and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Cash.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>POLICE 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes John by the arm. John stands.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me Sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Come with us now.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't speak English. He's epileptic or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Policeman help John to the front of the gate, where he is shown to the front of the queue. The Policeman explains to the airline staff. We see that Nadia is one behind in the queue. The Police turn and walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Can he walk? Can you walk?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NADIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name's Sophia.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sophia. Hello Sophia. Mine's still John.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doors slide open. John and Sophia walk through, and disappear. SFX. The roar of Jet engines.</context>
      <utterance>Hello John.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl looks round.</context>
      <utterance>Nadia!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs past us and we follow to see a couple sitting on the grass having a picnic. The girl hurries towards them and we realise the couple are John and Sophia, the girl her child. She sits down with them.</context>
      <utterance>Nadia!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
