<movie id="80" title="Black Snake Moan">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still need a lift?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill and Rae's eyes meet. Gill sees that Rae is crying.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Transmission's shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie shuts the door and feels a wave of sudden nausea. He rushes past Rae.</context>
      <utterance>Gonna have a smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill backs away, allowing Ronnie and Rae some privacy. The two lovers stare into each others eyes and then embrace. Rae peeks over Ronnie's shoulder at Gill with an expression of dread. Anger seizes her.</context>
      <utterance>You sick? Rae doesn't answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This ain't gonna work.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rae...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see why we gotta lie 'bout it when you and I know this ain't gonna work.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rae don't do this now...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's stupid... It's so fucking stupid!</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Rae melts. Tears stream down her face.</context>
      <utterance>Rae!</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look it. I got somethin' for us. This is gonna help, okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie removes a small digital watch and fastens it around her wrist.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna miss your bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie holds out his own wrist to show her his identical watch.</context>
      <utterance>This watch here is gonna beep at midnight. Every night. That's when it comes up on you the hardest, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae is shaking. He grips her by the back of her neck and pushes their faces inches away. Eye to eye.</context>
      <utterance>And wherever I'm at, my watch'll beep, too. We'll be thinkin' bout each other at the same time. Wherever we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae sees the fear in his eyes. She swallows her own anxiety and nods.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta believe we can do this or I ain't gonna make it, Rae.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss passionately.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Afraid of his swelling emotion, Ronnie quickly breaks away from her. Rae watches as her love leaves in Gill's pick-up. Compelled to follow, she absently walks after the truck, down the gravel drive. She stops. Silence. She is alone. An intense wave of sorrow hits, like a kick to her gut. She gasps for breath as she struggles to hold back the flood of her tears. Rae drops to her knees, right there in the gravel drive. Her hair falls in front of her face, masking her grief. Her shoulders shudder. Her middle finger begins to scratch at her thigh repeatedly -- a nervous habit that has always accompanied this burning sensation that consumes her.</context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears come to her. She's not going to be able to stop it.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddammit, Ronnie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't gonna make a fuss, are you?  Nothing a man can do when a woman make up her mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never laid a hand on her in anger. Not a day. Not even when I's drinkin'. But this business got me wonderin' what a good shake and slap would do for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That kind of talk is between us. Don't you go in there with that shit on your tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz tries to stop his lip from quivering: the man is hurting.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't start this, R.L.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna pray with me 'fore you go in? Laz?  Heavenly Father...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Laz crosses to Rose's booth -- the distance seems to stretch out into eternity.</context>
      <utterance>We do not question your divine plan for us, Oh God. But in these times, when our spirit lies in shadow. When we are lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Laz sits across from his wife.</context>
      <utterance>We ask that you give us strength. Give us strength that surpasses all understanding. In your name we pray. Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't remember the last time I saw you in that suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress is kind and twangy as she asks for their order.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother's funeral. I's a pallbearer, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I start you both off with some coffee 'fore I take your order?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress leaves. The sounds of the cafe fill the silence.</context>
      <utterance>We won't be stayin' long. Coffee'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We leavin' this weekend. Deke got a friend in Mobile gonna get him a job at the water company...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you come to talk about that muthafucka, I'm gonna get up and leave you sittin' pretty in that new suit he bought'cha.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think this about money still, ya old fool?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say what you gotta say, but I ain't gonna hear you speak his name to me. Not never. You hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress places the coffee between them and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>How many times we been over this, Laz? How many times?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought we was gonna be friendly about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carryin' on behind my back. Make me out to look like a fool to all our people. Tell me, what's friendly about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not ready to grow old, Laz. Livin' with you. I feel it. Like I'm one foot in the dirt. Saw it happen to my momma. And that's not gonna happen to me. I got living to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rose doesn't answer. Lazarus softens, touching her hand.</context>
      <utterance>And you gonna live it with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rose. Folks get sick. But you do what you can to get on the mend. Our marriage... it just got sick. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk to me about sick. Ain't been right since I moved into that drafty house.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I keep the heat on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That damned, rusty, radiator, bout burned the skin off my legs each time I passed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's over. Laz has lost her for good.</context>
      <utterance>Kept us warm for twelve years.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I deserve better than this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better'n me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better than what you give.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rose... please...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laz... You can't say nothin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we get with a counselor. At the church, maybe they's...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words are daggers. Laz is wounded beyond concealment. Rose picks up her purse, preparing to leave.</context>
      <utterance>I don't love ya no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands and attempts to walk away. Laz grips her tightly by the wrist.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry you hurtin'. But, like I say, this the only life I got.  I said my piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God forgive you, for how you done me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Daddy told me that a younger woman would bleed me dry. And that's what you did. Ya bled me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go of my arm...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would'a chopped my arm off if you asked. And this how you do me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>LAZ, I said let...!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better pray, gal. You better pray...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whole cafe is silent. All eyes are on Rose.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you lay a CURSE ON ME!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she's gone, right out the front door.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, go'on! Look! See if I give a shit about any of you people!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got any money?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought you had a man for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said we wasn't gonna talk about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What we just did, you askin' for money, make a man stop. I ain't callin' you no ho. But I ain't gonna be played like no trick, neither. Remember... you called me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Save that hustle talk to them field ballers you sell crack to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I tell you?  I don't do none of that shit no more. I'm in communications now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae starts coughing.</context>
      <utterance>Stolen phone cards and two-ways is what you sayin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mobile technology is the new fix for these niggaz, I'm tellin' you. I'm just lookin' ahead.  Anyways, ain't no money in drugs no more with these rednecks popping cough pills like they's Skittles. Hey, that's what you need, girl. Get you some cough medicine. What, you sick?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a cough. Sugar and a spoonful of Jack'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. How much you need, ho?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you call me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tehronne catches Rae's wrist as she goes to slap. He quickly yanks her arm behind her back and bends her backwards, shoving his face close to her own. He grips the money in a fist and cocks it to punch -- all in jest.</context>
      <utterance>Eh, if the bootie fits...</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae's chest begins to heave with deep breaths. Tehronne looks down at her legs as she anxiously rubs them together.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna get rough? Is that what you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae gets control of the burning. She takes the money.</context>
      <utterance>I swear, I seen some buck-wild bitches in my time, but you the illest I ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just got a cough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's already noon, Rae. You think that skirt should still be on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae stops in her tracks, looking up at her estranged mother, SANDY, smoking a cigarette outside the grocery store. Sandy has bleached hair with dark roots. She is in her late-forties: once a sexy girl, now she's lost all her tread.</context>
      <utterance>Cough drops or condoms?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't know you was workin' here now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae walks away -- deeply affected by Sandy's presence.</context>
      <utterance>I just like dressin' up in these goddamn blue vests.  Your money ticket get shipped today?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You let me know if I can be of any assistance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't at the square this mornin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me ten bags of mulch.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lincoln runs off. Laz yanks off his black tie.</context>
      <utterance>Yes'sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep the change on that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz smiles. He takes the change. Climbs in his truck.</context>
      <utterance>Naw... I got it, Mr. Lazarus.  You wanna tip me, best do it in butter beans. Momma say she need a bag 'a yours, none of that store-bought junk. That's what she said.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, Lincoln. You come on by, I'll load you up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>MAYELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOJO is reading a paper behind the bar. He's short and stout, looking like a sad bull dog.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna put some Luther Vandross in here? Shit, he black ain't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He black alright, he just ain't blue.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you stop havin' dancin' on Saturday? Used to have bands... all kind's live shit. Like a wake up in here, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Folks can dance when they want. Didn't buy that mirror ball for nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mayella lifts up her leg and stretches it over the bar with a provocative flourish. Her shoe is bright blue.</context>
      <utterance>You seen my snake-skin shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're from New York. My niece gets 'em on the computer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mayella turns to Laz sipping a beer at the end of the bar.</context>
      <utterance>They got blue snakes up north?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw. They got some blue dye, though. You think them boots you got on come from a black cow?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna get on somebody 'bout live music, get on ol' Laz, there. He the one got this place shakin' back in the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't gotta tell me. Me and my girlfriends use-ta talk 'bout them hard fingertips he got pickin' that guitar.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mayella moves in close, with the tips of her tits touching his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Got'em pickin' peas, not strings.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They still hard?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mayella. It ain't happened yet. Ain't happenin' tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mayella saunters over to the pool table with the others.</context>
      <utterance>I know you hurtin', Laz. I got ears, you know. But you should know more'n me... ain't no better cure for them blues than some good pussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whole lotta woman, right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens behind Laz. Bojo sees the man entering.</context>
      <utterance>She can still spread it around.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz turns to see the door shut behind his brother, DEKE WOODS. He is younger than Laz and a bit smaller. Laz turns to Bojo.</context>
      <utterance>Laz. We friends and all but... promise me you'll keep yo cool in my joint.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deke slowly approaches Laz at the bar.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna finish my beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind if I sit?  Rose said... it didn't go too well this afternoon. See, that's not how we wanted this to go down. I told her, I said, Rose, we ain't leavin' till we make peace with Laz. And that's God's truth. I laid it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You laid it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny. Layin' it down... for my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dry look on Laz's face could cool the sun.</context>
      <utterance>We're not gonna get through this clean. But it don't need to get dirty. All this... it just come together unexpected. You think I want to hurt you? I... I'd take a bullet for you, Laz.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz turns back to the bar. Deke begins to turn but stops.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna give that a try?  Bo. You still got that .22 behind the tap? My little brother say he'd take a bullet for me.  You come here to ease your heart. Well, I ain't gonna give it to you. You took her into your bed, now you gotta lie in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In one quick movement, Laz grips Deke by the throat and smashes the bottom of his bottle into jagged shards.</context>
      <utterance>I'll always love you, Laz. Till the end of my...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lazarus slams the bottle down on the pool table, shattering it. Laz lifts his hand. His own blood leaks from between his fingers. He wipes the blood across Deke's face.</context>
      <utterance>Cain slew Able. Slew him out of envy. And God put his mark on Cain for his sin. You want that mark, Deke? Give you that peace you come here for? I'll give it to you, just say that shit again. Say you love me. Go'on! Say YOU LOVE ME, NIGGA!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz releases Deke and exits. Deke calls after him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm through wit'cha both.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'chu gonna do? Nothin'. YOU AIN'T</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronnie ship out this mornin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so stupid. Says to me that he don't want nothin' to do with no military career. Says he wants to move. Open up an auto shop with his uncle up in Knoxville. I said, okay. How about now? Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'd be good for that. Shit, Ronnie knows cars.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He get stubborn. Starts talkin' 'bout obligation and duty and all that... Shit. I just want him to come home... I swear, if somethin' happens to him...</utterance>
   <speaker>KELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He fixed up that Buick for my uncle Dale. He say it purrs like a kitten every morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing's gonna happen. Not like everybody over there is in the line of fire with them Arabs blowin' themselves up.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't be thinkin' bout him every second of my day. I'll go outta my gourd.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should you waste your life waitin' and wonderin'. Not like you're married.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I begged him not to go. And he did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>CONNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tennessee Vols gotta practice indoors just so those Florida State sons-a- bitches don't spy on their plays with satellites and shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satellites... You mean in space?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse notices Rae coughing. She pulls her aside as Conner rambles.</context>
      <utterance>Good thing you can block, Conner, cuz you're dumb as a sack of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna go home?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It gets worse there. Leavin' me to my own mind. That's just not good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae and Jesse take a strong shot. It burns.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Pound this and I'll join you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they pound one more, Rae notices Gill, Ronnie's friend, staring at her from across the room.</context>
      <utterance>One more. Fuck the chaser.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BATSON and MARK approach Jesse and Rae. They are both sophomores, both skinny and harmless.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jess.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You robotrippin' tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae peeks at Gill maneuvering through the room.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just gonna smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got eight packs of DXM. Oxycontin. Got a shit load of Coricidin if you want to get out-a-body, n'all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just trying to get me outta my clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae pushes through the crowd of drunken kids to get to Gill.</context>
      <utterance>Be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not like I can't go out and have fun with my friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm Ronnie's spy or somethin'? Come tomorrow that dumb- ass gonna be halfway round the world tryin' to keep his head on his shoulders. You think he's gonna be thinkin' about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae pushes through the crowd, back toward the others.</context>
      <utterance>You go to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>QUICK CUTS of: Batson popping out five red cough pills. Rae swallowing all five and chasing them with vodka. Conner's girl falls off his lap. Kell laughs. The laughter echoes and grows as we:</context>
      <utterance>How many to fuck me up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse is straddling a guy in an arm chair, Chinese-eyed and bouncing. Rae tries to respond coherently as another football player rolls her over on all fours and takes her from behind.</context>
      <utterance>What's so funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't the kicker, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cuz let me tell you, you boys gotta run the ball more. You get into a kicking game, ya'll gonna lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I put it in your mouth?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz plays the blues, Mississippi, Bentonian style: one guitar, one voice, a mess of pain.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The music continues as we:</context>
      <utterance>Just like a bird without a feather, you know I'm lost without your love. Just like a bird without a feather, you know I'm lost without your love. You know I need your love just like the angels need heaven above.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jes? Jesse?  Oh shit... Wait... Wait... STOP!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae doesn't look up. The Coricidin is tripping her out.</context>
      <utterance>Stop what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ground is... turnin' upside down. I'm gonna...  I'm gonna fall off... Gill reaches down and pulls off the shoulder pads. The coughing fit passes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. That feels so much better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought you had a skirt earlier.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill pulls to the side of the road and kills the engine. He watches Rae tilt her head from side to side.</context>
      <utterance>I got others.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This thing you got... I've heard people say, you'd fuck a tree if it was handy. I can see that.  But that nigger Tehronne. Thinks he's some player cuz he hustles dope and stolen hubcaps. I mean, I can see a tree. But that piece of shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I begged him. Don't see why he had to go...</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill grabs her legs and spreads them with no resistance. Her head rolls from side to side on the truck seat as Gill unzips his pants. Rae starts giggling.</context>
      <utterance>I bet you did. Just had to get that black cock up in you. I swear to God. What Ronnie sees... you disgust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fuck you laughin' at?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill flinches upright. A rage builds in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You don't got half what Tehronne got.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up! I ain't playin'! OPEN YOUR</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hasty idea. He pushes her out of the truck. She falls to the dark pavement in a tangle of her own limbs. The door slams. Gill floors the gas. Rae lies motionless alone under the stars. Her watch alarm goes off: Beep-beep. Beep-beep. Beep-beep.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bojo called. Said you got to see your brother at the long end of a broken bottle.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna preach 'bout turnin' the other cheek?</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you did alright by God under the circumstances.  Your people are here for you, Laz. This is your home. No shame in showing your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know if God wanna see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>He knows where ya at. Just answer the door if he come knockin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MORNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's really hung over this morning. His eyes squeeze shut, he grips his neck in pain.</context>
      <utterance>Laz tosses the bags inside his trash cans.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes open. They remain fixed beyond us. The pain in his face is replaced with grave confusion. Rae lies on the side of the road. Her T-shirt and panties are damp from the early morning mist, her face caked with dried blood. Her skin is deathly white, her mouth open, her eyes shut and swollen. Lazarus carefully steps toward her. He leans down over her face.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmmmmmmmm... Mm!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae coughs. Laz flinches.</context>
      <utterance>Sweet... Jesus...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes open slightly -- just slits of white.</context>
      <utterance>Little lady? Miss? You need to open your eyes for me. Could ya do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whispers as she touches her fingers to his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>There we go. There we go. Just like you doin'. Go'on.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teh... Tehronne?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A labored breath followed by the most pitiful cough fit. Laz tries to calm her as her lungs fight for oxygen. Laz looks scared as the coughing stops in a desperate wheeze followed by silence.</context>
      <utterance>Tehronne? Tehronne done this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz touches the radiator. It burns him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm'a go into town. Get you some medicine to fix you up. You just rest, okay, gal? You just sleep. Get that chill out'cha.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God... damn...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the squash this year?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz rushes inside.</context>
      <utterance>It's good, Mister Melvin. I'll bring ya some.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lazarus?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! Gave me a start.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. It's these soft shoes I wear for my back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hurt it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm standing most of my day. They're for support.  Didn't see you in church this mornin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been on the crop. May need to get some extra hands if I don't want to work on Sundays.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela wants the conversation to continue but Laz remains silent. She smiles awkwardly.</context>
      <utterance>Well. It's good to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angela?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on, Laz. You can talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My little niece... she got this deep cough.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take her to a doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela thinks for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>No. No, she can't go. Mean to say... they's just no money fo'a doctor. Her daddy left for a job, and uh... give her to me to look on. I just...  I don't know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wait right here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your niece older than 12?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a white box with cough syrup inside.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, she older than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My sister got a bad cough with her pneumonia. I just copied her prescription. You don't need to pay anything... just take it. But if she gets worse, you give me a call. I wrote my number on the box.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This gonna get you in trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz doesn't know what to say. He puts the box in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Not if no one finds out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.  Oh. My wife. She had a card here for her migraine pills. She ain't gonna be around no more... So if you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already tossed that out.  Somethin' you should'a done to that woman long ago... how she treated you. Of course, that's none of my business.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela returns the smile.</context>
      <utterance>Don't make it less true.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lazarus. We closed up on Sunday.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need a word with Tehronne.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, T! Laz wanna holla at cha.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie nods Laz on. He crosses to the back pool table as Tehronne sinks the 8. Tehronne looks at his friend.</context>
      <utterance>Come on back, Cuz.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you call it a game when only one man win each time? I think you call it a damn shame.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tehronne hands his friend the pool cue. The two take a few steps away to talk.</context>
      <utterance>Word wit'cha. In private.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need some weed?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been years since I fooled with that.  You know a white girl? Dirty blond hair, split down the middle like?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't up to me to hook you up. Naw what I mean? She her own, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't pimp that.  You talkin' about who I think you talkin' about, you mean Rae. Rae Doole. Sexy little split tail, like you say. I can't hook you up with that. I got two girls. One ain't in town, the other one pregnant. So... you on your own.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Rae... you get with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. Who hasn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She got a spare minute she'll snatch up anyone... but me, I'm different. Sometimes she need the real deal, so she call me up. Girl got an itch. You know... what's a nigga to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She like it rough? You like beatin' on her?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't my scene. If that's somethin' you into...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, hold up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, that girl is in my favor. You heard me, nigga? You fuck with her rough, and you got me to fuck wit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You collar that dog, boy. I ain't gonna hurt nobody. Just wanted to know who she was.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I say, you wanna hook that up... I ain't in ya way. That switch of hers been all over this town. Got that sickness, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'chu sayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lazarus looks at him with a furrowed brow. Confused.</context>
      <utterance>She a freak. Got what you call a sexual addiction.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'chu sayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I'm tellin' you. Girl gotta get dick or she go crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae's eyes are open and filled with fear. She struggles to flee as Laz holds her in place, trying to reassure her.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on, now. Hold on!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae is too weak to talk or move. Laz clutches her small face in his dark hands.</context>
      <utterance>Now, I ain't gonna hurt'cha. Calm down, Miss.  Listen... Listen... LISTEN NOW, GAL!  I ain't gonna hurt ya, hear? Gotta get you well. Now, look me... HEY! Look me in the eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lazarus looks terrified as she cranes her head back and forward. Her mouth opens. In her sickened state, with the force of something evil and deep inside, Rae clasps her open mouth over Laz's. A shriek sounds in his brain as he holds her tighter, allowing the kiss to grow in intensity. Rae falls to her stomach as Laz abruptly stands and stumbles across the room. What he sees chills him to the bone. Rae is writhing on the floor as if she is possessed -- a rant of raspy words pour from her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Open your eyes. Go'on, now. You need to see, ain't no harm here. Ain't no harm.  My name is Lazarus Woods. And I ain't gonna let you die. Rae's eyes roll back.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lazarus gets spooked by what he is seeing. He looks to the mantle. His weathered Bible lies in a coat of dust. He picks it up as a wave of the burning hits Rae. She clutches her breast and crotch, rolling from side to side.</context>
      <utterance>...you don't... touch me... s'no... NO! Mm-mm... Mm-MMMMMMMMMMMMM! N- N'you FUCK!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm-mm... mm-mm... Ma-muh... Ma-MUH!  See... S... See if'I GIVE... GIVE'A...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae's shivering is abating. Her eyes fight to stay open. Laz touches her forehead to test her temperature.</context>
      <utterance>Put fear of the Devil in me, gal. Got me spooked like I's a kid, I tell you.  But the good Lord, He showed me what to do. He come knockin' like my man R.L. say... listen here...  This here Matthew. He talkin' on how Jesus was healin' the sick. And a man come up to the disciples and he say...  Have mercy on my son, for he is a lunatic, and sore vexed...  He got the devil in his mind and sores on his skin.  And he brought the boy to the disciples, but they could NOT cure him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then Jesus answered and said, O faithless and perverse generation... how long shall I suffer you? Bring the boy hither to me. And Jesus rebuked the devil.  You hear that?  Then the disciples say... Why could not we cast the devil out? And Jesus said unto them... Rae's eyes begin to close. Laz gently touches her head to rile her awake.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches her forehead again. Her eyes close.</context>
      <utterance>Listen now... This what he sayin' to us. He say...  If ye have faith... if ye have faith as a grain of mustard seed, ye shall say unto a mountain, remove hence... and it... shall... move. And nothin'... nothin' shall be impossible to you.  You hear that? You just need a bit of faith. You just gotta believe you gonna get well, like I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz leans against the wall, spent.</context>
      <utterance>That's better. You coolin' down. Okay. You rest. Okay. You rest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae crawls across a fallen soldier, following the sound of Ronnie's alarm. She struggles to breathe, she almost faints. She finds a soldier face down. With all her strength she turns him over. It is Ronnie, wide-eyed and lifeless. An awful groan comes out of Rae -- crippling sorrow. She pulls on his vest trying to wake him.</context>
      <utterance>Gal? Gal?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nn-nn... Nn-nn... no... N'RONNIE!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae looks like a terrified child. Her eyes well with tears as she shakes her head. Laz takes a step toward her.</context>
      <utterance>You travelin' right now, gal. You asleep and you don't even know it.  Now... come on inside with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm-mm... Mm-mm...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and runs away as best she can. Laz chases after her. He's much older than her and a bit slower, but her balance betrays her. Laz wraps his arms around her. Rae screams to the sky.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, gal...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Struggling with exhaustion, Rae moves Laz's hand to her bare stomach. She rubs it slowly up and down her form, suggestively. Laz slips his hand away and claps it tight over her eyes. Rae holds her breath, waiting to be molested, her lip quivering.</context>
      <utterance>Is'okay... Is'okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz backs away from her, a touch of fear in his heart. The voice of Tehronne is heard from earlier in the day.</context>
      <utterance>Goin' over that hill. Goin' over that hill. Well, I ain't gonna stop until I reach my God's top. I'm goin' over the hill. Well I went to the valley, I didn't go to stay. Soul got happy, I stayed all day. I'm goin' over that hill. Rae relaxes and falls into a deep sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She a freak. Got what you call a sexual addiction.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'chu sayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I'm tellin' you. Girl gotta get dick or she go crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First hooked up with that bitch when she was 16. Girl was fuckin' the principal and two of her teachers. You know coach Reynolds?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He tapped that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw!</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ask him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He crosses to the other side, pulls on a beaded chain turning on the single bulb above his work table.</context>
      <utterance>She been bumpin' around all her life, hookin' up with whoever keep her fed and fucked.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Laz opens an old wooden box on his work table. He looks inside.</context>
      <utterance>I seen her give it up on park benches, back of trucks, hoopty hoods, you name it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever seen a train run on a woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nuh-uh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tehronne's friend breaks on the pool table with a sharp crack. Lazarus is genuinely disturbed.</context>
      <utterance>Meanin' like a team of fellas go to work on her and she don't even break a sweat.  She into football, you know. You got a letter on your jacket you get that pussy in ya lap. I ain't playin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How a girl get like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I told you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The chain rattles as Laz walks backwards, pulling the long chain from the box. The shouting of his brother can be heard.</context>
      <utterance>Girl got a sickness.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'chu gonna do? Huh? Nothin'. YOU</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae lifts her head off the pillow. Laz comes to her side and helps her sit up.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy now. Don't rush it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long... how long I been out?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been in and out goin' on two... maybe two days.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two days?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae sits up on the couch, the quilt wrapped around her waist. She looks at the cough syrup bottle on the side table.</context>
      <utterance>After your fever broke, you'd wake up in spells... long enough to get that medicine in ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae touches the cut over her eye. That evening is still a blur.</context>
      <utterance>Found you on the side of the road. Someone took to beatin' on you pretty bad. You know who done that to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Ronnie?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae lifts her head, revealing tears in her eyes. She gets mad at herself and wipes them away.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. He left.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't got any money... for fixin' me up and all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't need none.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I better be on my way. Don't wanna put you out no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think it'd be best if you stayed put while we talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw'sir... I gotta be on my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae struggles for balance as she attempts to stand. The quilt falls away as a heavy chain slides off the couch and thuds on the floor by her feet. Rae feels a tug. She looks down to see a dark chain locked around her thin waist and coiled on the floor. The opposite end is locked around the side coil of the radiator. She is chained to the house, a prisoner.</context>
      <utterance>Best try gettin' ya wits about you 'fore you try to...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me say somethin' first...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you got me chained?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Way I see it, it's gonna take a while for you to get right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fuck you been doin' to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't laid a hand on ya but to ease yo fever... Remember like I say, I found you in the road...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae stumbles as she moves away from Laz. Laz tries to reassure her.</context>
      <utterance>Get this Goddamn thing off me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, no harm's come to you... and I aim to keep it that way. Ain't gonna... gonna run a train over ya... or however you call it... see... you was runnin' wild on me... these fever dreams you was havin'... these fits. I'd be chasin' you all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae waits.</context>
      <utterance>Well I'm woke now... you can take this off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gal, you ain't right yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm right enough to stand on my own two feet. Now take this Goddamn chain off...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you let men treat ya like they do?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These men you up under. How you let them do ya like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do me? Do me like this, you mean? Like chainin' me up?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I'm talkin' about.  All that mess with ya teachers and... boys in the backs of trucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you know about me?! You got no right to talk to me about that shit! The hell you think you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I give ya enough chain so's you can get about the house. Get you to the kitchen. You need the bathroom, it'll reach.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got everything we need. Plenty of food. Ya medicine still got a few good swallows in it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This statement terrifies Rae. The fear can be seen in her eyes. She backs away -- the chain scrapes across the floor.</context>
      <utterance>God saw to it to put you in my path. And I aim to cure ya of your wickedness.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You some kind'a pervert?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some crazy Jesus freak, gonna fuck the spirit into me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my house, you watch that lip...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look it, mister... you wanna have your way, you take it. I'll do whatever you want. But you gotta let me go. You can't do this! You can't</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps outside with resolve and strength. He picks up the chain and wraps it around his fist.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't gonna be moved.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz yanks her back, dragging her towards him. He grips the taut chain with his other hand and yanks her closer.</context>
      <utterance>GAL! I ain't gonna be moved on this!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you get up! And you get in my house!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae spits at Laz. Bad idea.</context>
      <utterance>Or what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it! Stop it! IT HURTS!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz yanks. Rae loses her grip and slams onto the porch.</context>
      <utterance>Whose doin' is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... OKAY! I'M COMIN' IN! NOW</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz crosses to the kitchen. Rae sits down on the couch, noticing the fallen lamp on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Say we talk. Just take a seat on the sofa. I'll get us somethin' cool to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finishes preparing the two waters. He crosses into the front room. Rae is not there. CRASH! Rae smashes the lamp on Laz's head. The water glasses shatter as Laz falls to the floor. Rae picks up a wooden chair and breaks it over his back. Before she can do any more damage, Laz grabs her by the wrists and throws her to the couch. Rae falls to the floor. Laz stumbles on his feet as he clutches his bleeding head. He loses his cool.</context>
      <utterance>You may not remember. But you spent a whole half day in my tub, tryin' to cool down. Melted four ice trays.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wicked little bitch... gonna cut me...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae freezes as she sees Laz undo his belt buckle. Her breath starts to quiver as she deeply inhales and exhales.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna get a lot more a'that, you keep me locked up like this!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz whips his belt off and wraps the buckle around his fist. He stops in his tracks. Rae is panting and shaking. Her middle finger is scratching at her own thigh.</context>
      <utterance>Think I'm gonna let you do me like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her anguished hum can be heard through her clenched teeth as she rocks back and forth. Her hands wander down to her inner thighs.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, now... I ain't gonna hit'cha.  Just lost my cool there.  Now take that look out'cha eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am. You stop that foolishness.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hm-mm... Hm-mm...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said... STOP!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wave is about to build in to a powerful climax. Rae gasps for breath. The door slams open. Laz drenches her with a gallon of cold well water from a tin bucket. Rae inhales and freezes. Laz waits and watches. The burning is gone. Laz kneels next to her and gently frees her bare ankle from the tangled chain.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmmmmm... Stop-it!... STOP-IT!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hungry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like this? Walkin' me through this field like I's your mule?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't sit all day on that sofa. Need to get your legs strong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Daddy was one of the first mens to organize soil conservation in these parts. That's a group of farmers, you know, each season they'd rotate the crop. Know why it's best to rotate em like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz moves in close and starts applying antibacterial cream to the cut above Rae's eye.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-uh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cuz once in a while soil need a change. Corn take up a lot of nitrate in the fertilizer. So next crop what ya do is plant ya some soy beans. That give off a lot of nitrate. Change keeps it all growin' and growin' strong.  Sting a bit?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Itches.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Means ya healin'.  So all this farmin' make me think on Matthew. Matthew 13. The parable of the sower? Man toss seed on rock, on the wayside, some fell in thorns... you know the story?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz starts putting the cream on her scabbed knees. He rubs them gently.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-uh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The seed that land on good soil is for them who hear the word of God... and understand the word of God. Not enough for you to hear what I'm sayin', you gotta understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I get it. What's Matthew doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae is aware that Laz is somewhere else, talking to someone else other than her. There is anger in his tone as he rubs ointment on her bare, scabbed knees.</context>
      <utterance>Gal... Matthew ain't doin' shit... this just a story...  Look it. I've seen it in nature, I've seen it in men. Ya got to change up your crop. Cuz that seed ain't gettin' in.  Ya gotta cut this shit out. Got no cause to be up under these fools, ruttin' on ya like you a bitch. Like you somebody's dog. No woman... who joins in union with Almighty God... or man... in the sanctity of marriage... should degrade herself... and bend to ANOTHER MAN'S WILL!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, gal, don't you got no SENSE? I ain't sayin' I ain't weak? Shit. Playin' guitar in the blood-bucket jukes all ya life... a nigga learn how to sin, let me tell you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae leans up into his face. The glass of water is touching her chest. Laz remains hypnotized by her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't mean to go off on a tear like I did. I just got to thinkin' about things...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz stands and backs away. He quickly leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Why is it you old men gotta talk so much? Like little boys, gotta talk yourself into fuckin' me.  We can take our time. I'm grown. I get it.  You wanna give me 'nother bath?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz sets up his folding table and uncovers his produce.</context>
      <utterance>There goes our fortune. We been doin' good for ourselves since you been away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'all know when Ella Mae's open up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You needin' to buy some pantyhose?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gene looks at Archie and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Just some dresses.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae drags the chain behind her as she crosses to the front door and looks outside. No truck.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She folds her arms and looks into the kitchen. There on the table is a covered plate and a small bottle of milk. Rae reads a note on top of the plate: BE BACK FOR SUPPER. She pulls off the top plate and finds sausage links, eggs, biscuits, sliced tomatoes, and sliced peaches.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe this shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She yanks her chain. It rattles across the floor as she sits.</context>
      <utterance>Enough to choke a Goddamn horse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ella Mae turns to her assistant, Rhonda. Rhonda is a 19-year- old black girl. She turns back to Laz, unsure how to proceed.</context>
      <utterance>I'm needin' some women's clothes. A few dresses. Maybe some shoes. But they gotta be nice. They gotta be proper. Clothes a woman would want, where she could feel and look like a woman without... you know, lookin' like a tramp or a hussy or somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, sir... do you have a size in mind for what you're lookin' for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That young lady's size, right'cher.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that makes it easier.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLA MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lazarus points to a small display of fine lotions.</context>
      <utterance>Well... I hope these will work for your niece. She can always come back in and swap sizes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind I ask, what's all this business here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are whipped body creams. It's like a lotion.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For your hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some women prefer not to scent their bodies with perfume. So now they have scented creams. They help moisturize a woman's skin.  This one's my favorite. It's called Ginger Souffle. I recommend... applying the cream while the skin is still damp. So... perhaps just after a shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take a jar of that, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lookin' for Miss Angela.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz makes his way to the back of the store. He spies Angela in the back pharmacy, sorting pills for a pick-up. He watches her work for a moment until, finally, she sees him.</context>
      <utterance>She in the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz waits as Angela rounds the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Wait right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brung you a little basket of goodies. Fresh squash, tomatoes, some okra, butter beans.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't have to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wanted to say how much I appreciate you helping me the other day. My niece, she's cured up, and I got you to thank.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela smiles. There is tension and attraction between the two.</context>
      <utterance>Well that's good. I'm happy to hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela is flush as Laz moves closer than he has ever been before. He reaches in the basket for the jar of cream.</context>
      <utterance>Look here. I got somethin' special for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz holds the jar up to her nose. Angela closes her eyes and smells. Her expression says enough -- she loves it.</context>
      <utterance>This here is a whipped... body cream. And it's got a smell to it. Tell me what you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela takes the lotion from his hand. She is subtle and demure, but the woman is deeply affected. She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>They call this Ginger Souffle. Best if it... if it go on your skin just after you been in a hot tub... or shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was very sweet of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela watches Laz as he walks out the door. The apathetic girl moves up behind Angela.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Hope you enjoy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooooo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hush up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna be on the square later on?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got all my honey-do's done with. I'm headin' home.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz pulls away in his truck and rounds the corner just as R.L. crosses the street. He steps over to talk to Red.</context>
      <utterance>Stay cool. It's a hot one.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Red. Was that Laz just left?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes'sir, Rev'rend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are my sunshine. My only sunshine. You make me happy when skies are gray. You'll never know dear how much I love you. Please don't take my sunshine away. A voice from outside spins her around. The guitar barks as Rae slams it down on the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Rae stays hidden as she peeks out the front window. Lincoln is standing before the house holding an old picnic basket. Rae's middle finger begins scraping against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Mister Lazarus?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae fights her dizziness. She crawls to the radiator as she hears each creak of Lincoln crossing to the front door.</context>
      <utterance>Mister Laz... I come for the butter beans.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The burning has started: deep gasps, itching, anxiety.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't seen you on the square. Mister Laz, can you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae watches the shadows of Lincoln's shoes under the door. They wait patiently and walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Mister Lazarus?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lincoln darts past Laz and runs into the barn, clutching his overalls. R.L. stops the car halfway down the drive and steps out.</context>
      <utterance>Lincoln, come on back.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that Lincoln James I seen run off?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's fine. Just had a bad fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's his britches round his knees?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>R.L. starts walking up the drive.</context>
      <utterance>R.L., you gonna have to get on. I can't have nobody round my place.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get a call from Rose?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This ain't got nothin' to do with that woman. Just don't want nobody around me now.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>R.L. stops in his tracks as Lazarus pulls out his hunting rifle from the rack behind his seat in his truck.</context>
      <utterance>Somethin' wrong with ya phone? Been callin' the last few days.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goin' dove huntin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta go, R.L.. I ain't foolin' this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sayin' that gun's for me if I don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode>LAZ CAN'T ANSWER</mode>
      <context>Laz is struggling. The rifle feels suddenly strange to him.</context>
      <utterance>Spell it out, Laz. Man big enough to pull a gun best have a tongue in his mouth if he ain't got a brain in his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't gonna talk me outta shit no more. I got my mind made up and I ain't gonna be moved on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't gonna be moved?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got no place for preachin' here. Not now. So you do as I say...</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>R.L. pushes his chest up against the rifle and shouts back.</context>
      <utterance>I told you to TURN BACK!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tear rolls down Laz's cheek. The shame is unbearable.</context>
      <utterance>Ought'a stomp yo ass pointing this at me.  Always gotta bring up the preachin'. Like you just a sheep in my flock and all I'm good for is poundin' on a pulpit.  Dammit, Laz... we may not be blood. But we sucked off the same old nurse since the day we was slapped on the ass. And you gonna point a gun at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz takes the bandana and wipes the tears away.</context>
      <utterance>If you in some trouble, than WE gonna figure somethin' out. You and me.  Wipe your face!</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now... this got anything to do with Rose?  Then what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you outta ya GODDAMN MIND?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man like you ought not take the Lord's name like you just done.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A naked woman, chained in ya house?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm tellin' you the truth, dammit. I found her beat. Left for dead. So I brung her home.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laz, I know about that girl.  Good number of this town's sinners got my ear, you know.  Oh, Laz. She's had a mess of crabs and them STD's. What'chu thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't laid a hand. On my life, R.L., my wick is dry on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say she was beat on. You call the sheriff on that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put yo'self in my shoes. Say you out here, alone, with a beaten, half naked, white woman loves to fuck. I been toe to toe with the law in this town for no more than being black and nearby.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz briefly looks off at the barn, knowing Lincoln is there.</context>
      <utterance>What's that chain around her for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you go'on and ask her. She need to talk wit somebody with sense. Folks been ruttin' and beatin' on this gal all her days. And this is how I'm handling it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HOW YOU HANDLING IT?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>R.L. nods. Lazarus smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Go in and talk to her. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Makin' steaks for supper. I expect you to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean with you and that woman chained to ya radiator?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You treat folks special when they company. It's just supper, R.L., shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz walks toward the barn and turns back to R.L..</context>
      <utterance>One thing at a time, Laz.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch y'self in there. That girl'll jump on ya junk like a grasshopper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lincoln shakes his head. Laz carefully sits next to him.</context>
      <utterance>Did I hurt'chu?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened in there... that won't your fault. Ain't a young man alive could keep they britches on with that girl being in heat like she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why she got a chain on her?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's between her and me. It's private. And I don't want you goin' off and tellin' ya daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't tell my daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lincoln nods. Laz hands him the bandana R.L. gave him.</context>
      <utterance>My mouth is shut, boy. And that's how we gonna keep it. Don't go braggin' to ya buddies, ya heard me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...  That your first time?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes'sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lincoln grins as he wipes the snot from his nose.</context>
      <utterance>You struck some gold, didn't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. My first time was with my second cousin behind my uncle's barn. She weighed two tons, if a pound. Could'a done a lot better for myself. You sho'nuf did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta ask you. Why do you think Laz is keepin' you chained like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how, like they say, you save someone's life, you responsible for them. Guess he just don't think it's safe for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae struggles to answer. Something is on her mind.</context>
      <utterance>So he got it into his head that the only thing gonna keep you from endin' up bleedin' on the side of the road again, without a stitch of clothing on is...  You think he's crazy for thinkin' that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a preacher?</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you a question?  People always say, you gotta get good with Jesus, if you want not to go to hell. That you say sorry for all you done and... and Jesus would let you go on to heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could put it that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's so fuckin' stupid.  I'm sorry. Didn't mean to curse.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's on your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't hurt people... and then just say, I'm sorry, and then everything just gets washed away. Why would heaven want people like that. People who... do what they want and then... switch.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae grins. R.L. leans closer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna tell you somethin', and it's just gonna be between you and me.  I think folks carry on about heaven too much. Like it's some all-you-can- eat buffet up in the clouds. And folks just gonna do as they're told so they can eat what they want behind some pearly gates. I can go to Shoney's for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae has never had anyone talk to her like this. She is listening. She is understanding.</context>
      <utterance>There's sin in my heart. There's evil in this world. But when I got no one... I talk to God. I ask for strength. I ask for forgiveness. Not for peace at the end of my days when there's no more life to live and no more good to do, but today. Right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae looks at her bare feet. She tries to respond but the pain in her chokes back the words. Tears come to her.</context>
      <utterance>What's your heaven? What gives you peace?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronnie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gonna eat with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I was told.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She still gonna have that chain on?</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I'm working on that.  So... what's goin' on in your life, Lincoln?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lincoln tosses a match on the coals. They ignite with flame.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't no virgin no more?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's sharp. That is sharp. Chain give you any trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-uh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Now I got the steaks on, potatoes at a boil, and biscuits ready to pop in the oven. R.L. and Lincoln out yonder grillin' up the corn. What do you know how to make?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't fuckin' cook.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gal, I been around hard-cursin' folk all my life. And let me tell you...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look it... I put the Goddamn dress on, didn't I? I think I'm handlin' myself with some... fuckin' restraint here... how you got me locked up like a dog on a...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If all you got is filth comin' out'cha mouth... people just gonna tune ya out.  Rae. RAE! I'm not fightin' with ya. I just know you got more in you than junk.  Now, you sayin' you don't know how to cook anything at all?  You know how to boil water?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can handle that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, get to it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAZARUS &amp; LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a sudden flurry of activity at the table as the four begin piling up their plates.</context>
      <utterance>Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pass them potatoes, Lincoln.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'all let me know if these steaks are too dry.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This all looks wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I skipped lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae's eyes are fixed on R.L. as he picks up a devilled egg. She looks over at Laz who is aware of her anxiety. He gives her a wink. R.L. bites into the egg and moans with delight.</context>
      <utterance>Well, dig in, son. Got plenty to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm. MM. Now these eggs got some kick to it. What'chu got in this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks at Rae, surprised. She feels a sudden rush of fear as she struggles to answer R.L.'s question.</context>
      <utterance>Ask the chef.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cayenne pepper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit down, man. Need a beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Herman.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie stiffens. Gill is confused.</context>
      <utterance>They buy you that big chicken dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got little names for everything in the corps when they trying to get rid of ya. Don't know what it's like in the guard. There's what you call a bad conduct discharge, a BCD... we all called it the big chicken dinner. It ain't the brig but it'll fuck ya for life if you wantin' to work for the government.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what this is about.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie looks away. He takes a sip of his beer.</context>
      <utterance>They got another little name called ad-sep. That sound about right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ad-sep. Administrative separation.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you get one of those?</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie loses his cool. He lunges at Herman. Gill holds him back.</context>
      <utterance>Blowin' boys in the head, for one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, son! I ain't sayin' shit about you. I'm just talkin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you don't know what you're talking about so why don't you shut the fuck up?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Herman gets up to leave with his beer.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's alright, man. It's alright.  Herman. Come on. He just got back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie glares at Herman as he moves to the other side of the bar. Gill moves closer to Ronnie to get the whole story.</context>
      <utterance>To get back ya had to've gone somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They been keepin' a folder on me cuz of my stomach. Like how it was just before we'd play ball back in school. Thought it was just some tic I got, or ulcers like my daddy had.  I can't... shoot. Target practice I'm a pro. I tag between the numbers each time but...  But when there's really loud noises around me... somethin' happens. I get shaky and... I lose my breath. They called it anxiety. Severe anxiety. It can be fixed and all... just not in time for....  It's a long process but... they sent me home.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill doesn't know what to say next.</context>
      <utterance>I guess it could be worse. You could be comin' back in a body bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get Rae on the phone. She's not at home... none of her friends seen her anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's around. Always is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. She's gettin' crazy, like she gets. Begged me not to go. Got real down. I just think somethin's happened. Like she run off with someone. You'd tell me if you knew somethin', right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been home yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-uh. I's hitchin' up the interstate when I seen your truck outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need a ride?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill enters. He sees that the trailer is the same as it was the day he picked up Ronnie, nothing is different.</context>
      <utterance>Rae?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This don't feel right. Kitchen looks just like I left it. I know, cuz I cleaned it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She ever tell you she was thinkin' of taking off?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill is disturbed by Ronnie's sudden flood of emotion and tears. He crosses to the pantry, already knowing which cupboard to pull the liquor out of. He pours two drinks. He hands one to Ronnie.</context>
      <utterance>I just been so mixed up lately, Gill. And, you know, with her history, I can see how she could get scared...  ...and run.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie manages a few swallows.</context>
      <utterance>Drink. Come on, drink some.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill stands over Ronnie, looking down on his pitiful face.</context>
      <utterance>Her momma works down at the grocery, down on the square. Maybe she seen her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronnie. You can't see cuz you're too close to it.  These nervous spells you get. You never had that shit back in school...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not right, really, cuz I...</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His words are painful to Ronnie. Gill doesn't hold back.</context>
      <utterance>You joined up in that monkey troop cuz you had a plan for yourself. Army'd pay for school. You were gonna get a degree, maybe somethin' in business or agriculture and you were gonna make somethin' of yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then you had to fall in love with the school slut.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With all she was doin'. With all the shit she kept doing! You stayed stuck to that bitch's ass and you wouldn't let go.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rage suddenly fills Gill. He grabs Ronnie and throws him against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>I know about how she was like. But we was different. I's the only person she talked to about it. How she's abused. Terrible things, Gill, just terrible...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not her fault, Gill. She's had to take care of me all this time, cuz I'd just start throwin' up... choking. Just losin' my grip. And she listened. She listened to me.  And... I got better. I don't get nervous like I used to. And since we been together... she been faithful to me. Put all that junk behind her...</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie can't respond. Tears roll down his face. Gill holds up the whiskey bottle.</context>
      <utterance>The only thing that cunt's had behind her is me and half the town fuckin' her.  Your first night away, I come over and drop off the spare keys like you wanted me to. You weren't gone two hours and she was aching to get me inside her. Like she was havin' some kind'a fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think it's funny how I know where everything in your house is?  I don't care if that hurts you or not. Truth is I don't know who you are anymore. So fuck it. Gill turns away. Ronnie grips Gill around the neck from behind. He bends him back painfully and throws his head up against the wall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna steal my truck?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill watches Ronnie tear down the drive in his own truck.</context>
      <utterance>Make yourself at home. You done it already.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta get that chain off her, Laz. Somethin' like this gets out, you could land in a heap of trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm dealin' with what God put before me.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You believe He wants this? A woman chained to ya radiator?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz is silent.</context>
      <utterance>She's tied to me, R.L.. We tied to each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz looks down at his shoes. He surrenders. He nods.</context>
      <utterance>I can't leave unless I get your word.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(this is not easy for</context>
      <utterance>Laz. I got some news you need to hear. It's about Rose and your brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz struggles with his emotions. He turns to R.L. stone faced and cold.</context>
      <utterance>She's pregnant. She gonna have a baby.  Her sister told my wife. You know how them sewing circles go. Just a matter of time till you got word. Thought that's why you been keepin' to yourself out here.  I don't know how much of this is to make her happy or to hurt you. But it is what it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm through with them both.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They sure liked them devilled eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You drink whiskey?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take it straight?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her a glass. Laz then looks at his as if he struggles with a decision.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae nods and downs the whiskey with Lazarus.</context>
      <utterance>To my baby brother. Gonna be a daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz pours another swig for himself and downs it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's good news. So you're gonna be someone's uncle.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want another?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We drinkin' buddies now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz pounds back his third shot.</context>
      <utterance>To freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still makin' jokes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz pulls Rae closer to him by the chain wrapped around her waist. He opens the old lock with a key.</context>
      <utterance>No joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chain falls to the floor with a hollow thud. Rae looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>Not my place to change your mind, or anybody else's. People gonna do how they please. You only get one life... should be lived the way you wanna live it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want... I can take you back to town now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two stare at each other in silence.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't in a hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you do somethin' for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz slides his calloused fingers across the strings, spurring the old guitar into an impressive wail. Rae grips the chair.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't played 'fore nobody in years.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A haunting slide guitar riff barks. Rae has a physical reaction to the music. She is fascinated and fearful.</context>
      <utterance>Funny how a sound just speak to ya heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz thinks for a moment. Continues playing.</context>
      <utterance>Wanted me some kids. A whole mess of 'em. But Rose, my wife... chil'ren was for another time.  They's this one spring... I saw a change in her. Her breasts start swellin' up. Come a few mornings I hear her heavin' in the bathroom. I seen it with women before. I knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guitar's song turns dark. Laz slides his fingers up the guitar strings, lingering on low growns.</context>
      <utterance>Come a day, Rose say she had to go visit her folks in Jackson. Didn't want me to come... so I stayed put.  When she come back...  They talk about a woman havin' that glow. Couldn't see it no more. She... took it away. Cut it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fear spreads across Rae's face. Laz is talking about something all too familiar.</context>
      <utterance>One night... While she sleepin'. Held a pillow in my hands. I could see myself killin' her. What evil in my heart make me wanna kill her, I don't know? It's that voice in me. Each time I think it's gone, he come howlin' back. Devil or no, I don't know. But I am a haunted man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz stops. He sways back and forth with his eyes closed. Rae hears the swell of the cicadas. Her eyes dart to the front door as the familiar creek of footsteps are heard.</context>
      <utterance>Calls me when I'm ailing. When I can't find my home, lost in the pines. I calls it the Black Snake Moan.  Mm-mm... Got no momma now.Mm-mm... Got no momma now.It's over late last night, don't need no momma now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door swings open. A white calloused hand appears around Rae's mouth. She gasps in terror, clutching Laz's leg. The white hand is gone. Tears come to her. She trembles as Laz sings.</context>
      <utterance>Sing, Lazarus.  Please keep singin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae rests her head against his knee.</context>
      <utterance>Mm-mm... Black snake crawlin' in my room.Mm-mm... Black snake crawlin' in my room.Some pretty momma better come and get this black snake soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Black snake is evil, black snake is all I see.Black snake is evil, black snake is all I see.Woke up this mornin', black snake moved in on me. Laz concludes the song. Rae raises up to her knees, facing Laz. Tears have run down his dried face. He opens his eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My life is gone. Only life I was livin'. And I lost it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae gently touches his cheek. The wind picks up outside.</context>
      <utterance>I had love in my heart. And I gave it to one woman. And she gone now.  Where am I gonna put all this love?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae kisses Laz. He is motionless at first, allowing it to happen. His hand moves from the neck of his guitar to the bend in her neck. The passion intensifies as they squeeze the guitar between them. Laz pulls his lips away and holds her head in his hands. They are so close, they are breathing into each other's mouths.</context>
      <utterance>You can give it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guitar clangs to the floor as Laz lifts Rae in his arms. They kiss, ravenous for each other. He knocks up against the side table, causing his Bible to fall to the floor, face up and open. The wind pushes the front door open, slamming it hard against the wall. They turn together, kissing, Laz slowly spinning with Rae in his arms. But Laz is soon distracted by the pages of his Bible fluttering on the floor. The wind is blowing the pages, turning them with an unseen hand.</context>
      <utterance>You can't start this and not finish. Not with me.  Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes a considerable effort to pull Rae away. She falls to the floor, dizzy and sucking in air.</context>
      <utterance>Wait... I gotta stop...  Rae stop...  Dammit, Rae... GET OFF!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae is struggling for breath. She desperately grabs at Laz.</context>
      <utterance>This ain't the way for me. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes roll back briefly, almost losing consciousness. Laz catches her and holds her tightly.</context>
      <utterance>Not gonna lie to you, Laz...  This one's a doozy. I don't think... I don't think I can stop this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz grips the chain and wraps it around Rae. As the burning increases. Laz holds Rae tight across his lap, his back up against the radiator.</context>
      <utterance>The... chain helps.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen a man die. He couldn't breathe... his heart was... was givin' out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just havin' a fit. You ain't goin' nowhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her legs itch like they are covered in ants. The wave is hitting her hard. Laz holds her face up to him.</context>
      <utterance>He told me... get help. I just stood there and watched him... I watched him die, Laz. Oh God! GODDAMMIT!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Laz... he hurt me. He... hurt me so many times.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's gonna hurt you no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly aware of the rising burn, Rae grits her teeth.</context>
      <utterance>You think God forgives people like that?  You think God forgives people like me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae turns away as Laz holds her head in his lap. She bites down on his middle finger as his hand moves over her mouth. She is gasping, screaming into his hand. It hits. Laz holds her. Rae's open mouth quivers as the sensation peaks. Her shoulders slump, her chest vibrates. She is crying softly.</context>
      <utterance>Hold me. Oh God...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pages of the Bible flip to the final pages in the wind.</context>
      <utterance>We'll just stay here. Wait till it passes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you gonna be?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right here. Be here all afternoon.  You ready for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae looks out the window, a touch of fear.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna just get some girl stuff, like make-up and... stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both step out of the truck. Gene and Archie watch Rae's ass as she walks by. They then look back at Laz, incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>This town ain't goin' nowhere. You take the time you need.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friend of mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet you have loyal customers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You liked what I brung ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been eatin' like a princess all week. Even got enough for us to take a picnic under the gazebo.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'd be nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela steps forward and pulls away her hair from her neck. She cranes, offering her neck for Laz to smell.</context>
      <utterance>I put on the lotion you got me. Can you smell it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae kneels down next to her. She's trying to make a connection.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to your face?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got in a little accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy stands and wipes her brow.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since you workin' on the square now, maybe we could get some coffee in the morning, if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need money again?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That's not why...  Why we always gotta do this? I mean, you and me been at each other as far back as I can remember. Wasn't no love between us. And I'm your daughter. I'm the only family you got.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never needed nobody. Always made that clear to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I know I did. But...  I'm tryin' to be dif'rent. I'm tryin' to... get some peace, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm workin' here, Rae. Can you see that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted some make-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae starts walking away. She quickly turns.</context>
      <utterance>All that shit's on aisle 5.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just think you should'a kept him off me, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell are you talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is clear from Sandy's reserved anguish that Rae is telling the truth. Sandy firmly grips her by the arm and walks her out. Rae winces in pain like a toddler being led off to a car for a good whipping.</context>
      <utterance>Now see? Don't do that. I'll go along with all you say about me. But that... you can't pretend no more on that. Cuz I was just a kid, Momma.  I didn't know about any of that stuff he was doin' to me.  And you let him do it. Some big nobody in your life... and you let him do as he wanted... with the only SOMEBODY you had.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... I didn't mean to shout...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All my life I been puttin' out your fires, with you givin' out your snatch to every waggin' dick in this town. And you gonna lay the blame at my feet? Well, I ain't gonna take that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... Momma... just tell me... not gonna be mad... we can just talk about it... Be eye to eye on this... You don't even got to say you're sorry... Just say how you knew...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy walks back up the aisle returning to her canned tuna. And then the rage hits Rae. With each breath Rae grits her teeth tighter. She grabs a mop off the side aisle and turns around. Sandy is pricing cans, down on her knees. She doesn't see Rae coming.</context>
      <utterance>Only thing I'm sorry for is listenin' to my parents and having you instead of doin' what I should'a done.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...tell me you don't know... goddamn</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I's thinkin' about singing in the choir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At church?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm-hm. I don't know if I got a good voice or not but... practice is only on Mondays and Wednesdays, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna sing me somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When? Now? Oh. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela blushes. She looks around and then leans in close to Laz. She sings softly, sweetly, with all her soul.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, just a little somethin'. Right here. Go'on now, don't be shy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz bolts toward the grocery as fast as he can.</context>
      <utterance>What? What is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts her up in his arms. She sobs into his chest as he carries her through the onlookers. Angela is there. She looks confused and shocked.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take you home now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz can't lie anymore. His gaze falls to the floor. He leaves the store without saying anything to Angela.</context>
      <utterance>This your cousin?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You took care of your wife, like you do me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie's hand appears from under the blue tarp in the back of Laz's truck. He pulls himself out and looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Nothin'. They go inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get'chu at that table up yonder.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Rae makes her way through the crowd of people, Laz marches over to R.L.</context>
      <utterance>You can handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell is this shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I called Bojo, like you say. Called up the fellas in the band...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fuck are all these people doin' here? Been drinkin' in this shit hole for years ain't seen this many people since I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit hole... Hey kiss my ass, Laz.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bojo turns away to another customer. R.L. grins as he removes a flask. He offers it to Laz. Laz snaps it away.</context>
      <utterance>Nigga, you go'on kiss my ass. Ya both called everybody, didn't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you go, preacher man. Get me drunk so I don't stick my foot up yo ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz and R.L. look over at Rae seated alone at a small table near the stage.</context>
      <utterance>I just know how you get. Good to know, them butterflies still in ya gut.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heard about this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz surprises R.L. by walking away and up onto the stage. Rae watches as Laz, shakes hands with some of the band members. A few whistles from the crowd. Laz sits down at a chair off to the right of a short mic stand. He plugs in. Rae watches curiously as Laz tunes his guitar -- moans of electric distortion. R.L. sits next to her.</context>
      <utterance>We ain't here to talk about that shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The drummer kicks in. Laz tears into the strings. The entire place begins to undulate and bounce as Laz returns to the blues.</context>
      <utterance>You in for it, now. He gonna nail it to the wall tonight. I done pissed him off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HERSHEL, a black man in his 30's, asks Rae to dance.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm goin' Georgia line. See if them women sweet like mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERSHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna cut it up, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae looks up at Laz. Laz smiles and nods. Rae takes the man's hand and moves out onto the dance floor. R.L. can't be seated anymore. He stands and stomps his foot.</context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you know you home, old man. You just walked through the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you drunk?  Keep drinkin' water and you won't get a headache in the mornin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, gal I been here before.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you have.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laz? Can I sleep with you tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think that'd be wise.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean it nothin' dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae understands. She crosses to Laz and kisses him on the cheek. Rae then walks down the hall to her couch in the front room. Laz turns off the light.</context>
      <utterance>I know you didn't. But you a grown girl. You can handle it. I got to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>ARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, where you goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna pee. I gotta take a break and go pee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, this isn't fair. You said I could do it, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae finds the light switch. She yelps upon seeing Ronnie crouched by the tub. Suddenly feeling violated Rae yanks down on her shirt to hide the fact that she's not wearing anything else.</context>
      <utterance>Eat shit and die, Arty. A girl can change her fuckin' mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie attempts to get up but it's too late, Rae has already squatted on the commode, pinning Ronnie between her and the bathtub. Rae is breathing heavy, her focus is scattered. She's coming up or coming down from a big burn.</context>
      <utterance>You don't gotta get up but... I gotta go...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think if I just piss... I'll be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feelin' sick?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just in one of my moods. You know how I get.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie tries to look away, trying to make an awkward moment less awkward. Rae's anxiety is hitting her.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it'd be better if you talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie nervously considers this before agreeing to open his mouth. He points into the tub.</context>
      <utterance>Just about anything, you know. It can be funny or... not. Just tell me somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. That's my vomit. I came in here to get sick. I thought I'd make the toilet but... anyway, I got sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you wasted?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I just got a messed up stomach.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit, Ronnie!  You're a fuckin' rock star.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie leans over and dry heaves into the tub. It is painful. Rae leans forward and touches his back, comforting him.</context>
      <utterance>All them people shoutin' your name like they were doing tonight! Shit! That arm you got'll get'chu on a box of cereal...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie falls back, gripping his stomach, there are tears in his eyes from the dry heaving. Suddenly emotion hits him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey? You okay, Ronnie?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae pulls Ronnie to her. He cries into her shoulder. She gently rubs his wet face and sings her words of comfort.</context>
      <utterance>Box of cereal... well, Goddamn...  Everybody keeps sayin' things to me take make me feel great. But I don't feel great at all. I feel like I'm comin' outta my skin. Like I'm losin' control of my mind.  I'm not like this. I'm not usually so... afraid.  I don't know what's... wrong...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie begins to calm down. The sobbing abates. The metal music from the party outside is muffled through the door. The two hold onto each other in silence. Rae pees. They both giggle, a welcome release of tension.</context>
      <utterance>Is'okay... Is'okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel better. Do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you know a song.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz sits next to her and takes the guitar from her.</context>
      <utterance>Don't know where I learn't it, but... it's there in my head.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you feelin' today?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how you feel when you come out of a bad hangover? Like your eyes can open a little bit more.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woke up real early. Sun was shining. Just thought I'd mess around, try to learn a song.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go'on and sing it, I'll play.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you do it. I can't sing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop that foolishness. Just do as I say and close your eyes.  Close your eyes. And think about... well, for a song like this, I'd say you think about what you love.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I love.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae's playful smile turns serious. Laz continues playing.</context>
      <utterance>Get a good picture in your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think on that. And sing wit me.  You are my sunshine. My only sunshine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE &amp; LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae opens her eyes with a delightful giggle. Laz continues playing.</context>
      <utterance>You make me happy when skies are gray. You'll never know dear, how much I love you. Please don't take my sunshine away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae doesn't hesitate to obey. With her eyes closed and Laz playing, neither can see Ronnie creeping up from the kitchen with his gun.</context>
      <utterance>Good. I know another. It go like this.  Last night dear, as I lay sleeping. I dreamed I held you in my arms. When I awoke dear, I was mistaken. So I hung my head and I cried.  Close your eyes Rae... sing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(opens her eyes)</context>
      <utterance>You'll never know dear, how much I love you. Please don't take your sunshine away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't been a week and you already some nigger's whore? Gill told me. Told me how you and he... you and everybody...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronnie. Please, baby...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz glares back, not saying a word.</context>
      <utterance>Did 'ya have fun with her? Sweet as a peach, I bet. Huh? Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it, I ask you a question, you better answer it, or I'm gonna blast a hole in ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae moves closer. Ronnie points his gun at her and screams.</context>
      <utterance>Ronnie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Careful how you point that gun, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or what? OR WHAT?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy? You here to make a point, or you here to kill somebody?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't gonna be callin' me boy when I blow your face off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sayin' you'll do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me, mother-fucker. I'll fuckin' kill..</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You testing me? Huh? You testin' me, old man?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie grips the shaking gun. A severe attack is on the rise as he listens to Laz.</context>
      <utterance>Test. Shit. What kind'a test you thinkin'? You mean like, if you a man or not? If you a killer? Only one way to prove that. You just look me in the eye, boy, and you squeeze that trigger back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie flinches. He tries to control his breathing.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't that easy, is it? I been in some scraps, son, I know. First there's that loud crack. Always louder than you think. Like it just come-up- a-cloud and clapped a mess thunder right in ya hand. BAM!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie almost vomits, but he holds it back.</context>
      <utterance>White light. Smell of smoke. Taste of my blood and brains in your mouth, stingin' ya eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae moves closer to him, wanting to comfort him but she stops as Ronnie points the gun at her. His eyes pleading for her to stay back.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, baby... just let me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A flood of tears are streaming down Ronnie's face. The gun is shaking furiously in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Put all your love and dreams into one woman... she turn around and give it all to another man. That's a good reason to paint the wall with me, kid. She'd fear ya then. Cuz there won't be no more question in her mind. She with a real man now. A real KILLER!</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't... don't say that to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, I'm grown. Don't got patience to suffer you children and this monkey junk. I'm too old to play house...  ...and cowboys. So let's have it. End me or get out of my face! Ronnie looks like a scared five year old having an asthma attack. Laz barks at him one last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(silence)</context>
      <utterance>Go'on. Do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae inches closer to Ronnie as he kneels over and weeps. She gently touches his shoulder. He turns his anguished face to her and tries to speak.</context>
      <utterance>Ronnie?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie hides his face in his hands. Rae throws her arms around him and holds him tight.</context>
      <utterance>I can't stop... I can't stop... being scared. What am I gonna do...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz removes the clip and crosses to the kitchen. He slams the gun on the sink, opens a drawer and removes the wall phone.</context>
      <utterance>I got you, baby... I got you...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?  You gonna call the cops? You think they gonna help this? They ever help you, Laz? Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMMIT LAZ PUT THE PHONE DOWN?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laz looks at Rae. There is hurt in his eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought you knew me better, gal.  I need you at my house... right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I imagine there's a lot of good between you two. But I want you to tell me what's bad. Go'on. And don't hold back. Ronnie is very uncomfortable. He looks at Rae seated next to him and then back at R.L..</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae starts shaking her head, tears come to her eyes. R.L. raises a hand to silence her.</context>
      <utterance>I hate this town. You can't round the corner without bumping into someone who's got your number.  We did a lot of dreamin', me and Rae. Makin' plans to get out. I'd do my tour and... we'd move outta here. Go to Chattanooga. And I'd work for my uncle.  But... when Rae gets like she does. And she does the things that she always done. Makes me feel like she loves this place more'n me.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on, Ronnie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All my life people called me shit like, sissy and... nervous and... I got few things in my life that make me feel like... like...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Rae, we're not here to fix you or judge you. Only you and the Almighty can do that. But I want you to tell me about these spells you get. Rae takes a deep breath. She looks up at Laz. He encourages her with a nod.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It starts like this... fire... that spreads. Starts in my head. Then moves to my stomach. Then it goes lower. I can stop it sometimes but mostly I just jump on and ride it out... then everything'll go back to normal, you know. Only thing ever took that feeling away was... was... when I met Ronnie.  Cuz I love him so much. He's all I got in my life that's special. And I like taking care of him and helping him when he gets nervous. When I can do that for him... it's like I'm givin' somethin' of myself that I haven't givin' nobody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae turns to Ronnie. Her nose is running as she wipes away her tears.</context>
      <utterance>Rae, look at Ronnie. And tell him how you feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie is very moved by Rae's plea. He touches her face and wipes away a tear.</context>
      <utterance>I think... I think we're fucked up. Both of us. I know I am. But... that don't mean what I feel ain't true. It don't mean I can't love. And I know, how I been is... is... REALLY BAD! So if you want to quit on me... I understand. But please... please... don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. What'chu two gonna do about this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. You wasn't at'cha work but that nosey gal up at the counter give me your home address. Hope you don't mind me comin' over.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela notices Rae and Ronnie seated in Laz's truck.</context>
      <utterance>I need ya help again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More cough syrup?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela takes a breath and opens the door wider.</context>
      <utterance>Can I come in?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lied to you. It was wrong. But at the time... I didn't know what to do. Imagine you got an earful from folks about that gal I's carryin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laz... you don't need to explain yourself to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela thinks on this. She rises out of her seat and crosses to Laz, sitting next to him on the love seat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do. Cuz I feel for you. Mean to say...  I got feelings for you. And I didn't want you to think... I didn't...  I don't want you to go away. There's better ways to say what I'm trying to say, but... they it is. Don't go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laz. I'm gonna put my trust in you. I'm gonna do it knowin' all too well I can get hurt like this. And I have been hurt. Just like you.  Woman like me, I got a lot of livin' to do. But my days are precious to me. They all I got left. Don't want no more fuss. I want love in my life. You understanding me, Laz?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stay locked in each others' sight. Then, the slowest, most gentle kiss happens between them. When they separate, Laz is lost in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I do. God's truth. I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what'chu need me to do? Cuz I'm gonna go do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pinetop grins and produces a black velvet cloth. He opens it gently and spreads it out, revealing a long, thin, gold chain. Laz nods, approvingly.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, this here Pinetop. I think he got what you lookin' for.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'll do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It got some miles on it, but my boys say she run good. Got fresh 22's on her. Ain't my doin'. That's just how it came to me. Don't worry. Nobody gonna come lookin' for it. I got the pinks... got no problem.  Ain't gonna have my girl ridin' no bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't see generosity much these days. Everything always got a catch. Guess I'm tryin' to say... thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEHRONNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tehronne walks back into the pool hall, leaving Laz alone.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody ever asks me to do shit like this for people. And you know what? I'm good at it. Naw what I mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wanted to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the rules.  You do know the rules, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then start taking them seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay to breathe, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You Ronnie?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Lincoln. Guess I'm gonna be your best man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie nods. Lincoln steps behind him to tie the tie.</context>
      <utterance>You havin' trouble with that tie? Cuz I'm pretty good at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta do it like this or I get all turned around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's sharp. That's real sharp. Miss Ella Mae set you up, didn't she? You like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had nice things before but I always ruined 'em somehow.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rae bows her head. She fights back tears.</context>
      <utterance>Well, this one's yours now. You ready to take care of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz holds her face in his hands. He speaks softly.</context>
      <utterance>I want to. More'n anything. But I...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His words are piercing and true. Rae nods, decides.</context>
      <utterance>Now... let's stop that.  You and me... we can handle this. You hear me, gal? We gonna be just fine. Now live ya life. Pull your shit together and live your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>R.L.'s words are heard as Rae wraps her arms around Laz and rests her head on his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to let go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was a child, I talked like a child. I thought like a child, I reasoned like a child.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ronnie is amazed with what he sees. Laz leads beautiful Rae down the steps as Angela tends to her side.</context>
      <utterance>When I became a man, I put childish ways behind me.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Rae holds firm to Laz's arm as they come together on the green grass to witness and perform this union.</context>
      <utterance>Now we see but a poor reflection as in the mirror; then we shall see face to face. I know in part; then I shall know fully, even as I am fully known.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now these three remain: faith, hope and love. But the greatest of these is love.  Who gives this girl in marriage?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lazarus takes a few steps with Rae, offering her arm to Ronnie. Ronnie and Laz stay locked in each other's gaze.</context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz stands next to Angela as Ronnie and Rae face R.L. together.</context>
      <utterance>You got her now?</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronnie. Rae. I want you to look at each other and listen to me carefully. Do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAE &amp; RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both obey -- each with a serious expression.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lincoln steps toward Ronnie and holds up the black velvet. Ronnie takes the gold chain and carefully wraps it around Rae's waist.</context>
      <utterance>I require and charge you both as you stand in the presence of God to remember that love and loyalty alone will avail as a foundation of a happy and enduring home.  Go on, hand it to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laz looks on -- a conflicted emotion of joy and loss.</context>
      <utterance>No human ties are more tender. No vows more sacred than those you now assume.</utterance>
   <speaker>R.L.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela reaches over and takes Laz's hand in hers.</context>
      <utterance>If these solemn vows be kept inviolate, the home which you are establishing will abide in peace and your life will be filled with joy.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
