<movie id="83" title="Blade Runner">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLADE RUNNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screenplay by</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMPTON FANCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>July 24, 1980 Brighton Productions Inc. 1420 No. Beachwood Drive Hollywood, Calif. 90028</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holden doesn't answer. He's centering Leon's eye on the machine.</context>
      <utterance>Okay if I talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kinda get nervous when I take tests.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries not to move but finally his lips can't help a sheepish smile.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Already had I.Q. test this year -- but I don't think I never had a...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reaction time is a factor in this, so please pay attention. Answer quickly as you can. Leon compresses his lips and nods his big head eagerly. Holden's voice is cold, geared to intimidate and evoke response.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in a desert, walking along in the sand when all of a sudden you look down and see a...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It was a timid interruption, hardly audible.</context>
      <utterance>What one?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What desert?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't make any difference what desert -- it's completely hypothetical.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how come I'd be there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you're fed up, maybe you want to be by yourself -- who knows. So you look down and see a tortoise. It's crawling towards you...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A tortoise. What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what a turtle is?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees Holden's patience is wearing thin.</context>
      <utterance>I never seen a turtle.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I understand what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keeping an eye on his subject, Holden notes the dials in the Voight-Kampff. One of the needles quivers slightly.</context>
      <utterance>You reach down and flip the tortoise over on its back, Leon.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disregarding the question, Holden continues, picking up the pace.</context>
      <utterance>You make these questions, Mr. Holden, or they write 'em down for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leon's upper lip is quivering.</context>
      <utterance>The tortoise lays on its back, its belly baking in the hot sun, beating its legs trying to turn itself over. But it can't. Not without your help. But you're not helping.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatcha mean, I'm not helping?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leon looks shocked, surprised. But the needles in the computer barely move. Holden goes for the inside of his coat. But big Leon is faster. His LASER BURNS a hole the size of a nickel through Holden's stomach. Unlike a bullet, a laser causes no impact. It goes through Holden's spine and comes out his back, clean as a whistle. Like a rag doll he falls back off the bench from the waist up. By the time he hits the floor, big slow Leon is already walking away. But he stops, turns and with a little smile of satisfaction, FIRES at the machine on the table. There's a flash and a puff of smoke. The Voight-Kampff is hit dead center, crippled but not destroyed; as Leon walks out of the room, one of its lights begins to blink, faint but steady.</context>
      <utterance>I mean you're not helping! Why is that, Leon?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A little detached, Deckard taps another sensor on the panel, lights up a cigarette and watches as his mes- sages flash across the viewer stating date, time and caller. The last one is repeated five times. Deckard sighs, switches off the viewer and gets on the radio.</context>
      <utterance>It was 97 degrees in the city and no hope of improvement. Not bad if you're a lizard. But two hours earlier I was drinking Acquavit with an Eskimo lady in North East Alaska. That's a tough change to make. It was so good, I didn't want to leave, so I left a day early.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SOUND OF A CHIME precedes the mechanical female voice that answers.</context>
      <utterance>Contact. This is Blade Runner One calling Com-fast 27.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. Followed by a husky male voice.</context>
      <utterance>Blade Runner One, stand by please.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deckard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah, Gaff.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAFF</speaker>
      <mode>VOICE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know where I been. I been on vacation.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time you go on vacation, do me a favor, let us know where it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a pause. That was bad news.</context>
      <utterance>Holden got hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Severed spine. You'd better get in here. Bryant's waiting for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ENGINE REVS, the wipers rake two weeks of dust off the windshield and Deckard jams out of the lot.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you in a minute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The door in front of Deckard slides open and he walks through.</context>
      <utterance>I-X-4-P-D referred to as a Nexus-6, The Tyrell Corporation's new pride and joy. Holden was administering the Voight-Kampff test when one nailed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Nexus-6 must be fast because Holden was as quick as they come. The report said there were six of them. Three males and three female. Led by a combat model called Roy Batty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bryant gets the safe open and brings out a bottle of whiskey.</context>
      <utterance>They escaped from the colonies two weeks ago. Killed twenty- three people and jumped a shuttle. An aerial patrol found the ship in the desert. No crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Deckard sets down the report and takes the shot Bryant just poured for him.</context>
      <utterance>Bryant's got a liver problem. A couple years back he handed me a bottle and said have a drink for another man. I been drinking for him ever since.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five. Three nights ago one of them managed to break into the Tyrell Corporation. Killed two guards and got as far as the Genetic Sector before he got fried going through an electro- field.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was he after?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A grim pause.</context>
      <utterance>There wasn't much left of him, so we can't be sure. But bio- chemical data and morphology records of the Nexus-6 were reported missing. Going on the possibility they might try to infiltrate we send Holden in to run Voight-Kampff tests on the new employees. Guess he found himself one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a machine on it yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're using Esper -- a 231 -- that picked up Holden's alarm. Its guess is that all five are in the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bryant's back at the safe locking up his bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Where do we start?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Tyrell Corporation has a demo model. Check it out on the Voight-Kampff. There's a chance the Nexus-6 is beyond out ability to detect. If that's the case, everybody's up shit creek.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was the cover on the one that got Holden?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Industrial refuse.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bryant nods.</context>
      <utterance>Garbage man?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bryant fishes a piece of paper out of his pocket, copies down a number and hands it over.</context>
      <utterance>Did personnel have an address on him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard stands and holds up his drink.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like a sick boy looking out of the window, Bryant watches Deckard down the whiskey. Deckard puts down the glass and turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>But I didn't give him a chance.</context>
      <utterance>The big incentive to emigrate was still free labor. If the public found out that their door-prizes might kill them, they might not be so hot to go up there. This was one of the worst one's we had and Bryant was worried. He wanted to tell me to be discrete or something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Latin beauty is replaced by an impeccable Ray Bolger type gentleman's gentleman who clicks his heels, snaps to attention and struts off to make room for the next.</context>
      <utterance>Choose from a variety of seventy nine different personality types. Each and every one a loyal trouble- free companion given to you upon your arrival absolutely free...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chinese are paying no attention, but the man and the woman seated at the table by the window are. The woman is pretty, a touch of gray in her hair, kind and blue-eyed. MARY looks like an American dream mom, right out of "Father Knows Best." The man also resembles a tradition: the gym instructor, short cropped hair with the body of a drill sergeant, but the eyes are grey and chilling. ROY BATTY is a presence of force with a lazy, but acute sense of what goes on around him. Leon has just come through the door behind them. Try- ing not to be the bull in a china shop, he approaches their table and kneels . Batty doesn't bother to look at him, which amplifies the note of sarcasm in his quiet voice.</context>
      <utterance>To use as personal body servant to tireless field hand -- the custom tailored humanoid robot, designed especially for your needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get your precious 'things'?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody was already there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Police.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leon looks sullen.</context>
      <utterance>Police man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's one next to him. Leon pulls it over and sits.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you have a seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the pot on the table, Mary pours tea and they sit so quiet and still in this noisy place that they seem almost invisible. The view they're "enjoying" is through the window. Outside the neon side in the win- dow directly across the street says: HANNIBAL CHEW,</context>
      <utterance>Enjoy the view.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>honey has a couple of defective cones. He snaps off the lamp and swings round to face his client. SEBASTIAN'S face is almost young, but something has gone too far, too fast. Premature old age has made his bones brittle and his co-ordination slow. The house may be dark but there's a light on in it. Se- bastian is a closet genius.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you're right. This little</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian's apologetic, especially around the acerbic Mr. Chew.</context>
      <utterance>You're a regular perfectionist, Sebastian.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gotta be right for my customer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chew snickers and beckons. Sebastian follows his down a high narrow hall to a heavy insulated door. There's a moth-eaten full length fur coat hanging by it. Chew tugs it on and they go through. The big door slams shut behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Your customer, eh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quick to accommodate, Sebastian removes a pencil-like device from a row of such things in his breast pocket and steps closer. The back of the eye is touched with the pencil and the pupil moves. Suddenly its staring back at them.</context>
      <utterance>You got a pocket-charger, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anxious to leave, Sebastian nods. Chew reseals the eye taking his time. He can afford to, he's wearing his coat.</context>
      <utterance>Is that good enough for your customer?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In place of an answer, Sebastian clears his throat, stares at the bag like he didn't hear.</context>
      <utterance>How much is he paying you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, when do you get paid?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon as I finish the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When might that be?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Day after tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian nods. Chew stares at the poor bastard, con- cerned in spite of himself.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! Day after tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian nods his head like that's exactly what he'll do. Chew sees it's hopeless and hands him the bag.</context>
      <utterance>The rich hate to pay, Sebastian. A guy like Tyrell keeps you waiting. Pay the little guy last. You should charge twice as much. It'll make him feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chew pulls the door open for him and Sebastian goes through quick as a dog.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Mr. Chew.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the bag. Hesitantly she reaches for it.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! You forgot your...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you were in my truck?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him, hand on her case, looking lost. Sebastian isn't good at this, but he tries.</context>
      <utterance>I was tired and didn't have any place to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't make up her mind.</context>
      <utterance>You can get back in if you want...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets in. Both of them are silent. People are not Sebastian's medium -- usually he's too shy, but this girl is shyer still, plus they're about the same age -- it gives him courage.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I won't hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pris.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine's J.F. Sebastian.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So pleased with the way that went, he forgets for a while what comes next.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs. That leaves him a lot of responsibility. He throws her side-long glances, but she's not helping.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! Where do you want to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to go home?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you do with a teenage beauty who looks like she's lost out of some "Welcome to Sunny Arizona" poster?</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are your folks?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They left.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans forward and rests her elbows on the dash. Her body would win prizes, from any angle.</context>
      <utterance>I have some, but I have to find out where they are staying.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him,a shadow of enticement in her clear blue eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Well, where should I take you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We scared each other pretty good didn't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She giggles and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>We sure did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry, J.F.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got stuff. If you wanna go to my place?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian's face is normally on the grey side, but it just turned red. He turns on the ignition and they pull away from the curb.</context>
      <utterance>I was hoping you'd say that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screen flashes back:</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEARANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deckard punches up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE RUNNER ONE CODE ML-33</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Screen flashes:</context>
      <utterance>Pause.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Machines can be helpful sometimes, but they can also be a pain in the ass. Ask for a trace on a forger and you might wind up at a steel- mill. I don't mind a bum-steer once in a while -- it's their personalities that usually get me. Somebody once said that man makes machines in his own image. If that's true, whoever made Esper should have been shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esper's deep melodious voice is anxious to please, and oiled with a touch of self-pity.</context>
      <utterance>This is Esper and I'm ready. Go ahead please.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You equipped for random questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, yes, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You start.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The five in question are third generation Nexus Sixes, constructed of skin-flesh culture, selected enogenic transfer conversion capable of self-perpetuating thought, para-physical abilities and developed for emigration program. Are you with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I stop one?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unlike a five, they can sustain massive traumas to several parts of the body without debilitating another. Sever a leg and it will perform quicker on the remaining leg than the fastest man can run,</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The communication is interrupted by a BELL which is immediately followed by a stern, MECHANICAL VOICE.</context>
      <utterance>I'm coming to that. Vulnerable zone is the base of the skull, the occipital bone. A direct hit is a positive retirement.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In his rear view mirror Deckard sees two black-clad motorcycle cops coming up behind him like the hounds of hell. They draw silently alongside. Deckard presses his I.D. to the window. The cop tosses a salute to Deckard and he and his partner accelerate, vanish in the night. And Deckard's car does too.</context>
      <utterance>You are in violation of traffic ordinance M-139 statutory freeway limit restricted by one-hundred and eighty kilometers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pris is light on her feet. She's standing behind him with a half-eaten sandwich in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatcha doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he's happy to see her.</context>
      <utterance>You scared me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's changed her dress and made up her face. Looks a little older and sexier.</context>
      <utterance>I'm working.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look... better.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches her as she prowls around the room, looking at this and that, eating her sandwich.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you live in this building all by yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trying to make light of it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I live here pretty much alone right now...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sprawls on the couch studying him.</context>
      <utterance>No housing shortage around here... plenty of room for everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't meet her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's not an easy subject. His voice is barely audible.</context>
      <utterance>What's your problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Methuselah Syndrome.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My glands. They grow old too fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why you're still here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a silence. He steals a glance at her.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I couldn't pass the test.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Under the desk he bats his knees together.</context>
      <utterance>I like you just the way you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, you get hold of your friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact I did. They've got some work to do tonight, but they're gonna come tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The implications catch up.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little gray mouse on the shelf above his head bobs up.</context>
      <utterance>I can sleep on the couch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking their cue from the mouse, some of the more talented animoids toot, flap and wheel about.</context>
      <utterance>Don't let the bed bugs bite!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pause.</context>
      <utterance>Nexus designated Leon: incept date April 10th, 2015 -- to be used in military experiments to determine how hyper metabolism functions in deep space. Nexus designated Batty incept data April 10th, 2015, combat model, level of self-sufficiency, optimum.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's something you might find interesting. They have been built to emulate the human in every way except in its emotional spectrum. However, after a period of time it is only logical that such a 'mechanism' would create its own emotional responses, hate, love, fear, anger, envy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know all that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about a summary then.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard starts to reach for the panel.</context>
      <utterance>I think we're through for the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Deckard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have something against science?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if it works.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what in your estimation works?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard picks up the umbrella and with it stabs the terminal off button before Esper can respond and the machine goes dead. He sits there for a moment then flips on the lamp. Leon's snap-shots are spread out before him.</context>
      <utterance>The umbrella.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The guard hands Deckard back his I.D., pushed a button and Deckard walks away.</context>
      <utterance>But so far they'd always managed to keep it quiet. Not to say that once in a while there wasn't bad publicity. Some fanatic bitching about equal rights for andies or an occasional trade union proclaiming it was aun-American for automatons to take jobs away from humans on the colony.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The elevator door slides open. The young lady inside would look right standing on a cliff, hair blowing in the wind, looking out to sea in a 19th Century painting.</context>
      <utterance>But what's more American than good old supply and demand? The Government needed them, industry made them and the church backed them. The big religious boys said that Androids, no matter how human, were objects; only God could make people. I'm not religious, but I was inclined to agree. Otherwise I'd be out of a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard tips his head to her and steps in.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Deckard. My name is Rachael.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems your department doesn't believe out new unit is to the public benefit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A humanoid robot is like any other machine, it can be a benefit or a hazard. If it's a benefit, it's not our problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard?</context>
      <utterance>But because your department can't do an adequate job in detecting the miniscule number at large, it's a problem. Correct, Mr.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard nods. Rachael claps her hands. The owl opens its yellow eyes and blinks at them.</context>
      <utterance>You like our owl?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's artificial?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hands thrust in her pockets, she strides off towards the exit without looking back. The exit is another tube. Just big enough for two. No room for excess. He tries to ignore her cool appraising stare.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard has nothing to say.</context>
      <utterance>You're in a very unique position, Mr. Deckard. You could affect the future of this entire organization according to how you work your little test.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you apprehensive?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I be?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door slides open. Deckard looks down at her.</context>
      <utterance>For the responsibility of your power. Being a police bureaucrat, you've got more than your share.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets it sink in.</context>
      <utterance>You got it wrong, girl. I work with the bureau not for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks out of the elevator first.</context>
      <utterance>My job isn't to detect malfunctioning andies, it's to eliminate them. The more the better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Deckard. Dr. Eldon Tyrell.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do, Mr. Deckard. Please sit down. Would you care for a cup of coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Black?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell pours from an old time sylex into small china cups and hands one to Deckard. The congenial light in his eyes could almost pass for warmth -- dragon warmth.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Deckard a cup of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Somehow, I didn't expect that the man who did the dirty work would be the man to do the technical work. Here you are, Mr. Deckard.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this to be an empathy test?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard nods.</context>
      <utterance>Capillary dilation of the so-called blush response? Plus fluctuation of the pupil, plus involuntary dilation of the iris?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I ask a personal question?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever retired a human by mistake?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But in your profession that is a risk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing is infallible, but so far the Voight-Kampff scale bas been foolproof.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you said, Mr. Deckard, a machine can be a hazard. The Voight-Kampff scale is a machine, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One that relies on human interpretation. Where's the subject?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard stares at Rachael, then back at Tyrell. Delighted, Tyrell takes a cup of coffee. Accepting the challenge, Deckard opens his briefcase and starts fishing out the apparatus.</context>
      <utterance>Sitting next to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="44">
   <speaker>DECKARD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the soft green glow of the dials, the needles in both gauges are at rest. Dr. Tyrell stands silhouetted behind Deckard, who sits in front of Rachael, a pencil beam trained on her eye. Wire mesh discs are attached to her cheeks.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The needles in both gauges swing violently past green to red, then subside.</context>
      <utterance>You're given a calfskin wallet for your birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't accept it. Also, I'd report the person who gave it to me to the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again the gauges register, but not so far.</context>
      <utterance>You have a little boy. He shows you his butterfly collection, plus the killing jar.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd take him to the doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're watching T.V. and suddenly you notice a wasp crawling on your wrist.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both needles go to red. Deckard makes a note, takes a sip of coffee and continues.</context>
      <utterance>I'd kill it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a magazine you come across a full-page photo of a nude girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this testing whether I'm an android or a lesbian?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl is lying on a bearskin rug.</context>
      <utterance>You show the picture to your husband. He likes it and hangs it on the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't let him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard frowns, then smiles. His smile looks a little like a grimace or the other way around.</context>
      <utterance>I should be enough for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You become pregnant by a man who runs off with your best friend, and you decide to get an abortion.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd never get an abortion.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be murder, Mr. Deckard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In your opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would be my child.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He notes the needles. One goes green and the other remains inert.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds like you speaks from experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last question. You're watching an old movie. It shows a banquet in progress, the guests are enjoying raw oysters.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both needles swing swiftly.</context>
      <utterance>Ugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Needles move less.</context>
      <utterance>The entree consists of boiled dog stuffed with rice.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard moves the adhesive discs from her cheeks and switches off his beam.</context>
      <utterance>The raw oysters are less acceptable to you than a dish of boiled dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights come on.</context>
      <utterance>Lights please.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she is, the machine works.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachael sits very still. Except her eyes -- they go to Tyrell and hang on. He stares back at her as he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>The machine works. She is.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many questions did it take?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachael sits rigidly in her chair, as the ground crumbles around her, her big mermaid eyes locked with Tyrell. His voice is quiet and strong, mesmerizing. She's hang- ing by a thread. Deckard watches with a bas taste in his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Thirteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't know?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachael nods fixedly. Careful not to let go her grasp.</context>
      <utterance>Memory implant. She was programmed. But I think she has transcended her conditioning. I think she was beginning to suspect.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many questions does it usually take, Mr. Deckard?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly, carefully, Tyrell unlocks his gaze from Rachael and turns towards Deckard, who is starting to put away his equipment.</context>
      <utterance>Five, maybe six.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard glances back at him.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to have to be on your toes, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Less of a man might shrink at the end of Deckard's look, but not Tyrell.</context>
      <utterance>It's a complex problem and we wouldn't want anything to happen to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard almost smiles at the nasty power of Tyrell's style. He turns away and starts packing up the Voight- Kampff.</context>
      <utterance>For the good of all, I recommend you take Rachael with you. Considering her uniqueness, I'm sure she could prove quite helpful.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard is ready to go.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how is it one man will be able to cover so much ground?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Discreetly.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>All pertinent information is being fed into your departmental computer, an Esper 231 -- I believe -- and a photo over-lay packet is being produced.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachael sits there very pale and expressionless, her feet flat on the floor, alone is the word. Trying to keep the fury out of it, Deckard's voice comes out in a whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Deckard, I think it would be wise to reconsider my offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the last word, Rachael glances up at him and Deckard turns away. The outer door slides open and he goes through it.</context>
      <utterance>I work alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's keep our eyes on the road, Deckard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abruptly the VIEW FLASHES BACK TO:</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to have to start the sequence again if you don't stay with me, Deckard. Concentrate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know I'm not?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not responding to the stimulus. I can see right here, I'm not getting a reading.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm tired of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost through.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Wheeler is a thin boney man, aloof but a promise of compassion in his sunken eyes.</context>
      <utterance>So how did I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nerves of steel.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No rust?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say that. Your motivity rate checked out a little slower than last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard starts to dress.</context>
      <utterance>Meaning you don't run as fast as you used to.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>During the road test...</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mind kept wandering. That bothered me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Considering the nature of your work, that could be unhealthy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wheeler studies his "desk" for a moment and his finger comes down on the section illuminating Deckard's simple statistics.</context>
      <utterance>True.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard bends over slipping on his shoes. Wheeler looks up, concerned.</context>
      <utterance>You got a birthday coming up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you haven't put in for emigration.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to be over the limit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I could make you a long list of complaints about this fucken city but I still rather be here than up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if you change your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll change the limit before I change my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard is ready to go. Looking at Wheeler, a little touched with his concern.</context>
      <utterance>Never been more sure of anything in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too old.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wheeler considers it a moment, smiles and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>But if you could?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My job is here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands and Deckard walks.</context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not ready yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty nods he can't wait. Pris glances at Mary and gives a frigid little smile. Pris backs out and closes the door behind her. Batty blows air through his nostrils. Like an animal.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow, he says.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard looks down at the over-turned plate and nods.</context>
      <utterance>Was that your dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's holding out a cassette the size of a cigarette pack. But it's taking Deckard's adrenalin time to recede.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I called and found out you were on your way home. These were already delivered to your department but I thought you should have copies as soon as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the cassette, but a man with so many locks must be wondering how they were gotten through so easily. He doesn't even want to ask.</context>
      <utterance>It's the Nexus information you wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He realizes he's still got the gun aimed at her and sticks it back in his belt and they're left staring at each other. The situation makes awkward silence. At least for him. She's looking at him like she's got something to say but isn't saying it.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you think it complicates your work, but I'm here to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've already got more help than I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't, but she's not backing off.</context>
      <utterance>I think you need more help than you've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's two reasons a man rejects help. Either because he's so good at what he does he doesn't think he needs it, or he's so insecure he can't admit it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like I'm an ass-hole either way, but the answer is still no.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two of us might be more effective than one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I work alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lets it sink in.</context>
      <utterance>No you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You use your equipment, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a strong look that passes between them -- a long one. Maybe if he were on firmer ground he might do something about such an offer but... Deckard's eyes follow her down as Rachael bends to the floor and starts picking the food off the rug, put- ting it back on the plate.</context>
      <utterance>So, I'm a piece of equipment. Use me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bends down to help, but she's already done it. Their heads a few inches apart. Something in her eyes diminishes the distance even more.</context>
      <utterance>That's okay, I'll get it...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I make you nervous?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she is. And suddenly he is too. She hands him the plate and they stand. She's looking at the floor, almost shy, then she looks up and he's watching her. She says it plain and simple.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard nods. He feels it, but doesn't know what to do about it.</context>
      <utterance>It's strange to suddenly realize that what you thought was your life is actually someone else's fabrication.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>These are not some of Deckard's finer moments. But she doesn't seem to notice.</context>
      <utterance>Can you? I couldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard nods, waits the respectable interval and is glad to have a plate to take into the kitchen. In the scrambled sanctuary of his kitchen Deckard looks around for a place to put the plate, but things have piled up on him in here. He contemplates the refrig- erator.</context>
      <utterance>A part of me is glad. I think I feel more. I don't like who I was before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's a lot more comfortable talking shop.</context>
      <utterance>So why do you think they were after their records.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They probably want to find out when they were made.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dumps his dinner in the garbage and comes back out. She's writing something on a card.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No way he can keep his foot out of it. She looks up and hands him the card.</context>
      <utterance>I guess the date of your birth is important if you know you're not made to last.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes to the door, opens it but hesitates before going through.</context>
      <utterance>That's my number. If you need me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks back at him and smiles -- the smile says she's talking about all kinds of locks. Deckard looks like he might ask her to stay, but...</context>
      <utterance>You better get better locks -- if you want to keep me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she's gone.</context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at the number. It's the back side of a snapshot. He turns it over. The picture of a man and a woman. The little girl between them looks like a six-year old Rachael.</context>
      <utterance>Night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>On top of the monitor there's an open can of beans with a spoon stuck in it. Deckard puts out his cigarette and reaches for them as the PHONE RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>The possibilities were infinite. They could change their appearances but not their future. Like she said, it was short. Longevity is what they were after. The garbage man even wanted a past. Poor fuck. I'd check it out but I knew she was right. The market worked on turn-over. Built-in obsolescence was the name of the game. That meant her too. It was something I didn't want to think about.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bryant here. Regarding the rundown you requested on job applicants, Esper's concluded that the only irregular category that Tyrell's got is the entertainment section. You better get on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just about to have my dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard hangs up and looks at the beans. He didn't want them anyway. He gets up and walks to the bedroom. Looks through the pile of clothes on the floor, finds his ankle laser and straps it on.</context>
      <utterance>If you hurry you'll get back before it gets cold. I got a spinner on your roof in five minutes. Good luck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EPSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nexus designated Rachael is a prototype. Created for in-house use by special mandate form the Scientific Development Regulatory Committee. Will live conventional term -- no para-physical abilities.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is a conventional term?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four years. Which would make her termination date...</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind. Do they have that knowledge?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back to business.</context>
      <utterance>Longevity is classified. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, gimme a run-down on the three females.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nexus designated Mary: incept November 1 2017, domestic conditioning non competitive, trained for day care position.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nexus designated Pris: incept data December 13 2017, competitive, programmed to provide pleasure for long term spacers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number three.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nexus designated Zhora: incept June 13th 2017, athletic conditioning, highly competitive, special abilities in the entertainment field.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taffey Lewis?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a pause lasting the time it takes Taffey not to think of a way to say no. The door opens and Deckard enters. Except for the drool coming out of the corner of her mouth, and the fluttering eye-lids, Venus doesn't move a muscle.</context>
      <utterance>Can I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard takes the Identikit hard copies our of his pocket and pushing some junk out of the way, fans them out on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse my niece there... She's studying for an exam.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like you to take a look at these pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taffey bends down really close, peering at the pictures from about two inches away.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see I lost my contacts a couple of days ago around here somewhere and my sight is a little... What am I supposed to be looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops at Zhora.</context>
      <utterance>Do you recognize any of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This one looks familiar, but I don't know. Naw. There's one came in today looks a little like this one but...</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did she want?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girl that doesn't look like that girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. She wanted to know about suck night.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What night?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know if I wanted to handle her -- I already got a snake act. But my partner goes down there to the Opera House on suck night to book the good ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's suck night?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we call in the trade, audition free-for- alls and most of it sucks. Bit I don't think that's her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taffey nods. Deckard goes to the door and turns.</context>
      <utterance>You talking about the Opera House on the Main?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Book the good ones for where?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lots of places. The tours, the clubs, the Silicone shows, private parties.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What shows?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's starting to get a little gooey. Deckard tips his head good night and backs out of the door.</context>
      <utterance>Silicone Valley. Lots of these science guys never leave that place. We book two shows a month in there. Those big time techs and bio- guys might be real high zoners up here, but when it comes to the arts, they like it loud and lewd.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scattered APPLAUSE. Hand in hand, the Hermano Brothers bow deeply, spring up and trot offstage.</context>
      <utterance>Let's hear it for the Hermano Brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old boys in the pit strike up a tinny version of "In a Persian Market" as SALOME dances onstage. She's a black-haired beauty in a scant belly dancer costume, a couple of pounds overweight but all in the right places. She kneels ceremoniously center stage and sets the basket down before her. Carefully removing the lid, she reaches in and lifts out a four- foot harlequin-patterned python. Grinding her hips to the music, she rises, holding the coiling snake out like an offering. Sounds of approval from the audience. The gold coins covering her breasts jingle and shimmer, as she weaves sensuously around the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Next we're gonna see a little charmer who keeps her dancing partner in a basket! She comes to us all the way from exotic Casablanca. 'Salome.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns. Deckard's posture and attitude suggest hum- ble, sleazy persistence. He comes closer with his shit-eating grin.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Miss Salome.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salome stands almost six feet high in her high heels -- she looks down on him with the haughty suspicion of a chick who knows how to handle cheap hits.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to have a word with you if I could.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up a hand as if to stop her from protesting.</context>
      <utterance>I'm with the American Federation of Variety Artists...</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances around like a guy who's not supposed to be there.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I'm not here to make you join -- that's not my department.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, taking it a little more seriously.</context>
      <utterance>I'm an investigator for the Confidential Committee on Moral Abuses.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's been reports of management sexually abusing the artists in this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know nothing about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's definitely puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>You haven't felt yourself to be exploited by the management in any way?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you mean 'exploited'?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like to get this position. Did you or were you asked to do anything lewd or unsavory or otherwise repulsive to your person?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you for real?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. You'd be surprised what goes on around here. I'd like to check the dressing room if I could.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck for?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This guy might be an asshole but he's funny.</context>
      <utterance>For holes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs and they go in.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It that mother real?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course he's not real. You think I'd be working here if I could afford a real snake?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a good job.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard nods. There's not much costume to take off but she's doing it.</context>
      <utterance>You mean the snake.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand reaches out to touch it. As his fingers make contact there's an electric "snap." He jerks his hand back from the shock.</context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeezus!</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slides behind the screen and turns on the shower. Deckard starts creeping around pacing around the room like he's inspecting the walls.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Do your job but don't wreck mine, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes are moving over everything she's got.</context>
      <utterance>They have their ways of doing their dirty work without the victim knowing what's going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be surprised what a guy'll go through to get a glimpse of a beautiful body.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And to his amazement he actually spots one. It's down low on the wall. Not a good idea to turn his back on work but he can't resist.</context>
      <utterance>Little dirty holes the bastards drill in the wall so they can watch a lady undress.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the hole Deckard is looking at a pair of fat legs.</context>
      <utterance>And what if somebody did try to 'exploit' me? Who do I go to?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALOME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks back. She's some out of the shower dripping nude. She's taken off her black wig. Her hair is short and blonde. Deckard recognizes her immediately from the identikit. He stares at her a moment too long.</context>
      <utterance>And who do I go to about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard grins and she returns it. She takes a towel off the table and starts to dry her body. The snake noses through the cosmetics, tongue flicking trying to get back to its mistress. Absently, she reaches out to stroke the snake and suddenly laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmmmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZHORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand closes around the snake's head. Deckard sees it coming but can't move fast enough. She strikes him so hard it knocks him off his feet. Before he hits the floor, she kicks him in the stomach. The snake whistles through the air again as Deckard rolls out of the way. It slams down so hard it ruptures against the floor. He goes for his laser, but she's already out the door.</context>
      <utterance>You ever get the feeling things aren't the way they seem?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't. The beam flashes through the air, but she's already around the corner. With his bottom lip between his teeth, it hurts to move so fast, Deckard jack-legs it into the street and jumps in front of the first car coming. It screeches to a stop. Deckard scrambles for the door, but the guy be- hind the wheel has other ideas. He peels out fast. The next car slows down and swerves trying not to hit him. Deckard goes for the door and before the old ma- tron inside can lock it, Deckard's yanked it open and jumps in. She screams as he pushes her into the pas- senger seat and jams the car into a wrenching about face. The lady squeals like a pig as the momentum plasters her against the door. Deckard slams it around the corner and guns it down the street. It's long and it's empty and it's going by fast. Nothing the old lady cares to see -- she's got her hands over her eyes, whimpering, hoping she'll faint before she dies. Deckard takes the next left so hard he almost lays it over. As the car bounces off the curb he floors it. Zhora's a hundred yards ahead, halfway down the street, trying to make it back into the crowded mall. She's running fast, but the car is faster. As he passes her, Deckard hits the brakes and skids broadside seventy feet. The door flies open and he rolls out FIRING. Zhora's ducking it with no where to go, except... The showcase window on her left EXPLODES as she crashes through. It's a corner shop joined to a series of stores, front- ing the mall. Deckard runs to the opening she's made and pours FIRE through the tunnel of her jagged wake as Zhora breaks through one window after another, getting sliced, getting shot, trying to get away from Deckard's laser. But she doesn't. His last shot burns a hole through the base of her skull. It kills her but doesn't stop her. Her speed takes what's left of her through the last two windows and into the street where she runs into a parked car with such force that she embeds herself in the side of it. Hunched over, breathing hard, Deckard comes slowly for- ward. The crowd starting to gather. There's something for everybody and they're coming from all directions. Deckard moves through them, edging to have a look. It's not a good thing to see. It looks like Salome and the car tries to eat each other. A bloody feast of metal and flesh. Deckard bows his head, sick, exhausted. So much commo- tion he doesn't notice THREE COPS closing in from behind.</context>
      <utterance>Stop or you're dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard has his back to them. They're fanned out and crouched, ready to fire. Deckard drops his laser. Two of them rush up, spin him around while the third does a frisk. TWO MORE COPS arrive, wary and wild-eyed, pushing the people back -- his is not a good place for cops. Deckard's ankle laser is discovered by the Cop frisking him. With a snarl he pulls it out and hands it back to the SERGEANT covering the action.</context>
      <utterance>Drop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard's not in the mood for it.</context>
      <utterance>On your belly!</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's reaching for his ID. The Cop with the rubber billy hits him in the head. One thrill after another. Somebody in the crowd YEOWLS. The last thing Deckard hears as he falls. The Cop reaches inside Deckard's coat for the concealed weapon they missed, but it's an ID card. He looks at it for a moment, then looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Sergeant...</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An embarrassing situation.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Sarge, this guy's a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cops start pushing. And for one split second one of the crowd looks a lot like Leon.</context>
      <utterance>Clear this fuckin' crowd.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's not the sort of question that expects an answer. Deckard's washing his face in the basin hoping it'll all go away.</context>
      <utterance>Just because it's a Nexus 6 doesn't change procedure. A little known fact can become a well-known fact and part of our job, Deckard, is to make sure that doesn't happen. Now how can be do that if you blow one away in front of a fuckin' audience.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard looks up dripping, reaches for a paper towel. Bryant slaps one in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was gonna get away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bryant takes a couple of deep breaths.</context>
      <utterance>Then let her get away. I thought you were a pro -- you're supposed to be a fuckin' tracker!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard's voice is barely audible.</context>
      <utterance>I'd say you got a little carried away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't like her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams the handle on one of the urinals.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't like her!?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PLUMPING ROARS and SUCKS and DIES. There's nothing to do but nod. Deckard nods. Poor bastard has had a rough night. Bryant pulls a flask out of his coat and hands it to him. Deckard puts it to his mouth and Bryant watches Deckard's Adam's apple like he's count- ing the swallows. Deckard hands it back empty. Bryant caps it, puts it back in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>You start liking or disliking andies it's time to hang it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Take an aspirin.</context>
      <utterance>Look, go home. Get some rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bryant shuffles out like an old bear.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard glances at his stool-mate. A huge MAN, slumped over the bar like a beached whale.</context>
      <utterance>I can't protect your drinks, mister; while you was in the potty, this hummer snatched it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whale doesn't move, but it speaks, with a gravelly Russian accent.</context>
      <utterance>No problem. Gimme another.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSSIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me. I thought was free drink. I will pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the big man's digging through his pockets. Deck- ard's drink arrives and the Russian raises his head. It's a big melancholy face with a glint of warmth in his red-rimmed eyes and a smile that could melt your heart. But it's Leon.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I have no money.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I would like to buy you drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll but you one. What'll you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vodka!</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shot of vodka, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard brings out his smokes. Offers one. Leon takes it and they light up. The drinks come.</context>
      <utterance>My pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prosit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down the hatch. Leon slaps his glass on the bar, reach- es into his pocket, brings out a little match box and slaps that down too. It's done with such pride that Deckard has to look.</context>
      <utterance>Prosit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to see my friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, don't have the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leon smiles broadly and with ceremonious care opens the box and dumps three live cockroaches on the bar.</context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those cockroaches?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard looks interested. One of them starts to scamp- er away, but Leon walls off the next with his huge hand.</context>
      <utterance>Ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long you had these guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leon leans closer like he doesn't want the cockroaches to hear.</context>
      <utterance>Two months. But this one is not guy. It is girl. His girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard nods, definitely interested. He signals the bartender for another round. The drinks arrive.</context>
      <utterance>Usually Blackie waits until Igor is eating; then, when his back is turned, he tries to take advantage of Anna.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prosit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down the hatch. Their eyes meet at the bottom.</context>
      <utterance>Prosit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leon smiles slyly.</context>
      <utterance>You never saw a cockroach make love? Deckard shakes his head, but he'd like to.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leon brings a cube of sugar out of his pocket and puts it on the bar. They both lean down and watch intently. The drinks come and are put away, but the cockroaches are not cooperating.</context>
      <utterance>We will try.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leon is catching the roaches and one by one puts them back in their box. He holds up the last and kisses it.</context>
      <utterance>It must be that he is not hungry or maybe she is not hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like to kiss her goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What neither of them notices is that between Leon's fingers, his stub of his cigarette is burning his flesh. Deckard lifts his glass, it is empty.</context>
      <utterance>Make sure you take your girlfriends with you when you leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard gets on his feet, leans forward like a man in a stiff wind and stops.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leon watches his walk a perfect straight line through the bar down the passage and out of the rear exit.</context>
      <utterance>I think I'll piss outside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand is lightning. It shoots out, grabs Deckard's hair.</context>
      <utterance>How come you know where Zhora was so quick?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard is pale. The sweat is starting to run.</context>
      <utterance>I showed pictures. Somebody recognized her. I went to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The grip tightens and twists.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How long do I live?</context>
      <utterance>My birthday is April 10, 2015.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets go.</context>
      <utterance>Four years.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard's knees come up fast. Leon's fist comes down faster, like a hammer.</context>
      <utterance>More than you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard is doubled over, hugging his thigh.</context>
      <utterance>Painful to live in fear, isn't it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even hurt, Deckard is fast. He goes for his ankle gun, but Leon's got it out of his hand before he can even raise it and throws it down the alley. Deckard hurls forward, knocking him off balance, and scrambles to get away. Leon grabs him by the foot, drags him back and jerks him off the ground.</context>
      <utterance>But that's how it is to be a slave. The future is sealed off, he grovels, he waits.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams Deckard into the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Sex, reproduction, security, the simple things. But no way to satisfy them. To be homesick with no place to go. Potential with no way to use it. Lots of little oversights in the Nexus 6.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>than having an itch you can never scratch. Deckard slides down the wall to his knees and huddles, protecting his head with his arms, waiting for the next one. Leon folds his big hands together and raises them over his head, pausing just a second to savor the satisfac- tion of smashing Deckard's skull. The spasm that runs through Leon's face is not from satisfaction. It's the bullet that went through his neck. He hits the ground hard, his big teeth biting the air like a rabid dog. Dead. Rachael is standing in the alley. Deckard lies there looking at her. She comes slowly and quietly forward and drops Deckard's gun by his side. Deckard gets to his hands and knees and tries to get up, but can't quite manage it. He looks up at her, panting, spits blood and almost smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I tell you, nothing is worse</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a long moment, she bends down to touch him.</context>
      <utterance>Like I said, I don't need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look terrible, you know that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He takes a drink and clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>I knew a cop once who was involved in a high-speed chase. They shot out one of his tires and he went over a cliff at hundred and fifty miles an hour. They found him in the morning with a broken skull, six fractured ribs and second- degree burns. On the way to the hospital he made a play for the nurse.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! I thought you were supposed to be taking care of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't answer. Lies there sipping his drink. Rachael comes in a little uncertain, a little droll, and stands there looking down at him.</context>
      <utterance>What do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't just stand there looking at me. It's not polite.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits on the edge of the tub.</context>
      <utterance>Sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's wearing a short-sleeved dress. It's a long, del- icate arm and Deckard holds it, inspecting it like a maestro with a Stradivarius. He looks up at her.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme your arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever take a bath with a man before?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's got her hand in the water and had begun to soap her arm. Starting with her wrist and running the bar to her elbow, up and down, slow and slippery. She watches, not quite sure of the ritual. He pulls her closer, and runs his hand up higher, mould- ing and pressing, working around her flesh, up and under her arm into the privacy of her dress.</context>
      <utterance>There's a lot I haven't done with a man before.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh, yes. For a moment Deckard stares at her like some furry-legged satyr in rut, the fingers of his other hand rake through her hair and into the water she comes.</context>
      <utterance>You're getting me wet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RACHAEL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's not soon enough. Deckard hangs up, puts the phone on the floor and leans back on the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I am not in at the moment, but if you'll leave your name and number I'll return your call as soon as I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody seems to be home except his chickens. As Sebas- tian enters, closing the door behind him, a goose charges out of the bedroom hissing and honking.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Deetchum? Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeming to recognize Sebastian as no intruder, Waddles veers off from the attack. As Sebastian crosses the room a pig peeks out from behind the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Now, now, Waddles.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the chickens and collects some eggs, putting them into a bowl he's brought. He puts down the bowl and reaching into his pocket carefully counts out the payment and puts the money on a plate. He's about to leave but notices there's no water in the dispenser.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Wrigley.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pouring from a jug on the table, he fills the dispenser with water, scatters a little grain on the floor, gets his bowel of eggs and leaves. Wrigley grunts and comes out from behind the couch for a long drink.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Deetchum isn't taking very good care of you people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiling, Batty hands them back to Sebastian, who is too startled to speak. Pris runs up and gives Batty and Mary a big hug, steps back effusing and smiling, everybody's favorite teen- ager.</context>
      <utterance>Whoops.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my Uncle Roy, Sebastian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pumps Sebastian's free hand.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, glad to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian turns and there's Aunt Mary, modest and warm.</context>
      <utterance>And my Aunt Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian stands there with his eggs, bashful and ex- cited, the hero of this little family's warm attention.</context>
      <utterance>And this is my savior, J.F. Sebastian, everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If you hadn't come along...</context>
      <utterance>Can't thank you enough, Mr. Sebastian.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian is nodding and smiling.</context>
      <utterance>We were worried to death. It's awfully kind of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not used to the big city. Where we come from it's not so easy to get lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You certainly have a nice place here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty looks around admiringly. Sebastian mumbles some- thing that sounds like "Thank you."</context>
      <utterance>Well stocked.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sebastian doesn't like to go out too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I keep a lot of provisions right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like a man who stays put. An admirable thing to be able to sustain yourself in these times. You live here all by yourself, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody nods. A long pause.</context>
      <utterance>Well, no, not really. There's Mr. Deetchum, he's the watchman, he lives on the first floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They glance around the room, waiting for Sebastian to pick up the ball.</context>
      <utterance>We haven't found it easy, Mr. Sebastian.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about breakfast, I was just going to make some.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it wouldn't be too much of a bother... a little bite to eat would be...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no bother, I'd be glad to.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, actually</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian is truly happy.</context>
      <utterance>We're famished.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He disappears into the kitchen. Batty looks happy with the way things are going.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, then. You make yourselves comfortable and I'll bring the food right out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pris comes up close. Her tone muted but demanding.</context>
      <utterance>Charming.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty finds her attitude amusing, which makes her even more pugnacious.</context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a punitive edge to Batty's response.</context>
      <utterance>I want to know what's going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pris is shocked. Her whisper comes out a hiss.</context>
      <utterance>There's only three of us left.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we're stupid and we'll die.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little spotted pig on the table sits up.</context>
      <utterance>Not if everybody is doing their job here at home. How are things at home?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all turn and stare at the pig. Batty is delighted.</context>
      <utterance>Home again, jiggidy jig.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BELL-TONE from the microwave goes off in the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>I don't trust him. I don't think he knows what he's doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows what he's doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he won't cooperate?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Sebastian is a host who wants to be appreciated. We'll appreciate him and he'll cooperate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holden's voice is just a whisper -- the kind of whisper that comes out of the joker at the back of the class.</context>
      <utterance>How are you doing, old man?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm great. I mean, I know I'm not really great, but I feel just great. How you like my new suit?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holden's eyes close, his smile gets bigger and little spasms of laughter pump out of his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you don't have to worry about getting it wrinkled.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make me laugh. It makes me pee.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So how are you doing?</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's okay. I like to pee.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm doing okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From what I hear you're doing great. Bryant tells me you're going like a god damn one-man army. Making a lot of money, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.  But that's what I wanted to talk to you about.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Money?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I got a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holden giggles. Starts to laugh again. A blue light on the panel begins to turn very bright. They both notice it.</context>
      <utterance>I think I'm starting to empathize with these Nexus-sixes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They wait for the light to abate.</context>
      <utterance>I'm taking a piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard doesn't deny it. Holden smiles like a cherub.</context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you something, Deck. You been having intimate relations with one of these units?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I thought... one of the liabilities of the trade -- you has sex with your prey, old buddy. That's bound to create problems, unless you're a black widow. Deckard has to wait for him to stop giggling.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holden bites his bottom lip to keep the laugher out of his voice, but he can't.</context>
      <utterance>What about -- not sex -- but love?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love is just another name for sex. Love is sexy and sex is lovely -- I don't care what you call it, an android can't have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These aren't just...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holden stops talking for a moment to get some air.</context>
      <utterance>I know what they are, Deck -- Look, maybe they can pretend to feel, but far as the raw, hot emotions of the old heart -- no way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holden laughs, Deckard doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>Believe me, take it from an old pro, no matter how good we get, we're never gonna make an artificial anything that can feel. It's a contradiction. You might as well go fuck your washing machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just go out there and keep up the good work. Holden's whispers have become harder to hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard stands.</context>
      <utterance>Got to save it, Deck, I'm getting sleepy. It's been good talking to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he's already asleep. Deckard stands there a moment looking at him, then walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you I'd come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He likes that.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't hear me. You were sleeping.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is. She's spunky. Hasn't seen this place in the daytime. Pleased, he watched her move around the mess. She spots a little framed photograph. Picks it up. It's a man with a shotgun and a boy holding up a quail.</context>
      <utterance>Are you glad I'm here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me and my dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts it down and comes to him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you're not on the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am. Part of my job is to sit on a couch and try and figure things out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pleased as hell, they both sit there staring straight ahead. He looks at her. She looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Not too good. She sits next to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do people do in the afternoon?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they are smart, they take naps.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you dream?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand moves over her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I could.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand goes under the sheet.</context>
      <utterance>Wishing is a kind of dreaming.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She feels good. He moves closer.</context>
      <utterance>I mean asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you cry when your father died?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her lightly on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>That's another thing I can't do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody is freer than when he dreams. I read that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't very good last night, was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I have nothing to compare it to. I guess I thought there was something more to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I think I missed something.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her face is close. She's looking right at him. Her lips are right there.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. Is there a secret?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly their lips touch and his arms slide under her body.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. If there is I'd like to find it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you staring at us?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty nods his head, smiling, sending home the fact and Sebastian is certainly getting it.</context>
      <utterance>You're just all so... so different.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, Sebastian?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pause.</context>
      <utterance>You're androids.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian is smiling from ear to ear.</context>
      <utterance>You're all so perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What generation are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nexus - 6.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian looks like a kid on Christmas Eve.</context>
      <utterance>We can trust Sebastian, ladies. He's been working with mechanisms all his life. He's a wizard and a very perceptive man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice is trembling.</context>
      <utterance>Could you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me something?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like a million things, but he's too excited to think of one.</context>
      <utterance>Like...</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pris perks up proudly.</context>
      <utterance>We're not computers, Sebastian, we're physical.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think, therefore I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a command Pris is pleased to obey. She sits quiet- ly a moment, hands folded in her lap, prim and proper. Mary doesn't like these displays, but Batty is beaming. Those hands in Pris' lap suddenly move, almost faster than the eye can see and slam down on either side of her, digging into the material with such ferocity that Sebastian jumps. She plunges into the guts of the couch up to her elbows and comes up holding springs and stuff- ing. Except for the clenched teeth, she is smiling like an angel. Sebastian is riveted, his eyes wide and astounded, like he's just seen the devil. He laughs nervously, glad that the devil is a friend.</context>
      <utterance>Very good, Pris. Now show him why.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a lot in common.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean that you can't come here and I can't go there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But we don't want to die quite yet.</context>
      <utterance>Not only that, but we have smiliar problems. Accelerated decrepitude.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could help us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know much about biomechanics, Roy. I wish I did, but you're out of my league.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian sneaks a glance. Pris is staring at him with big childlike eyes, Sebastian looks back at Batty, moved but helpless.</context>
      <utterance>If we don't find help soon, Pris hasn't got long to live.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about your friend, the man who owns this building?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty nods.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Tyrell?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not really my friend. I just do a job for him now and then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyrell could help us, Sebastian.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He could?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His company made us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be happy to mention it to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be better if I could talk to him in person. But he's not an easy man to get to.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do you deliver your project?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty leans forward and looks right into Sebastian's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>This afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's no way Sebastian could say no, even if he wanted to.</context>
      <utterance>Will you help us?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pris sits up smiling. Mary sighs a breath of relief and Batty leans back nodding in gratitude.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure glad you found us, Sebastian. What do you think, Mary?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think there is another human being in this whole world who would have helped us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pris gets up and comes to Sebastian and kisses him. That has a lot of impact. Sebastian looks around try- ing to keep the tears from coming.</context>
      <utterance>Pris?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're our best and only friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was the last time you cleaned this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever cleaned your apartment?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be fooled by appearances.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rolls over to admire her legs.</context>
      <utterance>It appears to be dirty -- why don't you get somebody?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses the back of her thigh.</context>
      <utterance>Because they would ruin the arrangement.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They could clean around the arrangement.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her other thigh, gets up and goes into the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like people snooping around my stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachael lies there a moment, then gets up and goes into the front room and opens the closet door. The vacuum is not easy to get to, but finally she wrestles it out. As she starts to plug it in --</context>
      <utterance>There's a vacuum in the front room closet is you wanna give it a try.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's wrapped in a sheet, watching her from the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no, don't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if I don't plug it in how can</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind the plug, just go through the motions.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But then how can you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him like he's nuts.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like the noise. Just practice. Practice makes perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly she makes some half-hearted passes with the thing.</context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. Go ahead. Show me how you would do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bends over to get it. Deckard pulls up a chair and sits down with his chin in his hands. She looks back at him.</context>
      <utterance>How about under the couch there. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This feels stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drops the vacuum and sits on the floor. Deckard gets up and comes towards her. Her eyes travel halfway down his sheet and she leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Good for a smart girl to feel stupid. Part of your education.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sick, Deckard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never felt better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STYLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian would rather put it in the boss's hands, but Styles takes it and is almost through the door when Sebastian stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'll take that now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He almost forgot.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian hands him a little box. Styles stuffs it in his pocket and shuts the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Can't fly without the pilot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Basically an avian invention, it has wings and plumage, the head of an eagle, the body of a lion and weighs no more than eight pounds. It cranes its neck and testing its balance, stands on one leg and then hops to the edge of the table and into the air. The littlest tot claps her hands as the griffon beats its wings rapidly and rises towards the ceiling. Turn- ing in a forty-five degree, it suddenly drops into a dive. Delighted, the children shriek and scream as the griffon swoops over their crouching heads and sails the length of the hall -- its silhouette flickering briefly over the ancestral portraits of the Tyrell clan. Reaching the end of the room, it banks sharply and flies back towards the table, cups its wings, spreads its tail and comes in for an awkward landing. They're laughing and clapping as it waddles down the table and knocks over a glass and stops in front of Ian.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>IAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papa! Did you make this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bends down and kisses his wife.</context>
      <utterance>No. We can make man, but not a griffon.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pleased he excuses himself and heads for the den.</context>
      <utterance>Have to give the cottage industry a chance too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend of yours, Sebastian?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, this is someone who wants to talk to you, Dr. Tyrell.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name is Batty. Roy Batty.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Very slowly Tyrell's hand moves towards the back side of the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's in Batty's eyes completes the warning. Tyrell decides to heed it.</context>
      <utterance>To act without understanding could lead to the very thing the act seeks to avoid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell looks at Sebastian. Considers consequences. Back to Batty.</context>
      <utterance>A little talk it all I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty thinks it over.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to talk in private then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It might be better if we talk in private, Sebastian. Why don't you go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's your check, my boy. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slips out closing the door behind him. Opens it again and sticks his head it.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Dr. Tyrell. I'll see you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was everything okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If Tyrell is scared he's doing a good job of concealing it.</context>
      <utterance>Just beautiful. He's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm surprised you didn't come to me sooner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not an easy thing to meet your maker.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what can he do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can the maker repair what he makes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to be modified?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had in mind something a little more radical.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty cuts in with a whisper.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid that's a little out of my...</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want more life, fucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty walks forward.</context>
      <utterance>Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty does.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The facts of life. I'll be blunt. To make an alteration in the evolvement of an organic life system, at least by men, makers or not, it fatal. A coding sequence can't be revised once it's established.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because by the second day of incubation any cells that have undergone reversion mutation give rise to revertant colonies -- like rats leaving a sinking ship. The ship sinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about E.M.S. recombination?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty nods grimly.</context>
      <utterance>We've already tried it -- ethyl methane sulfonate is an alkylating agent and a potent mutagen -- it creates a virus so lethal the subject was destroyed before we left the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then a repressor protein that blocks the operating cells.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't obstruct replication, but it does give rise to an error in replication, so that the newly formed DNA strand carries a mutation and you're got a virus again... but all this is academic -- you are made as good as we could make you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not to last.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty smiles bitterly.</context>
      <utterance>Put it this way. Rolls Royces are made to last -- as least they were. But I'm afraid you're a Ferrari. A high strung racing car -- built to win, not to last.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also you're too valuable to experiment with.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell can't help a flash of pride.</context>
      <utterance>I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shoulders hunched, Batty looks down, an uncharacteristic note of guilt in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>The bast of all possible androids. We're proud of our prodigal son -- glad you're returned. You're quite a prize.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've done some questionable things.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also extraordinary things.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share a laugh. In spite of himself, there's a look of relief in Tyrell's face as Batty extends his hand. Tyrell takes it and they shake. The reverence in Bat- ty's eyes caused Tyrell a fatherly smile. The smile turns into a growl as he feels the bones in his hands crack. Before the scream comes out of his mouth, Batty stifles it. Tyrell claws at the iron fingers, but they're sinking into his face. Placing his other hand behind Tyrell's head, Batty squeezes them together and squashes the man's head like a melon. The mess is not small. Palms up, like a surgeon, Batty walks to the drapes and wipes off the gore and without looking back, strolls out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing the God of biomechanics wouldn't let you in heaven for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She looks up stunned by the beauty of a photo, but with no need to comment. It's in her eyes. She stares at him, a revelation taking shape.</context>
      <utterance>She'd never seen the great outdoors. Never even seen books on the subject. She went through everything I had, and we talked. And there were subjects we didn't discuss and they were words we didn't say, I couldn't say, like death, like future, like real. But it was hard because she was curious and full of questions. She was more alive than anyone I'd ever known.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He considers it and she stares at him, smiling at the wonder of it.</context>
      <utterance>You and I are good friends, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Convinced and not convinced, he nods his head. She laughs at his solemnity. She's irresistible. Deckard's pretty irresistible himself.</context>
      <utterance>It's so easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever known anybody a long time?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean a woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a long time?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten years.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CHIME on the PHONE next to the bed GOES OFF. He reaches out and brings it to his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Nope. Nobody could stand me that long.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Bryant. Are you alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Who.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a number. Canapt 1700, tenth floor, Villa Vita District, Olympia South.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, here it is. Eldon Tyrell, his family and half his staff were just massacred. The cat is about to get out of the bag. Pressure is definitely on. The Nexus program is terminated. When you finish there, locate Nexus designated Rachael and retire.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't, we will. It has to be total, Deckard. That's an order from as high as it comes. Got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up the receiver and gets up. She watches him from the bed. The gun goes into his belt. He loads the ankle job and straps it on. She watches every move.</context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you call it retire, why don't you call it murder?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think anything that can suffer deserves to be considered?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andies only simulate suffering -- if they're programmed for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think I simulated what happened between us?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without looking at her, he puts on his jacket. He's standing in the middle of the floor with his back to her. He turns and they're facing one another. Neither of them moves.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't leave here. Don't open the door, don't answer the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What difference will it make?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Just wait here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I think?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>That some of the folks around here are more programmed then me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what else I think?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECAKRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and goes through the door.</context>
      <utterance>This was the best day of my life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go while there is still time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the point?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not to be trapped.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian has almost reached the door.</context>
      <utterance>You underestimate the trap, Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going, Sebastian?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just thought I'd...</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian walks away from the door.</context>
      <utterance>No, you stay here with us. Out last night together. They all watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's too fragile for that logic, but it appeals to Pris. She and Batty hold a look that burns. Sebastian is by the window.</context>
      <utterance>Think of yourself as a light, Mary. Shine before you're turned off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty goes to the window and looks down.</context>
      <utterance>Someone is coming here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One man.  He must be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then go get him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian looks ready to bolt. Batty puts an arm around him.</context>
      <utterance>That wouldn't be very sporting.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, but don't kill him. Save a little for everybody. A masterpiece.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn out the lights, Pris.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard FIRES. Batty's fast. He ducks into a doorway. Pops out again.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna play?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The makeup on Batty's face is somewhere between a Coman- che warrior and a transvestite. The immensity of his insolence awesome -- the muscles of his body are swol- len, trembling from the thrill of it.</context>
      <utterance>Not very sporting to fire on an unarmed opponent. I thought you were supposed to be good. Aren't you the man?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a blue of lightning-like action, Batty whips down the hall, zigzagging off the walls towards Deckard so fast that Deckard gets only three SHOTS off before the blur crashes through the wall on his left with a laugh. Deckard stands there a moment -- digesting the impact of it, then edges up to the gaping wall. Batty is be- hind him. He knees Deckard in the back and slaps him in the head. Deckard goes to his knees, then over on his face. Batty kneels next to him.</context>
      <utterance>This is how we do it up there, lad! Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard's eyes are closed, mouth bleeding. He exhales and makes and effort. He slides his hands up even with his chest and starts to push.</context>
      <utterance>Not hurt, are you? You better get it up or I'm going to have to kill you. Unless you're alive you can't play. And if you don't play, you don't get to be alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like a matador, Batty walks away. By the time Deckard's on his feet, Batty's disappeared through one of the doors. Deckard wipes the blood from his mouth, bends down and picks up his laser, reloads and looks down the hall, towards the jeering voice.</context>
      <utterance>That's the spirit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard gets to the door, BLASTS it, kicks it open and FIRES at Batty. But it's only the reflection of Batty.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Deckard, show me what you got! I'm right here on the other side of the door. But you gotta shoot straight 'cause I'm fast!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're face to face.</context>
      <utterance>Straight doesn't seem to be good enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In an exaggeration of weary disappointment, Batty drops his head to the side.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have a chance, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard stares back at him, but doesn't respond. Sud- denly fury storms through Batty. He throws Deckard out the door, knocking him down, grabs him by the collar and rams his head into the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like I'm gonna have to scale it down for you. Give you a handicap. I won't run through any more walls. Okay? I promise to use the doors. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, let's use that brain!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He yanks him further and bashes his head again.</context>
      <utterance>Think! We need a little resilience around here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard hangs in Batty's hand like a bag of laundry.</context>
      <utterance>Where are those balls of yours?! Let's see a little bravery! The storm passes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops him.</context>
      <utterance>That was irrational of me -- not to mention unsportsmanlike. Won't happen again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty walks off and disappears through one of the doors. Deckard gets to his knees, leans against the wall a mo- ment, then punches it with his fist. On his feet he's a little wobbly. Holding his breath so he can hear above his own breathing, he listens. No sound. No sign of Batty. The laser is laying nearby. He doesn't bother. Deckard is backing down the hall, quiet as he can. He had a job to do. He would like to have done it, but he's not insane. He gets to the landing and turns. On the first step down, he stops. Batty's on the land- ing below, looking up at him.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be down the hall when you're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wait a moment for Deckard's answer.</context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard turns back into the hall. Batty smiles. Deckard's running down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>No cheating. A promise is a promise. I'll honor the handicapped, but we gotta play on the top floor. You go get your laser gun now. And I'll give you a few seconds before I come.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Halfway down the hall he finds his laser.</context>
      <utterance>One!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard darts into the nearest door. The apartment above Sebastian's, with the hole in the floor. Deckard considers it.</context>
      <utterance>Two!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard dashes back into the hall, chooses another door and goes in.</context>
      <utterance>No fair jumping through holes. You might get hurt doing that! THREE!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BATTY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the next door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I wonder where he is. Not in here, I don't think. Eight!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe here. Doesn't sound like it. Nine! Batty moves to the next. The door to Deckard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door explodes! A shape hurtles across the room. Deckard pivots, fol- lowing it with RAPID FIRE. It's a TV. He spins back. but Batty's already on him. He gets one SHOT off be- fore Batty's got his hand. There's a hole over Batty's right eye. Blood running down his face, dripping on Deckard. The right side of his face isn't working too good. The corner of his mouth doesn't quite shut -- his voice comes out slurred, a little hollow.</context>
      <utterance>Ten!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The would doesn't minimize his omnipotence, just makes it more malignant. He throws Deckard against the far wall. Deckard FIRES. Hits Batty in the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>One point for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes at Deckard, jerking back and forth, a cobra in fast motion, faking, weaving, yelping with excitement as Deckard tries to get a shot, FIRING AWAY until his laser's empty. Bloody and crazed, Batty pushes up against him.</context>
      <utterance>Ho ho! Try it again!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm what we've made!</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong? Don't you like me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard's pedaling backwards over the floor.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong? Aren't you a lover of Faster, Bigger and Better?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard throws the laser at him. It misses. Batty throws his head back and laughs. A one-eyed colossus about to eat the world. Suddenly he stops. His eye moves over the wall.</context>
      <utterance>It's time to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out and pinches something. His lips compress as he yanks it out of the wall. It's a ten-penny nail. He holds it out to Deckard and drops it. Deckard catches it.</context>
      <utterance>Ah!</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One side of Batty's face smiles savagely.</context>
      <utterance>That's for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard stares at the nail in his hand, then up at his executioner.</context>
      <utterance>Stick it in your ear and push. If that doesn't work, try the eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Batty watches him, hoping the stimulus might inspire his victim to more action. It doesn't look like it.</context>
      <utterance>Believe me, it'll be better for you than what I'm about to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deckard springs to his feet and bolts. But instead of going for the stairwell he turns in the first available door.</context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Rachael's face in the window watching the woods stream by.</context>
      <utterance>She wanted to go to a place I knew. Out of the city. Like one of those pictures she saw. Where there were trees but no buildings.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a good time. She told me a funny story and I taught her a song. A song about monkeys and elephants. And it made us laugh so hard we couldn't sing.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
