<movie id="84" title="Blade Trinity">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MALE FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman removes her helmet. This is DANICA TALOS. A vampire. Intense, appearing to be in her 30s. Possessing a regal air. She wears a silver crucifix around her neck.</context>
      <utterance>That's great. We've got dick.  Is there any reason we had to embark on this cluster-fuck during the day?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One by one, the others remove their helmets. All vampires: GRIMWOOD (30s), a hulking vampire with an imposing physique and an even more imposing set of surgical steel teeth/fangs. ASHER (4Os), a natural-born leader with easygoing charisma. WOLFE (30s), quiet and deliberative. Right now he's readying a portable ground-penetrating radar unit. Grimwood studies the writing on the walls.</context>
      <utterance>Night-time's too tricky, Grimwood. You know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIMWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this chicken-scratch?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cuneiform. Dates back about four thousand years.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIMWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because this was the cradle of civilization. He would've been comfortable here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Dan. Seems like another dead-end.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOLFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wolfe looks at his unit, excited. The others gather round.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not so sure --</utterance>
   <speaker>WOLFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something beneath us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRIMWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grimwood pounds his fist against the stone. It's solid. He tries to find a hand-hold, tries to shoulder it open in some way, but the barrier is unmovable. They're trapped.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck --?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Radio back-up. See if they can open it from the other --</utterance>
   <speaker>WOLFE</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>Wolfe points at the ground. A tiny depression has formed, with sand funneling into it. Wolfe sets his radar unit down and kneels before the hole. The grains of sand are falling faster now, the depression gradually widening. Curious, Wolfe leans closer --</context>
      <utterance>Guys?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he been doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Just sitting there since we brought him here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDRIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think we've got enough security?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others look at her like she's insane. Nevertheless, Danica places her hand on the biometric scanner. Hendrix keys in a series of commands on a nearby computer console. The vault doors open with a HUM, allowing Danica into --</context>
      <utterance>Hendrix, if he wanted to out of there - there isn't an army in the world that could keep us safe. We didn't capture him. He allowed us to take him in. You understand?  Now open up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why have you woken me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kneels, bowing her head.</context>
      <utterance>Your people need you, Sire.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hand emerges from the darkness, armored. Danica wants to bolt. Instead, she fights to keep herself from flinching as a taloned finger brushes her throat.</context>
      <utterance>What makes you think I wanted to be brought back?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Times have changed. Science has made great strides. Your blood, the sacrament you provide -- it can set us free now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. And the one I killed earlier? He was vampire?  You must forgive me. It had been centuries since I last fed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then offer yourself to me, child --  -- and let me quench my thirst again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ASKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, shaking, struggling to recompose herself.</context>
      <utterance>Danica! Are you alright --?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him out -- he wants to see what's become of his world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>A VIDEO MONITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>LARRY KING launching into the intro of his show.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight, Dr. Edgar Vance, forensic psychiatrist and author of the New York Times best seller "Human Health: The Whole Being Breakthrough". Also with us is Martin Vreede, Chief of Police. They're here for an hour and they'll take your calls. Next on Larry King Live.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Vance -- you're a psychiatrist and a biochemist, isn't that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I've long believed that in order to achieve true health, we have to reconcile the body and the mind. Of course that also requires letting go of a lot of our old notions and superstitions, which is what my work is all about.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vance leans forward, skillfully playing to the cameras.</context>
      <utterance>Let's talk about that. How do you account for the fascination with things that go bump in the night? Movies, books, videogames -- seems like we can't get enough of our boogeymen?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monsters provide a means for us to transfer our more primal and darker urges into something external. In the case of vampires, you're dealing with taboo issues like predatory rage and sexual sadism. These are scary subjects for people to own up to.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we pass the buck to someone else?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Historically, people suffering from medical conditions have always been our psychological scapegoats. In the Middle Ages schizophrenia was often attributed to demonic possession.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And vampires?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's a hereditary blood disease known as porphyria that has symptoms remarkably similar to the classic vampiric traits. People suffering from this disease are anemic, they become sensitive to sunlight, they can't tolerate garlic --</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is too bad, since my doctor tells me that's good for the heart.  Chief Vreede? What's your take on all the recent rumors we've been hearing about vampires?</utterance>
   <speaker>VREEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only vampires I'm worried about are the ones passing the bar exam.  Seriously, if vampires existed, don't you think we'd be on to them by now? The truth is, our streets have never been safer. Homicides, assaults -- violent crime is down across the board. If people want to be concerned, they should focus on criminals like Blade.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now who's this? Tell me about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VREEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a sociopath we've been pursuing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of GUNFIRE pre-laps over from the next scene as we --</context>
      <utterance>Blade is a very disturbed individual. Even the name he's chosen for himself is troubling. According to witnesses, he operates under the belief that a vast conspiracy of vampires live amongst us. You have to look at the psychiatric underpinnings here. What does a person like Blade really want? Odds are, he's really trying to work out some kind of inner trauma. He thinks he's slaying monsters, but he's really trying to murder aspects of himself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whistler! I'm on the Stonebridge overpass at Clemons --</utterance>
   <speaker>WHISTLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade dodges past a HONKING car, stepping onto and over the trunk, then leaps atop the safety rail of the overpass as --</context>
      <utterance>Got it! Heading eastbound, I'm just beneath you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gedge coughs blood, struggles to speak:</context>
      <utterance>Staked you with silver. Why aren't you ash?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gedge tugs at his fangs. They're fake, PROSTHETIC. Gedge is looking past Blade. Blade turns, looking up --</context>
      <utterance>Why aren't you smarter? Not a vampire, dumbshit -- set your sorry ass up --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whistler reaches for a bottle of whiskey, takes a sip.</context>
      <utterance>How should I know? He was human.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHISTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been getting careless, Blade. You kill a vampire, they ash, don't leave any proof of their existence. But something like this, a human corpse, it's messy --  -- you better hope nobody IDed you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HALE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>WILSON HALE (20s), Ray's subordinate, rushes in, excited. Ray stands, ripping down a photo of Blade and Whistler.</context>
      <utterance>Ray! Heard we've got a lead!</utterance>
   <speaker>CUMBERLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Book us a flight, Hale. Time to take these cowboys down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FBI AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHIP-PAN to a parked CAR, Cumberland and Hale seated within.</context>
      <utterance>Subject is heading West.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUMBERLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cumberland starts the car, starts following Whistler.</context>
      <utterance>Got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHISTLER</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations. You're famous. Just what we needed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WHISTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody screwed us. Your face is all over the papers, the television. Media's eating it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I care?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHISTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should. Something like this --  -- taking out a human, even one working for the vampires -- far as the rest of the world's concerned, you're public enemy number one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whistler shakes his head, frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't realize this was a popularity contest.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHISTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damnit, Blade, don't you see what's happening?! The fuckers are finally getting smart. They're waging a goddamn PR campaign. Now it's not just vampires we have to worry about, we're gonna have to take on the rest of the world too.  They've got us on the run. These last few months we've barely been staying ahead of the curve.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You worry too much, old man.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHISTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been doing this since before you were born, Blade. The moment you stop worrying, you're dead. Then Whistler's face softens for a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHISTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since the day I found you, you've been like a son to me. I taught you everything I know.  But I'm tired. You understand?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No fatties. They taste like Cheetos.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about that shrunken apple-head beeyatch-a-saurus over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We hear LAUGHTER and we WHIP-PAN over to a grimy office building, ZIPPING UP the face of it to --</context>
      <utterance>Fucking blow me, man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, just pick one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They keep looking. Then, Flick suddenly points, excited --</context>
      <utterance>Once you buy a prize, it's yours and yours to keep.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it, got it! Baby on board!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BACK TO THE SKATE-PUNKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dingo nods and smiles approvingly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like we got ourselves a combo meal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, pretty lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dingo and Proof reveal their fangs. Abigail SCREAMS, runs -- -- right into the arms of Flick and Squid! They grab her, RIPPING the BabyBjorn carrier from her chest, SHOVING her back at Dingo and Proof. In seconds, Dingo and Proof have Abigail on the floor. They're tearing away at her clothing, LAUGHING.</context>
      <utterance>Sophisticated mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>DINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scream if this hurts, chica!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WHISTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>standing in the shadows, clutching a handgun.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHISTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They listen. Just the sound of the ocean swell. Then --</context>
      <utterance>What you've been worrying about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CUMBERLAN D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're fragging their hard drives!</context>
      <utterance>Some kind of self-destruct program!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move a finger and you're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHISTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whistler lets his other hand uncurl. He's got a REMOTE in his palm, with a tiny digital timer counting-down.</context>
      <utterance>How 'bout this one?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got something in his-- 00:03. 00:02. 00:01. The timer reaches zero.</utterance>
   <speaker>A SERIES OF EXPLOSIONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>rock the workshop, knocking the agents back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CUMBERLAND</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PULL BACK. We are in a room with a one-way mirrored window. Blade sits, hands cuffed behind him, BRIGHT LIGHTS shining down on him. He looks disoriented, battered. Very weak. Cumberland and Hale are sitting across from Blade.</context>
      <utterance>Rise and shine, sleepyhead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who --?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUMBERLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Special Agents Ray Cumberland and Wilson Hale, FBI. We've been tracking you for a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whistler --</utterance>
   <speaker>HALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade shuts his eyes -- as if he could just wish them away.</context>
      <utterance>Dead. Just like all of your victims.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUMBERLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many people have you killed? Thirty? Forty? A hundred?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those were familiars -- people who worked for them --</utterance>
   <speaker>CUMBERLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And by "them" you mean vampires, right? I suppose next you'll be telling us that Bigfoot's in on the conspiracy too? So what kills these bloodsu~kers, tough guy? Maybe you can give us some pointers.  You can stake 'em, right? Then there's sunlight -- what about crosses, Wilson? Do those still work?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Ray. What if a vampire's Jewish?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUMBERLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hale laughs. Cumberland shakes his head, his smile fading.</context>
      <utterance>That's a good point. And does garlic work on a Hindu vampire? Or do you need saffron or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUMBERLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can keep doing your song and dance as long as you want, Blade, but it's not going to play. You're a stone-cold killer. And you're sick as fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's leave the diagnosis to the professionals.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cumberland nods. They rise, exiting the room. Vance smiles, trying to project a sympathetic air.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Blade. My name is Doctor Vance. I'm with the Department of Mental Health. I've been charged with conducting a psychiatric evaluation of you.  Gentleman, would you mind giving us a few moments alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade just stares daggers at Vance.</context>
      <utterance>I imagine this must be very frightening for you. But I want you to know that I'm here to help. In order to do that, however, I need to ask you some questions.  Now. Can you tell me what day it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the President? Do you know who's in the White House at the moment?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An ass-hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright then, let's talk about vampires -- what can you tell me about that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing to tell. They exist.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And are you one of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade just glares at Vance.</context>
      <utterance>What about blood? When you drink it, do you find yourself sexually aroused?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade glares. If he escapes, he's going to kill this guy.</context>
      <utterance>You see, it strikes me that this business of vampirism has strong connotations of sexual confusion. Bodily fluids being exchanged, that sort of thing. You have to ask where that comes from. I'm wondering, for instance, what your relationship was like with your mother. Were the two of you close?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VREEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your assessment, Doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's psychotic, with paranoid features, possessing dangerous levels of sociopathy. He's exhibiting disorganized behavior. He obviously doesn't have a properly formed conscience --  For his safety and the public's, I'm recommending that he be transferred to County Psychiatric for further treatment.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUMBERLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's unacceptable. This man's wanted in connection with a laundry list of federal crimes. I need him on a plane to the Detention Center in Washington tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cumberland and Hale look to Vreede with disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Agent Cumberland, that man is in no condition to undergo prosecution.</utterance>
   <speaker>HALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief, we've got a federal arrest warrant here that clearly supersedes --</utterance>
   <speaker>VREEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care about your warrant. We're in my jurisdiction now. You've got an issue with that, you take it up with the local magistrate. Dr. Vance shrugs as if to say he's sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, gentlemen, but the call has already been made. A team from the hospital should be here momentarily to oversee the transfer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little something to keep you compliant. The normal dose is two, maybe three hundred milligrams. But for a strapping young hybrid like yourself -- Vance pokes the needle of the syringe into the ampule.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vance reaches for Blade's arm. Blade struggles, tries to pull back, but Vance manages to inject him nonetheless.</context>
      <utterance>-- I think we'll kick it up to a couple thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There. That wasn't so bad, was it?  You're weak, aren't you? In need of your serum. Who would've guessed a mere human like myself could overpower you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're with them -- a familiar --</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vance extends his arm, pulling back his shirt cuff a little to reveal a VAMPIRE GLYPH tattooed on the underside of his wrist. Then he pulls his cuff back down, smiles at Blade.</context>
      <utterance>Going on five years now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the end-game, Blade. All their plans are finally coming to fruition. So just sit back and enjoy the show. Blade looks to the one-way mirror, SCREAMS.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vance looks to the one-way mirror as well and shrugs as if to say -- "The man's deranged. What can I do?"</context>
      <utterance>He's one of them! Damnit, he's working for them!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She draws closer, enjoying herself.</context>
      <utterance>Easy, lover. You're not going anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade tries to LUNGE from his chair at her and -- WHACK! Grimwood punches Blade across the jaw. A brutal blow.</context>
      <utterance>We moved the humans around like, pawns, Blade. Used them to flush you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIMWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danica motions to the two vampire orderlies. They step forward with the straight-jacket, start to put it on Blade. Blade THRASHES madly. Asher LAUGHS, enjoying this.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Captain Sunshine. Soon as we get you out of here, you'll get a chance to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BA-BOOM! The one-way mirror SHATTERS, exploding outward in a shower of SLOW-MOTION GLASS FRAGMENTS, carrying with it -- -- a BODY, one of the vampire mental health flunkies -- ASHING in mid-air as he sails into the room! Seconds later --</context>
      <utterance>Don't make this any harder than it has to be. You're all alone, Blade. No one can help you now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danica spins, enraged, recognizing King instantly --</context>
      <utterance>Why'd the Polish vampire starve to death?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He kept biting his own lip.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights go out. Immediately, backup lights come on, followed by FIRE ALARMS. In the ensuing confusion ~ both pistols at Asher, who drops, allowing one of the vampire orderlies behind him to take the hit.</context>
      <utterance>King!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CUMBERLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King FIRES into the room behind him, then pulls a GRENADE secured to a bandolier and tosses it through the doorway -- An EXPLOSION rocks the interrogation room, filling the corridor with smoke, knocking Cumberland and Hale back. King turns his attention to Blade's handcuffs, FIRING between them, freeing Blade's hands. Blade collapses against the wall. He's shaking, close to passing out.</context>
      <utterance>He's getting away!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King drags Blade up. They continue down the corridor to --</context>
      <utterance>Don't die on me, you undead motherfucker!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whistler? Abigail spins, dispatching the last officer with a kick to the mid-section while tossing a PNEUMATIC INJECTOR at King. He snatches it, places it in Blade's hands. Blade injects himself in the neck. Moments later, he's reenergized. He looks to King, clear-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Whistler! We need that serum NOW!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade responds by PUNCHING King across the jaw.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Blacula, you ready to shake and bake?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King massages his jaw, tossing Blade a pistol even as -- -- Grimwood rounds the corner, hungry for blood, TWO MORE VAMPIRE ORDERLIES behind him. Blade FIRES round after round of EXPLOSIVE BULLETS, causing Grimwood and the others to fall back. Blade and King move, joining Abigail. MORE SMOKE, darkness, only the emergency lights to illuminate the station.</context>
      <utterance>Call me that again and I'll give you fucking brain damage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're pinned down!  Can't you do something?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't shoot around corners!</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As King and Blade lay down COVER FIRE, Abigail reaches behind her, withdrawing a device that's been secured there. She gives it a SNAP and it springs open, taking the shape of a --</context>
      <utterance>I can.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My sword. They still have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Blade is already heading back the way they came and --</context>
      <utterance>Are you insane?! We're practically home free! We can't go hunting for your fucking butter-knife now!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Abigail grabs King's shoulder, pulling him to the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! HEY!!! COME BACK HERE!!! This is supposed to be a rescue!</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, King. Let's move.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we can go.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The police close in around them, pinning the trio down with FIREPOWER. Yet King and Abigail seem unconcerned because --</context>
      <utterance>Is he epic or what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have him. We'll be there soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you people?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abigail just stares back at Blade, silently appraising him.</context>
      <utterance>My name's Hannibal King. I'm a hunter, like you.  And this little hellion is Abigail Whistler.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King reaches into an inner pocket, pulls out a pack of gum. He selects a stick, offers one to Blade.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, Blade. You're not hearing things. She's Whistler's daughter. You see, Abby, Dex, myself -- we're all part of Whistler's "contingency plan".</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juicyfruit?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought the vampires murdered Whistler's family.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As King and Abigail lead Blade towards a stairway, Blade catches sight of --</context>
      <utterance>They did. I'm the product of an earlier fling of my Dad's, born out of wedlock. After the murders happened, he kept me hidden. He wanted me safe. Away from all of this --  -- but I guess hunting just runs in our blood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the honeycomb hideout.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you bankroll this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Internet porn. See, we're using cock suckers to pay for the blood-suckers.  Joke. Come on, man. This isn't some piddly little hoopty-ass operation, Blade. We take our jobs very seriously.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King gestures to them in turn. They're all refugees in one way or another, sharing a common guardedness, their lives having been shattered by the vampires.</context>
      <utterance>You met Dex. This is Hedges, Sommerfield--</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The runt you saw earlier is Sommerfield's daughter, Zoe. We call ourselves the Nightstalkers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sound like rejects from a Saturday morning cartoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abigail rids herself of her weapons -- bow, arrows, silver stakes and knives. She hands her compound bow to Hedges.</context>
      <utterance>We were gonna call ourselves the Super Friends, but that was taken.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tiller needs adjustment.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEDGES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade examines some of the equipment being developed.</context>
      <utterance>I'll run it through the bow press.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many of you are there total?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough. We operate in sleeper cells. When one goes down, a new cell activates to pick up the slack. Consider us your reinforcements.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Never been much of a team player.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures to the computer equipment around her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think you understand, Blade. Whistler meant for us to help you. When he died, he activated an emergency protocol. All his knowledge --</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--was transferred to our servers here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King reaches for his collar, pulling it down to reveal a telltale mass of scar tissue in the shape of a BITE MARK.</context>
      <utterance>And what makes you think you know so much about killing vampires?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well for starters, I used to be one.  Do I pass the audition?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asher raises his hands as if to say "no harm, no foul". Danica continues her tantrum, SMASHING a statue apart, SHATTERING a heavy glass tabletop. Finally, she gives it a rest, collapsing into a chair, shoulders sagging.</context>
      <utterance>I should've ripped his ripped his bleeding heart out when I had the chance!  And don't you dare tell me "I told you so"!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You through remodeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Face it, Dan. We got caught with our pants down. We underestimated the Nightstalkers.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIMWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grimwood GRUNTS in pain as the arrow is removed. Asher broaches a more serious subject.</context>
      <utterance>Pants down?! They practically fucking ass-raped us!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has he been told yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A MAN (30s) enters the room. The same being we glimpsed in the vault. He has a haunting gaze and a commanding presence. We will learn who he is momentarily. But for now, it's enough to know that everyone in the room pays him deference.</context>
      <utterance>About your failure?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places a hand on Danica's shoulder. She tenses.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I've been told.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps it's time I entered the fray.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>features Asher and Danica and Grimwood. It's been slowed to a near standstill and now advances frame by frame.</context>
      <utterance>You know the kind of woman that just screams trouble? You see her and every warning bell in your brain starts going off but you still ask for her number? Well that's all I ever hook up with. But this betty blew 'em all away in the shitstorm sweepstakes. King reaches out to a keyboard, calling up a piece of surveillance footage on a nearby monitor. The footage</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King types a command. The image ZOOMS IN, tracking Grimwood.</context>
      <utterance>Her name's Danica Talos. You met her earlier. The man on her left is Asher, her brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King freezes the footage on Danica's grainy, pixelated face.</context>
      <utterance>The neanderthal behind them is Jarko Grimwood.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I picked Danica up in a bar, had a one night stand with her -- then spent the next five years playing step-and-fetch-it as her little vampire cabana boy.  Eventually Abigail found me. Sommerfield here managed to treat me with a cure. Now I kill them.  That's called turning a frown upside down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to pool our resources, Blade.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King tosses a TOMB OF DRACULA comic book over to Blade. Blade glances at the cover, then looks at them, incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>Because He's come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta be kidding me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's real, Blade. Dig beneath all the movies and myths. All the layers of bullshit that've cluttered our culture for the last five hundred years and eventually you'll strike the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the movies are true?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The movies are just a comforting fairytale compared to the real deal. There's no happy ending with this guy. Peter Cushing isn't going to run in at the last second and save the day with a cross and some holy water.  See, good old Brain Stoker, he wrote a nice yarn. But the events he described in 1897 were only a tiny piece of the mosaic. The rea1 Dracula's origin goes back much earlier than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How early?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Blade's astonished look we --</context>
      <utterance>Try six or seven thousand years.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>FLASH! 17th century France, the time of Louis the XIV. The pace becomes breathless.</context>
      <utterance>-- moving behind the scenes --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>FLASH! 18th century Russia, the time of Peter the Great. The soundtrack is THUNDEROUS. Drake has become a bloody blur of bestial rage and unfettered horror and --</context>
      <utterance>-- cutting a bloody path through the Ages until suddenly --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- just like that --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goth Guy looks up, wiping his mouth with a napkin. Doesn't want to engage with Drake at all.</context>
      <utterance>In the window -- you sell vampire merchandise?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOTH GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and the Goth Vixen have a snicker at Drake's expense. Then she tries to be a little more helpful.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, yeah -- look around, we might have a few things.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOTH VIXEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Drake looks around, what he sees matches his ascending rage. Costumes, candles, vampire Christmas ornaments. Posters from different films -- Nosferatu, Lugosi, Lee -- then Love at First Bite and The Little Vampire.</context>
      <utterance>We've got Dracula lunchboxes. Did you see those? And there're bobbleheads, Pez dispensers. We've got just about anything --  -- even vampire vibrators.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOTH VIXEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches into a case, pulling out a soft-drink. The label reads: "DRA-COLA" and has a stylized vampire on it.</context>
      <utterance>Here, check this out --</utterance>
   <speaker>GOTH VIXEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake just stares at the can. His mind seems to have retreated elsewhere. Back through the ages.</context>
      <utterance>"Dracola". Makes you want to cry, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOTH VIXEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake doesn't respond. A kind of melancholy has settled over him. He's an outsider now. The world has moved on.</context>
      <utterance>Was there something special you needed?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOTH-GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake looks up as Goth Guy pours a bowl of Count Chocula.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, guy, she's talking to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wake up Drake now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we've been trying to figure out.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was under the fang there used to be talk about some kind of vampire 'Final Solution'. But I could never figure out why they'd want to destroy their food source. I mean, seems stupid, right? They've always had plans for the human race. Seems likely that whatever they're cooking up, Drake's return is a part of it. Blade nods, pensive.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's face it, Blade -- we're fighting a losing battle. So we kill a few hundred of them a year. Big deal. There are thousands of them out there. Maybe tens of th'usands. We need a new tactic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sommerfield moves to her Braille keyboard, types.</context>
      <utterance>A biological weapon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think about it, Blade. We could wipe them all out in a single move.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's been holding you back?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've tried it on a number of captive subjects. We've got the disease vector worked out fine -- it's easily transmittable. But the lethality in vampires is still spotty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bottom line is, we need a better DNA sample to work with.  We need Dracula's blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vampire DNA is a hodge-podge of different genes, mixed in with all sorts of useless junk DNA. Because Dracula's the progenitor of the vampire race, his DNA is still pure. It hasn't been diluted by a hundred generations of selective mutation. It still has all the necessary cellular compounds for the virus to code to. We get his blood, we can boost Daystar's viral efficacy to a hundred percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. You want to join our club? Can we sign you up for a Nightstalkers secret decoder ring?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This world sickens me. The humans have soiled it with their filth.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake just stares at her, not convinced.</context>
      <utterance>We can raze their cities to the ground. We can bring the old world back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come closer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do you know why?  Once, all of my kind could brave the day. We were true predators. The world was ours. And then, somewhere along the way, the purity of our bloodline became diluted. Polluted with human DNA.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible --</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake stands, drawing close to Danica. He grips her wrist --</context>
      <utterance>Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and pulls her hand towards one of the sunlight shafts. To her credit, Danica keeps staring at Drake. She'll be damned if she will give him the satisfaction of seeing her break. Drake pulls her hand closer to the light -- to the very edge. And the tips of Danica's fingers begin to burn. She winces, clearly in agony -- -- and Drake releases her hand. She cradles it against her chest, blinking away tears that have welled up in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You are bastard children. No longer as pure as you pride yourselves on being.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake reaches out, brushes a tear from Danica's cheek, then turns and walks away -- through the alternating shafts of sunlight and darkness.</context>
      <utterance>My people. How far you have fallen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HEDGES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King tosses Blade a bullet. He studies it -- it's more complex than a standard round.</context>
      <utterance>We've got a wide assortment of ass- kickery for your viewing pleasure --  Electronic pistol. Comes with a built-in fingerprint security system. Fires a three-shot burst in 1/500th of a second. Bullets can also be triggered remotely.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Explosive rounds?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hedges tosses King one of the four-barreled firearms. On the stock is an irreverent decal of the mud-flap girl silhouette.</context>
      <utterance>But with a concentrated burst of UV light instead of your standard hollow-points. I call 'em sun dogs.  Hedges -- super-size me, baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Next, Hedges shows Blade the CRESCENT-SHAPED DEVICE that Abigail used. He gives the device a twist and --</context>
      <utterance>This little mamacita -- a modified version of the Army's Objective Individual Combat Weapon. Pick your poison -- stakes, sun dogs, heat-seeking mini-rockets. Whatever gets you hard, this puppy will pump out.  Of course it doesn't have the range of a sword but --</utterance>
   <speaker>HEDGES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHINKT! The device extends from either end, telescoping outward. Connecting the tips is a concentrated UV LASER.</context>
      <utterance>We call this the UV arc --</utterance>
   <speaker>HEDGES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hold the arc in the center, curved away from you. Connecting the tips is a powerful UV laser beam. Because of its high focus, the laser cuts through vampire flesh like a knife through butter.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're still trying to sort out fact from fiction when it comes to Dracula. Turning into mist? Kinda doubt it. But general shape-shifting? Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEDGES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not into a bat or a wolf or anything like that. But another human, someone with the same approximate body mass -- given enough practice it might be possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEDGES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wouldn't have a traditional skeletal structure. Probably something more like a snake, with thousands of tiny bones in the place of a normal array. Commensurate with this would be an exquisite control of electrical potential across his tissues, resulting in an ability to effectively change shape at will --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Question. Have you ever been laid, Hedges?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want another spin, ass-hole? Eventually, your head's gonna pop off.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! Oh Jesus, please, please --</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's your handler?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- but a CELL PHONE in Hoop's jacket RINGS. Blade fishes it out. The screen reads: EDGAR VANCE, 555-5631.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know his name, I swear I -- Blade prepares to drop Hoop again --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Blade -- why didn't the vampire bite Mick Jagger?  Cause you can't get blood from a Stone. As Blade walks off --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, they can't all be gems!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Past the RECEPTION DESK are the elevators with more monitors showing the video greeting. As Blade, King, and Abigail approach, TWO SECURITY GUARDS move to intercept them.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Dr. Vance. Welcome to our facility. As a member of the medical profession I want to assure you that I will do everything in my power ro provide you with the care and compassion that you deserve.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRACK! Blade effortlessly tosses the guards aside, sending them CRASHING into the nearest monitors.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, can I help y--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abigail KICKS out the man's knee, then slices her hand into his windpipe, silencing him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry but you can't --</utterance>
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade aims his shotgun at the door leading to Vance's office. He FIRES at the keycard lock, KICKS down the door --</context>
      <utterance>Now, I'd like to take a moment to exolain how a series of remarkable new breakthroughs can immeasurably improve the quality of your life</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What --?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Blade aims his shotgun at Vance's head. Vance just smiles, seemingly unconcerned as -- -- Abigail circles around the other side, getting a view behind Vance's desk where --</context>
      <utterance>Payback, Vance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you kill Vance?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'd outlived his purpose. He'd become a liabi1ity. Drake nods at Blade's sword --</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your sword -- I've seen that hilt before. Eight or nine centuries ago. The hunter who carried it was an accomplished fighter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was honorable, in his own way. He died a good death.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't know about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade pauses, looking for some kind of opening.</context>
      <utterance>You lie. You're part of a grand tradition, Blade. You hunters have plagued my people since the day we first walked the earth. And I have vanquished them. One by one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you exist in the daylight?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always been able to. Haven't you read Mr. Stoker's fable? I was the first of the vampires. I am unique.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why they brought you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake glances down at the street people. Throngs of PEOPLE are massing there, pointing up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. My children seek to isolate the properties in my blood that make me immune to sunlight. Through me, they believe they can all become Daywalkers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world's changed much since I went to sleep. How crowded it's become. Look at them down there. Lives brief as fireflies. Do you think they can ever grasp what it means to be immortal like us?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake smiles, intrigued by an obviously worthy opponent.</context>
      <utterance>You're not immortal. I must've heard a hundred of you people make the same claim. And every one of them's seen the end of my sword.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake tosses the infant at Blade. Blade twists around to catch it, scooping it safely up. But when he looks back -- -- Drake is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps I will as well, then. But I think it's more likely that you will fall before mine.  Catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abigail ignores King, cuts open his shirt. She removes a small aerosol cannister from her belt.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, it hurts. I wanna be a vampire again -- fuck! Did you see that guy?! We're gonna lose, man. We're gonna fucking lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Together they spread the wound apart. King is really hurting, breathing hard as he tries to fight back the pain.</context>
      <utterance>Fibrin sealant foam, it's an elastic protein. Help me spread the wound open. The foam should seal the hemorrhaging in his body cavity from within --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey -- what'd the one lesbian vampire say to the other?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, King.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King's voice trails off as he passes out. Abigail triggers the dispenser, spraying a jet of compressed foam into it. The foam condenses, sealing the wound up.</context>
      <utterance>-- see you in twenty-eight days --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HEDGES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So basically we're in an arms race. They're using Drake's DNA to build themselves a better vampire --</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and we need his blood to kill them.  How's this weapon of yours coming along?</utterance>
   <speaker>SODDERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures to a series of ampule-like prototypes. (We'll see the completed version of this device later on.)</context>
      <utterance>We're almost there --</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The virus is harmless to humans. So we decided to go after the vampires' food source. The one thing we know for sure about vampires is that they have to drink blood. If we manage to pull this off, we'll be able to contaminate every blood source on the planet. They won't have anyone left to feed on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sommerfield lowers her head, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't do us any good if we don't have time to finish it. We can't just sit here. We need to take the battle to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the vampires are trying to isolate the hereditary factor in Drake that makes him immune to sunlight, they'll require certain kinds of laboratory equipment and provisions. For instance, there's an enzyme called Taq Polymerase. And there are only a limited number of suppliers.  Give me a few hours. I'll see if I can't hunt us up some leads.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you wear that -- symbol?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old habits -- She sits up, draping a sheet over her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake nods, his thoughts distant.</context>
      <utterance>I was a good Catholic school girl Once.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was there when they crucified him. He died -- for their sins, not mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what are your sins? Would you care to confess them?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too numerous to remember.  Take it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake draws her in, biting her gently on the neck, sinking his fangs into her flesh. He pulls his head back. Two rivulets of BLOOD trickle from the fresh wounds.</context>
      <utterance>I'll make you a better one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake reaches for the sheet, pulling it away from Danica's chest. Then he dips his fingertips into her flowing blood - PAINTING a long streak of it down between her breasts.</context>
      <utterance>There's an old saying --</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill one man, you're a murderer. Kill a million, a king.  Kill them all, a God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something bad inside of me. This keeps it from getting out. Zee considers this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't you just be nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good question.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I've got a lead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Biomedica Enterprises. They've been buying up all sorts of supplies -- Taq polymerase, bone marrow growth supplement, genetic sequencing enzymes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll check it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade nods to Abigail. She reaches onto Vreede's jacket to disarm him. Blade grips Hendrix by the shirt collar.</context>
      <utterance>Doing a little moonlighting, Chief?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade PUNCHES Hendrix in the face. Hendrix sags for a moment, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>C'mere. We need to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now spill it, bite-boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hendrix shoots a quick look to Vreede. Then he turns on Blade, all fangs and claws, trying to tear Blade's eyes out -- Abigail FIRES her UV gun with blinding speed and -- -- Hendrix is dead before he knows it. ASHING all over Blade. Blade brushes Hendrix' s remains from coat collar, shoots Abigail a look: "Did you really have to do that?"</context>
      <utterance>What's back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade looks to the floor. Aside from some cinders, all that remains of Hendrix are his glasses and a singed keycard. Blade picks up the keycard, looks to Vreede.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Abigail cringes. Mea culpa.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's behind Door Number One?</utterance>
   <speaker>VREEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll kill me --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vreede pauses before answering, looking uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>What was this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>VREEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a blood farming facility.  They decided that hunting humans on a piece-meal basis was too inefficient. Why kill your prey when you can keep them alive? Productive. Under optimal conditions a donor can generate anywhere from fifty to a hundred pints of blood a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But where did you get all these people?</utterance>
   <speaker>VREEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade shakes his head, admiring the horrible efficiency.</context>
      <utterance>The streets. In any given year you've got two to three million homeless people wandering around America --  No one cares about them. We're doing the country a service, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abigail moves towards one of the pods, touching her hand to the glass, studyihg the comatose person within.</context>
      <utterance>The vampire Final Solution.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they aware? Do they feel anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>VREEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade angrily SLAMS Vreede's face against one of the pods.</context>
      <utterance>They're in a chemical-induced coma. They're brain-dead, vegetables.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vreede starts crying, blubbering.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this! Is this the future you want? You think there's a place for you in their world?</utterance>
   <speaker>VREEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade pulls Vreede back so they're nose to nose --</context>
      <utterance>We don't have a choice! They're going to win, don't you see that?! He's come back! There's nothing stopping them now!</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and Blade releases Vreede.</context>
      <utterance>There's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vreede turns and runs, stumbling towards the door. Despite his promise, Blade lifts his MACH. Without even looking in Vreede's direction, Blade FIRES. We hear Vreede drop. Blade turns to Abigail. She can hardly contain herself. Nearby is a control console. Blade UNLOADS his MACH pistol into it, damaging the interlinked life support systems. One by one, the vital signs and EKGs on the pods flat-line, their warning tones rising into a collective, PIERCING WAIL.</context>
      <utterance>Go. You've got thirty seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Blade and Abigail leave, turning the lights out as they go.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zoe hesitates. Sommerfield senses it and lashes out with her cane, BANGING a rack of equipment, startling the girl.</context>
      <utterance>Zoe, go find some place to hide, sweety.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl scurries away. Sommerfield TAP-TAPS with her cane, moving towards the storage area. She finds a gun cabinet, feels around with her hands, locates an electronic pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Damnit, go! Get out of here, Zoe!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZOE'S POV</speaker>
      <mode>THROUGH GRATE</mode>
      <context>Zoe holds her breath. We HEAR Drake searching the bathroom, opening the lockers and bathroom stalls.</context>
      <utterance>A pair of boots appear in the doorway -- Drake.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE'S POV</speaker>
      <mode>THROUGH GRATE</mode>
      <context>Zoe shuts her eyes. She can't stand it. Finally, we hear Drake's FOOTSTEPS receding away. Relieved, Zoe takes in a breath and opens her eyes --</context>
      <utterance>Drake's boot-clad feet pass by the grate again, closer, tn~s time. They pause for an interminable moment --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abigail doesn't respond. Her whole body is shaking.</context>
      <utterance>Use it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Abigail raises her head, her eyes filled with hatred. Blade doesn't let up. He's like a drill instructor, galvanizing her with his words.</context>
      <utterance>Use it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rottweiler's jaws open, revealing more teeth than any dog should probably have. Its muzzle splits in two as both sides of the rottweiler mandible fold back on either side of its head, disgorging a hellish and barbed tongue stalk! The mutant dog ROARS, ready to bite King's face off and --</context>
      <utterance>Back off, pooch --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Grimwood appears from off-screen, LAUGHING, pulling the animal back. We see Danica and Asher now as well.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck?! WHAT THE FUCK?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Asher pets the rottweiler, its muzzle closes back up again. It looks up at him, panting happily, tongue lolling.</context>
      <utterance>His name's Beau. We've been experimenting with porting the vampire gene over into other species.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You made a goddamn vampire dog?!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIMWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Cool, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danica wipes a little blood from the corner of King's mouth. She touches her fingertips to her tongue, tasting his blood.</context>
      <utterance>Poor little King. You look so distraught.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're tasting a little bland, lover. Not getting enough fatty acids in your diet? Have you tried mackerel? Lake trout?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about you take a sugar-frosted fuck off the end of my dick?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, there'll be time to play doctor later, believe me. But for now, we need to have a little talk.  Tell us about this bio-weapon you've been building.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grimwood steps forward, throttling King for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I can tell you two things. Diddly. And shit. And diddly just left the building.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRINWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spit it out, you fucking fruitcake!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grimwood moves in to choke him again, but Danica intervenes.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, here's the deal with the weapon -  It's a new flavor crystal formula. Twice the chocolaty-goodness, half the calories. Plus, it helps prevent tooth decay --</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're brave, King, I'll give you that. But underneath all your swagger -- She leans closer, caressing his face.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King's smile falters for a moment. Maybe she does know. She rubs her cheek against his.</context>
      <utterance>-- I know what you really fear. What would hurt you more than anything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King tries to turn his head away, but Danica grips his chin, turning his head back. He's sweating now. Worried.</context>
      <utterance>You don't want to go back to being one of us --  -- do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. Drake appears, holding Zoe. She's alive. Terrified. Held firm in Drake's arms.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to bite you again, King. And then I'm going to leave you here while you turn. I'm going to watch you, day after day, while the Thirst keeps building and building. And then, when you can't stand it anymore --</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King shuts his eyes, sickened at the thought. Danica smiles.</context>
      <utterance>-- I'm going to bring the little girl for you to feed on. Would you like that, King? Would you enjoy taking her life?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we're getting somewhere, my pet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>appears in the doorway, watching her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade nods. He's going to leave her alone -- but then he hesitates, wrestling to say something.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abigail takes a deep breath, pausing in her work.</context>
      <utterance>Don't let it turn inward.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade nods. He understands all too well. He leaves.</context>
      <utterance>It already has. Since I can remember I've had this knife of sadness in my heart. As long as it stays there, I'm strong. I'm untouchable. But the moment I pull it out --  -- I'll die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you taking us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAULDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another safehouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We told you, Blade. We operate in sleeper cells. When one goes down, a new cell activates to pick up the slack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're watching this, I'm already dead. If Zoe's still alive, I want you to promise you'll take care of her. I've been reading her The Oz books every night. We just started The Emerald City of Oz, the one with the Nome King -- Her voice cracks and she pauses, wiping away a tear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zoe hesitates, deciding how to broach the next subject.</context>
      <utterance>I think I've managed to cultivate a workable strain of the Daystar virus. As a precaution, I transmitted the genetic sequence to Caulder, in case our main stock was destroyed. In order for it to achieve maximum lethality, you'll need to interfuse it with Drake's blood. If it works, any vampires in the immediate vicinity should die almost instantly. After that, it should take only a few weeks for the virus to spread throughout the rest of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMMERFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The video cuts to STATIC. Abigail turns off the monitor, looking to Blade. God only knows what he's thinking.</context>
      <utterance>There's one other thing, Blade. You need to know that there's a chance the virus could destroy you too. Because you're a hybrid, I'm not sure whether your immune system will be able tolerate it.  I'm sorry. We didn't have enough time to properly test it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAULDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caulder reaches for a refrigerated aluminum case, snapping it open. Inside, resting on a bed of form-fitting foam, is a glass ampule that's been fitted into a stake-like contraption. It looks like the head of a high-tech harpoon.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look at the plague arrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAULDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only had time to fabricate a small batch of Daystar. I outfitted it with a compressed gas projectile, so you should be able to fire it from one of the fourbarrel rifles or a bow.  Just make sure the shot counts, cause we don't have enough for a second try.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know who I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake smiles at this.</context>
      <utterance>You're the Nome King.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Nome King. I like that.  Tell me, child. Do you want to die? Zoe is terrified but tries to remain defiant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not afraid -- I'll go to Heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Drake talks his pupils seem to widen -- until the darkness nearly occludes the whites of his eyes. Zoe stares at him. Can't tear her gaze away. His eyes are hypnotic.</context>
      <utterance>There is no Heaven. No God. No angels. No happy ending for good little girls. The only thing you have to look forward to is nothingness.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out, running a sharp fingernail over her cheek.</context>
      <utterance>But what if you could change that? What if you could remain a child forever?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zoe reaches out, calmly touches Drake's cheek.</context>
      <utterance>What if you could keep this little doll- like face of yours until the sun itself cooled to a cold, hard rock?  Wouldn't you like that? Wouldn't you accept that gift?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friends are coming to kill you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- gonna be sorry you did that --</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's coming for you, King.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure they are. Left a trail of digital bread crumbs --</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One thing you need to know about us Nightstalkers. When you join our club, you get this nifty little tracking node surgically implanted in your body --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIMWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grimwood looks to Asher and Danica, unsure.</context>
      <utterance>Scout's honor. One of us gets lost, the others just dial up the satellite and presto, instant cavalry.</utterance>
   <speaker>AS HER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's bluffing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions for her to draw closer, whispering.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, King, where did they put this tracking node of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHACK! Danica slaps King's face, making him see stars.</context>
      <utterance>It's in my left ass-cheek --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHACK! Danica slaps King again, this time knocking his head the other way. He spits out blood --</context>
      <utterance>Alright. alright, it's in my right ass- cheek --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- it's in the meat of my butt, right below my Bart Simpson tattoo -- Danica PUNCHES King's mid-section. He sucks air. Despite his attempts at humor, he's hurting now. His body sags --</context>
      <utterance>No, seriously --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- pull down my tighty-whities -- see for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind Danica, Grimwood and Asher both COUGH. King lifts his bruised face, staring up at Danica through blood-shrouded eyes. For the first time, we get a sense of his true hatred for her.</context>
      <utterance>ENOUGH! It's not funny anymore!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's not, you horse-humping bitch --  -- but it will be a few seconds from now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what happens then, lover?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>See, that tickle in your throat you're feeling right now? Danica COUGHS again, blinks repeatedly, as if her eyes were irritated. She rubs them, looks to the others. They're feeling the effects too. And Grimwood's face is smoking!</context>
      <utterance>Hammer time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danica keys into the RUMBLE of the air-conditioning system and a HISSING SOUND beneath that. She looks up --</context>
      <utterance>That's atomized colloidal silver.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's being pumped into the building's air conditioning system.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abigail hits the release switch on the high-tech pillory and the cuffs around his wrists open. As Abigail helps King out:</context>
      <utterance>Nothing a hot tub full of Bactine won't fix.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zoe --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abigail nods, handing King her pistol. Then she's out the door. Seconds later, King follows --</context>
      <utterance>Drake's got her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TWO MORE ROTTWEILERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>emerge behind Beau. They're all GROWLING now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three of them break, BARKING like crazy, snouts splitting open as their jaws flower apart.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck. Me. Sideways.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you ready to die, Blade?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been ready since the day I was born, mother-fucker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No offense, Danica --  -- but I've wanted to kill you since the moment we slept together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King reaches a palsied hand for his discarded pistol, points it vaguely in Danica's direction. She LAUGHS.</context>
      <utterance>I was that bad, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No bullets in your gun, King.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- these babies can be triggered remotely. King pulls the trigger. The scattered sun dog bullets ERUPT with UV LIGHT. Danica SHRIEKS, trying to shield her already burning face from the glare. She runs, horribly wounded.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but here's the beauty --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blade stares back. At this point, he's just trying to remain conscious. He's lost a ton of blood.</context>
      <utterance>Well done, hunter. Well done.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake shudders, his breathing becoming increasingly shallow.</context>
      <utterance>You fought with honor --</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drake grows still, his eyes locked on Blade's.</context>
      <utterance>-- as I knew you would. The humans are coming for you, you know. In their eyes, you and I are the same. Allow me one last indulgence, then --  -- a parting gift --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>By the time Cumberland and his men have entered, fanning out through the atrium, all they find are a series of corpse shaped piles of ash and singe marks.</context>
      <utterance>When they got there, all of Drake's people were dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the weeks that followed, the rest of the world's vampires also perished.  We'd finally won.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Blade flings his sword over the cliff, into the ocean below.</context>
      <utterance>And so Blade took it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We never saw him again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ABIGAIL</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- they become legends.</utterance>
   <speaker>FADE TO BLACK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over darkness we hear the sound of TRAFFIC.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evening Lucius.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>King, what the hell are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little sport hunting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUCIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't no vampires left, King. So who do you have to hunt?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an interesting question, my friend. And I've got a question for you in return.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door to the men's room EXPLODES OPEN. Abigail comes flying out. She hits the far wall of the hallway, slides to th floor. But she's up in an instant, pulling a knife on --</context>
      <utterance>What do you get when you cross a vampire with a werewolf?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fur coat that sticks to your neck.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
