<movie id="89" title="Blue Valentine">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode>HUSHED</mode>
      <context>Frankie uses the footrest to crawl up onto her dad's belly.</context>
      <utterance>Daddydaddydaddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wake up Daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>WAKING</mode>
      <context>She sniffles. He notices.</context>
      <utterance>What time is it baby?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's she going to get back?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She probably just went out for a run. She'll be back soon because she's going to get thirsty.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's going to be thirsty?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean's optimism is infectious. Frankie nods slowly.</context>
      <utterance>You know what we should do? We should leave her bowl full of water and her dish full of food. Because she's gotta get hungry and thirsty sometime. You know?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean pretends to gnaw at Frankie's toes. Breaks her sadness.</context>
      <utterance>Like me. I'm hungry. I'm so hungry I could eat your toes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sleeping!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pin her arms above her head and 'furber' her armpit.</context>
      <utterance>We're hungry! We're going to eat you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy doesn't laugh, she screams.</context>
      <utterance>Don't laugh. Come on, don't laugh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frankie takes a tiny bite and makes a sour face.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, eat, you can't be late today.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy turns on the faucet over a pile of dishes, returns to the computer to e-mail herself the missing dog flyer.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like it...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean spoons the raisins out of her bowl onto the table.</context>
      <utterance>Here... we can make it taste better.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He laps up his coffee like a cat. She mimics. Dean laughs.</context>
      <utterance>This is how a leopard eats.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Frankie, use a spoon. You know how to use a spoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lepers don't use spoons.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context>Frankie reluctantly takes a tiny bite. Her face sours and she lets the food fall out of her mouth and back in the bowl. Cindy returns to the dishes.</context>
      <utterance>Are you gonna listen to your mother? I think you better.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean gets up, goes to Cindy at the sink.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, eat five bites.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tries to take the dish sponge away from her. She resists.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta get a dishwasher...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She drops the sponge, dries her hands.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do it. Come on let me do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frankie ignores her.</context>
      <utterance>Frankie! We're leaving in 15. Eat!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She pulls Frankie out of her seat and carries her under one arm to the back room. Frankie protests. Dean watches, shakes his head. He sees the computer on, Cindy's e-mail is still open. He shuts off the running water. He scans through messages from a bunch of names of people Dean doesn't know. He sweats, clicks open a return message from a real estate company - apartment now available.</context>
      <utterance>Alright...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>7 CONTINUED: 7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her on the corner of her mouth. A hesitation.</context>
      <utterance>DEAN  Love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean pulls his head out of the window.</context>
      <utterance>...Love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to back up.</context>
      <utterance>Put your seat belt on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy does as she's told, looks over her shoulder, scrapes the curb.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon. What's the big deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy cranks the wheel straight, puts on the gas and burns down the road. Dean stands there in his driveway, muttering to himself. He watches the car disappear down the street. Another car, headed the opposite direction, barrels down the road, past the Periera home.</context>
      <utterance>Watch...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slow that piece of shit down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy places the flyers in her folder in a rush.</context>
      <utterance>There you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry...I'm almost done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a second? Did you get a chance to talk it over with your family yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I'm going to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to tell you, it's a huge opportunity...</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I know. I should know for sure by Monday.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Monday's our day. I want the A team up there with me. Talk it over. Feinberg walks away down the hallway.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheer up man. God wants you to be happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God's a woman and she's pissed off at me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>10 CONTINUED: 10</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Feinberg releases Cindy's hand and removes his latex gloves. DR. FEINBERG (cont'd) Very good, Cindy. You're in good hands. Cindy is one of our favorites. Cindy blushes. She is transfixed on the monitor.</context>
      <utterance>DR. FEINBERG  Easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to know the sex?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't think you were gonna make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I miss her?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean kisses her cheek. Cindy settles, arranges her things.</context>
      <utterance>Almost. Her class is coming up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a good day?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was alright... Busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy shakes her head "no." She drops her keys into her purse, but they miss the target and she fumbles after them.</context>
      <utterance>Anything good happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy shakes her head. Takes the water from Dean. He stares at her. She concentrates on closing the clasp on her purse.</context>
      <utterance>Is something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She doesn't want to start crying. Dean gets visibly frustrated. He's sick of prying everything out of her.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The song ends. A patter of applause. The teacher introduces the next song "THE BATTLE HYMN OF THE REPUBLIC".</context>
      <utterance>Why do you gotta make me beg? I know there's something wrong. It's gonna come out eventually. Just tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found Megan.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy doesn't answer. She can't. She tries to keep from crying. He quickly realizes what she's trying to tell him.</context>
      <utterance>That's great, where?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over on Urbandale... near Spur.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy wipes tears. She has to look up and blink to keep them from rolling down her cheek. Dean puts his arm around her, holds her close. She tries to pull away. He won't let her.</context>
      <utterance>I told you you gotta close that fucking gate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. It's not your fault.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were great.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you find Megan?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frankie nods. Dean gets her to the car. Straps her in.</context>
      <utterance>No. But... I was thinking... Maybe she got a job or something... You know? So she could make some money and buy some food. Or maybe she moved out to Hollywood to become a movie dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking...you should have some fun tonight1 Don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy listens in the front seat. She doesn't approve.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry growls at Frankie. She screams, scared but delighted. A yapping dog named SAMMY jumps on her. Jerry nods at Dean who keeps his distance by the van.</context>
      <utterance>Pa!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean gives a sour look and lights a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't you coming up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's an old man.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy gives Dean a slow look of contempt, grabs the backpack and walks toward the house. Jerry stands over the hose spigot with Frankie at his side.</context>
      <utterance>What? I can't smoke around his oxygen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sprinkler jets on. Cindy comes up and kisses her dad on the cheek. She straightens Frankie's ears.</context>
      <utterance>...Want me to show you a magic trick? Here's how you turn the grass green. You can teach it to your dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go say goodbye to Daddy. You're not going to see him until tomorrow. Jerry holds Frankie back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frankie runs to Dean, dodging the water stream. She hugs his leg. He picks her up.</context>
      <utterance>Wait...! OK...one, two, three GO!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey leopard. You be good now. You remember what to do when Pa snores?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cover his mouth and hold his nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean hugs her and she squeezes back as hard as her arms allow. Dean plays as if his neck was being pinched off. He sets her on the ground running back to the porch. She gets caught in the diameter of the sprinkler spray. She screams as the water chases her.</context>
      <utterance>That's my girl. Gimme a squeezer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean and Cindy both laugh. Their eyes meet for the first time in days, maybe weeks. They exchange a brief smile, filled with mutual love, pride and respect - connected by their little girl. Frankie stands in front of Cindy, water drips from her bangs.</context>
      <utterance>It got you! Go right! OTHER RIGHT!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on silly. Let's go in and get dry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna take off my costume!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy leads Frankie with one hand and pulls Jerry's oxygen tank with the other. Jerry takes Frankie's free hand. Dean smokes and watches... Cindy hold the screen open with her foot and maneuver father, tank and child inside. The screen door closes. Sammy barks at Dean through the screen door. He tugs his smoke, memories flood. He drifts...</context>
      <utterance>You don't have to. Let's just go in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CURTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean does. All he sees is brown box.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa whoa. You gonna break your neck homey. Look down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURTIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Curtis takes the boxes from Dean and demonstrates.</context>
      <utterance>Can't see your feet. If you can't see your feet, how you gonna know where the step is? You goin' bust your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURTIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Curtis hefts the boxes on Dean's back. He pulls his arms around the back to hold onto them in an awkward position.</context>
      <utterance>Turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURTIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean is unsure. He proceeds, imbalanced down the stairs. He makes it to the truck where Saned waits to help him get the boxes in. Dean can't quite manage a 30-pound, behind the back hand-off. He ends up spilling up the boxes and their contents all over the sidewalk. Saned gets pissed. Dean gets down on his hands and knees and packs up the boxes - quickly.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta be a mule. Always carry on your back. Give `er a try.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CURTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Saned elbows in with rolls of tape and contractor bags.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think that old man's been up here in 10 years.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANED</speaker>
      <mode>TO DEAN</mode>
      <context>- Dean finds jars of yellow liquid everywhere. "What's this?" He opens a jars and is overwhelmed by the stench of urine.</context>
      <utterance>Box up everything on the first floor. Toss everything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- He runs to the toilet and pukes in to a shit stained porcelain bowl. Saned berates him for wasting time.</context>
      <utterance>It's fucking pee!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>- He ties a bandana around his nose. Gets back to packing. - boxes full of the old man's life (religious items, framed pictures, old cameras and reams of polaroids). - Boxes are packed, taped and stacked.</context>
      <utterance>How could you live like this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SANED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last one. Lets get a move on. Gotta make it home for the game. Dean holds up the man's wedding picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look how handsome he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Saned hands Dean a wad of bills.</context>
      <utterance>What are you fucking queer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Saned walks down the hall, calling out to hurry up. Dean sets the bills down on the dresser. Continues to arrange the things. He stares at a picture of old man and his wife. ELLIPSE - A nurse wheels Walter down the hallway and introduces him to his new room.</context>
      <utterance>Finish up, we gotta 2 hour drive back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the wheelchair from the nurse, wheels Walter out of the room, picks him out out of his wheelchair, and carries him back into the room across the threshold of his new home.</context>
      <utterance>Wait up. We gotta do this right...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean sets him down in a recliner, then gives him a tour of his room - tells him which drawer his socks are in, where put the aftershave, etc. Curtis pokes his head around the corner.</context>
      <utterance>You are gonna be the new stud in this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean cuts the tour short, wishes the old man luck and tells him he'll come visit him someday. He backs out of the doorway, grabs his money off the dresser, and says goodbye. Dean turns and is frozen in his tracks. Something or someone makes his expression change to that of wonder, eyes fill with love... he puts the money in his pocket. Blue Valentine Official Green Script as of 6/9/09 15A.</context>
      <utterance>Boss says we gotta go. We gotta go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we going to tell her?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean turns Cindy around, closes his eyes, and hugs her.</context>
      <utterance>We'll tell her Monday. After the weekend. Let's not ruin her Holiday.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blue Valentine Official Green Script as of 6/9/09 16.</context>
      <utterance>She would have wanted to say goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy stops and watches him. He holds up a gift certificate in an old anniversary card.</context>
      <utterance>You remember where we put...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here! Let's get the fuck out of here. Dean grabs the phone and dials. DEAN   Hello, I want to see if I can reserve a room for the night... tonight. I have a gift certificate but I don't know if it's still good. Can I give you a number?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean lowers the receiver to his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Taking us away. We gotta get outta this house.  It's still good? Good... Well, what rooms do you got?...Hold on a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>What room do you want? The North Pole, the Moon Room or Cupid's cave. Which one?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to hear any excuses. We're going. We deserve it. One night. Because we belong to each other. Pick a room.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to decide? I'll decide. That's how decisions get made. Dean gets a shit-eating grin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He returns to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Come on let's go get drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give us the moon room. Periera. P-E-R-I- E-R-A... 2... Great... Dean hangs up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pack our bags. We're going to the moon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Cindy turns and sees BOBBY ONTARIO, her college sweetheart. She lifts the glasses on her head, blood rushes to her face.</context>
      <utterance>Is that Cindy Heller?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bobby Ontario?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...So, you been faithful to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a strange question to ask someone you haven't seen in forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a strange person.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you have or yes you haven't?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...I haven't. I mean I have...I have been...Why are you looking at me like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not looking at you like anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hard to be faithful. I don't know if monogamy is possible, especially if you're a man...</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Taylor. He's two. Got a little girl at home. Irene.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drooling, and with a toothless smile, Taylor gives his daddy five. Bobby beams.</context>
      <utterance>Kids are great. They pick up on things so fast. Like watch... Hey Spence, give me five... Give me five, buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Taylor holds up his hand limply so that Cindy has to give him an awkward five. Bobby laughs. They reach the register.</context>
      <utterance>Give Cindy five.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To see yourself in your kid's face... I never experienced anything like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an uncomfortable silence between them. Cindy starts to unload her purchases.</context>
      <utterance>I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really happy for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's your kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. They speak at the same time.</context>
      <utterance>She's good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you go...</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... I was going to say, you ask her what kind of hair she's got and she says, a bob. It's pretty funny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's her name?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fumbling, she starts bagging her groceries.</context>
      <utterance>Frankie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy hands the CHECKER a fifty. The Checker holds it out.</context>
      <utterance>That's $58.42.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy searches her wallet, goes into her change purse.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Checker looks at the receipt.</context>
      <utterance>How much was the vodka?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby holds out a twenty dollar bill.</context>
      <utterance>Can I put that back? I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothankyou.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>TO CHECKER</mode>
      <context>Bobby drops the bill on the scanner.</context>
      <utterance>Just take it off please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can get me back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy hops in the driver's seat. Dean rides on the end of the buggy and crashes it into the buggy corral. She fires up the engine and honks. He throws his hands up.</context>
      <utterance>You're drivin'?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy is zoned into the road. She turns off the radio.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, lead foot. It's not a race.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean places his hand on Cindy's hand that rests on the car seat. A small squeeze. She squeezes back. Dean looks at her with tenderness. Her eyes are on the road. She lifts her hand to the wheel. Dean reaches for the radio.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't it funny how you can be driving for 20 minutes and it feels like you've only been driving for 20 seconds. The time just gets swallowed up somewhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mind if I turn this back on?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was kind of enjoying the silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just see if there's something on... He scans through the low stations.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns it off.</context>
      <utterance>Anything? Fuck it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy nods. Dean rolls down his window, spits his gum as far as he can. He rolls it back up.</context>
      <utterance>That's better. You're right. It never gets to be just quiet. You know?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean looks at Cindy, waiting for her to respond.</context>
      <utterance>What are you thinking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean reaches for the glasses on top of Cindy's head. She feels the dangling tag - "woops." She tears off the tag and tosses the glasses on the dashboard.</context>
      <utterance>Where d'you get these?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy shakes her head "no." Dean puts them on his face. He poses for Cindy. She grabs the glasses and puts them on. She looks at Dean. He holds in a chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>Try em' on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy takes them off. Back on the dash.</context>
      <utterance>You look like your mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get any snacks?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean unbuckles his seatbelt, crawls to the back of the van digs through the bags. Cindy can't see out of the rear-view.</context>
      <utterance>There should be some fig newtons back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which bag?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers her another one. She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm. These are good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car stops on the shoulder of the two lane highway. Cindy gets out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>I have to pee.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't wait? We're almost there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy jogs across the road. Dean sees traffic coming.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the side of the road, she stares into the woods. Cars pass behind her, headlights flood the night. She descends into the thicket until the sound of the highway is faint. Wind through the leaves. She drops her pants and pees. Something rustles and she looks into the woods.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit Cindy!! Pay attention!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands up and zips up her pants. Eyes search the shadows. ...Cindy is ALONE. A leaf falls to earth. She stares at it and her mind drifts back to...</context>
      <utterance>...Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Research.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're supposed to be a quadriplegic?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quads can't use their arms. I'm a paraplegic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses himself into her and mauls her with a wet kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Don't I give you enough attention?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He lifts her expensive necklace out from under her dress - looks at it admiringly. Then, Cindy. BOBBY (close (cont'd) Can you come over?</context>
      <utterance>Wonder what people would think if they saw me making out with a paraplegic?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy rolls the wheelchair back.</context>
      <utterance>I can't. I have to go get gramma.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby tries to hide the erection trapped in his wrestling singlet. Blue Valentine Official Green Script as of 6/9/09 25.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme a sec.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GLENDA HELLER - 50's, desperate - peeks her head out of the kitchen. She holds a coffee mug filled with gin on the rocks.</context>
      <utterance>Get down Napoleon! Get down!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ope - I thought you were your Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy kisses her mom on the cheek, can smell the alcohol.</context>
      <utterance>Just us.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was the beauty shop?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GLENDA, JERRY AND GRAMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glenda, Jerry, Gramma Francis and Cindy sit around a dining room table. Glenda slices a knife through a greenish meatloaf. She serves a watery slice to Gramma.</context>
      <utterance>Come lord Jesus, be our guest, and let Thy gifts to us be blessed. Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glenda averts her eyes. She cuts another slice. Cindy offers Glenda her plate. The meat breaks apart and half of it lands on the table cloth. A brownish-green oil.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's OK mom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes it across the table an inch. Glenda lowers a slice onto Jerry's plate with a SPLAT. Jerry looks at his dinner. Glenda serves herself. Cindy cuts Gramma's meat with her fork and looks over at her dad. His face is turning beat-red... Suddenly, Jerry pounds his fist into the mound of meatloaf, obliterating it. Particles of ground meat fly everywhere. Glenda won't look up, her shoulders tremble. Jerry raises his steaming fist. Bits of ground beef stick to his knuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Can I have your plate Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you do to meatloaf? Huh?!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They had it ready-made in the deli. I... thought it looked good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding me? How long does it take to make a meatloaf? Five minutes? You mean to tell me that you didn't have five minutes to make a meatloaf? I been up since six this morning busting my fucking ass and you don't have five minutes to make a meatloaf?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it would be nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...for a change...</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what gave you the idea that any of us needed a change? Did you ask for a change? Cindy? She doesn't ask for anything... She doesn't talk. You didn't ask for a change, did you mom?...She can't hear! And I don't remember asking for a change. So, it was you, wasn't it? You wanted a change. I work all day so you can sit on your fat ass, thinkin' about yourself. How you'd like a change.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry? What good is sorry now?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want me to make you some eggs?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He storms out of the dining room. Glenda, Cindy and Gramma sit in silence. Cindy takes a bite.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to enjoy your fucking dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glenda retreats into the kitchen. Gramma and Cindy eat.</context>
      <utterance>Oh bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...When I was a young physician, I used to leave the hospital everyday in tears.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just broken down from seeing the suffering of my patients.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMMA FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get my hair.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode>BREATHLESS</mode>
      <context>She stops moving, feels him shrinking inside of her.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>REALIZING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets out from underneath him.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't help it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy is white, tries to contain her terror. She disappears into the BATHROOM. Bobby sits up. BOBBY (calls out) (cont'd) Don't trip. It'll be OK...OK? Bobby lies back, frustrated, and buttons his pants.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't help it... You felt too good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy presses her lips together. She leaps at Bobby and squeezes his crotch and gets her underwear back. Bobby's face turns vicious. He snatches them back aggressively.</context>
      <utterance>Give em!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy picks her pants up off the floor - pulls them on.</context>
      <utterance>Say you're sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tears off his necklace, throws it at him, slams the door.</context>
      <utterance>Take a deep whiff, you fucking douchebag!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just joking! God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>B61 B61</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- Cindy reads to Gramma... but she keeps getting distracted by the commotion across the hall - movers carry boxes and furniture down the hallway. One in particular, tall, handsome, catches her eye. It is Dean. She cranes her head to see - him decorating the inside of the old man's room.</context>
      <utterance>- Cindy helps gramma with bedtime rituals.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy returns to the book, but there is something about the mover that has captured her attention. She can't stop watching him every time he passes her door.</context>
      <utterance>It looks like you have a new neighbor.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glenda... I mean Cindy... can I have a cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gramma nods. Cindy turns the page, looks up, sees Dean lift the old man over the threshold and into the room.</context>
      <utterance>No, Gramma, you're in bed now. It's bedtime. Do you want me to keep reading?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cindy. Have you got a cigarette!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy gets up and opens the window. She turns on the fan, digs in Gramma's purse, gets a cigarette and a lighter. Cindy walks to her gramma's door, sees Curtis walking away from the old man's room.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, shhh. But you gotta be quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURTIS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She starts closing the door, then sees Dean backing out of the old man's room. He puts a roll of money in his pocket, turns to leave and sees Cindy watching him.</context>
      <utterance>Boss says we gotta go. We gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>LOOKS DOWN AT HIS MONEY</mode>
      <context>Cindy doesn't know what this guy is talking about. DEAN (CONT'D) (cont'd) You think I just stole that money?</context>
      <utterance>I didn't just steal that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do. No, you do. I know that you do. And the reason that I know that you do is - I have stolen money before... a lot of it. And I know what it feels like to have someone look at you like that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The way your lookin'. Just so you know, I have a job where I make money. Money that I can take girls out on dates with.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to pick up on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANED</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Dean looks toward the door, then back at Cindy. He sees that he has kind of went to far with his rant.</context>
      <utterance>Pack it up Periera. Bus is leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He feels inside his shirt pocket, pulls out a business card. Finds a pen. Dean writes his name across the card. Hands it to Cindy. DEAN (CONT'D) (cont'd) I'm Dean. Just call and you can ask for me. I'll get it. Cindy looks down at the card, at his name. Then back up to him. Dean run out, chasing after his ride. He looking behind before he leaves. Cindy watches him go out the door. Blue Valentine Official Green Script as of 6/9/09 31.</context>
      <utterance>Can I give you my number or something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs his hands through his hair then shows her his palms - three fallen hairs. His magic trick.</context>
      <utterance>Now watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy ignores Dean who is mesmerized.</context>
      <utterance>See. I tol' ya. It's falling out!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy waves him away. Jerry picks up the line.</context>
      <utterance>Oooooooooh shiiiiiiit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>62 CONTINUED: 62</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hi Dad. We're here... It's kind of crazy. I don't know, should I feel bad? Dean trots back into the BATHROOM. He is screaming like a hyena.</context>
      <utterance>CINDY</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...it's just Dean... he's losing his hair. What are you guys doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemme talk to the little one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>SHOUTS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Francis? Hey!? Don't hang up until I talk to her!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean walks up from behind, putting on a clean, white T-shirt. He snaps his fingers at Cindy. Cindy swipes his hand away with more force than necessary.</context>
      <utterance>Did Pa make you something to eat yet? ...Frankie? ...What'd you and Pa eat? ...Was it cooked all the way through? No pink in there? ...</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy sets down the receiver and walks away. Dean snacks on tortilla chips and picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Okay sweetheart, your daddy wants to talk to you. I love you... love you... Don't forget to brush your teeth tonight okay. Okay? Here's your dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks into the living room, stretching the phone cord, grabs the remote and turns on the television - animal doc. Dean turns the channel. Tennis.</context>
      <utterance>Are you ready to go to sleep now? I'll call you first thing in the morning, OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>CLICK. The news.</context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean hangs up and returns to the living room. He changes the station. A porno. He turns the volume down and watches. He hears water running in the BATHROOM. CLICK. A show on space.</context>
      <utterance>...Well, I love you more. Sleep tight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it look like I'm doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like the place?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna go order dinner now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any special requests?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean closes the door, remains in the BATHROOM, watches his naked wife, removes his clothes. Cindy does a double take.</context>
      <utterance>Close the door!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean pulls back the shower curtain and steps in.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it look like I'm doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The small shower presses them close. Dean's smile infects her. He leans over, they kiss. Brushing lips at first. Dean presses closer. Cindy pulls back and pivots him around until the stream of water catches his body. He leans his head back, the water pours over his hair and face. He places his hands on Cindy's hips and pulls her close to him. Cindy hands him a bar of soap. He builds a gentle lather. Cindy inches back, turns around. Dean lathers her back, slow and languid.</context>
      <utterance>Dean.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember the first time I saw your back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lowers his hands from her back to her behind. Cindy turns.</context>
      <utterance>Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy grabs under his armpits. He refuses, but she wins. She pivots them around again. Standing in the stream of water, Cindy washes the soap off her body, eyes closed, head back. Dean reaches for her and follows with his fingertips the flow of water down the front of her body.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She forms a quick lather in her hands. She rubs it into his chest, her strong hands making circles of suds. Dean is a tranquil participant. She lifts up his left arm, scrubs his armpit, then his right. Her hands build a lather and wash his penis. Dean catches his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Give me the soap.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean obeys. She continues wash his back, buttocks and legs and stops. Dean turns around to Cindy who holds a squirt of shampoo in her hands. She reaches up and scours his head.</context>
      <utterance>Turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting thinner, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy pivots him around into the water and rinses him.</context>
      <utterance>Your hair is not falling out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pecks him on the lips.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I love you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, get out. I have to finish washing myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Go order dinner. I'm hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, I didn't wash your hair...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy stands in a towel at the bar, waiting for the ice.</context>
      <utterance>We have neighbors.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She makes 2 drinks - vodka on the rocks. She hands Dean his drink.</context>
      <utterance>Grump. Grump.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She pecks him on the cheek, walks to the bedroom to change.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you put some music on Dean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a big drink, sifts through cassettes in his bag. In the bedroom, Cindy buttons up one of Dean's big flannel shirts.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>74 74</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bobby trains, 200 sit ups, his abdomen taught.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURTIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At that point they got no choice but to become one river.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the flowers, pushes Gramma into the house. The screen door closes between them.</context>
      <utterance>Hasn't anyone ever been nice to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make me give up on you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CURTIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Curtis - with harmonica - and Dean - with ukulele - eat hamburgers on their lunchbreak.</context>
      <utterance>It's just nature, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURTIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And instead of thinking about it you gotta just do something about it. Action, not thought.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRAMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He went out for groceries.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the girl that was with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The conversation moves in circles. Not much information is gained. Dean ends up just holding her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy remembers him now - he's just dressed nicer - he doesn't look like a mover</context>
      <utterance>I just had a long talk with your gramma... is that, is that your gramma?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was looking for that old guy who moved across the hall, you know? Do you know what happened to him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean feels for the locket around his neck. He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I think he passed away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the locket out from behind his shirt. He unclasps it. Shows her the pictures.</context>
      <utterance>That's exactly what happened to my dog. My parents moved out of our house and three days later she was a goner.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>He was so handsome, wasn't he? I was trying to give it back to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean thinks about the old man. The bus drives.</context>
      <utterance>She was pretty too..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She must have been crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause there's one thing I know... the prettier a girl is the more nuts she is. I mean, look at you... you must be insane.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy pulls the chain to stop the bus.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, I mean, I get it. It's not your fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bus slows. She gets up to leave. Doors open.</context>
      <utterance>Home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy thinks about it.</context>
      <utterance>Can I walk with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Doors to the bus open. Cindy thinks about it.</context>
      <utterance>Just for a little bit... And when you don't want to walk with me no more, then just speed up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's you house?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We passed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean looks back. He sees a bunch of houses that all look the same. They keep walking. ELLIPSE: Cindy smokes one of Dean's cigarettes, calls her dad</context>
      <utterance>Back there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think it would be okay if I looked in your purse?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy thinks about it for a moment. Against her better judgement, she hands over her bag. It weighs a lot.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez... What you got in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Books. Mostly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lot of books. You doing good?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna be when you grow up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to get into med school.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to be a doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someday.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pretends to bump into a pole. Cindy laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? What should I do about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He digs through text books, pens, a wallet, asthma inhaler. Then he comes to a bottle of lotion. Opens the cap, sniffs.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it. DEAN  You're gonna be a good doctor. I can tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy nods, "I guess so."</context>
      <utterance>Mmm. This is what you smell like?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna smell like you. Can I?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean nods, applies a little lotion to his fingertips, rubs it in circles on his hands, applies it to his forearms, neck, face. He enjoys the feeling of it, offers her some. She say's no. He digs through her purse and finds lip balm, smells it.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna put on my lotion?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts some on his lips.</context>
      <utterance>This is what your lips smell like? They must smell good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm. Your lips must taste good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you fucking with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blue Valentine Official Green Script as of 6/9/09 45.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes her purse back.</context>
      <utterance>What's in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Throughout the rest of the night Dean tries to continually steal Cindy's purse from her. It is a game. Innocent.</context>
      <utterance>Because.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you gonna miss your train?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably. I think I... I think I already did. It's okay. There's an early one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are just gonna stay up all night?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until you get tired...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you grow up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy gives him a grimace.</context>
      <utterance>Here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same streets. Same people. Everything here is the same. You walk down the street, you can't get lost... you know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk to an old playground. Cindy gets an idea.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you want to go? I mean, if you could go anywhere..</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy runs to an old, creaky merry-go round, jumps on.</context>
      <utterance>There!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to love these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God... I hate these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean is tentative, but goes along with her. He starts slow, but she eggs him to go faster. He runs in circles picking up speed until he is in a breathless, circular sprint. He can't keep up with the centrifugal force.</context>
      <utterance>Push me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean does as he's told. They both hold on for dear life. The world spins in a frenzy. The dread on Dean's face builds to insane laughter. It is super fun. Cindy screams. Her hair snaps in her face. Then, a look of sickness steals her smile away. She wants it to stop, which, slowly, it does. She gets off first, tries to walk, but is too dizzy. She just keeps falling to the ground. Dean crawls off the merry-go round on all fours, laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Get on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened, tough guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She refuses.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta puke... it's the only way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He sticks his finger down his throat and forces himself to vomit. The sound of it is too much for her. She gags. Side by side, they puke into the gravel. They finish their business and end up on their backs and out of breath, side by side, looking up at the stars. They are both covered in sweat. We see their breath.</context>
      <utterance>It's the only way. It will make you feel better. Don't be embarrassed. I'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still spinning.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's just the Earth that's spinning.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. Birds begin to awaken and fly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We're flying.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The morning air chills their bodies. Dean takes off his jacket and uses it as a blanket. They get close together to get warm and watch the stars spin above them.</context>
      <utterance>You should come visit me in the city sometime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Wait up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean makes his toast. CLINK. Dean quaffs his glass.</context>
      <utterance>We're toasting tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean imitates a Chinese man - it goes on too long.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes you don't make any sense. You might as well be speaking Chinese.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy starts to eat a spread of Indian food and booze.</context>
      <utterance>Happy belated anniversary.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. How did Frankie sound?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. She's the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't sound sad?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean chews a bite of meat and washes it down with a shot of vodka. He refills both their glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Naw. She's the champ. She's the best parts of you and the best parts of me put together. Everyday she gets more and more amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy's little girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not mine. I'm hers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>92 CONTINUED:  92</speaker>
      <mode>2</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cindy slows down.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm her father. She isn't there for me... I'm there for her. That's the way I look at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the choice I made when she was born. Silence. They chew. Cindy stares through Dean.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you do something...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... isn't there anything you want to do? Dean thinks about it. Shakes his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I supposed to want to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You could do anything you wanted.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... You have so many things you could do. You're good at everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Cindy tries not to look disappointed.</context>
      <utterance>I just wanna be with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look like an animal right now. Your eyes look like an animal. Like a bear's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like right before the bear eats the man?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean is amused but fearful. Cindy's confidence surges.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... You do. It's true. That's what you look like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatchu thinking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How different we are. You and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Different?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a good thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think that's good that we're different?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. We don't have to get in each other's way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's the way you like it, don't you? You don't like me to bother you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's all. We're grown people.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't say that. What I meant is that it's important for us to have our space.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well there's not much space here. So I guess you won't be able to get away from me will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You just blab. Blab.</context>
      <utterance>You know, we rarely sit down and have a conversation. An adult conversation. Because every time we do, you turn something that I say around and make it mean something that I didn't mean to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're not interested in hearing what I think I just won't say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck. I just want you to think about what you say sometimes instead of saying what you think all the time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy lifts up her empty wine glass to the light.</context>
      <utterance>OK. I'm going to say something. And what I'm about to say I've thought long and hard about. I'm the luckiest person alive because I'm living my dream - you, her, this, us, all of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy cuts around her food and pushes a piece aside.</context>
      <utterance>I think my glass has a hole in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the flavor. Eat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean stabs a piece of fat and pops it into his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to. You eat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's going straight to your tits.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean opens his shirt and peers down at his chest.</context>
      <utterance>My tits? I got tits?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could still kick yer ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shiiit. I bet you a nickel you can't even beat me at arm wrestling.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy gulps more champagne. They scoot dishes out of the way and clasp hands in the middle of the table.</context>
      <utterance>A dime and you're on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm always ready, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy flexes and starts.</context>
      <utterance>On the count of three... One... Two...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy ignores his taunts and pushes as hard as she can. Slowly, she begins to push Dean's hand down. Dean groans, letting her win a little. Cindy presses down with all her weight. His hand is centimeters from hitting the table. Then, he turns the tide. Cindy battles back with all the strength she can muster. Dean laughs, realizing her passion for victory. Dean pounds her hand into the table. He stands kisses his flexed bicep. Cindy lifts her hand. A fork is stuck in the back of it. She looks at it with curiosity.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Go! Start.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm alright.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plucks the fork from her hand, leaving four vampire bites.</context>
      <utterance>Hold still.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean leads her to the kitchen, holds her hand under the faucet.</context>
      <utterance>Ow ow ow.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy shoots him a look. Dean wraps her hand with a dishrag.</context>
      <utterance>You think we should rush you to the hospital before you bleed to death?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean tries to pick up Cindy. She struggles against it. Finally he cradles her like a squirming baby.</context>
      <utterance>It stings a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean huffs a little. Cindy adjusts her weight, self- conscious. He hefts her down the hallway to the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>No, no... Put me down. It's okay...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To numb the pain. Doctors orders. I'm an anesthesiologist.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits up. They toast. Dean gulps his. Cindy takes a sip.</context>
      <utterance>I'm spinning.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tops off her glass, refills his own, and quaffs it.</context>
      <utterance>Drink up. We haven't gotten loaded together in years.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He kisses her on the forehead, stumbles. Cindy hears Dean urinating. She is sickened by it. She tries to set her full glass on the floor that spins beneath her. The toilet flushes. The drink tips over. A loud crash comes from the BATHROOM. Cindy sits up.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta take a piss. Don't fall asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An agonizing moan comes from down the hall. Cindy staggers off the spinning bed and stumbles to the bathroom door.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing in there? ...Dean?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She pushes the door but it is blocked. Dean moans louder. Cindy pushes again and inches it open. She sticks her head in, sees him laying on his back looking up at the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right? Dean...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>SLURS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fell over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ew. Come on, get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy opens the door and Dean scoots, making room for her. He lets out an "ow" before extending his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Nope, I want you to come here first. I want you to laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy reluctantly joins him on the bathroom floor. Their faces are close, eyes locked.</context>
      <utterance>Come close. I want to hear you... I want to tell you... Shh, come here...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to hear a joke? OK. What's better than winning a gold medal at the Special Olympics?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy looks down.</context>
      <utterance>Not being retarded.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey...that's not funny? How come you don't think I'm funny any more? I tell you something funny. You laugh. I see you laugh. But you don't really laugh so much. You don't laugh anymore Cindy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dean... Come on, it's time for bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears well up in her eyes. Dean rolls on top of her. He cups her face in his hands and stares long into her watery eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No I want to make you laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello...</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're drunk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment, their lips meet in an awkward rejuvenation. She moves her head away and pats Dean on the shoulder in a gesture of friendship. Dean kisses her neck.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm just still in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy bites her lip. He slides his hand between her legs.</context>
      <utterance>Do you... you want to have another baby? ... I want another child.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She removes his hand and places it on her hip. Dean continues to kiss her neck. He slides his hand up to her breasts. Cindy turns her head in the other direction. She pushes his hand away. He brings it back aggressive. Again. Cindy squirms underneath him. He grabs her wrists and holds her arms over her head. His tongue licks Cindy from her breasts to her face. She worms her arms away and grabs onto his hair. She arches her back, looks at him through slit eyes. His pelvis pulses and he moans. He looks up at her over his brow into her desperate eyes. He springs up. Sweat beads on his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>No... Dean... Wait a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy covers her face with her hand.</context>
      <utterance>What!? I can't have sex with my wife!?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I repulse you that much? I'm good to you. I'm good to Frankie. I deserve a little affection. Do you want me to stop loving you? Do you want me to fuck other women? Do you want me to beat you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop... stop... stop...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy raises her hips and slips off her panties. She lifts the shirt up over her head, positions her feet on the door jam. Her arm falls over her eyes. Breathless, Dean awkwardly moves one hand up and down her bodice.</context>
      <utterance>Is that what you think you deserve? Would that make it easier on you so you can treat me like this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are my hands cold?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna go somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where can we go?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your roommate awake?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context>Dean tiptoes over to Jake's room. Peeks in his door. Returns to the couch where Cindy is taking off her jacket. He crawls back under the sheet. DEAN (WHISPERS) (cont'd) He's just watching TV. They start to make out while listening for Jake.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Let me go check.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think he's gonna come out?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context>She nods. He throws off the sheet and goes into the bathroom, touches the bristles of Jake's tooth brush. Cindy takes off her socks and waits for Dean to return.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... Should I go see if he brushed his teeth?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>97 CONTINUED: 97</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets back on the couch. They kiss. Slowly. Silently. Their hands search each other under the blanket. Clothing is removed and there is alot of movement, but the details of what occurs under that single sheet remain largely a mystery. Jake's bedroom door opens and Jake walks out into the living room and into the kitchen. Dean and Cindy pantomime sleeping. They listen and hear Jake opening the refrigerator, pouring himself a bowl of cereal, crunching. They feel like he's watching them. Cindy tries her hardest not to laugh. Jake stares at the trembling sheet with contempt before returning to his room. Cindy releases her laugh. Dean tries to shush her, but he can't help laughing himself.</context>
      <utterance>DEAN  It's still dry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be quiet! Seriously. He's gonna kill me. He already hates me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hear Jake changing channels in the other room. As quietly as possible, they have sex under the sheet.</context>
      <utterance>You think he's gonna go to sleep now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy nods.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CURTIS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Dean turns around and sees his work buddies busting him for being a Romeo. He waves goodbye to them, turns back to Cindy, embarrassed but happy. She smiles, concealing something. Blue Valentine Official Green Script as of 6/9/09 60.</context>
      <utterance>See you later, Elvis!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy looks Dean in the eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Is it mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't know... It might be...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You let that asshole knock you up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'm sorry...I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When'd this happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy nods. Silence.</context>
      <utterance>We'll keep it. We'll take care of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean looks down, pauses and looks back to Cindy.</context>
      <utterance>It's not the right time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to take care of it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>102 CONTINUED: 102</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cindy does.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DOCTOR wheels over to the table in the center of the room. She pulls out a clean sheet of examination table paper.</context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy gets on the table, looks over at a tray of instruments. The Doctor pulls a mask up over her face - the vacuum aspirator on a wheeled base. Cindy focuses her gaze at the corrugated ceiling, dim light.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to have you lie up here, and put your feet in the stirrups.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor touches Cindy's knee to spread her legs, picks up an instrument off the table.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor inserts a speculum into Cindy's vagina.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to try and relax. This is going to be a little cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There, take a deep breath... What do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a student...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor dips a long swab into a solution, inserts it into her vagina.</context>
      <utterance>What are you studying?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm studying to be a DOCTOR...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I studied.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy looks back up at the ceiling. She steady's her breath.</context>
      <utterance>This is a mild anesthetic for your cervix. You're going to feel a pinch and then it's going to feel like electricity.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cindy coughs.</context>
      <utterance>Can you cough for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Wheels move across the linoleum floor. The Doctor positions the vacuum aspirator.</context>
      <utterance>Good... Why do you want to be a Doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy cuts herself off. The Doctor holds a hose.</context>
      <utterance>Because... I always thought... it would be wonderful to take a sick child and...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...heal them...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor turns on the vacuum. Panic flushes Cindy's face. Her eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>Cindy, I'm going to begin the procedure. It won't take long. You may feel a little cramping.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait... wait.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not in this alone. This baby is ours. It's us. Let's start a family.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy breathes deep &amp; settles into him. Dean hums a lullaby.</context>
      <utterance>Your eyes ever wide open, and you're dreaming?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You smell like you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>105 CONTINUED: 105</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CINDY</utterance>
   <speaker>105 CONTINUED: 105</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She hangs up, eases the door open. Dean is passed out in the middle of the hallway. She tries to wake him, but he's hibernating. She steps over his fallen body.</context>
      <utterance>...Who didn't show?...Meredith again? How long can she keep doing this?... Did you try Janet?...She's your first call....I'm out of town too...Yes I know, I know all of it. Yes...It's going to take me a few hours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response. He struggles up and stumbles to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Cynthia!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A prerecorded message.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>MESSAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning. This is your...11:30 a.m...wake up call.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>109 109</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dean leans on the concierge desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was she with a guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCIERGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He types on the computer.</context>
      <utterance>Like I said, I couldn't say. I just got here, so maybe she left before I came in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCIERGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, she didn't check out. You're still booked until...Monday morning. 11 am. Is there anything else I can help you with sir?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean continues his work.</context>
      <utterance>Hey faggot!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your name Dean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby rushes him, throws a shoulder into his stomach. They both flail to the floor. The two lock. Everything is quick. Bobby sends a flurry of punches to Dean's ribs and guts. Dean pummels the back of Bobby's head with blind overhead rights. It becomes clear that Bobby has the upper hand. He holds Dean's bloodied head in some kind of jiujitsu headlock.</context>
      <utterance>Who's askin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean struggles to breathe but manages to say...</context>
      <utterance>Think I'm dumb? Think I'm that dumb?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby hits him again, harder. Harder.</context>
      <utterance>I think you're a fucking idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- Troy and Tony watch the door and egg Bobby on. - THE PHONE RINGS OFF THE HOOK in the EMPTY OFFICE.</context>
      <utterance>Fucking faggot!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay away from her!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby looks at his bloodied hands. He lacks the strength to lift he arms. Gives one last weak kick into Dean's bloodied face. Troy and Tony pull Bobby out. The gang leaves, victorious yet somehow defeated. The office phone, which has been ringing incessantly, stops. Dean is on the floor in the fetal position. It takes him a while, but he manages to sit up. He feels the inside of his split lip with his tongue. He doesn't feel pain as much as he feels tingling and ringing - all over. Jo comes in. She freezes when she sees him.</context>
      <utterance>Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>JO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes Dean a while to get up, but he does. And it takes him a while to get to the office where his phone call awaits. Once there, he holds the receiver in his hand for a beat...</context>
      <utterance>Dean... Telephone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Hispanic women, MARIA GUEVARA - robust, 50's - clutches her purse and rises off a waiting area chair. Cindy smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Mediplex... You are going to need to come in... We're going to need to see him... I can't diagnose over the phone... About 20- 30 minutes... Okay? ...okay, bye... Cindy hangs up. She holds a clipboard. CINDY   Maria?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right this way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria has a blank look.</context>
      <utterance>Have a seat on the table, Mrs. Guevara.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Maria holds her fingers up, indicating an inch.</context>
      <utterance>Do you speak English? Hablas Ingles?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Small.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poquito?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Si.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo tabien. De donde eres tu?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>El Salvador.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...Tu famalia esta aqui? Here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No no.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're in El Salvador?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sola?</context>
      <utterance>Si....Yo...sola. How you say en Ingles?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...Sola...Alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Si. Alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria hides her face with her hand and lets out a self- pitying giggle. Cindy looks at her clipboard.</context>
      <utterance>But hopefully not lonely.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're feeling some pain in your left breast. Uh...Tu dueles en tu chiche?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Si Si.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy hands her a paper robe.</context>
      <utterance>Well let's take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Maria nods and takes the robe. Cindy turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Can you take off tu ropas and pongas... put this on? Okay? Comprende?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lo siento mi Espanol es muy mal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DR. FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy's holds her clipboard to her chest. He tilts it down with his finger. DR. FEINBERG (cont'd) What do you have?</context>
      <utterance>Busy. Haven't sat down yet. Walk with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A woman in 215. Hispanic. 53. Lives alone. Complaining of pain in her left breast.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh. I'll be in in a minute. By the way, I was thinking about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well I can understand how you might not be able to relocate your whole family up to Riverdale, with your daughter being in school and everything. But, I was thinking, maybe, you could get an apartment. Work during the week, drive down on weekends. They arrive at a door, Room 220.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>123 CONTINUED: 123</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy blushes and then her brow furrows.</context>
      <utterance>DR. FEINBERG  You wouldn't have to worry about being alone... We could hang out together. Grab some dinners sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm married.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a proposition, I'm just trying to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up his hands and leaves Cindy alone in the hallway. She looks at the ground, turns around and walks to Room 215.</context>
      <utterance>I don't remember asking you for help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy pantomimes undoing her shirt.</context>
      <utterance>What's the problem, Maria? Tu sabes?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Maria nods and undoes her blouse. Cindy turns her back. Maria sits slumped with her blouse opened. Cindy pantomimes removing her shirt fully. Maria does so and sits with her hand covering her face. Cindy gestures to her bra.</context>
      <utterance>No comprende? Necessita take off tu comisitas. Your shirt. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Maria unhooks her bra. A purplish cantaloupe-size abscess grows on her left breast. Cindy's covers her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Por favor, Maria. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Maria puts back on her blouse.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. Jesus Christ. Maria...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Maria starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Maria! Que eso? Why didn't you come in sooner? Why did you wait this long?! Eso es muy mal. Very bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dr. Feinberg walks into the room.</context>
      <utterance>How could you look at yourself in the mirror and pretend it's not there? How long have you been pretending?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy points to Maria.</context>
      <utterance>Cindy. What's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Feinberg takes Cindy's clipboard from her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Her breast. Her breast!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for the trembling Maria's blouse. Maria flinches.</context>
      <utterance>I can take over from here. He talks to Maria calm and clear. DR. FEINBERG  Hello Mrs. Guevara. I'm Dr. Feinberg. I'm your DOCTOR. Let me see. It's OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Feinberg turns to Cindy.</context>
      <utterance>It's probably been growing for years!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to Maria and places his hand on her shoulder. DR. FEINBERG (cont'd) It's going to be alright, Mrs. Guevara. Cindy backs out of the room. Blue Valentine Official Green Script as of 6/9/09 74.</context>
      <utterance>Out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode>ON PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma'am you're going to have to bring him in...you have to bring him in...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him an in-patient form. Dean looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>Where's my wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mimi cups her hand over the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mimi returns to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You need to fill that out, sir. You can go over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean hands her back the clipboard.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing wrong with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you need to fill it out, sir. Bring it back up to me when you're done.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mimi lowers the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Where's my wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's your wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cynthia. Where is she?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you Dean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the phone on hold and disappears into the clinic. Dean turns around and looks at the people in the waiting room. He has a slight confrontation with a gang banger. Cindy approaches from the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, are you deaf or are you just dumb?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>TURNS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saved you a trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see that. How'd you get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mimi appears behind Cindy.</context>
      <utterance>I got a ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- I was going out of my mind. I didn't know if there's an emergency. I didn't know if Francis was hurt. Did you think about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean nods. He looks over Cindy's shoulder at Mimi.</context>
      <utterance>Frankie's fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mimi sits down at her desk and picks up a ringing phone.</context>
      <utterance>Taking pictures?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy crosses the counter, grabs the bags by Dean's feet. CINDY (to Mimi) (cont'd) Give me a few minutes.</context>
      <utterance>We're not going to do this here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be right here. Don't let him brainwash you again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy walks out of the clinic hefting her bags.</context>
      <utterance>Live your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean grabs the remaining luggage and follows, throwing back a look to both Mimi and the Gang-banger.</context>
      <utterance>Help me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>127 127</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dean follows behind Cindy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy hurls the bags into the back of the car. Dean helps.</context>
      <utterance>Last night got fucked up, OK? I know it. I know I'm lazy, I eat too much, I drink too much, I drive you crazy with all my jealous bullshit. I fuck up. I know I'm clumsy. But you're not trying anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't make me be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you drunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you drive?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him the keys.</context>
      <utterance>No, you go. Take the car home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy walks back to the clinic. Dean follows close behind.</context>
      <utterance>You don't think about anyone but yourself. Do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got no time for me anymore. It all goes to this fucking job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how many sacrifices I make every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You! What about me? I gave up everything for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy enters through the electric doors.</context>
      <utterance>I never asked you to! I can't take this shit anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take what? What can't you take... The truth? I know you can't... You never could.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right Dean, I can't take the truth...I've had it with the truth or whatever it is you make up along the way and label as truth... You win. I give up... I've been lying to you for a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me, Dean. I didn't want to hurt you. But I'm not the person you fell in love with. And you won't let me be anything but that person. That's why I can't look at you. Because every time I do I can't stop thinking about how much I want you to hate me. But you're too stupid to see it, and too chicken shit to do anything about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her in a hug. Her arms are pressed into her side.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a second...</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls back his fist and swings, hitting the metal locker behind Cindy's head. He repeats the blows with thunderous rage. Feinberg enters the room.</context>
      <utterance>I don't love you anymore... Why can't you stop loving me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean turns and takes a blind swing at Feinberg. One blow and Feinberg reels against the metal lockers. He hits the ground with a thud. His nose gushes blood. Dean paces around Feinberg like a caged animal. He pulls down a locker with his hand. It crashes to the floor. Cindy kneels over Feinberg.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on!?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Let me see.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean jerks Cindy up off the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You're done. Leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hits Dean with a flurry of flailing fists.</context>
      <utterance>Get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Punches catch him in the nose. Cindy bullies Dean backwards with repeated shoves to the chest. He backs up down the hallway. Mimi stands in the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>You son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god. Call 911. I'm going to call</utterance>
   <speaker>911.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doors slide open and Dean backs outside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She has emptied herself. Her whole body is numb and it feels as if she is floating in space. Anger overcomes Dean. He hits the dashboard with concrete fists.</context>
      <utterance>I want a divorce!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the suitcase next to him and opens the door. He throws it through the air into a FIELD - trying rid himself of pain, longing, and desperation. He clutches his wedding ring, but can't yank it off of his fat finger. Finally, he gets it off and tosses it into the field. The moment he releases it, he wishes he hadn't. MOMENTS LATER - Dean and Cindy search for the ring. It is lost. Music begins to play in reverse.</context>
      <utterance>I know!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points at his face. Behind Jerry, Cindy peeks out from the kitchen at the end of the hallway. It is the first time she has seen Dean since the fight. She is shocked.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't know if it was pot luck so I brought an eggplant.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean holds out his hand. Jerry looks Dean up and down.</context>
      <utterance>Face looks like an eggplant, don't it? How you doing sir, I'm Dean.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy squeezes by her father to Dean. The expression on her face says it all. Dean hands her the flowers, leans in and kisses her. While he's there he whispers.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stole these for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean nods. She leads him down the hall. Jerry stops, turns. JERRY (to Cindy) Tell him to take off his shoes. Dean removes his boots. A toe wiggles out of a holey sock. He gathers the hole and tucks it between his big toe and his second toe. Cindy leads him by the hand to the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does and is interrupted by... The FAINT SOUND of her parents fighting downstairs.</context>
      <utterance>No. It feels good. Keep doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...She's going to struggle the rest of her Goddamn life with that fucking loser. And that's okay with you. Sit there...sit there on your fat ass don't do a goddamn thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? They'll stop soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to miss my train.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy goes over to her stereo and turns on some music, low - it is the same song that Dean and Cindy listened to in the moon room. It drowns out some of the fighting. She approaches him, starts unbuttoning his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise me one thing... you'll never let me become an adult.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him. Opens up his shirt. Reveals a severely bruised torso. He winces a bit from the movement. She redresses his wounds, nursing him back to health.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses his chest. Dean starts getting underneath Cindy's clothes. He places his palm on her belly.</context>
      <utterance>That motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From here on out, their actions increase with urgency. Each moment that goes by makes them more and more desperate to feel the other's skin. They are down to their underwear when they hear a door slam downstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are your parent's gonna walk in on us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They make sweet love.</context>
      <utterance>They never come in here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy's car sits in the driveway. Cindy gets out, grabs her suitcase. Jerry emerges from the house. Cindy kneels down and hugs Frankie. She is electricity in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy! Daddy! Mommy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who had candy for breakfast?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frankie leaps into Dean's arms. Cindy walks up to the house.</context>
      <utterance>Hey sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was Frankie?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was good. Are you OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy kisses her father on the cheek, closes the screen door. DEAN (holding Frankie) I can't play right now, okay? He releases his wired daughter who runs circles around him. Dean walks up to the porch. He and Jerry stand face to face.</context>
      <utterance>I'm OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jerry backs away. Dean walks past him into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Do you want to get out of my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean closes the screen door behind him and locks it. Jerry pulls on the door.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what happened up there. But please Dean, come on. Don't push it. Let it be...</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean calls back.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! You can't lock me out of my own house!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep an eye on Francis.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blue Valentine Official Green Script as of 6/9/09 84.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have my oxygen! Hey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fear strikes Dean. He presses the base of his palms into his eyes, rubbing until he sees stars.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not coming home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not alone here Cynthia. We have a little girl. We need to think about her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am thinking about her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All you're thinking about is yourself. You. Francis is gonna grow up in a broken home and that's OK with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't let her grow up in a home where her parents don't love each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean approaches her from behind. Reaches out...</context>
      <utterance>Don't love each other? I've only ever loved you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean looks up. He has tears in his eyes. Frankie touches one as it streams down his face.</context>
      <utterance>I want to stay at Grampa's house next time for fifty nights.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you crying?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>145 CONTINUED:  145</speaker>
      <mode>2</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cindy comes down the stairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dean stands and picks up Frankie. He walks to Cindy and hands her over.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy's gonna go now, OK.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dean walks out the front door where he passes Jerry who stands on the porch. He moves across the lawn to the sidewalk. Vermillion light falls in the sky. Cindy sets Frankie down and she runs out the door. Jerry catches the little girl by the arm and holds her tight. Dean walks toward the horizon. FRANKIE (SCREAMS) (cont'd) Daddy! Dean stops and turns. Cindy walks to the porch.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry releases her and Frankie runs fast to Dean. She jumps at him to go into his arms. He doesn't pick her up. From the porch Cindy and Jerry watch Dean as he points to them. Frankie doesn't move. Dean yells for her to go back. Frankie heads back to her mother, confused. Cindy kneels down and takes her in her arms. Families light fireworks off in the middle of the streets.</context>
      <utterance>Let her go, Dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
