<movie id="106" title="Bringing Out the Dead">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The radio continues: "Zebra, 13Z, 524 East 17--"</context>
      <utterance>Thursday started out with a bang: a gunshot to the chest on a drug deal gone bad. Heat, humidity, moonlight-- all the elements in place for a long weekend. I was good at my job: there were periods when my hands moved with a speed and skill beyond me and my mind worked with a cool authority I had never known. But in the last year I had started to lose that control. Things had turned bad. I hadn't saved anyone for months. I just needed a few slow nights, a week without tragedy followed by a couple of days off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ambulance breaks to a halt in front of a row of vintage walk-ups. Frank and Larry jump out: Frank lugs the EKG monitor and airway bag, Larry the drug box, yellow oxygen pack slung over his shoulder. Neighbors crowd around.</context>
      <utterance>We're there.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which apartment? Which apartment?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move back. Where's the stairs? 5A.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The front door opens, a young boy holding it. Author's note: in emergency situations, either on the street or in the hospital, it is assumed there is continual background noise--voices, sirens, cries, questions, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus, it's Mr. Burke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were just watching TV and Dad yelled out and started punching his chest, next thing he locked himself in the bathroom. I said we were gonna call you guys and he said not to. He was crying, I never heard him crying before, then he sorta stopped. We pulled him out and put him on the bed. Frank and Larry moving the body to the floor:</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long ago did he stop breathing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please, you gotta do something.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe ten minutes. Woman on the phone tried to tell us how to do CPR.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry ripping open Mr. Burke's shirt, prepping electrode patches, hooking wires, Frank opening Burke's mouth, feeling a puff of gas escape; Larry calling for backup. Burke's EKG rhythm on the monitor a flat green line. Frank's training takes over: he injects the long steel laryngoscope down Burke's throat, he finds a vein, injects epinephrine, followed by atrophine, followed by another epi: no response on the monitor. Larry pulls out the paddles:</context>
      <utterance>We'll do all we can.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Larry activates defibrillator, shock--Burke's body heaves. Sweat drips from Larry's nose onto Burke's chest.</context>
      <utterance>Clear! Clear!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shock him again. This time the body moves less. Frank glances up: Mr. and Mrs. Burke's wedding photo sits on the nightstand. Other pictures: a day at the beach, a young serviceman, happy parents. Frank's mind drifts:</context>
      <utterance>No more, please don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Frank feels Burke's heart beneath cracked ribs. The EEG remains flat. He's dead. It's time to quit.</context>
      <utterance>In the last year I had come to believe in such things as spirits leaving the body and not wanting to be put back, spirits angry at the awkward places death had left them. I understood how crazy it was to think this way, but I was convinced if I turned around, I'd see Old Man Burke standing at the window, watching, waiting for us to finish.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any music?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Music. I think it helps if you play something he liked.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John enters crying. Mary repeats softly:</context>
      <utterance>John, play the Sinatra.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John exits. Frank notices Mary for the first time: blond hair dyed black, cut short, loose fitting tank dress, black makeup running down her cheeks. He notices her prom picture, glances back to Mary: it seems she hasn't smiled since that day eight years before. Something special about her, that something that hits you right away. "September of My Years" plays from the other room. Frank continues massaging Mr. Burke's chest (now to Sinatra beat), even though it's hopeless. Larry returns:</context>
      <utterance>Play the Sinatra.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank feels something strange, looks into Burke's pupils, checks his neck pulse, wrist pulse. His eyes go to Larry:</context>
      <utterance>It's OK, Frank. We can call it. Eighty- three.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we can't. He's got a pulse.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry checks the monitor: the green line up and down. Mary senses a change in status:</context>
      <utterance>No shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he going to be alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A distant siren signals the arrival of backup. Frank turns to Larry:</context>
      <utterance>His heart's beating.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks from Mary back to Mr. Burke--breathing but comatose.</context>
      <utterance>Have 'em bring up a stretcher.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>GRISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey partner. Your man does not look well. They're not gonna appreciate you inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Griss, let us in.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Griss pushes a button, activating the automatic door, striking the bandaged leg of a man lying down on a stretcher in the hall. Larry and Frank wheel Burke inside. A pleading family tries to follow. Griss stretches out his hand:</context>
      <utterance>Things are backing up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRISS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mary, John and Mrs. Burke rush in from the street, hoping some miracle has occurred during the drive to the hospital, approach the sign-in desk. Frank and Larry pass four stretchers lined against the wall-- a passage nicknamed "Skid Row" leading past triage NURSE CONSTANCE's station.</context>
      <utterance>You can't go in there, folks.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CONSTANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nurse Constance turns back to the nervous man seated beside her:</context>
      <utterance>Just keep moving. Don't even slow down.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CONSTANCE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Larry and Frank slow at the last Skid Row stretchers. On one, NOEL, a young dark-skinned man with chaotic mess of dreadlocks, pulls feverishly at his restraints:</context>
      <utterance>Sir, you say you've been snorting cocaine for three days and now you feel your heart is beating too fast and you would like us to help you. To tell the truth, I don't see why I should. If I'm mistaken, correct me. Did we sell you the cocaine? Did we push it up your nose?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the next stretcher a man with feet swollen purple like prize eggplants replies:</context>
      <utterance>For God's sake, give me some water.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG FEET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Goddamn civilians.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NURSE CRUPP stops Frank and Larry as they approach the Critical care room. inside, the staff appears as if under siege by a battalion of shriveled men and women lying on a field of white sheets.</context>
      <utterance>Give me some water!</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CRUPP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't take another step. We're on diversion. Can't accept any more patients. Your dispatcher should have told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got him at Eighteen and Second. You're closest.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CRUPP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where will I put him, Frank? Look. Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wanted to come here. Said the nurses at Misery were the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. You are a very kind man. I can see that. A man like you could not refuse a poor sick dying helpless man a small cup of water.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. I have to stay with my patient.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG FEET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DR. HAZMAT, 30, steps over.</context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up! If it wasn't for these dun feet I'd get up and kick your ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Godammit, guys, what are you doing to me? We're all backed up in here. Christ, would you look at him? He's gonna need the works. What's wrong with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should know. You pronounced him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me he was dead. Flatline.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He got better.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate pronouncing people dead over the phone.  Better, huh? They're fixed and dilated. He's plant food.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CRUPP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We stole a stretcher from X-ray. No pad on it, but I don't think he'll mind. Put him in three, next to the overdose.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back at SECURITY, the Burkes confront Griss.</context>
      <utterance>He's our lowest priority now. He shouldn't even be here. All this technology. What a waste.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In CRITICAL CARE, Larry wheels Burke into unit three as Dr. Hazmat turns Frank to face the room, explaining:</context>
      <utterance>Please folks, step back.  Don't make me take off my sunglasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hazmat pulls out a vial marked with a red skull and crossbones, shows it to Frank.</context>
      <utterance>First-time heart attack, age 45. Should have gone to the CCU ten hours ago. There's three bodies up there Mike the one you just brought in. over there, two AIDS patients, one in twelve filling up with liquid. I'm gonna hafta intubate because the kid's mother won't sign the Do Not Resuscitate. Mercy killing doesn't translate well in Spanish. It's a sin to tube this kid. Three more ODs from some new killer junk. They call it Red Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Water, water, water, doctor man, water.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A mix of heroin and I don't know what else, some kind of amino acid maybe. Stuff so strong they're drinking it with grain alcohol. You have to use ten times the usual amount of Narcan and watch out when they wake up, liable to go nuts on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He one of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's Noel. Used to be a regular off and on, hasn't been in in a while. He seized and almost coded--I gave him a hypertonic solution. He drank so much the kidneys were taking out salt. One for the textbooks.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh doctor, you are the greatest. You must help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG FEET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For God's sake, give him a drink of water.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nurse Crupp pulls on Hazmat's arm.</context>
      <utterance>I am helping you, Noel. You could die if you drink more water.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She points to Burke. His monitor is ringing like a fire alarm. Hazmat and Crupp rush over, wave to others:</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As the staff crowds around Burke, pulling the paddles from off the monitor, Frank, pushing his stretcher away, notices Big Feet climb onto his infected feet, hobble over, work to untie Noel.</context>
      <utterance>Crupp, start CPR. Milagros, get me an epi. Odette wake up Dr. Stark. Tell him I need a blood gas, stat.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless you sir, bless you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG FEET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank heads down Skid Row pushing the stretcher, passing Nurse Constance speaking with a man with a gash over his eye:</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CONSTANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank pushes the automatic door button--and is suddenly hit from behind by Noel. The stretcher spins sideways. Noel dives out the doors for the water fountain, snorting up water like a bull. Mary Burke, standing with her family, looks at Frank.</context>
      <utterance>... so you get drunk every day and you fall down. Tell me why we should help you when you're going to get drunk tomorrow and fall down again?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's very very sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know him. That's Noel.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd better go outside. Quickly. Frank and Mary step out into the humid night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there any chance?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noel, Noel, it's me, Mary. From 17th Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary, Mary, Mary. I'm so thirsty. They won't give me anything to drink. Please, Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank watches: Mary returns with a cup of water, gives it to a grateful Noel.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get you some.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't do that.  The doctor seems to think he's suffering from some rare disorder.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary starts to cry. Frank fumbles in his pocket, finds a tissue, gives it to her.</context>
      <utterance>It's not so rare. He grew up on our street. He's had a rough life and he's a little crazy from it, but that's no excuse for not giving someone a lousy cup of water.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father's dying, Noel.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noel hugs her clumsily, his shoulders bobbing. Frank watches, realizing this is what he should have done for her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Mary, Mary, Mary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Chinese close in five minutes. Beef lo mein. It's been on my mind since I woke. Whatjathink?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think the moment that food hits your mouth we'll get a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Franks turns, gets jammed up behind a pimp car at Second and Avenue B, a corner populated by pushers and hookers. TWO WHORES stand in front of an abandoned building. Frank turns to look.</context>
      <utterance>Turn here. You missed it. The Chink is on 3rd.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHORE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second whore, wearing a yellow vinyl coat, turns. She has a face that instantly freezes Frank: the Rose face. Pregnant, she gestures to her belly:</context>
      <utterance>Hey ambulance man. What you looking at?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHORE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty soon you'll be coming for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank hits the whoop-whoop siren. The pimps in the black BMW jump, look back, realize its only an ambulance, and pull away.</context>
      <utterance>Some partner you are Frank. I coulda walked there faster. I'm starving and you stop to talk to hookers. You're making me nuts. Is that what you're trying to do, drag me down with you to nutsville?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no!--I just remembered.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so stupid. I had beef lo mein last night. I can't eat the same thing two nights in a row. It's almost two o'clock, what the hell am I gonna do? What you getting?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, you don't eat food.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I eat. I just haven't had coffee yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank speeds up Avenue B. Noel, wearing generic homeless combat fatigues, muttering to his friends in Hell, passes on the sidewalk. Frank notices another hooker, catches her face: the same face as the pregnant Whore 2. The Rose face. His mind drifts:</context>
      <utterance>Coffee and whiskey, lucky you ain't dead with that diet. Wait, I've got it. Half fried chicken with fries. Let's go, hurry up. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rose was getting closer. Ever since the call a month before, when I'd lost her, she seemed like all the girls in the neighborhood. One of the first things you learn is to avoid bad memories. I used to be an expert, but lately I'd found some holes. Anything could trigger it. The last month belonged to Rose, but there were a hundred more ready to come out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Larry gets his chicken, chats with counter clerk, returns.</context>
      <utterance>These spirits were part of the job. It was impossible to pass a building that didn't bold the spirit of something: the eyes of a corpse, the screams of a loved one. All bodies leave their mark. You cannot be near the new dead without feeling it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Larry climbs in, sets his take-out on the dash, hands Frank a coffee. A police walkie-talkie is in the front tray.</context>
      <utterance>I could handle that. What haunted me now was more savage: spirits born half-finished, homicides, suicides, overdoses, innocent or not, accusing me of being there, witnessing a humiliation which they could never forgive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what. The radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE DISPATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ladder Four, respond to a 10-22 four flight residential, 317 East 32nd.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do it. It might be a good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted it turned off. There's no such thing as a good fire. People get burned up. They can't breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we're here for. Come on, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't push it, Larry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're burned out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One-three Zebra. Zebra three, I need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, he's giving it to us anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zebra, are you there? I'm holding an unconscious at First and St. Marks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! It's three o'clock. That can only mean one thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Mr. Oh. I'm not answering it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer the radio Zebra. You know it's that time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four times this week I've had him. Aren't there any other units out there? Don't answer the radio. They'll give it to someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Neither moves.</context>
      <utterance>Thirteen Zebra. One-Three Zebra. You're going out of service in two seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Frank, when I say don't answer it, that means answer it.  You can do that for me at least.  Three Zebra.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Zebra. You'll be driving to the man who needs no introduction, chronic caller of the year three straight and shooting for number four. The duke of drunk, the king of stink, our most frequent flier, Mr. Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten-four.  Don't go. Not this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, it's a street job, easy except for the smell. We'll just throw him in back and zip over to Mercy--no blood, no dying, that's how I look at it. He's just a drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not our job to taxi drunks around.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll just keep calling.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's gonna die someday causa that bum, going to have a cardiac and the only medics will be taking care of Mr. Oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MALE STREET PERSON #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's bad mister. He ain't eaten nuthin all day, he's seizing and throwing up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's different?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE STREET PERSON #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says his feet hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well why didn't you say so?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE STREET PERSON #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's sick. You gotta help him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's fine. He can walk to the hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE STREET PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walk? You crazy? He's in a wheelchair.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank crouches over Oh, tries to pull Oh's pants over his white, dirt-stained ass. Oh moans:</context>
      <utterance>Don't start that. I've seen him walk. He walks better than me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, oh, oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry and Frank get Oh to his feet only to have him stumble over his lowered trousers. This time Frank lifts him, sets his white ass cheeks into the wheelchair. They push him toward the ambulance.</context>
      <utterance>That's him, Mr. Oh.  Get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck! Get better!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Faster! God!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Faster!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GRISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank and Larry stand beside Oh slumped in his wheelchair. Fellow drunks welcome their comrade from plastic chairs. Nurse Constance escorts a young man from the triage area:</context>
      <utterance>Get that stinky-assed motherfucking bug-ridden skell out of my face.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CONSTANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Griss shows young man the door.</context>
      <utterance>I would have to register you to give you something to eat and my conscience just will not allow that. Griss, the gentleman wants to leave.  He looks pale. You're not eating enough. You need more fiber.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's wasted. That's my diagnosis: shit-faced.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CONSTANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just needs a bath and some food. Take him in back and see if you can find a stretcher.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Griss returns as Crupp calls from critical care area:</context>
      <utterance>She's nuts. That's why he comes here. She encourages him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CRUPP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you dare! That's my last stretcher. This is not a homeless shelter. He'll have to wait in the lobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry and Frank turn, secretly pleased, and wheel Mr. Oh outside.</context>
      <utterance>No way man. Not even in the corner. Griss cannot abide the funk tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my first cigarette in over a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first is always the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the waiting that's killing me, not knowing, you know? It's really hard on my mother. The doctor doesn't think my father'll make it. He says he was dead too long, after six minutes the brain starts to die and once that goes, close the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean if he was dead, I could handle that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least he's got people around him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not so sure. My father and I haven't spoken in three years. When my brother called to say my father was having a heart attack, that he'd locked himself in the bathroom, all the way going over I was thinking how I was gonna tell him what a bastard he was. Then when I got up the stairs and we moved him onto the bed, I thought of all these other things I wanted to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even when you say the things, there's always more things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now, I'm more worried about my mother than anything. They won't let her see my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go home. Take her home. Get some rest. Not going to find anything out now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry walks back with a coffee for himself and a brown bag beer for Frank.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I told her. If she could just see him a second, then I could take her home.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to switch. I wheel, you heal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RADIO DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry driving at a good clip, riding both the gas and the break pedals, enjoying the newfound freedom of movement.</context>
      <utterance>12 David on the corner of Thirty- eight and Two you'll find a three- car accident, two taxis and a taxi. One-two Henry, 427 East Two-two, report of a very bad smell. No further information ...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry, swing over on Eighth. We're gonna hafta run one of these calls.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank places both hands on the dash as Larry squeals around a corner.</context>
      <utterance>Relax, will you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Larry slows down on a side street. Frank turns to watch a homeless man. The man looks back: it's Rose. The Rose face.</context>
      <utterance>The biggest problem with not driving is that whenever there's a patient in back you're also in the back. The doors close, you're trapped. Four in the morning is always the worst time for me, just before dawn, just when you've been lulled into thinking it might be safe to close your eyes for one minute. That's when I first found Rose ...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank turns to Larry:</context>
      <utterance>She was on the sidewalk, not breathing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not feeling very well, Larry. I say we go back to the hospital and call it a night.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no sick time, Frank. No time of any kind. Everyone knows that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take me back, put me to bed; I surrender. We've done enough damage tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take things too seriously. Look at us, we're cruising around, talking, taking some quiet time, getting paid for it. We've got a good job here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry pulls into the Jacob Riis projects by the river, slows to a stop. Larry cuts the lights, not bothering to inform his partner what his partner already knows: they're taking a rest.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, you ever think of doing anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry tosses the cigarette out the window, leans against the door jab, closes his eyes. In a second he's asleep. Frank turns down the radio volume: the calls are fewer and further between now. Frank leans back, tries to rest:</context>
      <utterance>Sure, I'm taking the captain's exam next year. After the kids are in school, Louise can go back to the post office and, I thought, what the hell, I'll start my own medic service. Out on the Island the volunteers are becoming salaried municipal. It's just a matter of time and who you know. Someday it's going to be Chief Larry calling the shots.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>TIMECUT: radio wakes Frank from his reverie.</context>
      <utterance>I'd always had nightmares, but now the ghosts didn't wait for me to sleep. I drank every day. Help others and you help yourself, that was my motto, but I hadn't saved anyone in months. It seemed all my patients were dying. I'd waited, sure the sickness would break, tomorrow night, the next call, the feeling would drop away. More than anything else I wanted to sleep like that, close my eyes and drift away ...</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zebra. One-three Zebra.  Zebra, answer the radio. Come on, I've got one for you. Pick up the radio and push the button on the side and speak into the front.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zebra.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Male bleeding, corner of Houston and One. No further information.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten-four. Frank hangs up, bangs Larry's steering wheel:</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Larry instinctively reaches for the ignition key, starts the engine, drops the ambulance into gear, hits lights, jerks the EMS bus away, still half asleep.</context>
      <utterance>We have a call Chief. Somebody's bleeding, Houston and First.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noel has sliced up a tire and fastened the pieces with string over his shoulders. Tin cans circle his wrists and ankles. One hand carries a broken bottle, the other a stringless violin. Frank jumps back inside as Noel rams the window, leaving stains from his blood-matted dreadlocks. Larry calls for backup: medics, police, firemen, anybody. The side window glass bends as Noel rams his head against it. Frank reaches for the short club between the seats; Noel holds the jagged bottle to his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noel drops the bottle. Frank rolls down the window.</context>
      <utterance>Noel, don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I can't do it. I came out of the desert.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came out of the hospital. You were tied down and hallucinating. You got some bad chemicals in your head, Noel. There's some medicine at the hospital that will fix that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noel swings his bloody dreadlocks: Frank ducking, getting splattered anyway, rolling up the window.</context>
      <utterance>No, no medicine!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BLACK PUNK calls from the crowd:</context>
      <utterance>He got you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK PUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noel, spraying blood, chases the Punk. The crowd scatters. Noel trips, falls to the sidewalk. Frank, carrying the short bat, gets out, walks over, hunches beside Noel:</context>
      <utterance>Do it! Man wants to die. Take him out! I know how to kill that mother.  Pop, pop.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noel, you didn't let me finish. We have rules against killing people on the street. Looks bad, but there's a special room at the hospital for terminating. A nice quiet room with a big bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man, do you mean that?  Thank you man, thank you. How?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A siren draws closer, Noel gets to his feet as Larry opens the rear doors.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you have your choice: pills, injection, gas.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A second ambulance skids to a stop. TOM WALLS, 35, a 220 pound bald-headed bruiser, gets out.</context>
      <utterance>I think pills. Yes, pills, definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Tom Walls, that crazy motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Used to be my partner.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, this the guy you called about? I know him.  You give my friend here any trouble and I'll kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, at the hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This looks like a very bad man I took in a couple weeks ago, a man who'd been holding two priests hostage with a screwdriver. I told him if I ever caught him making trouble again I'd kick the murdering life outta him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not worth it, Tom. He's surrendering.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No prisoners. Don't worry, Frank, just a little psychological first aid. Walls hauls back, swings at Noel; Noel ducks.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Walls throws Noel against the bus, knocks him down, sets to kicking him.</context>
      <utterance>Stay still, dammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noel moans. Larry sticks his head out the back of the bus:</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it, Tom!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a double shooting three blocks- up. First and Third. confirmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walls releasing Noel as Noel scrambles into the bus, Frank stepping over him, Larry climbing into the driver's seat, Frank closing the doors. Noel trembles:</context>
      <utterance>We'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry squeals off full gun, all sirens blaring: the Wah, the Yelp, the Super Yelp. Strobe bar, side strobes, quarter panel strobes. Rock n' roll.</context>
      <utterance>At the hospital. You told me at the hospital.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANK &amp; WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>EMS. Move it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BYSTANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two boys, DRUG DEALERS, lie bleeding on the sidewalk. Frank drops to his knees beside one, Walls the other. Larry wheels out the stretcher.</context>
      <utterance>Man just walked up and shot 'em. Not a word. Man, that was cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you hit?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE IN CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two white vials roll out of the Drug Dealer's shirt: marked with red skull and crossbones. Frank looks over--they're gone, swiped by eager hands. Listening for a heartbeat, Frank calls to Walls:</context>
      <utterance>Outlaw did this. He works for Cy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major Tom, I'm going to Misery. You take yours to Bellvue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna feel a stick in your arm. Don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUG DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to die. I'm the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUG DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus, I don't want to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up. You're going to die and he's not. Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUG DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold my hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. I got to do the other arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUG DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Frank feels for a pulse, listens with the stethoscope: nothing. Larry opens the doors.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right. We're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank turns to his partner:</context>
      <utterance>Noel, let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry and Frank pull the dead boy out of the bus.</context>
      <utterance>He's not breathing. Call a code.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers a cigarette. She accepts:</context>
      <utterance>Hello again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. They're prescription.  Works better with a little whiskey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry jumps theatrically out of the ambulance, swings the mop wildly over his head:</context>
      <utterance>That's my brother's problem. He's passed out inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary laughs once, less than a second. She notices blood stains on Frank's shirt:</context>
      <utterance>That's it! I can't do it anymore!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That boy you brought in, he was shot, wasn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think this place stinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our Lady of Misery.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see my father?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's crazy in there. What's wrong with that doctor? He keeps mumbling, poking himself in the eye when he talks to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's working a double shift.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does.</context>
      <utterance>Thing is, I'm supposed to be the fuckup. The one on the stretcher in there--that's supposed to be me. With my parents crying out here. I got a lot of guilt, you know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father's in a coma, now my mother's going crazy. It's like she's in a trance.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She should go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks at her, trying to say the right thing. He notices Mrs. Burke coming from inside.</context>
      <utterance>I'd take her, but then who would stay here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Burke, dazed, steps out. They join her.</context>
      <utterance>Here she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saw him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They showed me someone. It wasn't him. It wasn't my husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Burke, please, they'll take care of him. You should go home now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drifts away. Frank speaks to Mary:</context>
      <utterance>I should know my own husband. They wouldn't let me see him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry and I'll drop her back home. Help me get her to the ambulance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk Mrs. Burke to 13 Zebra.</context>
      <utterance>You want some coffee? I have some apple sauce cake too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary watches as Larry backs up the EMS vehicle, Frank sitting in the back with her mother, pulls into first light.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>TIME DISSOLVES: Frank paces the room. Pours himself another drink.</context>
      <utterance>Saving someone's life is like falling in love, the best drug in the world. For days, sometimes weeks afterwards, you walk the street making infinite whatever you see. Once, for weeks I couldn't feel the earth. Everything I touched became light. Horns played in my shoes; flowers fell from my pockets ...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>TIME DISSOLVE: window is closed. Frank tosses in his sleep. Nightstand alarm buzzes. Frank sits up, looks at the clock. Stretching his neck, he walks over to the sink, runs water on his hands and face.</context>
      <utterance>You wonder if you've become immortal, as if you saved your own life as well. What was once criminal and happenstance suddenly makes sense. God has passed through you, why deny it, that for a moment there, God was you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Capt. Barney looks over to MISS WILLIAMS, his secretary, seated at a desk perpendicular to his:</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPT. BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I going to to do with this guy?  Pierce, I was just on the phone with Borough Command. Out of twelve shifts this month, you've been late for nine, sick four and that includes the shift where you came late and went home early.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sick. That's what I've been telling you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPT. BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're killing me, you know that? You got no sick time according to Command. I've been told to terminate.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. I'll just get my things out of the locker.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPT. BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never fired anyone in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Captain. Don't take it too hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPT. BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody tells me to fire anyone. I told them: shove it up the big one.  Sorry.  I said, you want to fire him, come over and do it yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know they won't do it. It's up to you. You gotta be strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPT. BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel for you, but we got an emergency here. It's a weekend of full moons. Everyone's called in sick. Larry, Veeber, Stanley too. We need bodies out there. I had to put Marcus on Twelve Young. You know he's not supposed to work two nights in a row.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You swore you'd fire me if I came in late again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPT. BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll fire you tomorrow. Hell, better than that, I'll forward you some sick time. A week, two weeks off-- how about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think a week's gonna do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPT. BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Pierce.  You're going out with Marcus. Duty calls. The City needs you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Lord mother man, you look like hell. What were you drinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The captain almost fired me tonight. I'm on my way out. Anytime now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody gets fired. Look at me. Only thing they might do is transfer you to the Bronx. You look like you aged ten years since I rode with you last.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ghosts--</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever notice people who see shit always, are crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think the worst is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LOVE, a black, tough-talking female dispatcher, comes on the radio:</context>
      <utterance>It can always get worse. You can't change what's out there, only where you're coming from. You got to let the Lord take over, in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER LOVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve Young.  Let's go, Twelve Young. Answer the radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marcus, it's Love. I haven't heard her in months.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She only works when I'm on. I make her wait and it drives her crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true that you and Love went on a blind date?  She hit you with a bottle?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She loves me the way no woman ever has.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER LOVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve Young, I don't have time for your games. Now answer me or do I have to come out there myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I usually don't do calls before coffee. But I think it might do you some good.  Twelve Young is here and I'm gonna take care of you, baby. Don't you worry about a thing, yahear, cause Marcus is alive and on arrival.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER LOVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not your baby, Young, I'm not your mother either. You're going to a cardiac arrest, Avenue C and Ninth, northeast corner. It's a club. Take the side entrance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus flips on the lights and siren.</context>
      <utterance>Ten-four, hon.  This is for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going to be all right, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead and there's nothing we can do. Come on, Frank, that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not dead. It's a heroin overdose. Break out the Narcon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead unless you folks want to stop bullshitting me and tell it straight. Then, Lord willing, we'll try to bring him back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BYSTANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He broke up with his old lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLFRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't break up. We were just seeing other people.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still waiting and this young man is still dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BYSTANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girlfriend shoots a look at the Bystander. Marcus just stands, hands on hips, silent. Frank opens the drug box. The Drummer relents:</context>
      <utterance>She broke his heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, all right, he's been snorting that Red Death stuff. Been going for four days.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>IB Bangin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you mean IB Bangin? What kind of name is IB Bangin?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLFRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Frederick. Frederick Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Freddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLFRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Frederick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus assists them as Frank breaks the cellophane off a syringe, locates a vial of Narcon. Frank gives Marcus the high sign--Marcus raises his hands:</context>
      <utterance>Okay, IB Bangin, we're gonna bring you back. Every person here grab the hand of the person next to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank injects IB Bangin: he responds to the Narcon with a jolt, opening his eyes, raising his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Lord, here I am again to ask one more chance for a sinner. Bring back IB Bangin, Lord. You have the power, the might, the super light, to spare this worthless man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLFRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frederick!</utterance>
   <speaker>BYSTANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh wow, man. Oh wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>IB BANGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLFRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You died, you stupid bastard. I warned you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are awesome.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank and the Girlfriend guide IB Bangin to the door as Marcus collects the gear.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows Frank, IB Bangin and Girlfriend out, calling for the crowd to clear.</context>
      <utterance>Not us. The first step is Love. The second is Mercy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy I brought in yesterday, post-cardiac arrest. He's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burke. You won't believe it. He's showing cognitive signs. He started with spontaneous respiration, now he's fighting to pull out the tube. Had to sedate him. He's in a CAT scan. I'm giving him every test I can: thromboytics, steroids, nitrodrips, heparin.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knows? It's all lower-brain-stem- activity. The heart refuses to stabilize--he's coded eleven times since he got here. This guy's a fighter. Every time the Valium wears off he starts yanking those restraints.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The family know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank nods, walks down Skid Row, passing Nurse Constance lecturing IB Bangin:</context>
      <utterance>I wanted to bring them in, to see if he'd respond to voices, but they weren't in the waiting room. The guy's daughter was in my face all last night and when I finally have something positive to tell her, she's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CONSTANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... you put poison in your veins and now that you're breathing again you can't wait to say thank you and go back to poison shopping. Well, since we saved your life, maybe you could do us a favor and stop breathing in another city next time ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ever tell you about the time years ago I was on this ledge uptown, trying to talk this psycho inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the guy jumped and you almost fell. No, you never told me that story.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you never listened. I was going, man, if someone on high hadn't pulled me in. I had put all I had into saving this dumbass lowlife suicidal that when he went down, there was a part of me that wanted to go with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make a left here. I want to stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank gets out, walks over to the intercom, pushes the button for 5A. Mary answers:</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, I'm Frank Pierce, from the ambulance last night. I brought your father into the hospital and I just learned some news.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mary appears in a white sweater and simple gray skirt like schoolgirls wear. The dark makeup is gone. She looks happy.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's better, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the doctor says he's showing some movement. It's still early, it might mean nothing, but I thought you'd want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew. I sensed it when I heard your voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look so different.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. It's awful, isn't it? Night of the Living Cheerleaders.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it looks good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was going nuts in that waiting room so I came back to check on my mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sleeping.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just going to get some food. Pizza. Maybe we could.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary steps to the curb, raises her hand for a taxi. None in sight.</context>
      <utterance>You can't kill my father that easy. He'll fight forever. Like with me: hasn't talked to me in three years. But it's okay. Sometimes you have to put things behind you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be tough to get a taxi here. We can give you a ride if you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank opens the back doors of the bus, climbs in behind Mary. They sit on the bench opposite the stretcher.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the daughter of a cardiac arrest I brought in last night. I told her we'd give her a ride back to Misery. Her father's showing signs of improving.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Frank, you've got it bad, so much worse than I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry too. We gotta get some food after this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus turns on the radio, an old song from the sixties, as they head uptown.</context>
      <utterance>God help us, he's hungry too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nearby patient SCREAMS. Mary Burke SCREAMS too:</context>
      <utterance>Dad, can you hear me?  Open your eyes if you can hear me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dr. Hazmat and MILAGROS, an intern, walk over.</context>
      <utterance>He squeezed my hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be damned.  It's movement, but I'm not sure how voluntary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke's eyes fully open. His cheeks ripple and his lips smack against the tube between them. His back arches, his body shakes, his arms yank at their restraints as if reaching to pull out the wires and tubes. Green lights dance across the EKG screen, ALARMS sound: first the cardiac monitor, next the ventilator.</context>
      <utterance>He hears me. Open your eyes, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hazmat and Milagros hold down Burke's arms as Crupp prepares the Valium. Mary backs away.</context>
      <utterance>Nurse Crupp, I need ten milligrams of Valium.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They step away.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we go outside for a little while, wait until this passes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to pull that tube out. It's pretty painful--that's why they keep him sedated--but it's a good sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits across from her, wishing he could be in three seats at once, each to watch her from a different angle.</context>
      <utterance>You sure? I know my father would hate to be tied down. He wouldn't even go to the dentist.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's how it's done. You have to keep the body going until the brain and heart recover enough to go on their own.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's better, though, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus enters with a small pizza and two cokes.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm sorry, but it's important to me. I mean, a week ago I was wishing he was dead. And now I want hear his voice again, just once more-- you know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Went over to Sal's got this. There must be some place in Hell for a guy who sells a dollar-fifty a slice. I call you if anything comes up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus exits.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She says as she picks up a slice of cheese pizza.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not really hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father was a great man, you know. There was nobody he wouldn't help. You know that crazy guy Noel who I gave water to last night? He lived in our house for almost a year. A total stranger he'd do anything for, his own family though ...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's best not to ...  It's good pizza, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not as good as Nino's.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember that pizza place, Joe's on Tenth Street maybe fifteen years ago? When you ordered a pie it came with a little plastic madonna in the middle?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, or Saint Anthony. You from the neighborhood?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I grew up on Elizabeth. I went to Blessed Sacrament.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On yeah? I went to Holy Name. Where'd you go to high school?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We moved out after that. Upstate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like everybody else--except us. Always standing on the sidewalk waving goodbye to moving trucks. Your parents</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're fine. My old man was a bus driver, mom a nurse--I was sort of born to it, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You married?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, no. I was.  It's hard to explain. She had a hard time adjusting to, well, maybe it was my fault too. Pause. This thought hangs in the air. From outside: a BELLICOSE DRUNK is escorted into the ER.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>White cocksuckers! Get your--Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it always this bad in here? I mean, how does anyone survive?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been bad lately, but it's always bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long you been doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five years.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, you musta seen some things, huh? What's the worst thing you ever seen?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You learn to sort of block it out, you know, like cops fence off a crime scene. But then something good will happen and everything will just glow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must get a lot of overdoses. I bet you picked me up a couple of times.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'd remember that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe not. I was a different person then. Does everybody you meet spill their problems on you like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mostly. It must be my face. My mother always said I looked like a priest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I better go check on my father. Thanks for the pizza. I owe you one. Maybe when he gets better, you know, when we're done with all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank puts his hand out but she's already on her feet. He grabs the last slice of pizza, hands it to Griss as she heads back to Critical Care.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Griss nods.</context>
      <utterance>Look after her, Griss, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rule number one: Don't get involved with patients. Rule number two: Don't get involved with patient's daughters. You understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about rule number three: Don't get involved with dispatchers named Love.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus swings up First Ave:</context>
      <utterance>You don't know the first thing about rule number three, cannot begin to understand the complexities of that rule. Come on, let's go look at some hookers. The Kit Kat will be letting out.  Don't ever call a junkie whore a crackhead. They get real mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank watches night tableaus (police cars flashing, lovers kissing, woman crying hysterically, drunken slugfest) as his mind wanders:</context>
      <utterance>Look at these women. You can't even tell who's a hooker anymore. Whatever happened to go-go boots and hot pants? They wear anything now, walk outta the house with whatever they got on ...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Frank notices another EMS bus: Tom Walls wheeling a stretcher-- Noel, face bloodied, lies restrained as Walls' partner opens the rear doors.</context>
      <utterance>The street is so much more unpredictable than the ER and to prepare for the unexpected I was taught to act without thinking, like an army private who can take apart and reassemble a gun blindfolded ...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Marcus continues as if uninterrupted:</context>
      <utterance>I realized that my training was useful in less than ten percent of the calls and saving someone's life was rarer than that. As the years went by I grew to understand that my role was less about saving lives than about bearing witness. I was a grief mop and much of my job was to remove, if even for a short time, the grief starter or the grief product. It was enough I simply showed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass a working girl in a rain slicker who pulls off her hood to look at them: a familiar face.</context>
      <utterance>... look at her. Leaves you no idea what's underneath, not even a suggestion. Could be a skeleton for all you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice though, pulling back her hood as we drive by. There's a mystery to it, then she shows you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's no whore, Marcus.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're all whores, Frank. You know what I'm talking about, the way she looked at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank, looking back at the Rose face, hears her faintly say:</context>
      <utterance>She wasn't looking at you, man, she was looking at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>"ROSE"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you kill me, Frank?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus, not hearing "Rose's" voice, replies:</context>
      <utterance>I didn't kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you didn't, Frank, thank you. But there's still a couple hours left on the shift.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dispatcher Love's voice cuts through:</context>
      <utterance>I need a drink, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER LOVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve Young, answer the radio. I have a call for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said to me, I love the way you talk on the radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER LOVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't wait all night, Young. I'm holding a priority and if you don't answer I'm going to knock you out of service.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, hon. Young is here and he's gonna help out--just remember, you owe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER LOVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to three-four Avenue C, 17 year-old female cardiac arrest, no further information.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus hits the siren.</context>
      <utterance>Ten-four, hon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that. A fat junkie. That's a first.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlos speaks broken English:</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No English. She has terrible pain in her belly.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, that's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria shakes her head, looks away.</context>
      <utterance>Are you pregnant? Estas embarazada?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you walk? Puedes caminar?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She say she in great pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the translation.  What's your name? Nombre?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maria.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's have a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know each other a long time?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two years. Ever since we left island.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In that time, you ever have sex?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never. No cigarettes, no drugs, no booze.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No underwear?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are virgins.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus radioing for assistance.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus, we'd better go. Call for backup.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's coming.  Hold her down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that, Frank?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three legs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's too many.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Backup?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she dying?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's having a baby. Twins.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Es impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can trust me on this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria SCREAMS. Marcus kneels beside Frank as a distant EMS siren grows louder.</context>
      <utterance>It's a miracle.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks up at the screaming mother: it's not her face. It's Rose. The Rose face.</context>
      <utterance>You take the first one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had a pulse.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CONSTANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hazmat rushing over:</context>
      <utterance>Code! Code Blue!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus, put her on the monitor. Where's the pediatric code cart?  Odette give me that tube. All right, flatline--let's do CPR. step back, Frank. How many months?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across the room an obscenity-spouting FEMALE CRACKHEAD being restrained by a patrolman and hospital security--adding to the sense of emergency and chaos. DR. MISHRA, 50, Pediatric MD, and nurses squeeze toward newborn edging Frank back. Mishra takes an osteocatheter out of the cart, forces it into the now obscured baby as Nurse Constance massages the infant's chest. Hazmat steps over to the now restrained Crackhead.</context>
      <utterance>Can't tell. It was a breech, twins. The other one seems okay, though. Marcus is taking him and the mother to Maternity.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRACKHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a mother! I got a daughter! I got rights!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mishra, worried, checks with Nurse Constance--they're losing the newborn:</context>
      <utterance>10 mil Valium, stat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISHRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Status.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CONSTANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looking at the EKG monitor--a green flatline--backs away.</context>
      <utterance>I think there's a pulse. I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISHRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CONSTANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank walking away, not looking where he's going, backs into Noel's gurney.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noel, his face battered from his encounter with Walls, pulls at his restraints, howls:</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir, excuse me, I would please trouble you for one cup of water. The smallest thing in the world to ask for, water. A man is dying and that is me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Hazmat looks over:</context>
      <utterance>For days I've eaten nothing but sand, O Lord, I waited so long.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ. Who the hell woke him up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give me that look.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What look?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I'm talking about. It's all over your face. That I-just- saved-a-little-baby-boy look.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just saved a little baby boy. Think of it that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus reaches under the seat, pulls a pint of vodka, a quart of orange juice and two cups out of an old gym bag, passes them to Frank.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to hear about it, okay? That's three jobs for the night. It's over. Three jobs and time for a drink. Six am, the cocktail hour. Pass the bottle; I know you're holding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank mixes a screwdriver for Marcus, straight vodka for himself.</context>
      <utterance>The bar is now open.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate vodka.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, a little decorum if you will. What I was going to say is, is that holding that baby in my arms, I felt like I was twenty-one again. A call like that makes me think of going back to three nights a week, not two, start running again, cut down on the drinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll drink to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's to the greatest job in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greatest job in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER LOVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve Young, I have priorities holding. Pick up the radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do it, Marcus. Tell her the bus died, our radio's not working, our backs are out. Tell her we're too drunk to take any more calls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do it!  It's Marcus, Love, only for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER LOVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Male diff breather, approximately 30, Houston and A.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus hits the sirens and lights, accelerates to full speed. The vodka spills; Frank grabs the dash.</context>
      <utterance>Ten-four.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Marcus swings the bus wildly to avoid a cab, SKIDS into a turn--and smack toward a parked truck. Frank covers his face and screams. CRASH! The back of the ambulance rams into the truck, the rear windows shatter.</context>
      <utterance>I'm coming, Love! I'm coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank looks around, realizes no one is hurt. He climbs out:</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I quit! I'm through!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank walks up Avenue A, leaving Marcus and the disabled vehicle. The first rays of sun strike the buildings ahead.</context>
      <utterance>You can't leave me now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Emergency doors open: Mary Burke, head down, looking neither direction, walks away from Frank. Griss steps out after her. Frank joins him:</context>
      <utterance>So long, Noel.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on, Griss?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary starts to run. Frank follows. She pushes her way through a group of high schoolers; Frank does likewise, keeping his distance. Five blocks later, Mary hesitates at a plaza outside the Stuyvesant Town projects,</context>
      <utterance>Your friend there just untied the water beggar. Griss was coming out to thank her. Probably saved Griss a murder charge.  Having a tough time of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. You seemed like you were in trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all right. I just can't stand to see people tied up. I'm in the waiting room for hours, listening to Noel screaming. The only reason he's screaming is 'cause he's tied up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't seem so bad to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that. I wanted to cut my father loose too. They told me he almost died and five minutes later they say he's better and I go in. It's killing me seeing him fighting like that.  Look, since you're here, maybe you could do me a favor. I need you to wait for me outside this building, okay? I have to visit a friend who's sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary takes a few steps, turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm only asking because it's a dangerous building. There's been some robberies, a woman was raped not long ago. This woman I'm seeing, she'll want to talk to me all day, but if I can point to you out the window and say you're waiting, I can be out quick. if anything happens, I'll be in apartment 16M.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should come up with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm not back in fifteen minutes, hit the buzzer. That way she'll let me go.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing's going to happen. I'll come with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks into the building. He follows.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'll be fine. I'm just visiting a sick friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shouldn't have asked you to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You asked me not to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise you won't go inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just have to relax a little. Not feel so guilty all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can still go back. I'll walk you home. You sleep a couple of hours, watch some TV, take a bath.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be a cop. If you have any doubts about this, it's my fault. The elevator jerks to a stop; the doors open.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary pushes the bell at 16M. KANITA, 25, wearing a paisley robe, opens the doors and says:</context>
      <utterance>You go on home, okay. I'm fine, really. I don't need you. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KANITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Cy, guess who's here?</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The elevator doors close on Frank.</context>
      <utterance>Mary ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>KANITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Burke. She's a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>KANITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank pushes past her.</context>
      <utterance>She's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KANITA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>CY COATES, 45, light-skinned black, stands in the smoky room. Dark curtained windows block the sunlight; a dirty fish tank casts a green glow across the beat-up furniture. A large framed photo of a volcano hangs over the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. You can't go in.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, Kanita. Come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>KANITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks like a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not a cop, he's a medic.  I'm CY Coates.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank Pierce.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary said you might be coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sleeping in the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She asked me to pick her up.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but she told me to tell you she wants to crash here a few hours. Terrible about her father, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kanita sits on the sofa next to an unshaven sleeping man. Coates gestures:</context>
      <utterance>I better just go in and see her.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank heads down the hall toward the rear of the apartment; Coates follows. They pass an open door where inside TIGER, a fat man with dried blood running down the corner of his mouth, sits punching computer keys at a desk.</context>
      <utterance>I call this the Oasis. Refuge from the world out there. Did you know two people were shot in this building last week?</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>In the NEXT ROOM Mary lies on a mattress on the floor, yellow sheet pulled up to her neck. Frank leans over her:</context>
      <utterance>Careful. That's the Tiger. The lady's down the hall. Welcome to Sunrise Enterprises, Frank, the stress-free factory.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary. Mary, we've got to get going.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wanted something to help her sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary blindly swings her fist at him, collapses unconscious back to the mattress.</context>
      <utterance>Mary, we really have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, she's suffered enough. She's okay, I promise.  C'mon, Frank. Coates escorts Frank back to the LIVING ROOM.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm always interested in people in stressful occupations and being a paramedic is about as stressful as I can imagine. Here, sit down. What's it like? Tell me some war stories.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cy sits across from him, pulls out a pin-sized joint, lights it:</context>
      <utterance>Got a beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That shit is poison, Frank. We don't drink alcohol here. What you need is one of these.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you give Mary something called Red Death?</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red Death?  Tell me something, Frank--does killing your clients make good business sense to you? The kids selling that shit have no sense. They'll be taken care of, don't worry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should be going. I just quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank watches as Kanita gets up, walks to the kitchen. Coates places the pill in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Sleep is all stress reduction. Here.  You take one of these, sleep two hours, that's all you need.  Why do you think I'm telling you this, Frank--for my health? You ought to look at yourself in the mirror, man. Kanita, get him a glass of water.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this what you gave Mary?</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No language, only brute power. You can't believe how relaxing it is. Kanita returns with a glass of water, gives it to Frank; Coates stands, feeds the fish.</context>
      <utterance>That's the stuff. I call it the Red Lion. Very king-of-the-jungle.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank swallows the white pill, drinks the water. He places his arms on the chair:</context>
      <utterance>Frank, I'm trying to help you. Drink up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I'll be going.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks around the smoke-filled room. Kanita walks over, extends her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Just take it easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KANITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take my pulse.  It's good, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>KANITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kanita runs her hand across his shoulders. Frank starts to nod. The room getting warm and dark. His eyelids lower: sleep, precious sleep.</context>
      <utterance>I knew it. I was wrong about you. You're not so bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in the stomach!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rose!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name. Rose.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somewhere: CY Coates laughs.</context>
      <utterance>You're in the stomach, man. Frank pulling the tube out, trying again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in the stomach! Let me try.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rose going blue, pulse rate dropping, EKG Slowing: Jim Morrison singing.</context>
      <utterance>One more time!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stomach again.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry ripping the tube from Frank's hands, taking over, pushing Frank aside, trying CPR, intubating Rose, air moving into her lungs--it doesn't matter. Rose is gone. Frank hears a SCREAM: it's his own voice.</context>
      <utterance>No way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, take it easy. what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>KANITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank bends over in pain.</context>
      <utterance>He flipped out.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be cool, man. You're having a paradoxical reaction. It can happen.  Didn't I tell you this guy was stressed out?</utterance>
   <speaker>KANITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank heads to where Mary sleeps.</context>
      <utterance>Stressed? He's psycho.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the BACK BEDROOM, Frank picks up Mary, hoists her over his shoulder fireman-style and heads out.</context>
      <utterance>Frank, where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank opens the front door--no one stops him--exits.</context>
      <utterance>You're making a mistake. Sit down and relax a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be back. And, by the way, you owe me ten bucks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary heads up the avenue: past baby strollers, postal workers, deliverymen.</context>
      <utterance>Let go of me.  You shouldn't have come up. I told you not to. You could have gotten us both killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and CY have a nice talk? He tell you about Sunrise Enterprises, helping people? Well, I've seen him hurt people. Why are you following me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank walking slightly beside and behind, lights a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Because you can barely walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop at a three-story brick apartment building.</context>
      <utterance>You remember Noel, from the other night, how Noel is now? He wasn't always like that. He was my brother's best friend. Cy or Tiger or one of those other goons put a bullet in Noel's head. He was in a coma three months. Crazy ever since.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She unlocks the door. He follows her in.</context>
      <utterance>This is my place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? You want to help me, you feel sorry for me? Keep it to yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to sit down a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary opens the door to her first floor apartment; Frank follows. The room is clean and feminine. Unframed water colors stacked against the wall atop a desk. A black lab greets Mary, she pets him. Frank slumps on the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>Or maybe you wanna fuck me? Everyone else has.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank keels over onto his side, his head hitting a cushion, eyes closed, dog licking his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>I've been clean two years now. I got a job. I paint when I'm home. Don't bother anybody. Then all this shit happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He's asleep, the sound of her crying fading in his head.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no you don't. You can't stay here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes the blanket Mary has laid over him, stands:</context>
      <utterance>Hello, I'm Frank. Mary's friend. A very close friend who loves animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank walks cautiously through the dark, finds a bathroom lit by a glowing Mickey Mouse switch. He flips on the switch: a string of green and red Christmas lights glow. Three types of soap sit on the sink. He turns on the faucet:</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I washed my face with three kinds of soap, each smelling like a different season. It felt good to be in a woman's room again, especially a woman who wasn't comatose or severely disabled. I felt that perhaps I had turned a corner, like I saved someone, though I didn't know who.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAPT. BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're late, Pierce. I know, but I can't fire you. I've got nobody to work sixteen XRay with Walls.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No ...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPT. BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got some forms here to fill out about that accident when you get the time.  I'll fire you tomorrow. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if there is no tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPT. BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on, get outta here, Pierce, before I give you a big hug.  I love this guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>GRISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make me take off my sunglasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning, Griss.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE CONSTANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank walks over to unit three, Mr. Burke's cubicle, pulls back the curtain. Burke lies sedated, wired and tubed. Frank leans over, feels Burke's pulse. Frank's expression changes--he looks at the EKG monitor: green lines seem to be at war, normal beats marching in formation against wild-looking rhythms, the heart working hard and not getting much done. Burke's face twitches.</context>
      <utterance>We're full up tonight, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Burke?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The alarms start to ring: EKG first, followed by the bells off the oxygen saturation monitor and low drone of ventilator. Intern Milagros pulling open the curtain behind Frank, shaking her head, reaching for the defribilator paddles, handing them to Frank. He steps back:</context>
      <utterance>I'm going. I've had enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILAGROS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't reach. You're taller.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought he was getting better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILAGROS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Technically, yeah. I suppose. It doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILAGROS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tha family wants us to do everything to save him--so, that's it. They want to keep him alive, they want to believe in miracles, we keep him alive. Shock him, Frank. He'll come back. He always comes back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank shocks Burke: his body convulses.</context>
      <utterance>Clear!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The heartbeats on monitor return to regular formation.</context>
      <utterance>Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILAGROS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I increase the lidocaine? Frank, despondent, not listening, walks away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank places an open drug box on the stretcher, pulls out an IV set, wraps a tourniquet around his left bicep.</context>
      <utterance>Frank, what you doing back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sick, Tom. I need a cure.  Vitamin B cocktail, followed by an amp of glucose and a drop of adrenaline. Not as good as beer, but all I got.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank crawls back in front carrying the IV bag, puts on the oxygen mask, turns on the main tanks, takes a deep hit.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Frank. There's blood spilling in the streets.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are hard times, Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Great, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great to be drunk. Sobriety's killing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look up, Frank. Full moon. The blood's gonna run tonight. I can feel it. Our mission: to save lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our mission is coffee, Tom. A shot of the bull, Puerto Rican espresso.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walls hits the sirens, accelerates.</context>
      <utterance>Ten-four. El Toro de Oro. Blast off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cure's not working, Tom. Maybe we should go back to the hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walls turns up the radio, drums his hands against the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, kid. Tom'll take care of you. Put your head out the window, get some of that summer air. Listen to the music. El Toro de Oro. Andale. Pronto.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, units, it's suicide hour. Fourteen Boy, I show you in the hospital sixty minutes but I know you're in the diner on 14th. Put down the burger, I got a call for you around the corner, 14 and 3rd, a man with a noose around his neck and nothing to hang it on. Sixteen XRay, don't even think about getting coffee, I have a call for you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixteen XTerminator here. We like our coffee bloody. Make it good--my partner's dying to help someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank pulls the IV needle out of his arm, searches the glove compartment:</context>
      <utterance>You're in luck, X: your patient awaits you with bleeding wrists on Avenue C and Fourth.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom, where are the Band-aids? This is an ambulance, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>16 XRay lurches forward.</context>
      <utterance>Look out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut Wrists gets up, leans against the ambulance, shaking.</context>
      <utterance>You've gotta take him to the hospital. He tried to kill himself. Show him your wrist. Show A.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK #1</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, he ain't right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold it. I will not take anyone anywhere against his will. This is America. People have rights.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was bleeding before. He kept spilling his beer. I gave him mouth- to-mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're lucky you didn't kill him.  We're going to hear it straight from the loony's mouth. Are you crazy? Did you try to bump yourself off?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUT WRISTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesssss.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walls escorts Cut Wrists into the back of the bus, pulls a plastic electric patch off the EKG monitor. Frank joins them.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you say so.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cut Wrists nods.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I am going to give you some medicine that is still very experimental. It's from NASA, and although the astronauts have been using it for years, we are the first service to try it. I will put this patch on your forehead like this, and in about a minute you will have to relax.  You will forget all your suicidal feelings. It's very important that you wear this for a least twenty- four hours and keep checking the mirror. If the patch turns green you have to see the doctor immediately. The side effects could be fatal.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the worst suicide attempt I've ever seen. You feel the pulse? Here. That's where you cut, and it's not across, it's down like so.  Here take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUT WRISTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut Wrists bolts out of the back of the bus, trips as he hits the ground, runs down the street, turning the corner still holding the patch to his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>With all the poor people of this city who wanted only to live and were viciously murdered, you have the nerve to sit here waiting to die and not go through with it. You make me sick. Take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We cured him, Frank. When we work together there's nothing we can't fix.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank watches a hooker on the sidewalk. Two street punks dripping gold and attitude head the opposite direction: one turns his head, looks at Frank--it's Rose. The Rose face. Frank getting up, grabbing his walkie and coffee, heading out.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, hello. Major Tom to Frank, time to come home.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Tom. The city's burning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatja doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel the need, the need for speed. I'm driving out of myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The brakes are shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've taken that into consideration.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never felt better in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixteen XRay, XRay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First of all, I want you to know how sorry I am about this. I've always liked you two. A unit above none, a legend in its own lunchtime, so it hurts me deeply to do this but I have no choice. You must go to Second and St. Marks. In front of a liquor store you'll find a forty year-old male, unconscious, lying next to his wheelchair. Do I have to say more?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've said too much already.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's early for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom hears something on the police band: a call for units to Stuyvesant Town.</context>
      <utterance>That's all right, we're not meant to do Oh tonight. Something is going to happen. I can feel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bingo.  EMS to Central. What was that call?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE DISPATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A jumper. Stuyvesant Town.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten-four. One minute out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But they're not listening--Frank's off to Stuyvesant Town.</context>
      <utterance>Sixteen, Sixteen XRay. Level One Emergency.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whadda we bring?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better bring it all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The elevator's fucked. We'd never all fit anyway. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's thirteen flights.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The news guys just pulled up.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sergeant leads a half dozen cops and firemen up the stairs as the elevator doors open. Tom, Frank and two COPS squeeze inside.</context>
      <utterance>The stairs, men, the stairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy a jumper?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got a call for shots fired on the sixteenth floor. The jumper called right after.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the elevator doors close.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to sixteen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank, looking over the balcony, sees Cy three floors below.</context>
      <utterance>That's it, nobody else home.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank heads clown the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to thirteen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get this, Frank--we got two patients. Number one, the scarecrow outside. Number two misses the railing but breaks both legs on the balcony, then throws himself through a glass window, heads to the bedroom, where he's now passed out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he's the steakhead of the night, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think the fire people can touch him out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank goes over to Coates as two cops strap on harnesses. CY hangs impaled on the railing, a steel spike passing through his hip. Glowing in spotlights from thirteen floors below, Frank takes Coates' vital signs, gently presses his abdomen:</context>
      <utterance>I haven't had a chance to see him yet. I'm going to take care of sleeping beauty.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank, IV bag in his teeth, putting an oxygen mask on Coates:</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cops behind click on harnesses ("You in?" "Yeah" "You in?") attach straps to pitons they've hammered into the brick wall, bring out metal cutters and torches.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think you've hurt any major organs.  We got to get you off this thing without setting off bleeding.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna torch the fence. You're gonna feel the metal getting warm, maybe very warm.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank passes the IV bag to one of the cops, holds Coates, head. CY relaxes his neck as SPARKS splay like fireworks beneath him, fall to the concrete.</context>
      <utterance>I can't hold up my head anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Frank, am I going to live?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to live.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking about things. Meditating on my financial future. You guys gave me plenty of time to meditate on the future. Whatja do, stop for Chinese on the way over? There's plenty of food in my place.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was tired. I needed a coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Kanita?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's too bad. Get some money, a nice looking girl on your arm, and everyone wants to take a piece. Some kid I wouldn't let wash my Mercedes is in my house, shooting at me. Damn, I thought I could make it onto the balcony like Tiger. He's fat, that's why, falls faster. I'm trying to watch my weight, and look what happens. Am I shot, Frank?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks: the spike in Coates' hip starting to glow red. CY stretches his hand toward the skyline, his face backlit by raining acetylene sparks:</context>
      <utterance>Boy can't shoot for shit, either. Goddamn that's hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The torch breaks the spike free: Frank and Coates FREE FALL three feet, jerk to a stop. Cy yelps. The crowd cheers from below. Frank now grabbing, holding Coates tightly--Frank's hands the only thing keeping Coates from falling--as the cops hoist them up.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't it beautiful? When the fires start to fall, then the strongest rule it all. I love this city.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good thing we buckled you in, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>COATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me? Who's supposed to buckle me?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ventilator alarm goes off as Burke pulls at his restraints.</context>
      <utterance>Nurse Crupp, we're going to need some Valium here. He's waking up again.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nurse Crupp walks briskly over, injects needle into one of Burke's IV bags. Burke's voice speaks in Frank's head:</context>
      <utterance>Where's that Valium?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't. Don't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank helps Hazmat force in a bite stick. The monitor alarm cuts off, the ventilator starts up again, pumping air in, pulling air out.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a hand, Frank. I've got to get something between those teeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't believe how much he's improved.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many times have you shocked him tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fourteen. We finally got him a room upstairs. Should be up there in a couple of hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you do, just have someone follow him around with a defribilator?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good, Frank. No, but they might surgically implant one, about the size of my thumb. It goes near the shoulder here, with two electrodes connected to the heart. It sends a shock whenever it senses a drop in blood flow. Amazing, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A medical miracle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank greets them.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone, this is the medic who brought my father in. Frank, these are some of my father's friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMILY FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We live out an the Island now, but we used to live right down the block from Pat. He was like a saint to us. Came as soon as we heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary whispers something to her mother, joins him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going out for a smoke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard CY Coates was brought in. He looked pretty bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll be all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad. He called me up today, can you believe that? I don't know how he got my number. He asks me do I want to come over and see him, I tell him I'd rather go to a leper colony. He says there's a new gang that wants to kill him, take over the business. I told him I hope he's right. That they kill him. That's what I told him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be a while before he's up and running again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, last night I was weak. it won't happen again. And all that shit I said--it was just because I was stoned. Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem. Thanks for letting me crash. It was the best sleep I've had in months. I used some of your soap.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish these people would leave already. I can't listen to another story. Did you see him?  That doctor says the brain is coming around. They're waiting for the heart to stabilize. I don't know who to believe. He says they still have to keep him tied up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I bring you something back to eat--a falafal, some pizza?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we just ate. I only remember how tough my father was. Now I know he had to be like that, to make us tough. This city'll kill you if you aren't strong enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walls flashes 16 XRay's headlights, hits the horns.</context>
      <utterance>No, the city doesn't discriminate. It gets everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank, his heart pounding, steps closer to her.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go. Another call.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He leans as if to kiss her.</context>
      <utterance>We're all dying, Mary Burke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not a good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places his hand on her shoulder, kisses her lightly, walks toward Walls and the waiting ambulance.</context>
      <utterance>There's no time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get ready, Frank. Missed a drug shooting while you were dicking around in there. There's gonna be trauma tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as we keep moving. No standing still.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, look at your screen. Give up some blood!</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks at a group of girls exiting an after-hours club: every one a Rose. Rose faces.</context>
      <utterance>Sixteen XRay, a man at the bus terminal shot three years ago says his arm hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Tom, pick up a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some bum in the bus terminal? We'll wait for a real call.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get in a fight, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who with?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walls hits the accelerator: the old bus jerks forward:</context>
      <utterance>That's your job. Just keep driving, keep moving. No stopping. We're sharks. We stop too long, we die.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's break something, Tom. Let's bust something, bomb something.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to break?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know--let's break some windows.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Destruction, distraction. I feel the need.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need a reason, Frank. You don't just go around breaking people's windows. That's anarchy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the reason? Give me a reason, Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom hits the siren as he swings wildly around a stopped cab and its turban-headed driver:</context>
      <utterance>Let me think.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Walls turns onto a cross street, spots Noel standing by a Mustang, baseball bat on his shoulder. He wears yesterday's blood-stained clothes, cut tires tied to his shoulders and elbows, chest and belly wrapped with steel wire.</context>
      <utterance>Classic cabbie move.  Hey, swammy, that's called a crosswalk. You stop before it, not on it!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Walls slows as Noel lifts the bat, swings it into the Mustang's front window, shattering it, puts the bat down, using it like a cane as he walks to the next parked car.</context>
      <utterance>I know who to work over. Him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy's been terrorizing the neighborhood for weeks, ever since he got outta jail, wreaking general havoc, contributing to the bad name of the place. The term "menace to society" was made up for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's crazy. He can't help it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, why don't they put him away? Prisons don't want him. I took him to the hospital yesterday and here he is again. Noel reaches the next car, a Bronco, carefully hefts the bat, smashes it through the windshield.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that. Tell me that's a crazy person. Every move is calculated. He knows exactly what he's doing. This is the guy. I've been after him for weeks. He's quick, runs like a rat, tough for one person, but with two of us--</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, whatta I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he sees me, he'll run, so I'll get out here. You start talking to him about baseball or something while I sneak around behind and get down and you push him. When he falls we get him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe me, it always works. The simpler, the better.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You learn that in the army?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Walls slips out, crouches beside the bus. Frank, stepping out, walks over to Noel as he whacks the bat through the hatch of a Pinto.</context>
      <utterance>Flatbush.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a hell of a swing you got there, Noel. I'm thinking Strawberry in his prime.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noel hauls back, lays into a Volvo: glass shatters. Noel holds the bat out, extends handle towards Frank:</context>
      <utterance>Strawberry ain't shit. Drug pussy.  Me. I swing like Reggie. Mr. October. Number three, game six, World Series.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, you try.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'd better not.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure, give go.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank, intrigued by Noel's suggestion, has forgotten Walls' plan. He takes the bat as Tom sneaks behind Noel, crouching.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell.  The next year, tiebreaker for the division, in Boston, Yanks down two to nothing, Bucky Dent steps to the plate.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man, Bucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank cocks the baseball bat, relishing every moment, swings into the Volvo's side window. Shattered glass flies on his hands and clothes. Walls, fed up with this, stands:</context>
      <utterance>The pitch, high heater. Bucky knows what's coming. He steps in, smash, over the green monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noel, seeing Walls, grabs the bat, flees down an alley.</context>
      <utterance>Frank, what the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Walls takes off after Noel. Frank, taking out his flashlight, enters second alley, walks down dark stairs which hopefully circle around to Noel.</context>
      <utterance>You go down those stairs there. Meet me back here if you can't find him in ten minutes. Call out if you see him. Get with the program, Frank.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should have helped me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shadows like hands extend against the wall ahead.</context>
      <utterance>I tried to help. I wanted to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank moves toward the reaching arms. The shadows swing like baseball bats. Noel SCREAMS. Suddenly, before him, a blurry mass of bloody dreadlocks-- Noel goes flying to the ground, Walls standing over him swinging the bat, hitting him, killing him.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you love me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank stands back, watching Walls and Noel like some static black and white TV screen from his childhood. Noel, trying to protect himself, cries out.</context>
      <utterance>I got him, Frank!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the kit! We're gonna tube him!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna save you, Noel. You're gonna be all right.  Do it, Tom! I'll call for fucking backup, I swear!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noel unconscious: Tom hurries down the alley toward the ambulance as Frank opens Noel's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>You're crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pressing Noel's chest, Frank lowers his mouth, starts CPR. His mouth to Noel's. In the distance: Walls' footsteps returning.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to make it! You're going to make it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NURSE CONSTANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take him straight through.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who got that funky motherfucker this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last show of the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ. Nurse Crupp!  Anybody else hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walls pushes Noel into unit one. Frank looks over to unit three--Burke's cubicle is empty.</context>
      <utterance>Crazy fucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Burke?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank nods, walks out. Behind, Walls helps Hazmat and Crupp place Noel on a bed.</context>
      <utterance>Upstairs. 212. Had to shock him twice more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLOOR NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank steps back as the Nurse hits the emergency switch.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?  Code!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOOR NURSE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dr. Hazmat, out of breath, enters:</context>
      <utterance>Are we doing CPR?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOOR NURSE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He coded.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank pulls out the paddles, applies them to Burke's chest:</context>
      <utterance>Christ, what a way to start the day. He's in V-fib. Shock him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOOR NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank, knowing it's futile, shocks Burke: no result.</context>
      <utterance>Clear!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank goes through the motions, pretending to shock Burke. The flatline doesn't waver.</context>
      <utterance>Zap him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank backs out the door as a nurse and intern enter. In the corridor Frank listens as the activity becomes less urgent. Hazmat steps out:</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Get the cart, start compressions, get an epinephrine in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAZMAT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank nods.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough. I called it. Let's get some coffee.  You gonna tell the family?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead, Rose. Your father passed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE/MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can that be? He was getting better.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He coded. They shocked him one too many times. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE/MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was tough. You did all you could.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE/MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank nods.</context>
      <utterance>You have to keep the body going until the brain and heart recover enough to go on their own.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSE/MARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rose/Mary opens the door wider, closes it behind Frank.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
