<movie id="109" title="Buffy the Vampire Slayer">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barmaid pours him a cup of ale. He drinks deep, stands a moment.</context>
      <utterance>A tankard of ale, wench.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some plague we're having, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She looks up.</context>
      <utterance>The lord giveth, and the lord taketh away. Ashes, ashes...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are ten or more vampires walking slowly toward her in the otherwise deserted street. At the front, maybe ten feet away, is AMILYN. Amilyn is a grinning jackal, a servant to the Vampire-King. His garb is a rotted approximation of a courtier's livery. He ambles toward the Slayer, giggling, as she stands. Behind her is LOTHOS, the Vampire-King. His skin is deep white, and smooth. He wears a long coat -- his dress is not of any era. He is practically upon her before he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>... All fall down</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns. He smiles, almost lovingly.</context>
      <utterance>You must forgive Amilyn. He tends to drool before supper.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lothos...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swings at him but he grabs her arm. Amilyn laughs obnoxiously. Lothos grabs the back of the Slayer's head, brings her to him in a loving embrace.</context>
      <utterance>You people will never learn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you must. There is only one. Now you are that one. It is time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Why me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls aside her blouse to reveal a birthmark on her shoulder, identical to the barmaid's.</context>
      <utterance>She has died. You are the next to be called. Why do you think you were sent to me? Trained as you were? You bear the mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mark of the Coven.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man unravels a satchel of cloth. From it he pulls an elaborately carved wooden stake.</context>
      <utterance>Ever since Adam and Eve first left the garden, he followed: the serpent. Satan. He sends his legion in the shape of men, to feed on us, to breed his Hell on our earth. They are a plague upon us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But as long as there have been vampire, there has been the Coven; the line of Slayers. Ones with the strength and the skill to kill them, to find them where they gather and stop the swell of their numbers. One dies, the next is called.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her the stake. She feels the fit.</context>
      <utterance>You are much more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she grips the stake more tightly, an awareness and sense of power sees to fill her. She lifts the stake over her head.</context>
      <utterance>One dies, the next is called...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The players huddle.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, do the play! The one where... the one from the book! Where you make it go forward!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hits Grueller's helmet.</context>
      <utterance>All right, guys, come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grueller! Fill that hole! They were all over me! Okay. Let's run twenty-two. Grueller, close the pocket, watch out for thirty-five. Thompson, run the post, right, wide out. Jeffrey, go up the middle and run around like a chicken. They clap and break. As they line up, Jeffrey looks over at Buffy. She smiles at him. He winks, very suave.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY AND CHEERLEADERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the hike, Andy drops back and looks for a receiver. Jeffrey runs in circles like an idiot (and not unlike a chicken), waving his arms until Andy sails him the ball and he breaks for a touchdown. The crowd goes wild -- particularly Buffy, who does an impressive standing backflip. Nicole looks at her, impressed. Buffy smiles at her, giddy.</context>
      <utterance>Jeffrey! Jeffrey! He's our man! If he can't do it We don't want it!</utterance>
   <speaker>COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that good? Was that a good thing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Howard is so heinous. He's always giving me a hard time. I get a C-plus on the test and he tells me, 'You have no sense of history.' I have no sense of history? He wears a brown tie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a C-plus? I can't believe I cheated off you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dress on a rack outside a store has caught her eye. She takes it and holds it in front of her.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me for not knowing about El Salvador. Like I'm ever going to Spain anyway. Ooh!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimberly and Jennifer catch up to them.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm. Wouldn't I look just edible and nutritious in this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys, what's the sitch? I'm bored.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. It's so '91.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy puts it back.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we see a movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, where?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Omniplex?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nee sitch. No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No THX.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't even have Dolby.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beverly Center.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. They show previews for foreign movies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KIMBERLY/BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bogus corn!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Totally stale. And the ushers are like, the acne patrol. We're thinking Pavilion. Sitch?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds toasty. We're going Pavilion.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stranger, walking the other way, bumps into Buffy, doesn't stop. A man of about fifty, he is dressed shabbily, in a wrinkled black suit and a black shirt. He somewhat resembles a priest.</context>
      <utterance>What's playing there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse much! Not rude or anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice ensemble!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls continue walking. The man stops, turns to stare after them. His look is intense, slightly worried, his face somewhat haggard. Intelligence shines through his eyes. He holds himself stiffly, arms close to him, almost as if he expected something to strike at him. This is MERRICK. He pulls a picture out of his coat pocket, looks at it. Looks at them.</context>
      <utterance>What a homeless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, is Jeffrey really spending the night at your house?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your parents are always going away for the weekend. You're so lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mom doesn't go anywhere. She even does the shopping network. I'm gonna die a virgin.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did Jeffrey's dad say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Just remember you're in training, son'</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seated a few rows behind the girls are PIKE and BENNY. The are fairly punked out, (and not currently attending high school). Pike is long and lean, has short hair spiked and a taste for long coats and black. Benny is somewhat stockier, opts for a shaved head and suspenders. Doc Martins for both. Benny is clearly the more belligerent of the two -- when Pike speaks, it's with surprising wit and reserve. Sometimes.</context>
      <utterance>He is so bald.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you guys shut up, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike and Benny throw popcorn at her.</context>
      <utterance>It could happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Booo!</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suck!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong answer! No prize.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God! Take a chill lozenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like we don't have rights too?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ignore them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe these people. We paid money to see this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. But I still want to know what happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys stare at her.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone get horribly killed except the blonde girl in the nightie, who finally kills the monster with a machete but it's not really dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God. Is that true?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably. What movie is this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that moon! It's huge! Come on, guys, we gotta do something tonight. Party.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, if you would spend more time at home sleeping, you would spend less time on the field, sucking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were a bone out there today. Anyway, I'm booked. Gonna spend some quality time with the little woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY AND GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pussy-whipped. Pussy-whipped.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are pathetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Later for you, then. I'm blowing. Andy, you coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'll hitch a ride with Jeffrey.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Later.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy and Grueller bring their foreheads together with painstaking slowness, grimacing, and barely tap heads.</context>
      <utterance>Headbutt!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grueller walks off, head through a park. At the same time, Pike and Benny emerge from the theater. They pass Andy and Jeffrey and the two pairs circle each other, almost growling, eyes locked, before pike and Benny turn and walk off, not quite in the direction Grueller took. Buffy, Kimberly, Jennifer and Nicole come out right after. Buffy heads straight for Jeffrey and they kiss massively.</context>
      <utterance>Later.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice game.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeffrey, I don't mean to sound sexist or anything, but can I borrow her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. You'd get her dirty.  He would, honey. He's an animal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Yo! Who is that? Don't mess with me man, I'll rip your head off.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RUSTLING. No one.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, come out here. Let's see what you got.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns on his heel, ready to drop all show and bolt. WALLY BESSEL is right behind him. Wally is a ninth grader, small, nerdy, and recently undead. In marked contrast to the older vampire in the prologue, Wally is freshly undead. He still has fat on his face; in fact, he looks almost normal from afar. But his inhuman eyes and his uncommon pallor mark him as a vampire. And the way he speaks is unearthly. Hollow, almost detached; repeating phrases sometimes almost as though he had never heard them before. He smiles at Grueller.</context>
      <utterance>Forget this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bessel! What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Grueller.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you grinning at? You think I was scared?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grueller grabs Wally by his shirt collar and readily hoists his small body up, Wally's feet dangling two feet off the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Could be.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, you little worm. I could beat your head to a pulp for you, just like I did last year, you got that? You got that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets Wally go. Wally remains two feet in the air. Grueller's eyes go wide.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wally smiles even more broadly, quietly hissing. He has long fangs, made somehow more grotesque by the fact that he also has braces. Wally's hands vise onto Grueller's head, lightning quick. Grueller screams.</context>
      <utterance>What the...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - PIKE AND BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crossing a street, turning and listening.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the front seat next to Jeffrey, Buffy winces slightly.</context>
      <utterance>It's um... you had to be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... yeah, I'm okay. I'm fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BUFFY'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna be late. I knew it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's already out again by the end of this, as dad comes back in.</context>
      <utterance>Now, we'll be back on Sunday, number's on the fridge, don't drive the Jaguar and tell Consuela my underwear does not go in the dishwasher.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have fun be good stay away from the Jag.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he's out the back, mom entering on his heels.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She actually makes a kiss noise at her daughter.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's everything. Kiss noise.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy's mom heads out the door as Buffy heads into the living room.</context>
      <utterance>'Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BUFFY'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye-bye, Bobby!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye!  They think my name's Bobby?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... it's possible they think my name's Bobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real 'quality-timers,' Hugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy sits, squints disapprovingly at the screen. She has a bag of microwave lite popcorn and is spraying diet butter substitute on it.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it works for me. If they want to leave you alone in the house, all helpless and vulnerable...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What show is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the news, Buffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Who's in it?  I know what it is. It's what's on instead of the movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to see the basketball scores. It's important.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeffrey leans in toward her.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmnkay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts kissing her about the face and neck. She leans submissively back on the couch as he works his way on top of her. He gives her a long kiss on the mouth, then works over to her ear. As he is burrowing about in there, Buffy sneaks another handful of popcorn into her mouth. She leans back, by accident, on the remote.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, there are... other considerations...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - THE TV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Dracula" reappears.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Alone, the Girl hears a NOISE in the dark corner, a wet RUSTLING. Slowly she gets up to see. Approaches... It is a pool of blood. She stares at it, terrified. A hand reaches out of it. She runs out into the hall, but it leads nowhere but a dead end. Standing there, waiting for her, is Lothos. He smiles at her and we see she is now Buffy.</context>
      <utterance>You never touched my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wakes, grasping, her eyes melting into focus on Jeffrey's face.</context>
      <utterance>Buffy! Hey, what's the sitch?!? Wake up!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, wow. Oh, wow. Oh, wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He settles back down, his arms around her, and almost instantly begins to fall asleep again.</context>
      <utterance>You were having a nightmare.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you dream about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, what was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. It was just a dream.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="56">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They consider this a moment.</context>
      <utterance>The environment.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The homelesses?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are there any good sicknesses that aren't too depressing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys. The environment. I'm telling you, it's totally key. The earth is in terrible shape, we could al die, and besides, Sting's doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeffrey and Andy arrive, sit. Jeffrey straddles Buffy from behind, wrapping his arms around her. She snuggles in his grasp.</context>
      <utterance>I thought he was doing Indians.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Jeffrey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatchya guys doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The winter dance. We need to come up with a theme.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The senior dance? How about... 'Our Friend, the Beer?'</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Putting Out for Fun and Profit'... possible thought...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try new Clue-flakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has to be, like a socially conscious theme.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'One that reflects the students' growing awareness of and involvement in the world around them.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY|ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Downer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still say the environment. That's my suggestion.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a pretty crucial subject.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, Cassandra likes it. Cassandra's my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it. Can I be your friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay away from my thang.  Sorry, honey. 'Thing.'</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Environment. That's cool with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cassandra has paper and pen, is poised to make a list of suggestions. The other all look at each other uncomfortably. Cassandra obviously knows the answer, but regards her friends silently, waiting to see what the come up with.</context>
      <utterance>So, what are the most immediate threats to the world environment right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, um... litter?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone but Cassandra is impressed by this.</context>
      <utterance>Litter, yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Write that down.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, what else?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forest fires?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Communism?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, guys, how about the ozone layer?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GARY MURRAY, a well meaning but pompous little administrator, come up to the kids. He's kind of like Charlie Brown: you always say his whole name.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta get rid of that! That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARY MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't suppose you kids heard the first bell, did you? The first bell was saying, 'Start going to class, it's time to go to class.' In about thirty seconds the second bell is going to be saying, 'Already be in class.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're having a very important discussion here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARY MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I have trouble believing you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something from your childhood, maybe?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARY MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gary Murray walks off.</context>
      <utterance>Button it, Kramer. Classes are starting. Be there or beware.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man has a complex.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got a... What do you call it? A Napoleonic Code.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's 'cause he's so tiny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get up and start heading to class.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but what he lacks in height he makes up in shortness.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's meet tonight, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cafe Blase.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool. We can figure decorations and stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cassandra, you gotta come, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't. History report. The Normans and the Saxons.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bogutude. Blow it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really can't. Besides, it's pretty interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're weird and I'm afraid of you. Seriously, Cassandra, there's a lot cooler things you could be doing than your homework.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy smiles, trots off.</context>
      <utterance>Like my homework.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see why we have to invite everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kimberly, it's the senior dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we don't invite all the seniors we can't use the school funds, you know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't they make exceptions? Maryanne Heinel? She's such a scud. Can't we have a Maryanne clause?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look who's here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Fifties are over.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to learn to let go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give me any trouble, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit next to Buffy and begin pooling their money on the counter. It comes to about $2.50, heavy with pennies.</context>
      <utterance>No trouble. We just want to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, come on, fork up the scub.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it, man. That's the whole story.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He digs and produces a quarter from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>We're looking at a dog, possible coffee...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amazing!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smell of booze much.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice much.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we have a hot dog, please, medium rare, and a cup of joe?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are thrashed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking to them for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we're drunk. We're the Drunks. What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Figures.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy gives him a look.</context>
      <utterance>Do people ever call you 'Buffy the Buffalo?' I'm just wondering.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The don't. You kind of wish they would, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wit-tay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I'm Pike. This is Benny.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pike isn't a name. It's a fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, wait a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the guys from the movie!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls all make sad noises, real sarcastic.</context>
      <utterance>We hate you guys!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys were way rude. It was shocking.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just snuck in anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you have to ruin the movie for us? You know, other people have feelings, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress brings the hot do. Benny takes it out of the bun and holds it over his crotch, phallus-like.</context>
      <utterance>I am so sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other girls look down and shriek. Buffy looks at Benny, looks at him in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Buffy, you hungry? I got something for you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! She wasted my dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy looks off, a little surprised herself.</context>
      <utterance>Bummer metaphor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rich bitches. They're a plague. They've gotta be stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't like them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're all the same! They're so stuck up, they're just... they're not even human. I hate them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you sleep with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Definitely. Definitely. Please, God.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there it is, isn't it? You don't even like them, and you'd sleep with them. What's that all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a news flash, man, another shot of this and I'll have sex with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue walking. A shadowy figure appears behind them, following.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, and then you'll never call me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come one, that was so weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, it's not weird. I just cut the stupid hot dog in half.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe they still ate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you learn how to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't learn... I just... it's not a big deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy, I'm gonna tell Jeffrey you were playing with another man's Hebrew National.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get a boob job.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy makes a face. She doesn't want to hear this story. We HOLD on her as Nicole tells it.</context>
      <utterance>It's like when we took gymnastics in eighth grade.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy was on the uneven parallels -- she was really good; coach said she could have been in the Olympics -- but she was doing a routine, spinning, and the beam broke.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Snapped. Buffy was, you know, on the upswing, and I swear to God she went across the room. Perm over heels.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God! Ouch! No wonder you quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She makes a hyper-intense face. The others laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's the thing. She landed on her feet. Didn't even sprain a toe. And I go up to her and she turns and looks at me and she's like this --</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- like she's gonna kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just scared is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It was mondo bizarro.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy, the ape-woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seriously, Buffy. That look was way twisted. What were you thinking about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike finishes the bottle, eats the worm, and chucks the BOTTLE over the side. There is a moment before they hear it SHATTER.</context>
      <utterance>I'll have it running in a week. It's be beauty. It just needs new shocks, you know, break pads, an engine, and some wheels. It'll be totally cherry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you get your car together, man, let's bail.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think? Split?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Utterly. Let's bail this town. It's getting... I don't know. Let's go somewhere where there aren't any rich bitches.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny wavers, catches hold of Pike.</context>
      <utterance>Our own world, where we could live and grow beans. Hundreds of beans.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over the side of the wall, hangs his head down.</context>
      <utterance>I think I'm gonna ralf.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike falls over backwards.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Benny. I'm here for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike passes out.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here for you, Ralf.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="60">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy shows her. They do it together for a minute.</context>
      <utterance>What was the step after... The one from Thursday. I never learned it right, I don't think.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is so cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody is even gonna look at the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I was thinking, for the dance, what about a big sign that says 'Don't Tread On Me'. You know, and a picture of the earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tread on the earth?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you not tread on the earth? I mean, you kind of have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never thought of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta bail. You coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys blow. I'm waiting on Cassandra. She's gonna help me with my history.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cassandra's really smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... She's okay, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going out with Jeffrey tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennifer laughs, uncomfortably.</context>
      <utterance>Jealous?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Jennifer. Someday your prince will come.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, just make sure you do first. Let's go, guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other girls leave. Buffy is alone on the empty field. She looks around her. She starts doing a routine, tentatively. Then she runs toward the middle of the field and jumps, flies into an extraordinary series of gymnastic flips and cartwheels. She rolls into one final flip, a huge one, and lands, a perfect ten, about three inches from Merrick. She screams in surprise, steps back.</context>
      <utterance>B'bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, where the hell did you come from? You scared me to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His accent is clipped -- British.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. That was impressive. The... tumbling.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Oh. I used to do gymnastics. Are you looking for someone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for you, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I in trouble or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. My name is Merrick. I was sent to find you some time ago. I should have found you much sooner but there were... complications. You should have been taught, prepared.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've searched the entire world for you, Buffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To bring you... your birthright.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrick looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>My birthright? You mean, like a trust fund?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a trust fund my great- grandfather, or maybe it was an inheritance, 'cause he's dead, and I spent it on shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must come with me. It's much too late already. You must come with me to the graveyard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. My birthright is in the graveyard? Later not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're one of those skanky old men that, like, attack girls and stuff. Forget you. My, um, my boyfriend is gonna be here in about thirty seconds, and he's way testy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't understand. You have been chosen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chosen to go to the graveyard? Why don't you just take the first runner up, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must believe me. You must come with me while there's still time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To stop the killing. To stop the vampires.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me get this straight. You're like, this greasy bum, and I have to go to the graveyard with you 'cause I'm chosen, and there's vampires.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does Elvis talk to you? Tell you to do things? Do you see spots?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps forward and pulls the neck of Buffy's shirt aside, revealing her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have time for your prattling. I have proof. You bear the mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no birthmark on her shoulder. He looks at the other one.</context>
      <utterance>The mark of the Coven! The -- where's the mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy pushes his hand off her.</context>
      <utterance>The mark of the -- wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>You mean that big hairy mole? Excuse me: eeyuu. I had it removed. And, like, knowing about my big old mole isn't proof of anything except that it's way past medication time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just stay away from me, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy stops. This obviously registers with her.</context>
      <utterance>Did you ever dream that you were someone else?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody does.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The last one hits the mark.</context>
      <utterance>In the past. A girl. Maybe... A Magyar peasant. An Indian princess. A slave.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was a slave.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Virginia.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It was... There was a big gram or something. And there's one, I'm like a prostitute...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>China.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrick rolls his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God. I never told anybody about this. I remember the one about the peasant, too. God, there's a bunch. Is this, like channeling or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a dream once where I was... There was like, knights in it, and I worked in this bar. And I... was fighting. I'm always fighting. And there's a guy... He's not always there, but he's horrible, all white, and he's always... trying to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The name has an obvious effect on the girl.</context>
      <utterance>Lothos.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to show you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe I'm doing this. I can't believe I'm in a graveyard with a strange man hunting for vampires on a school night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you ever tell anybody about your dreams?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy stops, winces slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, tell everyone I'm crazy. Beauty ida.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cramps?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of your business. God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy is standing on a freshly dug grave. The headstone reads:</context>
      <utterance>This is it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just for protection. You won't have to do anything. I just need you to watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. What do we do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrick goes over to the other headstone, crouches by it.</context>
      <utterance>We wait for Robert to wake up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any gum?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the other one?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It leaps at her, screaming. She throws it off, as Merrick produces another stake and throws it to her. Buffy sticks it in the vampire's heart. She dies, screaming, her face still smoking, blood spurting onto Buffy. Buffy looks at herself. At the blood.</context>
      <utterance>She --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to school tomorrow. Try to act normal. Don't let anyone know what's happening. This is important. When the vampires find out who you are... you won't be hunting them anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her a piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meet me at this address after school.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have cheerleading squad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy nods. Merrick starts back down the path.</context>
      <utterance>Skip it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrick stops.</context>
      <utterance>Merrick.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can't come in, right? Unless you invite them. Is that true?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrick moves on. Buffy goes inside.</context>
      <utterance>It's true.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUFFY'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what time it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mom taps her watch, annoyed.</context>
      <utterance>Uum... around ten?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>I knew this thing was slow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, baby, how ya doing? You look beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do? I guess I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you last night? I called your house like four times.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeffrey backs away from her.</context>
      <utterance>I went to sleep. I think I have the flu or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get sick. You know -- training and all. I'm gonna be late.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeffrey moves off to class. Buffy walks on a bit. She bumps into Nicole.</context>
      <utterance>'Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Buffers. You look thrashed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy looks confused for a moment, then remembers.</context>
      <utterance>You and Cassandra get anything done last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. No. She never showed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I find it restorative, sleeping in the life-blood of so many. To feel their souls coursing about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening? What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My parents have money...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cassandra turns. Amilyn stands behind her, grinning. He hisses, bares his fangs at Cassandra.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm sure they do. This place is everything you said it was, Amilyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps right up to her.</context>
      <utterance>Are we so strange? So alien to you? I've seen this culture, the wealth, the greed, the waste... it's truly heartwarming. The perfect place to spread my empire. Honestly, Eastern Europe was so dead, the Communists just drained the blood out of the place. It's livened up a bit in the past few years, but it's nothing compared to this.... this Mecca of consumption. The city of Angels.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cassandra pulls her gold card out of her wallet.</context>
      <utterance>So? Do we change this one, or do we just drain her?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amilyn snatches it from her, looks it over.</context>
      <utterance>Here, look. My gold card. It's your. I'll never report it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amilyn bites the card.</context>
      <utterance>She has a certain quality, this one...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think this is gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not as single-minded as the others, not as sybaritic. Almost thoughtful. She's useless.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, wait. I can be dumb. Really. Or mean, or whatever. I can learn. I'm useful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rips out her throat, tearing at it with his teeth as blood gushes around their faces and she wriggle, twists, dies. He hurls her into the door and wipes blood from his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Swear to God.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly Cassandra slides down the wall, her eyes glazing over. As she descends we see, stenciled on the wall, "Hemery High School. Maintenance Only."</context>
      <utterance>I wish you wouldn't mention him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrick looks up at her.</context>
      <utterance>Fire the help. No kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not pretty, but it does suit our purposes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She repeats it not with attitude, but a dull wonder at her connection with this strange man. She crosses to him.</context>
      <utterance>Our purposes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, um... What do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a great deal I have to show you, I'm not even sure where to start There's so little time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you keep saying that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what a Vampire-King is?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Vampire-King? You mean like Dracula?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. And the man from your dreams. Lothos.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. They travel about, usually with one or two of their followers to lay the groundwork. The vampires find a community and they feed on it, make it their own. You were difficult to trace, and I think the process has gone a lot further than I'd anticipated. Usually this goads a community into some kind of paranoid frenzy. But for some reason, nobody here seems to be paying any attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll cover it later.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still don't get how they happened to come to my town. I mean, was I born here because... because they were coming here? That Lothos guy, and his buddies?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a way, yes. Your fate is inexorably connected to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. First I have a birthright, now I've got a fate. Hey, do I have to take notes on this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy laughs.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to have the work hard. You'll need some excuse for staying out. For your parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a pressing issue.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you, the best thing I can do right now is find out more about you. What your strengths are, your likes... Everything. What's your best subject?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... gym.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you used to do gymnastics. But you stopped. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, everybody says... it's just kind of dorky. I mean, have you ever seen a gymnast's legs? They're like --  -- the mighty oak. It's not a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you enjoyed it, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I do cheerleading now. It's way cooler.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheerleading. For... sporting events, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sporting events, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Why don't you show me a cheer?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes. It would be interesting. A nice cheer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Buffy starts, a bit awkwardly, doing a cheer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who we gonna beat?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who we gonna beat?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- you don't have to --</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. I thought... you lead me --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You don't do anything. I do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts again.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gradually, Buffy gets more into the cheer. The steps become more complicated as she repeats the verse.</context>
      <utterance>Who we gonna beat? Who do we defeat? Who will we be pulverizing Into cream of wheat?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, what the hell is wrong with you? You threw a knife at my head!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to test you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you threw a knife at my head!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you caught it! Only the chosen one could have done that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is coming at him now. He begins to back up.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be the chosen one, okay? I don't want to spend the rest of my life chasing after vampires! I just want to graduate from high school, go to Europe, marry Charlie Sheen and die. It may not sound too exciting to a sconehead like you, but I think it's swell. And then you come along... and... and then I'm a member of the hairy mole club, so you throw things at me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last night. You knew I was sitting on a fresh grave, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy punches him in the face. He goes flying a good ways, lands on his back. His nose bleed merrily. Buffy stops.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think you understand the full implications of --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you see what's happening? You're changing. You've got powers you've only just begun to tap. Physical, mental prowess you've never dreamed of.  God, this hurts. I've administered a few shocks to your system to start the adrenaline working. I'm sorry I have to take so many shortcuts in the training process.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put your head back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two days ago, would you have even hit me? Let alone so powerfully?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I guess I would have gotten Jeffrey to hit you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy looks at the knife in her hand. The MUSIC COMES UP and we...</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. You're changing. You're becoming something extraordinarily powerful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooh, another embarrassment for the teabag, while the chosen one is still well under par.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy positions herself.</context>
      <utterance>Your turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about bats? Do they turn into bats?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No bats, no flying. They... float, occasionally. Not really flying.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toasty. Were there ever any, like, famous vampires?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, several. Lucretia Borgia, Joseph Mengele, Franklin Pangborn... are any of those names familiar?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I say 'no' does that make me a bad person?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good Lord. What do you study in history?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives a little 'isn't that funny' kind of laugh. He doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>My nails.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. You've heard of the emperor Caligula, perhaps? Or Jack the Ripper?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were vampires?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She considers this a moment. Tees off: another hole in one.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my child? Is something troubling you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sort of.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe I can help.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up a six-pack of Perrier.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Um... Could you bless these?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Buffy, who is staring down at her notebook.</context>
      <utterance>... Lothos was probably born in the eleventh or twelfth century; he's been difficult to trace. His power has increased with age. It will be a long while before you are ready to face him. We'll be lucky if we can get him to leave the area, to lie low for awhile. That will scatter the rest of them. Lothos is...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her. Is she listening?</context>
      <utterance>... is extremely powerful, but he is still a vampire, and vulnerable to the same...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is she?</context>
      <utterance>Daylight is still his enemy. The stake can still find his heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nope. No reaction, just another "Uh-huh."</context>
      <utterance>I have huge antlers growing out of my buttocks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try to pay attention.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike sits up, turns down the music. He goes to the window, begins to try to open it. It's stuck.</context>
      <utterance>Pike...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Benny, man, where you been? You bailed on me, I passed out, man, I almost did a Jimi Hendrix!</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me in.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike gets a good look at Benny for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm trying, but this window is burnt --</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Invite me in, Pike.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. What's wrong with you, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny grins, presses his slimy forehead against the glass.</context>
      <utterance>You look like shit, Benny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... feel.... pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No offense, man, but I think you're on something nasty. Why don't you just go and cool out and I'll see you in the morning or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs at his impression, brown spittle caking the window.</context>
      <utterance>The sun! It burns! It burns!</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me in, Pike! I'm hungry!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get away from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny smiles, moves suddenly out of sight. Pike looks at the window for a second, then bolts out of his room. He runs to the front door, frantically hooks the chain. Benny appears at the door's little window, banging and scraping the glass.</context>
      <utterance>I mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike backs away.</context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry! I'm hungry! I'm hungry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whistles some, keeps walking.</context>
      <utterance>Sure is cold. What a dark night. Nice night for a walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind her, another SOUND. She turns slowly. At the entrance to the alley stands a vampire. They stare at each other, some thirty feet away.</context>
      <utterance>Yeucch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves back a step. The vampire takes a step.</context>
      <utterance>Hello...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It floats rapidly at her, hissing. Buffy looks about her frantically, trapped. It hits her at top speed and she instantly rolls onto her back, flipping it and hurling it against the wall at the end of the alley. As it hits, Buffy, still rolling, produces a stake from her jacket and throws it directly at its heart. The stake punctures the startled creature's chest. Before he can so much as grab it, Buffy throws a roundhouse kick, driving the stake all the way home with her foot. The vampire screams, sinks to the ground. Buffy turns, triumphant.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toaster-caked him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was slow. Very simple. They won't all be that easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the alley was a mistake. Never corner yourself like that. If they'd come at you in force you'd be dead now. One vampire is a lot easier to kill then ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does the world 'Duhh' mean anything to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the warehouse.</context>
      <utterance>You felt a little sick, didn't you? The cramps.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice conversationalist! Yeah, I felt 'em a little, but I ain't due for two weeks since you're so excited about the subject.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's natural. A reaction to their presence, to the... unnaturalness of it. It's part of how you are able to track them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, wonderful. My secret weapon is - PMS. That's just great. Thanks for telling me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll get used to it. I'm more worried about your tactical mistakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are such a wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A wet! Didn't I just kill that vampire? I think I did. I didn't see you killing any vampires. You were too busy playing 'Beat the Clock'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't start with me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't I, like the chosen one? The one and only? The Grand High Poobah and doesn't that mean you have to be nice to me? Like, ever?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why are you always wearing black? It's so down. It's totally not your color. I don't think you have a color.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want? Encouragement?  'Gosh, Buffy, you're so special, I just want to give you a great big hug, oh I'm just having a warm fuzzy.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrick turns on her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know how many girls I've trained to be Slayers? Five. Five properly prepared girls, girls who faced their responsibilities, who worked hard to become women overnight -- harder than you've ever worked in your life -- and I saw them ripped apart. Do you want to live? Do you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy looks at him a bit.</context>
      <utterance>What did you think, that being able to jump about and hit people makes you a Slayer?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, basically, I've got the life expectancy of a zit, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if you're careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you keep doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what I was raised to do. There aren't many of us left, the Watchers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watchers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a small village in Hampshire, near Stonehenge...  ... near a bunch of big rocks. That's where I was born. My father taught me about the training, about finding the Slayers, reading the signs. There's a small cluster of us, a few families, really... most of the neighboring villagers think we're just a bunch of harmless old loonies. I thought so myself for a time, when I was younger...  I'm sorry. I'm not supposed to... I shouldn't go on like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you would.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't important.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm curious, is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy, don't... don't start thinking of me as your friend. It interferes with the work, and it...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>And it makes it worse when I die, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, I'm not gonna kick so easy. I've got a few things the other girls didn't have.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As for example, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... there's my keen fashion sense, for one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vampires of the world, beware.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In spite of himself, Merrick smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Merrick. You made a joke. Are you okay, I mean, do you want to lie down? I know it hurts the first time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they found Cassandra's body out by the railway tunnels. Nobody's saying anything, but they think she was involved in something, like, illegal or something. Like dealing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope so.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably was. What do you suppose she was doing out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coming from the opposite direction are Jeffrey, Andy and some of the other football players. They're suited up and heading for the gym.</context>
      <utterance>Eeyuu.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... And they're having some memorial service or something tomorrow. You going?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Coach said I had to work on my 'ab's.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass Buffy. Andy stops and grabs her from behind.</context>
      <utterance>Coach knows what abs are?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unthinkingly, Buffy flips Andy over and pins him against a locker.</context>
      <utterance>Got to get some!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Whoa! I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I don't actually need any right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't grab me, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. I see now the error of my mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeffrey puts his arm around Buffy but she shakes it off.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, keep your mitts off my thang. I'll pop you one.  Did he scare you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can take care of myself, Jeffrey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy goes off by herself. Jeffrey watches her.</context>
      <utterance>So I noticed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to feel needed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's move out!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lads move off. We see Nicole, Kimberly and Jennifer, who have been watching the whole exchange. Nicole and Kimberly are obviously disdainful of Buffy's behavior. Jennifer is feeling sorry for Jeffrey. Boy does she want him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, most of the time Jeffrey's really sweet, but sometimes he gets kind of... 'Me-Tarzan'ish, you know what I mean? Lately it bugs me, I guess.  Merrick? Are you still breathing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't work this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We call them zippers. They're not supposed to be a challenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's in the back. Why are we wasting time with this, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you clash, Merrick. You clash with everything. I mean you might as well go around with a sign, 'Slayers trained her.' Honestly, you look like something out of... Pasadena.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My clothes have always been perfectly serviceable.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrick comes out of the booth. He wears multi-colored parachute pants and an equally loud T-shirt. Buffy looks at him -- he looks at himself.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you're on my turf now. You're just gonna have to trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. The important thing is not to panic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike finishes, slams the hood. He picks up a battered guitar case and stuffs it into the car, shuts the door.</context>
      <utterance>You said you'd have the part by two! Christ, it's almost dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What nasty bug crawled up your bungus and where the hell are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving, man. I'm bailing town. This place has gotten way too hairy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I gonna find another mechanic stupid enough to work for my money?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, have you seen Benny lately?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... You want me to give him a message?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike gets in the car. It sputter, starts.</context>
      <utterance>You should think about leaving, too, man. Sell this place... Something's going on here. I don't know. Something real weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, you'll be coming back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Take care of yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. What should I do if I see Benny?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike peels out. Zeph watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>Run.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my guitar...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - THE SUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>burning down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amilyn hisses at him, then turns and races away, snarling, clutching what's left of his arm. One of the other vampires nears him. Pike tries to run and his knees buckle. He lands on them right next to the guitar case. As the vampire nears, he pulls the guitar out of the case and swings it, hitting the vampire in the head. He hits him again. The vampire bats away the guitar and grabs Pike. Brings his face to Pike's as Pike squirms. A blasting kick in the head from Buffy. The vampire is flung to one side, falls. He starts up at Buffy and she nails him with a stake. Pike stares at her. She pulls a walkie-talkie from her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, give me a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the walkie-talkie back.</context>
      <utterance>I'm on the east side, near the playground... all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your car?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The last vampire hits Pike from behind. Without missing a beat, Buffy picks up the guitar and snaps the neck off. She and the vampire meet in the middle -- the creature barely moves before she buries the guitar neck in its chest. It falls. Merrick runs up. He is wearing black jeans and a windbreaker. He is more modern than he was before, but subtly. He sees the decaying bodies, one with a guitar sticking out of its chest.</context>
      <utterance>It was. I think it's pretty much ready for the --</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kind of had to improvise.  Sorry about your guitar.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike's eyes glaze over slightly as he collapses into Buffy's arms.</context>
      <utterance>That's okay. Umm, listen, I'm not.... I have to fall down now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you!?!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My arm! He took my fucking arm!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lothos lets Amilyn go. Amilyn still fumes, quietly.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! You let him have it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You reckless imbecile. This place is ours for the taking and you let yourself... twelve hundred years old and you act like a child.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had him in my grasp.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only Lothos smiles at the joke. Amilyn raises his stump, looks at it. The tattered end of his jacket covers the grossness of it, but it still isn't good.</context>
      <utterance>Cheer up. You may still.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look horrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other two -- the new ones. Where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. But the boy, he couldn't kill them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns toward his chamber.</context>
      <utterance>No... Not a boy...  Find out if they're dead. And do something about that arm. Honestly, I don't know how you made it through the Crusades.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On his way through the door he passes a box on an oil drum. He plucks a large kitten out of it.</context>
      <utterance>Let me know about our little recruits. I'll be in my chamber...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... having a snack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm good. I'm good. Kind of miss my knees, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some water or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Water. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you do this kind of thing a lot? I mean, is this like a hobby?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were vampires, weren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy hands Pike the water and they move back into the living room. Pike curls up in an armchair by the window. Buffy begins stripping off her bloody clothes, leaving on a tank-top and jeans.</context>
      <utterance>God! Unbelievable. Vampires.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had a car full of stuff. Were you leaving?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I was bailing. I have a friend, and he's really... well, he's really vampire, I guess. Bad scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, stay here tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Tomorrow morning, I'm on a bus. I'm gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you gonna go?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Buffy strips down to her tank top, she notices a gash on her arm. It's not bleeding much any more, but it's fairly impressive. Pike jumps up to help as she pats it down with her shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I've always wanted to see Oxnard.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, jeez are you okay? You need a hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike looks at her a moment as she wraps her shirt around it.</context>
      <utterance>It's nothing. It doesn't hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy doesn't look up. The questions seems to upset her a great deal. She even fights back tears.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy smiles at this, though still upset. She sits down.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I just mean... well you seemed like such a flake. But, in a good way! I can just keep talking till you strike me dead, or...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things are kind of confusing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll back that up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three weeks ago all I thought about was... well, I didn't actually think about anything. I definitely didn't expect this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. My guidance counselor never mentioned anything about vampires. 'Prison' came up a few times, but nothing about undead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's weird. I went back to my old grade school once, to the playground -- I used to hang out there all the time, playing on the swings and stuff... I went back and it was so tiny, the whole place. I couldn't even fit on the swings. Everything just looked so small.  I'm sorry. I'm babbling.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she stands anyway, head to the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>No, you're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm kinda beat. You can stay in my mom's room if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll just hang out here. Make sure the sun comes up and everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll be fine. Got my chair, got my window, I'm great.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Mmkay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Buffy...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a look, heads upstairs. He watches her go, looks out the window.</context>
      <utterance>You know, you saved my life. And I just wanted to say... I forgive you for talking during the movie. Almost.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There isn't time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make time, okay? You're the one who told me to act normal. I've missed three practices already. If I'm not there for the Barber game tomorrow everyone's gonna talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another distraction. It's not right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why because it's not my fate? It's not in the Book-of-All- Knowledgefullness that I'm gonna be cheerleading at the Barber game?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sooner or later you're going to have to accept it. Your fate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pretty much learning not to accept anything anymore. Come on, Merrick. Football. Afterwards we can kill and kill until there is nothing left.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toasty. You should come; it's gonna be a great game.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll be there all right. I'm not letting you out of my sight. Not till you're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try and be inconspicuous, okay? Act like a fan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Football is my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to go.</context>
      <utterance>You're learning. Slowly, incredibly slowly, but you're learning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of the other girls ever gave me this much trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at him and runs up the steps, where Jeffrey is waiting for her. He looks at the departing figure of Merrick.</context>
      <utterance>And where are they now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's your tutor, huh? What is he, like, your boyfriend now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the building together.</context>
      <utterance>Jeffrey. Projectile vomit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some people say winning is a state of mind. Can't win out there if you don't win --  -- in here. I say, winning isn't a state of mind. I say winning is having more points. And how do we get point? By putting the thing, the ball over the.. in the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>End zone.</utterance>
   <speaker>COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. So I don't care about your minds. Maybe you're tired. Maybe you're worried about your grades. Maybe you dog just died or you've suddenly found that you're attracted to other men. I don't care! 'Cause we're a team. And there only on thing that matters to a team. What that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Winning!</utterance>
   <speaker>COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how do we win?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By putting the thing in the place!!</utterance>
   <speaker>COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So let's go!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They run out, full of fire. The coach turns to one player, whose face we cannot see.</context>
      <utterance>Yeahh!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coach heads out. The player turns around, smiles after him. It's Grueller.</context>
      <utterance>There you are! You missed practice again. You're benched till the fourth, um, the fourth part. Now get out there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHEERLEADERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the sidelines, a player hobbles out and coach pushes Grueller in. He passes Buffy and she winces slightly. It messes up the routine and Nicole practically falls over her.</context>
      <utterance>Two! Four! Six! Eight! Who do we emasculate! Barber! Barber! Yay!!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy, Jesus! You know these steps.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy starts cheering again as the players huddle.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, can I borrow your binoculars, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrick does turn.</context>
      <utterance>You're checking out the cheerleaders. All right. Buffy, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about her?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody knows about her, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The teen leans closer.</context>
      <utterance>Knows what about her?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods at Merrick; "You know what I mean". Merrick turns back.</context>
      <utterance>She's had sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on the wrong bloody side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The players scramble as Andy hands off. The carrier gets a few yards. When the pileup on the line of scrimmage peels apart, the player that had been facing Grueller is unconscious. As he is carted off the field, Grueller gleefully trots back to the huddle.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-three! Thirty-two! Hike!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watching the game, a little perplexed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - THE STANDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merrick watches Buffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - THE SIDELINES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The coach yells at the players.</utterance>
   <speaker>COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on! Do the thing! Where you... go towards the guy! Come one! Throw the thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smiling, listening to Andy call the play.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits back, turns to her neighbor.</context>
      <utterance>What are they doing? The clock's running out!  Throw the ball!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her neighbor smiles at her. He is a vampire, and he speaks in the same monotone that Grueller used. He waves a pennant.</context>
      <utterance>Are they so brain-dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAMPIRE FAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANGLE - BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She sees something is definitely wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a flash, she races onto the field.</context>
      <utterance>Jeffrey...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is she...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He stands, his eyes following Buffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She also see Buffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, wow. She's really lost it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAMPIRE FAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody rises to their feet and cheers as Jeffrey makes it to the end zone.</context>
      <utterance>Party hearty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - THE CLOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two, one, zero.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues to race after Grueller.</context>
      <utterance>He knows who I am!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLOSEUP - WHEEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>spinning</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSEUP - HAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy takes off at top speed.</context>
      <utterance>revving the engine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dyke! You're a dyke! I'm telling the world!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BUFFY'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grueller's smiling face appears over her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fall down go boom have to see the nurse.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He brings his face right next to hers. His voice is no longer passionless; it boils up from hell.</context>
      <utterance>Grueller, God, what did they do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They killed me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME SCENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He grabs her and hauls her up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She head-butts him with enormous force, sending him staggering back. Before he can recover, she dives for a pile of discarded lumber, chooses a nasty shard of wood. She turns on Grueller, who is smiling again. There are two more Vampires approaching her, surrounding her.</context>
      <utterance>No kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They rush her. She takes one on as the second hits her, knocking her over. They all three swarm over her, meeting her kicks with raking claws. The two hold her in front of Grueller.</context>
      <utterance>The Master walks tonight. This is his kingdom, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wooden shard in hand, Buffy sprints toward them, jumps into a series of flips. She lands with her legs around the vampire's shoulders, plants the stake in its heart as they topple onto Pike. For a moment, Pike and Buffy lie on top of each other, breathing hard. Then they get up awkwardly, embarrassed by their touching, (and by their slight arousal).</context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean it! I didn't mean it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't expect to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you come back?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I kind of thought I ought to be here. You know, this isn't exactly the kind of thing you can run away from.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start out of the site.</context>
      <utterance>Besides, Oxnard sucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I... I really do want to help. I mean, these guys are dag nasty, and somewhere my best friend is out there, and I'd like to, I don't know. Even the score. Do some damage. I'm good with damage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pike, I don't think you're up to this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I could help. You gonna tell me you don't need help?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see a girl come by here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't mean, like, a cheerleader?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I saw her. Bitch took my wheels.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wheels?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My bike! She's a lesbian, too. She told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way did she go?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points. The CAMERA PANS with Merrick as he takes a step in that direction, leaving the biker behind (and momentarily OUT</context>
      <utterance>Down there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA PAN back with Merrick as he turns to the biker, but in his place stands Lothos. Not five feet from Merrick.</context>
      <utterance>Idiot girl. Can't watch over her. How long ago did --</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the night. Merrick slowly reaches for a gun stuck in the back of his pants as Lothos continues.</context>
      <utterance>It's a beautiful night. I have never understood the human tendency to equate darkness with emptiness. To me the black is so thick with life, like soil... like blood. Darkness writhes under my eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who you are. She's out her, as well, isn't she? Another Slayer. Who is it this time? What offering have you brought me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy? What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God. It's him. I think it's him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy ups and runs in the direction of the noise. Calls back to Pike.</context>
      <utterance>Merrick...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs out of sight.</context>
      <utterance>Stay here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't really matter. The names, the faces, they all melt together. After a time, there really is no difference. One more pathetic bitch, begging for me to suck on her clotted heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This one may surprise you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs. He doesn't appear to have noticed the gun, but:</context>
      <utterance>I rather doubt it, if she was raised here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she? I can't wait to meet her. Do you think she's ready to face me? Or perhaps you can stop me with that gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrick looks out at the trees nearby.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at you. You pathetic thing. So small, so full of fury. After you've served me for a hundred years, I think you'll have a little more perspective.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lothos rushes suddenly at Merrick, hissing, his feet just off the ground. Merrick steps back, whips out the GUN, and SHOOTS himself without hesitation in the head. Buffy's eyes go wide. Lothos growls, holding Merrick's spurting corpse. A small, involuntary noise escapes Buffy.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits heavily on his grave.</context>
      <utterance>Ummm, our Father, Who art in Heaven, duhmm... hallowed be Thy name. Uhh, kingdom come, daily break, I don't know. I don't even know if you're religious. You probably are. But you're dead, you know. You're just totally dead. and...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, looks down for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>... and I don't know what to do. You were the one who... I don't know if the training was over. I don't even know if I passed. You're so stupid! How could you be so stupid? What am I supposed to do without you? You son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike pays no attention to this babbling monologue. Over the course of it he takes a slim, handmade wooden shaft, slightly thicker than an arrow, and rubs it with garlic. He places it in the crossbow, take aim in front of him. He fires into the tire of a truck. The tire pops flat. Zeph cracks up.</context>
      <utterance>Hah, I'd knew you'd be back. Didn't I say you'd be back? Ha, ha, ha! You're sitting in your old car saying 'Nope, I'm never coming back.' Hee, Hee! Like you got anywhere to go. 'I'm never coming back' But I knew you would. Birds got to return to the nest sooner or later. That's what I said. Just like I told you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike, still not listening, continues to work.</context>
      <utterance>Hah! Shot the damn tire, dumbass, didn't even look, just going around shooting things, popped it flat, ya bonehead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got all the plastic stuff. What should I do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennifer crosses out as the two resume their conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Throw it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really was way way too too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please! When she ran onto the field in the middle of the game? Was that the most out-of-it thing ever, or did I blink?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. Jennifer is the first to see Buffy walk in, looking cleaned-up but still ragged. They stop laughing.</context>
      <utterance>I'm, like, yelling at her, 'What are you doing?' And she's going 'Jeffrey, Jeffrey!' Way mental.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Buffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were supposed to be here at three.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy, what is your sitch? You're acting like The Thing From Another Tax-Bracket; it's too weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, a lot's been going on. That's what I wanted to tell you guys about. I need to tell you. You see... a while ago, I met this guy --</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God you're having an affair.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does Jeffrey know?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not that at all. This is an old guy, he's like fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY/NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eeyuu.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. Listen. Haven't you guys noticed how weird things have gotten around here? Like, people disappearing, people turning up dead...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weird? You mean like you hanging out with that homeless, Poke? I saw you last night after the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pike.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're having a fling with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't look fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys. Guys! Reality pulled out of her five minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you've got a grip.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're so out of it. You've blown off cheerleading, you've blown off dance committee --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me for having something important to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't important? The earth is our home.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kimberly, it's a dance. It's a stupid dance with a bunch of stupid kids that I see every stupid day.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, we're stupid now?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, just because you're having full-on wiggans doesn't mean you have to drag us into it. This isn't just any dance. It happens ot be the last dance of our last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except for Prom.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Spring Fling.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the January Semi-formal --</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay! Look, Buffy. You want to play house with the unwashed masses, that's fine. But personally, I think you ought to spend a little time prioritizing. I really do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to you. What language are you speaking?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She storms out.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of my facial.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess you got what you came for.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicole...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She also leaves, with Jennifer. Buffy stands alone in the room, small amidst the streamers.</context>
      <utterance>Later for it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BUFFY'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, seems to notice something about Buffy.</context>
      <utterance>Dinner's in the fridge, stay away from the Jag, we'll be back by twelve.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you gained a few pounds? Maybe it's that outfit...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's Bobby gonna say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Mom; I've never met Bobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she's out. Buffy looks at her clothes, herself.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't we the chatty ones. Kiss noise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy doesn't stop. He paces her.</context>
      <utterance>Buffy, hey, I've been looking all over for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been working on some stuff for you. What'cha doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going shopping. Don't try to stop me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool. I could actually use a couple of Allen wrenches. What do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dress, huh? What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come again?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to the senior dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops.</context>
      <utterance>Second word... sound like 'dance'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to the dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In order to dance and to drink punch and to be with my friends. Comprende?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe this. The world's under attack by the legions of the undead and you're going to a mixer?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a mixer. It's the senior dance. And it's important. You wouldn't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got that right. I thought you wanted to kill vampires.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to kill anybody, and I don't want to talk about it anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I know you're bummed about your friend, and I'm really sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did what he was supposed to.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Buffy, you're the guy, the chosen guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. I'm the chosen one. And I choose to be shopping.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy raises her fist at him; he starts back, involuntarily.</context>
      <utterance>I should have known.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy walks away, leaving Pike alone.</context>
      <utterance>Benny was right. You guys are all exactly the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Pike walks off, the camera TILTS UP the lamp post behind them. Benny is perched upon it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not disappointed, I'm just angry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy? Buffy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy enters the gym. She is wearing a long white strapless gown. It is lovely, but very conservative for this crowd. Over her shoulder is a purse that goes with the dress. She enters hesitantly, looking around her for Jeffrey. She passes Andy, who is moving away from Gary Murray.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it came with the tux.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy! Looking tasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Andy has moved on. Buffy works her way through the crowd to the punch bowl, sees Nicole and Kimberly. They stop whispering real quick.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Have you seen Jeffrey?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicole and Kimberly look at each other significantly.</context>
      <utterance>Have you guys seen Jeffrey? The limo never showed, I thought he might be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't seen him tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up a glass of punch.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you guys are here. It's good to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, whoops I came.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look way pretty, Kim.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I like your little outfit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's amazing what you can do with a parachute and some starch.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy is startled by this attack. Nicole giggles.</context>
      <utterance>As long as there's room for three in it. What, didn't you bring your new friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeffrey suddenly appears between them. Jennifer is on his arm.</context>
      <utterance>I guess you guys are mad at me. I'm sorry. I've been really --</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy, what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we were meeting here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- who is practically hyperventilating, pulling at his arm like a dog on a leash.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here with Jenny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on, Buffy. You know what's going on. It's not working out at all. I've got to move on. I mean, I've got needs, too. I told you about all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you didn't. When?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you get my message?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You broke up with my machine?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't home. Like always.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You left me a message?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the mention of her name Jenny jumps, and in her haste to get away, she bumps into Buffy's arm, spilling bright red punch on Buffy's chest. She flees, Jeffrey in tow. They leave the gym. Kimberly finds it all pretty funny. Nicole is silent. Buffy turns away, toward the wall. A soft BALLAD come on over the SPEAKERS. Tears are forming in Buffy's eyes, as she wipes futilely at her dress. Finally she turns, looks toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm out of here. Jenny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I crashed your party.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty shallow of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you came.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike picks up a glass of punch as he notices the stain on Buffy's dress. He looks about him a bit, then without hesitation dumps some punch on his lapel, matching stains. Buffy smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you look like you're having a swell time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will I get the shit kicked out of me if I ask you to dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin slow dancing, not too close.</context>
      <utterance>I don't actually think Jeffrey's gonna notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dance for a while, closer and closer.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, you're the one I'm afraid of.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy pulls him closer, holds him, whispers almost weakly in his ear.</context>
      <utterance>You know, you're not like the other girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see couples dancing, kissing... Gary Murray watching them.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The window SHATTERS by her head, a vampire's hand reaching for her. She screams, starts back. Other windows shatter, vampires appearing all around. A couple of students run for the inner door but it is locked shut from the other side. Gradually the party stops as everybody becomes aware of the situation. They vaguely herd to the middle of the room.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - BUFFY AND PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking around, assessing the situation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BLOODY STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He falls to the ground, a few feet in front of the doorway. Nobody moves for a second. Then one of the students starts toward the body.</context>
      <utterance>They're out there! They're vampires! God, help me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy does instead, checking the lifeless body and listening as a number of figures begin to lumber toward the door through the mist. Buffy steps back as three 17-year-old vampire come to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Don't go near the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST VAMPIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's party time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry! They can't come in here. They can't come in unless they're invited.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>I already invited them.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike reaches into an inner pocket and pulls out a number of small stakes he has made, hands them to Buffy. She opens her purse.</context>
      <utterance>They're seniors!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first thing we should --</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST VAMPIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy... You wanna dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you're busted.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND VAMPIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We want her! We want Buffy. Send her out.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST VAMPIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They fade back, almost out of sight. Pike looks out the window. More are gathering.</context>
      <utterance>Or we come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARY MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, everybody stay calm.  What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks bad, Buffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send her out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll kill us! She's the one they're mad at.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! Send her out!</utterance>
   <speaker>GARY MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody be quiet!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, are you kidding? They'll kill her!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll kill us!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some punch?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARY MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But other students have picked up the cry, are clamoring to sacrifice Buffy. Pike crosses to his bag, sitting by the door. Two guys move toward Buffy, Andy intervenes. Pike steps in front of Buffy, holding his custom made cartridge-load crossbow. Trains it on the others. They quiet down.</context>
      <utterance>I got detention slips here, I'm not afraid to use them...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy looks at the partygoers. Her friends. They stare back at her, scared, angry. She looks out the door. Back at her friends.</context>
      <utterance>There's gotta be a back way out of here, or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going out the front.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you nuts, Buffy? There's a hundred of them out there. They'll rip us apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're staying here.  Some of them might not come after me. If they don't this place is gonna turn into a total stain.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say that like it's a bad thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy, this is crazy. What do these guys want?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy looks at her a moment, moves off. Buffy goes to Pike's bag, starts pulling out stakes.</context>
      <utterance>Andy, start breaking up some chairs. You'll need weapons.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good thing one of us was prepared.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy stands up. She kisses Pike very hard on the lips.</context>
      <utterance>Buffy, there's no way you're going out there alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kneels down, begins to rip the hem of her dress.</context>
      <utterance>Don't piss me off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet you feel stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARY MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Students start mobilizing.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get away from these windows! Find something to cover them with.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring round the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nails and stuff we used to put everything up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy and some others drag a table forward. Pike helps hoist it up against the window. He looks one last time outside, then covers it up.</context>
      <utterance>Get 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes! Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they are spouting this nonsense, Buffy zooms IN and OUT OF the FRAME behind the car. After a second she walks back INTO the FRAME, staring at the two of them.</context>
      <utterance>Make me a woman! Yes! Make me a woman!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She books out again, the horde on her heels.</context>
      <utterance>That was quick!  Oops!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeffrey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm done. Are you done?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No --</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hoists Pike up and backhands him in the jaw, sends him flying against a wall. Pike shakes his head as Benny comes at him again, no longer smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't this great, Pike? Isn't it great? Finally got those bitches on the run.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns suddenly and grabs a girl, yells in her face.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I'm angry! I leave you alone for five minutes, and look who you're hanging out with!</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was gonna change you, man. I was gonna give you life! Do you know what that means?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy screams, turns, and Amilyn decks her, sends her flying back into the classroom. The stake flies out of her hand. It lands on a desk by the window. Buffy does not land nearly as well, crashing into a pile of desks and twisting her leg badly. Amilyn laughs repulsively, advancing.</context>
      <utterance>All clear?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleased to meet you! Won't you guess my --  -- name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kicks her again.</context>
      <utterance>It wouldn't be 'Dick,' would it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Lefty'?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her by the neck with his one arm and pins her against the wall in the corner. She reaches for the stake but it is just out of reach. He is squeezing the life out of her, his face inches from hers.</context>
      <utterance>You're a fool, bloodbag. Die a fool and go to hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy looks about for succor.</context>
      <utterance>The chosen one. You're just another bloodbag -- not even fit to die for the Master. When will you ever learn?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do know... one thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls down hard on the shade pull and lets go.</context>
      <utterance>I know... what time sunrise is.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns in horror, letting go of Buffy, trying to catch the shade. The instant he releases her, Buffy grabs the stake and in one swift motion, buries it in Amilyn's back. The shade goes up, flapping loudly as it spins. It is still pitch black out. Amilyn stare, wide-eyed and silent, at the night as he dies.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amilyn spins, dying rage in his eyes. He grabs her. His strength is formidable even as his body begins to smoke. Suddenly screaming, he forces her over suddenly with such power that the two of them go crashing through the floorboards.</context>
      <utterance>It's in about four hours, Dick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lothos rises from the pool, smiling. Buffy is clearly paralyzed by fear.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, god, no... not yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves toward her.</context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd come.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, my fool is dead. He was careless, always. Still, I'll pull out your tongue for that.  Don't you understand? I've killed you a dozen times. Your life is not a blink of my eye, not a single breath. I have lived in the shadows, in the pulsing filth behind men's eyes. A thousand years, and more. I have conversed with the worms that fed on my corpse and I have bathed in the blood of emperors.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever thrown up in the front row of a Richard Marx concert?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she is up, turning to run. He is thrown momentarily by her insolence.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kneels over her prostrate body. She is reaching frantically into her purse. He runs his hand along her body, a gesture both lustful and disdainful.</context>
      <utterance>You waste time. That is a sin.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're even weaker than the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls out a small cross, holds it in front of him. He snarls at it, then grabs it, his hand around her. The cross bursts into flame. He holds her hand onto it.</context>
      <utterance>I think you've forgotten something.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This? This is you only weapon? Your puny faith?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With her other hand, Buffy holds up her hair spray.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike and the others see her. Pike and Andy run to her to help.</context>
      <utterance>Don't let her in! Don't let her in!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes them away. Lothos crashes through the trap door behind her, ugly and crazed. He picks her up, floating a good two feet off the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurls her the length of the room. She hits a locker, which opens, spilling out someone's notebook. The binder falls open, inside it is a plastic pen case with pens and pencils within. Buffy looks, by this time, like shit. She props herself up as best she can, looks about her. There is nothing wooden, nothing sharp, within reach.</context>
      <utterance>You bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy charges Lothos from behind. Pike tries to stop him, but is too late, as Lothos grabs him by the face without even looking at him.</context>
      <utterance>You would challenge me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am a God! A God!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lothos roars. Furious, he charges Buffy, his feet just skimming the ground, racing toward her, violently fast, upon her... She spins, on her feet in a flash, one quick motion. She thrusts her palm forward and stops him, cold, like Superman stopping a train, palm at his chest. Silence. Buffy looks directly into his eyes, the mad rictus of his face. Lothos stops, almost wide-eyed, as he looks down at his chest. Sticking out of the middle of his chest is a small eraser, and a 2. He steps back, staring at Buffy. The expression on his horrible face seems to have changed to one almost of respect. Her look is unfathomable. Lothos smiles, graciously.</context>
      <utterance>I am so sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He falls gently to the ground. He's dust before he hits it. Silence. One by one the vampires, stricken, slip out into the night.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't... hurt... as much as I had imagined.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was even crazier after that. I mean it, you wouldn't even have recognized her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennifer nods. Kimberly wrinkles her nose in distaste.</context>
      <utterance>Buffy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't even hardly talk to anyone in school. All year. She didn't even go to the prom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennifer glares at him.</context>
      <utterance>I heard she got straight A's.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMBERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The worst is, her parents -- this is true -- her parents were gonna send her to the Bahamas for graduation, and she refused. True story. She said she didn't want to go. It is to vomit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, where is she now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say it was a bad idea, I just said the timing was off. We could maybe wait till later.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be such a fraidy-cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's afraid? Besides me, I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've come all this way. We just have to check it out. I got a hunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffy stops at a large, elaborately carved door. She turns to Pike.</context>
      <utterance>You're the boss, boss. I just thought maybe we should wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
