<movie id="111" title="Buried">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kicks and slams his hands against the top and sides of the coffin, all to no avail. His violent movements cause small grains of sand to trickle in through the space between the sides and top of the coffin, as well as a small gap that exists between one of the coffin's broken wooden planks. Sweat cascades down the side of his neck, dripping from his dampened brow. The heat inside the extremely close confines of the coffin is stifling.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! Help me!! Help me!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paul continues with his futile efforts to pry off the top of the coffin. The sides, the top, the bottom -- all are too thoroughly reinforced by the force of what surrounds the coffin. Sand. It becomes clear to him that he is buried. He tries his best to calm himself, though he has trouble catching his breath. It takes him some time, but he eventually achieves some semblance of calm. Getting a good look at him for the first time, we see that Paul is somewhere around 37 years old. Unshaven and physically unremarkable, he embodies the blue-collar American everyman. He coughs. The minimal amount of oxygen in the coffin makes it hard for him to breathe. His eyes widen a bit upon seeing an exposed, rusty nail. He tries desperately to use the nail to cut through the old, frayed ropes that bind his hands. Doing so is no easy task. The incredibly tight quarters makes his every action nearly impossible. After a lengthy struggle, the rope snaps. Paul quickly frees his hands. A small victory. Very small. The heat is unbearable. Paul takes off his button-down shirt, leaving him in a T-shirt. His body battles against the walls and the ceiling of the coffin with every move he makes. He tosses his button-down shirt down by his feet. His undershirt is drenched through with sweat. Still trying to calm himself, but having little success in doing so, Paul looks around the coffin. His feet, though only his body-length away, seem miles from him.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody help me! Please!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Getting only two digits into dialing the number, he cannot remember much more and closes the phone. He wedges the lit Zippo into sand, which is compacted against a small hole in the wall of the coffin. Paul reaches into his pants pocket, frantically searching for something. He hastily removes a prescription pill bottle and a small, metal flask. Both are not what he was looking for. He then reaches to his back pocket and removes his wallet. It's empty. His license, his credit cards, his cash and, most importantly at that very moment, a piece of paper with the Safe Number written on it, are all missing.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, come on. What was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He screams aloud again, hoping greatly that someone can hear him. His frenzied maneuvering puts out the flame of the Zippo.</context>
      <utterance>No. Where the hell is it? Son of a...Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>His words barely make it pass the coffin walls. With the cell phone still in hand, and laboring to reclaim the breath he just expended, Paul turns to desperation. He dials the international code of 001, and then dials 911. A FEMALE 911 OPERATOR answers almost immediately.</context>
      <utterance>Help me! Please! Somebody help me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>911, please hold. The Female 911 Operator places Paul on hold.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul accidentally bangs the cap of the Zippo against the coffin wall, putting out the flame. She quickly returns.</context>
      <utterance>No! Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>911. What is your emergency?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is so incredibly panicked that he has trouble remaining coherent. After a few sparks, the Zippo is re-lit.</context>
      <utterance>911. What's the problem, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm buried. You have to help me. You have to help me, I can't breathe...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm buried in a coffin. Please help me! Send someone to find me...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir...slow down. What is your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul. Paul Conroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Mister Conroy. Can you tell me your location?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please help me.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I'm in a coffin. I don't know where. I'm scared.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in a coffin?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's, like, one of those old, wooden ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you at a funeral home?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I don't know. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are calling me right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're buried in a coffin, where are you calling from?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A cell phone. There was an old cell phone in the coffin.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're calling from your cell phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. No. It's not mine, but yes, I'm calling from a cell phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a cell phone in the coffin when you climbed in?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't climb in.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you end up in the coffin, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was put here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the coffin?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Please send help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're saying the coffin is buried?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so. It's...it's hot in here. I can't breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know your location, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somewhere in Iraq.</context>
      <utterance>I told you, I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Iraq?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I'm a truck driver, an American. I work for CRT.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a soldier, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Please, please listen to me. I'm a truck driver. I work for CRT. I'm a civilian contractor working in Iraq. We were attacked in Baqubah, they...they...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>STARTS CRYING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...shot them. All of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They shot who, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of the other drivers.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're saying this happened in Iraq? The country?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Please, you have to help me. They gave me a safety number to call, but I had it stored in my wallet and --</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Conroy, this is 911 emergency in Youngstown, Ohio.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohio?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE 911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. I'm not sure exactly how you called here if you're in another country, but if you'd like, I can patch you through to the Sheriff's Department.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheriff's Department? No...you don't underst...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>GIVING UP</mode>
      <context>Realizing that his conversation is both lengthy and useless, Paul ends the call. He checks the battery life on the phone. It still holds steady at two bars. He immediately dials another number, one that he can recall with ease. He again enters the 001 international code before making the call. Paul then dials his home phone. It rings several times, so far unanswered.</context>
      <utterance>...forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After sitting through the agony of a few more rings, Paul is met with the answering machine. The voice of his young son, SHANE, is heard on the answering machine greeting.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, come on. Pick up. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the sound of the Beep, Paul leaves a frenzied, rambling message.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for calling the Conroy's. We're not home right now. Please leave a message at the beep. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Linda, honey, it's me. Listen, I need you to contact the National Guard right away. Or the Pentagon. Tell them we were attacked in the Diyala Provence, in Baqubah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paul hangs up. He dials his wife's cell phone right away. After several rings, her cell phone voice mail picks up. We hear the sound of Linda, Paul's wife, on her outgoing message.</context>
      <utterance>They have to find me. Please help me, baby. Please help them find me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Beep sounds and Paul immediately tears into his voice message.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, this is Linda. Please leave a message. Thanks and have a great day.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing himself say those last words gives him pause. The gravity of the situation fully takes hold.</context>
      <utterance>Linda, it's Paul. I need you to call me right away. This is an absolute emergency. Call the number that comes up on your phone. Call me at that number. If I don't answer, call the Pentagon or the F.B.I. I don't know what the hell is going on, but I'm buried in a box...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paul ends the call. He nervously looks at the amount of battery life remaining on the phone. Still holding strong at two bars. He notices the flickering light of the Zippo. It, too, appears to be using up small amounts of oxygen. He closes the lid, extinguishing the flame. Total darkness. Silence, save for Paul's increasingly heavy breaths. He begins to hyperventilate. He knows that preserving oxygen is paramount, so he does his best to calm himself. The healthy swig he takes from his flask helps.</context>
      <utterance>...I can't breathe in here. Make sure you call me right away. Please, baby, please call me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>411 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What city and state, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul reaches for his button-down shirt. Fishes for pens stashed in his lapel pocket, while keeping the phone pressed to his ear with his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Um...I don't know. The F.B.I., wherever they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>411 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a specific city you'd like to be connected to, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care, any city. Just connect me to the F.B.I.</utterance>
   <speaker>411 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul cannot bear to listen any further to this list that seemingly never ends.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I have F.B.I. field offices listed in Boston, New York, Philadelphia, New Haven, Los Angeles, Chicago, Denver --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anywhere! Any city, just connect me, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>411 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir, but I'm not allowed to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, um...Chicago. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>411 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please hold for your number. Paul is transferred to an AUTOMATED MESSAGE.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUTOMATED MESSAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The number you requested, 312-421-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>AUTOMATED MESSAGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He presses the number one and is connected directly. After a few rings, SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS answers.</context>
      <utterance>...can be connected for an additional charge of twenty-five cents by pressing the number one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chicago field office. Special Agent Harris.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Is this the F.B.I.?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it is, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm calling from Iraq. I'm buried in the desert somewhere. I need you to help me --</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa, sir. Slow down. When were you in Iraq?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now. I'm there now. I'm a truck driver for CRT. I've been here for nine months.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I have your name please, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul Conroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>saying it as he writes it</utterance>
   <speaker>DOWN)</speaker>
      <mode> DOWN)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul Conroy.  Okay, Paul, explain to me what's going on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. Me and a convoy of other drivers were delivering kitchen parts to a community center. As we got closer, a bunch of kids started throwing rocks at our trucks. Then an IED went off up ahead and blew up one of the other trucks. These guys came out from behind the houses with guns and started shooting everybody right there on the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you shot at?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know!  I don't know. I was way in the back of the convoy. I must have got hit in the head with one of the rocks and got knocked out. That's the last thing I remember. But now I just woke up, and I was tied up and buried in a coffin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who put you there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Special Agent Harris sounds slightly skeptical of Paul's claims.</context>
      <utterance>I guess whoever ambushed us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bunch of kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're not listening. The kids threw the rocks at us, but then some Iraqi guys -- maybe insurgents, I don't fucking know -- popped out of nowhere and started shooting at us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you said they didn't shoot at you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They didn't, I don't know! But they shot them!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, you're going to have to stop shouting if --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please!!</context>
      <utterance>I'm shouting because you're not listening! I need you to help me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul takes a moment to center himself.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you trace my call? GPS or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is it that they didn't shoot you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea. They didn't, that's all I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your social security number, Paul?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Who cares? I'm buried in the middle of the fucking desert! Who cares what my social security number is?! I'm an American citizen. Just send someone to find me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cell phone starts breaking up.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know where you're ...lo...if...dy..</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? What? I can't hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bet...un...near...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul checks the phone's display, where he sees that the call has been lost.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?! Hello?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cell phone service temporarily goes down. Paul lights the Zippo to help him see the cell phone screen. He tries to make a call, but nothing happens. He shakes the phone, moves it around the coffin, all in desperate hope that he will get a signal. He soon does. He looks at the number for the F.B.I. that he has written on the wall, thinking about calling them back. He then checks the battery life on his phone, which remains at two bars. Paul then decides to make a different call, this time to a phone number he has committed to memory: his employer back in the U.S., Crestin, Roland and Thomas (CRT). He closes the lid of the Zippo, extinguishing the flame. After a few rings, a CRT OPERATOR answers.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRT OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for calling Crestin, Roland and Thomas. How may I direct your call?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody, I need to talk to someone right away. It's an emergency.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRT OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul Conroy. I'm a driver for you guys. I'm calling from Iraq. My convoy was attacked.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRT OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, if this is a crisis situation you need to contact the Safety Number your were provided.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know, but I don't have it. They took it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRT OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who took it, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Iraqis, I think. I don't remember, I blacked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRT OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to put you through to Alan Davenport.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Davenport? Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRT OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Director of Personnel. Please hold.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is placed on hold. Synthesized soft rock plays in the background of the phone, maddening Paul further. Over the music, a CRT SPOKESMAN is heard, speaking a recorded testimonial during the on-hold message.</context>
      <utterance>Personnel? No, I need to talk --</utterance>
   <speaker>CRT SPOKESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The message is interrupted by ALAN DAVENPORT's outgoing voice message.</context>
      <utterance>At CRT, we work with our clients to provide effective and sustainable solutions to the challenges they face in our fast-growing, global economy. As the premiere...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BEEP sounds. Paul is confused as to why he was patched through to someone in human resources, but leaves a message nevertheless.</context>
      <utterance>You've reached Alan Davenport, personnel director at Crestin, Roland and Thomas. Please leave your name and number at the tone and I will return your call as soon as possible.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a beat, Paul hears breathing on the other end of the phone. He also hears a discordance of background sound; the din of a room filled with Arabic-speaking men.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Hello? Is anyone there? Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Still, Paul's words are only met with slow, measured breaths.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Who are you? Please, you have to help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The person on the other end eventually speaks. An Iraqi man, JABIR, talks forcefully and aggressively in broken English.</context>
      <utterance>Who is this? Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Breathe no breathe?</context>
      <utterance>Breathe no breathe, American? Ah?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I don't know what you're saying. Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>American can breathe no breathe?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I can't breathe. Please get me out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, please get me out. Help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soldier.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no I'm not a soldier. I'm a truck driver. That's it. I'm not a soldier. I'm a contractor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Contractor?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not a soldier.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's right. A contractor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blackwater.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not for Blackwater. I'm not a security contractor. Truck driver, I'm a truck driver. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are American.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despair falls upon Paul. It becomes clear that Jabir is responsible for all of this. As such, Paul crosses out the word "HELP?" Closes the lid of the Zippo, leaving only the cell phone display screen to illuminate his face.</context>
      <utterance>Then you are soldier.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But, you still shot at us.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not. I'm here unarmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In head and in throat, so you tell no more lies.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not lying! We were all drivers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trucks. The big trucks you see driving around with the supplies? That's us. That's me. We're not soldiers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five million money.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five million money tonight by nine PM or you stay. Buried like dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five million dollars? From who?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your family.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My family doesn't have five million dollars. If they did, I wouldn't be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Embassy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence on the other end of the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, yes, the Embassy will pay you. If you let me go, they'll pay you the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jabir hangs up the phone, forcing Paul to instantly come to grips with the fact that he is being held hostage. He lays back in the coffin, shell-shocked. Physically spent, the cell phone falls from his hands and onto the floor. The display screen casts a dim light throughout the coffin.</context>
      <utterance>Nine PM, five million money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>TO HIMSELF</mode>
      <context>He cannot remember the number he's thinking of. He notices that the flame of the Zippo flickers, indicating its use of his much-needed oxygen. Paul closes the lid, extinguishing the flame. A second later, we see him, lit by the cell phone display screen. He dials the international code for the United States, followed by 411 information. A MALE 411 OPERATOR answers.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, what's her number?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE 411 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What city and listing, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hastings, Michigan. I'm looking for Donna Mitchell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MALE 411 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have two Donna Mitchells, sir. One on Federal Road and one on Ardmore Avenue.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ardmore Avenue...I think. Yeah. Shit, I don't know. Just give me that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE 411 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ardmore Avenue?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Ardmore Avenue.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE 411 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is switched to an AUTOMATED MESSAGE.</context>
      <utterance>Please hold for your number.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUTOMATED MESSAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul writes Donna's number and name on the top of the coffin and then presses the number one. He is connected. Her phone rings and rings. Paul's frustration is evident.</context>
      <utterance>The number you requested, 269-948- 1998 can automatically be dialed for a charge of twenty-five cents by pressing the number one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings some more. Paul checks the battery life -- still at one and a half bars. DONNA eventually answers.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Where the hell is everyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing her voice, Paul hurriedly places the phone to his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donna, it's Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, how's it going?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna interrupts. We realize, as does Paul, that her voice was actually coming from her answering machine.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Linda? She's not answering her phone. I need to talk to her, I've been taken hostage by...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode>OVERLAPPING</mode>
      <context>His hand falls to his forehead, defeated.</context>
      <utterance>Fooled you. I'm not really home. But if you leave a message, I'll get back to you as soon as I get in. Bye-bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Donna, I need to talk to Linda. It's an absolute emergency. Have her call me. Use star sixty-nine and find out the number I'm calling from and have her call me...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donna.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to talk to Linda. Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I haven't talked to her all day. Call her cell phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you near a computer or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...yeah. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn it on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look up the number for the State Department for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just heading out to the supermarket. I really don't have</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donna, please, please, please -- just get me the number.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everything alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Everything is not alright! So, please, just look up the number.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't fucking yell at me, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not yelling!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you are. Just like you did last year at the cookout. I'm not going to tolerate --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>EXPLODING</mode>
      <context>Donna hangs up on him. Realizing this, Paul bangs his fists and claws at the top of the coffin, bloodying some of his fingers and knuckles in the process. He violently tosses and turns and screams at the top of his lungs, like an animal trapped in a cage. Tears spray from his eyes as spit shakes free from his mouth by the force of his shudder. He eventually calms quite a bit. Sniffing away tears and taking notice of the damage he's done to his hands, Paul slows his breathing as best he can.</context>
      <utterance>Just get me the fucking number!! Get me the number, get me the number!!</utterance>
   <speaker>24.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The silence is almost comforting. Paul closes his eyes, regretfully accepting what appears will be his inescapable fate. After a beat, he calls Donna back. Knowing it is Paul calling, she answers right away, attitude at the ready.</context>
      <utterance>He lies there, motionless.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes every ounce of Paul's being to keep himself from going off the deep end. He takes a beat to compose himself and then finally offers a very delicate and deliberate response.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donna, I'm very sorry I yelled. But, I'm only going to ask you once more to get me this number. If you don't get me this number, I'm going to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please...the number.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have time to explain.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>We hear Donna put down the phone. In the b.g., we hear the sound of keys being pressed on a computer keyboard. After a beat, she picks the phone back up.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...State Department. It's 202-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul hangs up on Donna mid-sentence. He dials the number the State Department right away. A STATE DEPARTMENT REP answers after a few rings.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell's going --</utterance>
   <speaker>STATE DEPARTMENT REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>United States Department of State.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm an American citizen, working in Iraq. I've been taken hostage. I need to speak to someone right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>STATE DEPARTMENT REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you calling from, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Iraq. I'm a truck driver for CRT -- Crestin, Roland and Thomas. We were attacked and now I'm being held for ransom.</utterance>
   <speaker>STATE DEPARTMENT REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are the kidnappers with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm buried somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>STATE DEPARTMENT REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're buried?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's an old coffin, I think.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, in a coffin, a wooden box.</utterance>
   <speaker>STATE DEPARTMENT REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you try contacting the military out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have the number.</utterance>
   <speaker>STATE DEPARTMENT REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What number?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was given a number to call, a safety number. But the people took it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>STATE DEPARTMENT REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people holding you hostage?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>STATE DEPARTMENT REP</speaker>
      <mode>DISCONCERTED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...hold on. Let me connect you...hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is placed on hold. As he waits, his eyes wander around the coffin. He looks at the numbers he has written. After a moment, REBECCA BROWNING, a State Department official, picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>No. Wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rebecca Browning.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, hello. I was just informed of your situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, my situation. I'm running out of time and you people keep putting me on hold. What the hell is wrong with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be sorry. Just help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just have a few questions for you, Mister Conroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to be kidding me.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's important that I get this information. It will make a rescue</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, wait, wait...how did you know my name?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rebecca is silent on the other end of the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I never gave you my name. I don't think I gave it to the other guy, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We received a call from a representative at CRT. You left him a message?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He contacted us right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, since you know what the hell is going on, what have you done to get me out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's little we can do from Washington.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, that's it? I'm just supposed to rot in here because there's little you can do?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to know where you were when your convoy was ambushed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the Diyala Provence. In Baqubah.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. And has contact been made with the kidnappers?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. The guy told me that he wants five million dollars by nine o'clock tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or else...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even faced with Paul's sarcasm, Rebecca remains stolid. Professional.</context>
      <utterance>Or else he'll bring me to Sea World. What do you think, lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll do everything we can.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you'll pay them?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That we can't do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait...what?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the policy of the United States government to not negotiate with terrorists.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To hell with that! It's easy for you to worry about policy, you're sitting in an air conditioned office somewhere, probably finishing up your sandwich from lunch. You're not the one stuck in a coffin, buried in the God damn desert!</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand your frustration --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rebecca is silent on the other end of the phone. Paul wonders if she is still there. The idea of being alone again scares him terribly.</context>
      <utterance>Frustration? Lady, I'm going to fucking die in here. Understand that!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Worried, Paul lights the Zippo. The reflection of the flame dances on his frightened eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Momentary relief. After a beat:</context>
      <utterance>I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then say something. Tell me how you're going to get me out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the number on the phone you're calling from?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Did it come up on your end?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul takes out his pen.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's listed as unavailable. Do this -- take down this number.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dan Brenner. He's the commander of the Hostage Working Group over in Iraq.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hostage Working Group?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul shakes his head in disgust.</context>
      <utterance>We formed it in 2004 to deal with situations such as yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Situations. I love how you keep calling it that.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you write down the number?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Hold on, I'll connect you with him now. He should be expecting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the news? I'm going to call them.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Do not, I repeat, do not contact the news.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul doesn't buy it.</context>
      <utterance>It will only complicate things further and threaten your chances of rescue.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's bullshit. You're just covering your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm covering yours. Everyone who needs to know about this does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't go looking for something if you don't know it's missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul still contemplates contacting the news, but soon acquiesces to Rebecca's pleas for him not to.</context>
      <utterance>That's why you need to contact Dan Brenner right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rebecca's gone. Paul waits. Several beeps sound as he's being transferred. Paul hears a faint sound coming from behind him, outside the coffin. While the beeps continue to sound, he lights the Zippo, circumspectly looking behind him. He doesn't see anything. With the Zippo still lit, Paul takes a deep, centering breath, followed by another. A few more long beeps pass before a ring is heard. After two rings, DAN BRENNER answers.</context>
      <utterance>I'm transferring you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brenner.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan is quick to figure out who it is that must be calling him.</context>
      <utterance>Dan Brenner?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this Paul Conroy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>EXCITED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes it's me. It's Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, I was informed of what's going on. I want you to know that we're already working on trying to get you out of there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you, God.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is that right?</context>
      <utterance>I was told that we have until 9pm.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what he said.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. That doesn't give us a whole lot of time. And just so I have this right, the kidnappers buried you in the ground?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, in an old, wooden coffin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. My guess is that since you're able to get a cell signal, you're no more than a few feet underground.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul looks at the display to find out.</context>
      <utterance>What about battery life? How much does the phone have left?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Less than half.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. You have to conserve that battery. Our best bet of finding you is by tracking your cell signal. Is the ringer set on a sound or vibrate?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vibrate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It will use less power.</context>
      <utterance>Press and hold down the asterisk key to change it to a ring tone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about my Zippo?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a lighter?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Use it to look around for markings, a logo -- whatever you can find.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't it use up oxygen?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much. Don't worry about that now. Try to find --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really dark in here without it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand, Paul. Try to find anything in there that might indicate where that coffin was made.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys have to hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're working as fast as we can, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know if there were any other survivors?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From your convoy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's still unclear at this point.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to do right by my family. That's all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know it was going to be like this over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While on the phone with Brenner, Paul gets another call coming in. He checks the display and reads the number. Matching it against a number he wrote on the top of the coffin, he sees that is Jabir calling.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think any of us did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's him. He's calling.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The kidnapper?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. What do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know his number?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the call?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone has rung several times. Paul fears that Jabir may hang up.</context>
      <utterance>Give me the number first.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going to hang up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the call.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul looks at his watch. Indeed, he has but two hours and six minutes until the time reaches 9pm.</context>
      <utterance>Two hour, six minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to give me more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talk to embassy? They give money?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. No. I talked to...someone. Government. They said that they won't pay the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No pay?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. They said that they don't negotiate with terrorists.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terrorists? I am terrorist?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. You are terrorist, you son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are terrified, so I am terrorist?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I ever do to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm here because it's a job, to make money. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have job until you come. Now, my family have nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jabir retorts with a spirited conviction similar to Paul's.</context>
      <utterance>That's not my fault!</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine, one, one was not my fault, but still you are here! Saddam was not my fault, but still you are here!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To help rebuild.</context>
      <utterance>I told you, I'm only here to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul cannot handle his stress any longer. He begins to crumble under the pressure.</context>
      <utterance>Rebuild what you destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence from the other end of the phone for an extended period of time.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! Just please, stop! I'm just a guy. I'm just a truck driver. Okay? I'm nobody that makes decisions about anything. I just want to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This surprisingly comes as good news to Paul.</context>
      <utterance>You make video, ransom video.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Please. Get me out of here and I'll make the video.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You make video now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...? How?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul's hopes are dashed. His sanguine head falls back onto the coffin floor.</context>
      <utterance>You use video on phone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paul shines the flame of his Zippo lighter toward his feet. He doesn't see anything.</context>
      <utterance>Near foot. You read note near foot in box.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where? I don't see --</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul repositions his legs as best he can. He can vaguely see the corner of a small metal box, partially sticking out of a broken plank on the bottom of the coffin.</context>
      <utterance>Near foot. Read note inside box.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The video...if I make it, will you let me go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only if we get money.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's going to pay five million dollars for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We take less. One million money.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they pay it, will you let me go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jabir hangs up, ending the call. Paul sits motionless for a moment, soaking in all that Jabir has just told him. He again looks down toward his feet. He can see the protruding corner of the metal box, but it's positioned in such a way that it will clearly not be easy for him to reach it. Paul then tries to clasp the box with his feet, but after several unsuccessful attempts, he realizes that a new strategy is necessary.</context>
      <utterance>One million money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul presses and holds down the shortcut button on the phone that changes the ringer from vibrate to an audible tone. The glow stick begins to slowly fade. Paul dials Dan Brenner. After a few rings, Dan answers.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul presses the green key, bringing up the last numbers dialed and received.</context>
      <utterance>Here's his number...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on. Alright, go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan says something to someone who is in the room with him, and then returns his attention to Paul.</context>
      <utterance>It's 07902-24-921.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is huge. Unless they're using a cloned line, we should be able to find where this is coming from in minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me? Can you track my cell signal?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're having a lot of trouble with yours. Seems to be an EDS line, probably through one of the Egyptian carriers.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That...it's not going to be easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants me to make a ransom video.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Hold off for as long as you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's going to get me out of here, I'm making it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The last thing we want is for this to end up all over Al Jazeera.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul becomes angry, again sensing that more emphasis is being placed on containing the situation than rescuing him.</context>
      <utterance>We?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This can't turn into an international incident.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all you people care about! But what about me? Don't you care about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do. That's why we're --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you don't! You people don't care about any of us. I've had eight friends killed out here, six of them today. We don't have any guns, any armor. Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not soldiers.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell that to the people who put me in this box! Tell that to the people who shot my friends!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're doing the best we can.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're not. All you people understand are your secret plans and your back room politics.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I were some diplomat or something, maybe even a hostage working group leader -- or whatever your fancy title is, I'd be out of here by now. Wouldn't I? But I'm not, so I'm just supposed to keep my mouth shut and die.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to stay focused, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan's heard enough.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul does not respond at first. Dan's retort clearly has an effect on him.</context>
      <utterance>Paul, listen to me: finding you is our primary concern. Bottom line. And we're searching just as hard as we would be for a four-star general, so don't literally waste your breath suggesting otherwise.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are they? The people who put me here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're just that -- people. No different from you and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm no terrorist.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither are they.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you were homeless, starving...actually, I take that back. If your family was homeless and starving, what would you do for them?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't kill someone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you be sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>GETTING FRUSTRATED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What difference does it make?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're criminals, desperate ones at that. They don't care about anything other than getting the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So pay them, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, if it was an option, I would do that in a heartbeat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many others have there been?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since I got here? Hundreds. Journalists, contractors, soldiers...hundreds have been taken. It's one of the only functioning businesses out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan is reluctant to answer the question.</context>
      <utterance>How many have you rescued?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not many.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me their names.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any of them. Make me know they really do matter to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark White.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was Mark White?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A kid from New Hampshire. Twenty- six years old. Med student. Came over here to help out local doctors.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Insurgents grabbed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul writes "MARK WHITE" on the top of the coffin, below the list of phone numbers. He circles the name.</context>
      <utterance>About three weeks ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember his name.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember all their names.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The glow stick begins to fade.</context>
      <utterance>Did he...? Is he...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing this affords Paul some semblance of relief. Paul shakes the glow stick, returning it to its full strength.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yeah, Paul, he's alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Home. Probably happy to be back at school.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We found him; we'll find you, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We already have a solid lead on the number you gave us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This news calms Paul's nerves.</context>
      <utterance>A unit's on it's way over there now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's...that's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I do in the meantime?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it's hard, but try to relax. The more worked up you are, the more air you're going to use.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't help it. I'm always anxious. I take pills for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul checks his pants pockets. He removes a small, orange pill bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have them with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take them. You need to preserve your oxygen level any way you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your Zippo still lit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel nauseous.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you need to save that battery. We're expecting some intel in about ten minutes. Call me back then.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The glow stick begins to slowly fade. Paul shakes it, causing it to brighten only momentarily before dimming again.</context>
      <utterance>Just hang in there, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan ends the call. Paul lets out a deep breath, finding it difficult to lay claim to its replacement. He looks at his watch. It's now 7:18pm. The ticking sound of the second hand turning is inordinately loud, due to the extreme silence of the coffin. Just then, the cell phone rings. Checking the number on the display, Paul sees that it is Jabir. Paul answers.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you make video?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jabir yells something in Arabic to the other Iraqi men we hear in the background. Collectively, they do not sound pleased. Slightly panicked, in fact, though it is difficult to tell for sure.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode>TO PAUL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You make video!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me out and I'll make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! You make video now. In box.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. I can't read the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make video now!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jabir is heard speaking with the men we hear arguing in the background. Although they speak in Arabic, it is clear from their tone that they are becoming worried and increasingly hostile. Jabir returns his attention back to Paul.</context>
      <utterance>I can't. I don't know what you want me to say. I can't read the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jabir ends the call. Paul closes the phone to help conserve battery life. He then reopens the phone and scrolls through the menu options. Everything is written in Arabic. He eventually comes across an icon with a movie camera -- the video function. He turns it on. Looks at himself though the viewfinder. After a beat, he closes the phone, clearly frustrated and growing more panicked. His breaths grow heavy and rapid, utilizing a great deal of oxygen.</context>
      <utterance>You make video now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul begins to freak out, restlessly squirming inside the coffin and pressing against the sides and top. The glow stick fades out almost completely, offering very little light. Paul shakes it, but with no change to its brightness. Moments later, it dies. Paul tries the flashlight. Click-click. Click-click. Nothing. He bangs it a few times with his hand. The white light turns on, but quickly turns back off. He twists the top, which causes the flashlight to switch bulbs. A red beam emits momentarily. Paul twists the top again and gives the flashlight a few good whacks. It turns on. White light shines dimly on his face. He takes a breath. In efforts to calm himself, he once again removes the orange pill bottle from his pocket. He pours two into his hand. He then removes his small, metal alcohol flask from his back pocket and takes a large swig, swallowing the two pills in the process. Still, Paul's heavy, labored breathing continues. He drops four additional pills into his and swallows them with yet another generous pull from the flask. He sits and waits. Nothing is happening, except that his extremely limited time keeps passing. After a moment, Paul picks up the cell phone. He holds it in front of him, hesitant to make a call. After some consideration, he dials. After a few rings, a NURSING HOME NURSE answers.</context>
      <utterance>I'm never getting out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSING HOME NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mountain View Nursing Home.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping I could speak with Maryanne Conroy, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSING HOME NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the Nurse walk down the tiled corridor floor. She soon reaches Paul's mother's room.</context>
      <utterance>Um...okay. Ah...let me bring the cordless phone to her room. Hold on a moment, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>NURSING HOME NURSE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paul's mother, MARYANNE, answers. Her voice is pleasant but confused. It's clear that she suffers from advanced stages of Alzheimer's Disease.</context>
      <utterance>Misses Conroy, you have a telephone call, dear. Here, you can use this phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom...it's Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Paul, Mom. Your son.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, Mom. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your son, Mom. It's Paulie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paulie?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Remember?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Remember? We lived over on Colfax Street, in the duplex.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode>REMEMBERING SLIGHTLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paulie?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, Mom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this Paulie?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is, Mom. It's Paulie. How's everything at the home?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's almost too much for Paul to take. He cries silent tears over a heartbroken smile.</context>
      <utterance>Very nice. Your father and I have been playing gin rummy every night.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...I don't think Pop's there with you, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you doing, sweetie?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not very good. This...uh, this may be the last time I talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get the flowers I sent a few months ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARYANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flowers?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maryanne doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I sent...never mind. Listen, I...I'm going to go now. I just wanted to talk to you, you know, just to say bye. I love you, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear me? Mom? I told you...do you want to tell me you</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul frantically dials the number to reach Jabir. As soon as the phone connects, Paul begins his desperate plea.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no. No, no, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Video make?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Woman is heard in the background of Jabir's phone, crying muffled words through her muzzled mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Let her go. Please. Please don't hurt her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We shoot her if you no make video.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No, please no shoot. No shoot her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get money. American million.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will, I promise. Just don't shoot her. She's a mother, she's got two kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. She has two kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have five. Now only one. You make video. Now!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No wait!! I give three seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't read the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you want me to say!</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jabir does not fire his gun. Paul attempts to catch his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Okay! Okay, I'll make the video. Just, please, don't shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to hang up to make the video. Okay? Is that okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have three minute to send video.</utterance>
   <speaker>52.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul reaches for the balled-up piece of paper that has the ransom script written on it. It takes some trouble for him to grab it, but he is soon able to. Placing the flashlight next to the paper, Paul is again reminded of the incoherent nature of the script.</context>
      <utterance>Jabir hangs up, ending the call.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops the paper to his side and opens the phone, setting it to the video record function. He places the flashlight close to his face so as to make his image more visible on the small, phone display screen. He presses the record button.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flashlight goes out. Paul continues speaking in the darkness. After a few quick smacks, the flashlight turns back on.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Paul Conroy. I'm an American citizen from Hastings, Michigan. I'm a civilian truck driver for Crestin, Roland and Thomas. I've been taken hostage somewhere in Iraq...and I need one million dollars by nine o'clock tonight, Baghdad time, or else I'll be left to die in this coffin I'm buried in. I've been told that if...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Trying to think of more to say, Paul soon opts for not saying anything further. He saves the message and then sends it to Jabir. We see that the screen displays an icon confirming the video has been sent. Paul places the phone on his chest. Still rubbing his temples, his eyes begin to flutter a bit. He tries to control his breathing and remain calm.</context>
      <utterance>...the money is paid, I will be let go. If it's not, I will die in here. These threats are real and will be followed through on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see, on the display of the phone, that Paul has found a listing of languages. He scrolls past many -- "FRANCAIS, DETSCHE, ESPANOL" -- stopping at "ENGLISH." Presses the button, instantly making all the text on the screen readable. He quickly navigates to the Tools menu. Scrolls down. Locates the number of the cell phone he is using. He scribbles the number onto the top of the coffin. Then a second pass, making it bolder than the others. Paul then dials his wife's cell phone. After only a few rings, he is met by her voice mail.</context>
      <utterance>There you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The beep sounds, and Paul frantically proceeds right into his message.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, this is Linda. Please leave a message. Thanks and have a great day.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Linda, here's the number for the phone. I just found it out. It's 07902-42-884. You have to use the international calling code first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paul hangs up. He looks at the battery life left on the phone. One bar. He then checks his watch. It's 8:19pm. Both are not good signs, and he knows it.</context>
      <utterance>Please call me as soon as you get this. I love you...I love you. Call me right away. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He begins to panic. Grabbing the pocket knife that was left inside the metal box, he slides the blade in the space between the sides of the coffin and the top. Paul grabs the glow stick. But, because it was partially melted to the floor, the stick snaps in two. Liquid oozes out of the small portion of the stick that remains stuck the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul grabs the flashlight. Turns it on. It works for a second, but then goes out. Shaking it only produces intermittent beams of light. He turns the top, switching to the red bulb. It works. The coffin fills with a reddish hue, but then it, too, goes out. Growing incensed, Paul switches back to the white bulb. It works. He returns his attention to the coffin. His efforts to use the knife as a fulcrum are futile. Still, he tries. Bending the blade well past its design, it nearly breaks off its handle. The flashlight turns off. After a good shaking, it turns back on, emitting white light. With oxygen levels extremely diminished, efforts of this kind are all too much for Paul to take. He has to stop and try to catch his breath. As he endeavors to get his wind back, the cell phone rings. Not a call this time, but instead a video message. It has been sent by Jabir. Paul's trepidation is evident. He fears what the incoming video may show.</context>
      <utterance>Son of a...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Woman, Pamela, looks off-screen to her right. Someone is fast approaching her. She cowers, protectively holding her bound hands in front of her face as she screams.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Pamela Gorham. I'm a food service worker at F.O.B. Anaconda, employed by Crestin, Roland and Thomas. My captors' requests for ransom have gone unanswered, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still in the throes of emotional torment, Paul vomits on himself. He doubles over, only to vomit once again. His body, taxed almost to the point of complete physical breakdown, gradually slows and levels itself. With his vomit- smeared face pressed cheek-down onto the bottom of the coffin, Paul stares into nothingness.</context>
      <utterance>No! No, no, no!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the hell did you make that video?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all a bunch of lies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is? What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody gives a shit about any of us. We're nothing to you people.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to find you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By looking the other way?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't start breaking on me now, Paul. You have to stay strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You let her die.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They shot her...and you didn't do anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't even know she had been taken hostage.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She sent three videos.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what they told her to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That your ransom video already has 47,000 hits on YouTube. And all the major networks are playing it, including Al Jazeera. So, now your captors have no choice but to follow through.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found out the number to this phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found a way to change the display language. I figured that out, and you didn't. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I didn't. Just like you and every other person on this planet, there are some things I know and some things I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how are you ever going to find me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their signal was cloned, like we figured. But, we're close. Real close.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're working on that, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm near a Mosque. I could hear the call to prayer over the P.A.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. That means that we're in the right area.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're nearby?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I spoke with soldiers from the third ID who were escorting your convoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a beat:</context>
      <utterance>They're alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not all of them. Both Bradley tanks were hit with IEDs. The rest got caught in small arms fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Paul doesn't answer at first.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell happened out there, Paul?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>After a beat:</context>
      <utterance>Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had just left Anaconda, everything seemed okay. We knew that a bunch of our CB radios had been stolen and that the Iraqis were listening in, so we made sure to switch from our usual channels. Pam was riding with Jeff Breer, the convoy commander. She wanted to ride with me like she usually did when she hitched a ride from base, but it seemed safer for her to be with the C.C. As we headed down the road, all these kids came running into the street. Dozens of them. It almost seemed like they were expecting us, except we got there faster than they thought we would. So they run on up in front of me, and I slam on my brakes. The rest of the drivers were already further up ahead, so they kept going. Next thing I know, one of the lead trucks got hit by an IED. I hear Tommy Wilkes on the radio saying, Sandman's hit, Sandman's hit. He's...he's everywhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's when the Iraqis came out of their mud huts from the side of the road and started shooting everybody. I couldn't believe what was happening. It seemed like slow- motion, like I was watching it on TV. People -- my friends -- were getting killed, and all I could do is watch. I didn't even notice that the kids were throwing bricks and rocks at me until one split my windshield. Sort of snapped me out of my trance. But then, I guess I got hit in the head with a rock, `cause I blacked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cell phone service begins to cut out. Suddenly, the coffin begins to vibrate slightly, dropping sand granules through the crack and onto the wood bottom, followed by the faint sound of an explosion. Within seconds, the explosions grow louder and more proximate. The vibration becomes so intense that it violently shakes Paul around the coffin. The sound of jet plane engines are heard coming from above, flying by as the massive explosions continue. Sand seeps in through the crack between the top and sides of the coffin as it shakes. Paul does his best to brace himself, but the bombardment is far too powerful. A large crack forms in the wooden cover to the coffin, spanning almost its entire length. Sand immediately pours through the concave shaped crack, seeping in onto Paul like an hourglass. Fearing that the top of the coffin may collapse under the immense pressure from the sand above, Paul positions himself underneath it and presses with all his might. He grunts and screams loudly, using what little strength he has left to keep the top from caving. The shaking soon stops, though the steady flow of sand continues.</context>
      <utterance>Do you happen to remem...mo... nea...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>EXHAUSTED</mode>
      <context>Paul clicks the flashlight to a different setting. White light shines, but then goes out. He shakes the flashlight and it stays on, shining its normal white beam. He assesses his situation, noticing that the coffin is already filled with a small layer of sand; a situation that is only going to get worse with time.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no...no...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see that Dan Brenner is no longer on the phone, and that the display menu shows an icon of a phone with a line through it -- No Service Available. Once he feels it is secure enough, Paul slowly moves his body away from the crack. Although slightly caved, it does not show any more signs of possible collapse. Sweat drenches his face. His eyes affixed, in utter disbelief, on the sand as it spills into the coffin, filling in around him inch-by-inch. He grabs the cell phone, only to see that he does not have a signal.</context>
      <utterance>This can't be happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He shakes the cell phone and moves it all around the coffin, hoping that it may somehow help. His efforts are futile. The flashlight goes dead. He hits it, shakes it. It turns back on. The brightness is diminished. Still the sand continues to fall, drowning him deeper and deeper in a pool of granules. Then, very surprisingly, the cell phone rings. Paul answers right away.</context>
      <utterance>No. Come on. Please work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>FRANTICALLY</mode>
      <context>Alan Davenport answers calmly from the other end.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Hello? Who's there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this Paul Conroy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes, this is Paul. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, my name's Alan Davenport, I'm the personnel director here at Crestin, Roland and Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I left you a message.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did. I also heard from Rebecca Browning over at the State Department. Are you able to speak on the status of your situation?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's worse. There was an explosion or something. The coffin's breaking, there's sand pouring in from everywhere. I only have a half an hour before --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay. Slow down. You should try to stay calm. Tell me something, Paul, who have you spoken to?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hostage takers, Dan Brenner from the hostage working group --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flashlight goes out. Paul hits it a few times and it turns back on.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Paul. I'm with you. How about the media. I know your ransom video leaked, but have you spoken directly to anyone about what's going on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul finds Alan's obvious concern with doing damage control to be infuriating.</context>
      <utterance>That's good. It needs to stay that way. It's important that we keep this situation as contained as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About three inches to my right, there's a wall. Three inches to my left, there's another wall. And about four inches above my head, there's a roof that's about to collapse and drown me in sand. I think this situation is pretty contained.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're upset --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help me! Help me! What are you going to do to help me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're upset. And, from what I've been told, steps are being taken to get you out of there. So, hopefully it won't be much longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, thank God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>A click is heard in the b.g. of Alan's phone, followed by a low, steady hum. Alan's speech becomes very laconic. His questions are clearly being read from a Human Resources handbook of some kind.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to switch on a recorder right now. Just a second... Paul's visage expresses his confusion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Alan Davenport, Personnel Director for Crestin, Roland and Thomas, Incorporated. The date is October 23, 2006. I am speaking with Paul Conroy. Mister Conroy, are you aware that I'm recording this conversation?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flashlight goes out again.</context>
      <utterance>Please answer the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul hits it, but it does not catch. He sits in darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Conroy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do I have your permission to do so?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What is all this?</context>
      <utterance>Why do you need my permission?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to answer yes or no, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul hits the flashlight. It turns back on.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Alright? Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Now, Mister Conroy, when were you hired by CRT?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About nine months ago. Around January of 2005. Why are you wasting time with this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have your official date of hire as January 4th, 2005. Is that correct?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares? This is fucking crazy --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>January 4th, 2005. Is that correct?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And during your initial training, before being sent to Iraq, were you made aware of the dangers inherent to the position for which you were hired.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flashlight dims. Paul angrily shakes it, returning it to full strength.</context>
      <utterance>You mean when I came down there to Dallas and you guys said that all of the trucks would be armored and have bulletproof glass?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean when you told us that things were safer than ever over here? Is that when I was made aware?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to answer yes or no, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>The flashlight begins to slowly dim.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>During that time, did you also receive and sign an employment contract with CRT, which thoroughly explained company policy as it pertained to your specific terms of employment?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I signed a bunch of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes or no.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I signed the contract. Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's our understanding that you were taken hostage in Iraq two hours ago, is that also correct?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alan breaks from the H.R. handbook script, though his tone remains just as matter-of-fact. The flashlight continues its steady, slow dim.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's completely correct. What is the point of all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our legal department requires that we obtain a sworn affidavit from employees, confirming that they understand the reasons for their forced separation from the company. As of this morning, your employment with CRT was officially terminated.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, wait, wait -- The flashlight dims even more.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was brought to our attention that you were engaging in relations with a fellow CRT employee -- Pamela Gorham.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Wait --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stipulated in your contract was a fraternization clause, in which it was stated quite clearly that any relationship, be it romantic or sexual in nature, deemed inappropriate by CRT senior officials is grounds for immediate termination.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We...we were just friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our records indicate differently.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul sees where Alan is going with this. He's thunderstruck.</context>
      <utterance>We're also legally required to inform you that because you were technically no longer under the employ of CRT at the time of your abduction, we cannot be held accountable for any injury that may befall upon you after your official date and time of termination. Therefore, in your case, that includes this incident or any consequences that may result from it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about my insurance money? My family will need that money...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Given that you were alive up until the time of your termination --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You son of a bitch. You can't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you understand everything --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alan takes a second before trying again.</context>
      <utterance>You can't do this!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul does not answer.</context>
      <utterance>Do you understand everything you've been told, Mister Conroy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Conroy?</utterance>
   <speaker>71.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After a long beat:</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A click is heard. The humming ceases.</context>
      <utterance>That concludes our interview with Paul Conroy. I am now turning off the recorder.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You people can't just wash your hands of this. You bastards put me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN DAVENPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alan ends the call. Paul looks at the phone -- it is still holding a steady signal. Battery life, however, is running quite low. All that remains is one blinking bar, indicating that Paul has very little battery life left. He shakes his hand free of the pile of sand that now covers it and looks at his watch. It's 8:31pm. The flashlight bulb dims until it goes out completely. Only the light of the cell phone display lights the coffin.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wasting little time, Paul dials Jabir. The phone rings and rings, but Jabir does not answer. Checking to make sure the he dialed the correct number, Paul matches it against the phone number he wrote onto the wall of the coffin. Seeing that he did, in fact, dial correctly, Paul again tries to call Jabir. While he waits through the many rings, he tries relighting the Zippo. Spark...spark...it catches. No one answers. Paul's disquietude is evident in his increasingly erratic behavior.</context>
      <utterance>Come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul tries Jabir once again, but still he does not answer the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Answer the phone!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's then that something occurs to Paul. He stares at the crack in the top of the coffin and the sand that pours in at an alarmingly fast rate. The crack has split Jabir's written phone number in half. The aerial bombing. He wonders how it may have affected Jabir and, consequently, his own chances of survival. He places his hand under the point from where the sand pours in most, allowing it to collect on his palm and slip through his fingers. The flickering Zippo flame tells of the diminished amount of oxygen. Paul attempts to control his breathing, realizing full well that there are not many more breaths he will be able to take. He then calls Dan Brenner. After a few rings, Brenner answers. Paul is surprisingly serene.</context>
      <utterance>Why won't you answer?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three F-16s levelled parts of the city a few minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Zippo flame flutters. Weakens.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I felt it. Did they know I was here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan does not answer.</context>
      <utterance>Did they care?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These people that took me -- if they're dead, they can't tell you where I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can still try to track down your signal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tried that already.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul appreciates Dan's effort, but he knows there is little hope left for him.</context>
      <utterance>We can try again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>After a long beat:</context>
      <utterance>It's over, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul doesn't say a word. He knows that Dan is lying. After a beat, Dan comes clean.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The flame of the Zippo becomes smaller. It clearly has little life left.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right -- just like everyone else on the planet, there are some things you know and some things you don't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish this could have gone differently.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a long beat, Paul ends the call. He forces a smile to his lachrymose face. Utterly hopeless, he opens the phone and turns on the video feature. He turns the phone to face himself, projecting his image on the display. He presses Record.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Paul Steven Conroy. Social Security number 048-32-1198, date of birth 3/19/68. This video will serve as my last will and testament. To my wife, Linda Conroy, I leave the seven hundred dollars in my personal savings and whatever I have left in my annuity. To my son, Shane Conroy, I...I don't know. I don't have anything else. My stuff, like, my clothes. I wish I had more...I wish I had done more. Your dad wasn't really much of anything, Shane, I'm sorry. Maybe if I was a famous baseball player, or a guy who wore a suit to work, I would have more to leave you. But, you can be one of those people if you want. You can be whatever you want. Just promise me that when you get older, you'll take good care of your mom. And promise me that you'll always try to do the right thing, no matter what. I love you very much, Shane. Maybe I never said that enough...maybe I did, I don't even know. That probably means I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Paul ends the video and closes the phone. He carefully places the phone into his pocket, where it may hopefully be found if he ever is.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Linda. I should have listened to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jabir is heard speaking frantically in Arabic to the several other people in the room with him.</context>
      <utterance>You're not dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jabir turns his attention to Paul.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Hello?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is money?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What don't know?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know where the money is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liar!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not lying! I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swear?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling the truth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Embassy, you get money now!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't!</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul shakes and hits the flashlight. It still does not work.</context>
      <utterance>I need more time. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more time!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jabir utters something in Arabic to someone standing next to him, seemingly asking a question and getting an answer from the same individual. Paul unscrews the top of the flashlight. Switches the positioning of the batteries. Screws the cap back on. Hits the switch. Nothing. Jabir returns to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>There's sand pouring in here. I can't...it's everywhere. Please, let me out of here and I will get you the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You show blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul unscrews the top of the flashlight again. Removes the batteries. Bites down on them a few times. Blows hard inside the flashlight tube.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You show blood, they give money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cut off thumb finger, send video.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not doing that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul puts the batteries back inside the flashlight. Begins screwing on the cap.</context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jabir again says something to someone in the room with him, returning to Paul after a brief moment. Paul finishes closing the top of the flashlight.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, no. You let me out of here, and I'll cut off my whole God damn hand if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Click. The flashlight turns on! Paul considers Jabir's question to be a potential sign of compassion.</context>
      <utterance>You have wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do. And a son. A young son. I want to go home...to see them. Please, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Sir. I say that out of respect...to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>243 East Walnut Street. Hastings, Michigan. U.S.A.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONCERNED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my...why did you say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You show blood...or they show blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's...you're lying. You're nobody...all of you. You can't get to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You're peasants, criminals, that's all. You don't even know where Michigan is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even this basic knowledge is enough to make Jabir's threats that much more real.</context>
      <utterance>Detroit. Ann Arbor.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You looked at a map. That's all you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>JABIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jabir ends the call. Realizing that Jabir is gone, Paul quickly dials his wife's cell phone. After several rings, her voice mail picks up.</context>
      <utterance>You show blood, or they show blood. Send video by five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, this is Linda. Please leave a message. Thanks and have a great day.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>FRANTICALLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Linda, listen to me: you and Shane have to go somewhere... anywhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paul hangs up. He takes a moment to look around, noticing that the coffin is almost halfway filled with sand.</context>
      <utterance>Don't stay at the house, whatever you do, do not stay at the house. The guy...the kidnapper, he knows our address. He stole my license and now he knows where we live. Go to the Sheriff's station if you have to, just don't go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paul then dials Dan Brenner. After only one ring, the call goes directly to voice mail. The flashlight starts to dim. Paul shakes it, causing it to regain its strength.</context>
      <utterance>Holy God.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The beep sounds. Paul delivers a frenzied message.</context>
      <utterance>This is Daniel Brenner. Please leave a message at the tone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unsure what to do next, Paul's heartbeat races. He fidgets, nervously shaking and tapping his thumb against the phone. He questions the validity of Jabir's threats toward his family.</context>
      <utterance>Brenner, where are you?! He's alive! He just called me! Call me right away! The fucking guy is still alive! Paul hangs up the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>TO HIMSELF</mode>
      <context>Paul opens the phone and brings up the photo of Pamela, bound and gagged. The image causes Paul to second guess himself. The flashlight goes out. The cell phone's display illuminates Paul's face.</context>
      <utterance>They can't find them. They...can't. There's no way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He places his hands against the side of the coffin, spreading his fingers. He stares intently at his thumb. With the extremely sharp knife in hand, Paul slowly lowers it just above his thumb. He inhales and exhales deep breaths, almost hyperventilating.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paul then reaches into the sand and finds one of the expired glow sticks. He shakes the sand off of it and places it across his mouth, biting into it hard. His heart races, his breaths are the deepest he's ever taken. After placing the flashlight on the ground, to ensure that the camera picks up the image, he presses the record button on the cell phone. Grinding his teeth into the glow stick and letting out a primordial scream, Paul closes his eyes and chops down with the knife. We see, through the display screen of the phone, Paul sever his thumb with a swift chop of the blade.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's down here!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get him out! Keep digging!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cacophony of voices form a mosaic of sound in Paul's head, each overlapping the other in distant echoes. Shovels, digging deep into the ground, are heard banging against the top of the coffin. The top of the coffin is torn open, sending a brilliant ray of white light onto Paul. He stares into the light, crying, eking out a tortured smile.</context>
      <utterance>Paul, we're here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul doesn't have the strength to answer.</context>
      <utterance>Paul, it's Brenner.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul? Are you there? Paul?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm...here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This news serves as somewhat of an adrenaline rush for Paul, who musters up even the modicum of strength he seemingly did not have left in him.</context>
      <utterance>We're coming for you now. You hear me? We know where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are, Paul. We're almost there now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coalition forces picked up a Shiite insurgent just outside of Baghdad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Said he knew where an American was buried alive. He agreed to show us where if we let him go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're coming for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An impossible smile fights its way to Paul's lips. His momentary joy is just that, however, for the sand has almost completely filled the coffin by this point.</context>
      <utterance>We're practically there already.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...you have to hurry. The sand...it's filling up fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is very hopeful that Dan is correct in his assumption.</context>
      <utterance>Just hang in there for three more minutes. This will all be over soon, I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beep is heard. Paul has another call coming in. He's visibly elated upon seeing who it is.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. I believe you. Thank you. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three minutes. Try to --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, no --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul switches to the other call, despite the fact that he has a mere eight inches left before the entire coffin is filled with sand from top-to-bottom. He holds the flashlight just above the top of the sand pile, allowing it to illuminate what little unoccupied area remains.</context>
      <utterance>Call me right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Linda is in hysterics, which is evident in her speech.</context>
      <utterance>Linda.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul? Paul is that you? Tell me it's you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me, sweetie.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, Paul! What are they doing to you? Please tell me you're okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm...okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flashlight dims. Paul shakes it, regaining a bit of its strength.</context>
      <utterance>I just saw the news. What...oh my God, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going to be okay now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I missed all your calls. I left my cell phone at home. I just found out what was going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're getting me out.</context>
      <utterance>That's okay. It's all okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people. Americans. They found out where I am and they're on their way to get me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode>ELATED</mode>
      <context>The flashlight flickers. Paul hits it. It flickers some more.</context>
      <utterance>They are? Oh thank God. Oh dear God, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all going to be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flashlight continues to flicker almost like a stroboscopic light from this point forward.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know for sure? Oh God, please tell me you're okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was so afraid I was going to lose you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Linda breaks down in joyous tears.</context>
      <utterance>You're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you so much. I love you so, so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>WELLING UP</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have never come here. You were right. I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweetie, I don't care. I just want you home. Please come home to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul then receives a call on the other line. He checks to see who's calling. It's Dan Brenner.</context>
      <utterance>I will. I swear I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're here!</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're calling me right now. I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you. Swear it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul clicks over to the other line, where Dan Brenner waits to speak with him. We hear Dan yelling to people who are with him. A great deal of commotion and action is heard through the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I swear. I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move! Move! Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brenner?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul? Paul?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan yells to one of the soldiers who are with him.</context>
      <utterance>We're here!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dan gets back on the phone with Paul</context>
      <utterance>Corporal, get your men over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He brought us right to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to hurry. It's almost full.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just hang in there!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul fights to keep his head above the sand. The flashlight dims.</context>
      <utterance>Dig! Dig! Dig!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't...are you close?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(to the soldiers)</context>
      <utterance>We're almost there, Paul. We're almost there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Faster!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>TO PAUL</mode>
      <context>The level of sand grows even higher. Paul spits away falling sand that threatens to suffocate him.</context>
      <utterance>We're almost there. We're right above you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't hear you! Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SOLDIER is heard OFF-SCREEN in the b.g. of Dan's phone.</context>
      <utterance>We're almost there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep digging!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry! Please!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul coughs out sand. He has a mere inch left above his head.</context>
      <utterance>We see the coffin! Just hang in there!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Soldier is again heard OFF-SCREEN in the b.g. Of Dan's phone.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry! Where are you? I don't hear you? Please hurry!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's clear!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nondescript noise is heard through the phone, until it comes to an abrupt stop.</context>
      <utterance>Open it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>SHOCKED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the circled name of "MARK WHITE" written in capital letters on the top of the coffin.</context>
      <utterance>It's Mark White. He brought us to Mark White. I'm --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said...!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode>OVERLAPPING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I know. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The battery life on Paul's phone runs out, causing it to power down. The filament of the flashlight bulb burns out. As it does, the sand finally consumes the coffin, filling it completely. We hear Paul's muffled screams emanate through the sand, until we no longer hear them at all.</context>
      <utterance>No!! No!! NO!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
