<movie id="112" title="Burlesque">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVEAL ...TESS. A stunner with impossibly long lashes, theatrical make-up and a sequined, skin-tight band-aid of a dress. She works the tight stage of the club, toying with the AUDIENCE.</context>
      <utterance>Once upon a time ...a long, looong time ago... there was a good little girl...and they called her...</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>MUSIC BLARES from a HOT YOUNG BUMPER BAND -- sax, drums, bass -- wearing bowler hats, suspenders and lots of ink. The crowd HOOTS. Lame streamers EXPLODE from the stage.</context>
      <utterance>Burlesque.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some say she up and died-of neglect. Abandonment.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPER</mode>
      <context>The club's red booths are about half-full with a hip crowd. Walls cluttered with photos. Celebrities tucked in shadows.</context>
      <utterance>.old age.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>SEAN (31), a cute gay guy with an armful of accessories pushes his way through the girls and in a blur, tightens a corset, tosses a boa, adjusts a garter just so.</context>
      <utterance>Come to think of it, none of them are all that good, which isn't all that bad...</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight shows a week. Sixteen gorgeous girls. Thirty-two towers of luscious legs...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The girls gather at the edge of the stage, lit by footlights, moving in place to the beat of the INTRO MUSIC. Hips sway. Fingers snap. Tess weaves playfully between them.</context>
      <utterance>Say hello to Scarlett. Jesse. Anna. Coco-puff. And Georgie-Girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of them the creme-de la creme.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CYMBAL CRASH</mode>
      <context>The girls strike nasty, (but funny) provocative poses, etc...</context>
      <utterance>De la creme.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>TWO GIRLS upside down on chairs NAIL aerial splits.</context>
      <utterance>Each one a bastion of bodacious...  Elegance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Coco raises a brow, moves her butt to a LOUD BUMP-AND-GRIND.</context>
      <utterance>Not to mention their other...  Ass-ets.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>FOOTLIGHTS FLARE, UPLIGHTING THE GIRLS. They shift their weight, hitting the beats with risque moves and hip-thrusts as they MOVE DOWNSTAGE suggestively toward the audience to the MUSIC...</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the Burlesque Lounge, dead smack in the center of the Sunset Strip-- did I say "strip?"  I meant TEASE...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALI ROSE. One hand holding a bar rag, the other planted on her hip. Ali has a look that's all her own: short shorts, white platform sandals, hair piled up high, more make-up than the rest of Grundy's women combined. She's young -- 22 -- but has a confidence that's got nothing to do with age.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, excuse me? You forgot something. He turns. Sees:</utterance>
   <speaker>REGULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's your tip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before the Regular can respond, Ali is joined by LORETTA -- 30's wearing every one of those years hard.</context>
      <utterance>Huh. See, now that's interesting -- you and I must do math completely differently, cause me? I start with the six beers I brought you, add the four spills I cleaned up, the five times I refilled your peanuts, plus the three times you "accidentally" touched my ass, then I tack on lying to your wife when she called looking for you, twice, and I come up with a sum that's a hell of a lot more than twenty-five cents.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Regular leaves. Loretta picks up the quarter.</context>
      <utterance>She's just teasing, Ike. You go on home now, and tell Kay I said hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's better than nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothin's cheap. A quarter's an insult.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll cover half a load down at the Spanky Clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali takes the quarter and heads to the back of the room, passing a GEEZER who's sitting by himself, drinking alone.</context>
      <utterance>There's only one thing a quarter is good for.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, hon, now you know how Dwight feels about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali stops in front of the rinky-dink karaoke machine.</context>
      <utterance>Dwight isn't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He could come back any minute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YEEEEEEEEAAAAAAAHHHHHH...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As other ENTERTAINERS appear onstage:</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE TATTOOED BAND blares as the troupe kicks in unison</context>
      <utterance>The insatiable La Puccini Triplets! Death-defying daredevils Missy and Kitten DeVille! The Countess of contortion, Eva Destruction! And how about a little love for those bad boys of burlesque, our naughty- bawdy bumber band!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People around here wouldn't know talent if it bit 'em in the Danglies. Where you gotta go is Des Moines. They got karaoke bars where you can win a hundred bucks a night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hops up onto the bar, spins around on her butt, one leg up in the air like a Varga girl, then hops down on the other side then gets back to work.</context>
      <utterance>Loretta-- when I get out of this butt-hole of a town, I sure as shit won't be heading for Des Moines.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell is Nikki?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BACKSTAGE DOOR BURSTS OPEN revealing--</context>
      <utterance>Rehab, if there's a God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki, a stunning, feisty brunette, sashays in--</context>
      <utterance>I heard that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Nikki, you're later than Georgia's period! Where were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drops her bag, quickly peels her clothes off, holds out her arms as Sean slips her corset onto her-- Tess eyes Nikki's body--</context>
      <utterance>Weave, wax, paws and claws.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki unwillingly steps on the scale. Tess shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it right there. Weigh in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nikki protests as Sean double-takes at Georgia -- who FLITS BY with a slightly protruding belly.</context>
      <utterance>Put on five pounds or I bump you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nanna? Got your pot roast here!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she stops in her tracks. Nanna -- 80's, housecoat, oxygen tank -- is slumped in her chair. The TV remote is on the floor. "ENTERTAINMENT TONIGHT" is blaring.</context>
      <utterance>They were out of steak fries, so I got you some of those...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nanna?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>YOUNG MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Lord, we gather here today not to mourn, but to celebrate the life of Alison Rose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arlene.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's Arlene. I'm Alison.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit.  Can I start over?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were real good to her, Ali.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rearranges the flowers resting on the plot, fixing it up.</context>
      <utterance>No, she was good to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she wasn't even my real Nanna.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Foster care. She took me in for the checks. When I turned eighteen, the money stopped coming. She could've kicked me out, but she didn't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had a lot of pain at the end. Nothing she talked about, but I could tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON ALI, thinking realizing:</context>
      <utterance>Well, then I guess this is a blessing. Now she's free.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I guess she is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girls look good tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amazing what a pink spotlight can do. Hides more cellulite than a burka.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're three days late.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a death in the family.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what, people stop drinking cause your grandma died? Get your apron and get to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not here to work. I'm leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>TO DWIGHT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just came for my back pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Payday's the end of the month.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, I won't be here then. And you owe me for three weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali sets down her suitcase and marches over to him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't owe anyone anything till the end of the month.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what, Dwight? Contrary to what you've been told, there's no law in Grundy that says you have to spend every waking minute being a tight-fisted, cheap-ass prick --</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooh, hon, I'm not sure that particular approach is gonna --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've spent three years of my life</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm only taking what he owes me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>Ali STUFFS a few TWENTIES into Loretta's apron-- pockets the rest.</context>
      <utterance>How much was that bike you been wanting for little Keith?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ali-- where are you gonna go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loretta hugs her tight, then looks Ali in the eye, concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Somewhere I can breathe. Now gimme a hug, I gotta get out of here before he gets back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't just head off into the sunset without a plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>RESOLUTE</mode>
      <context>Ali gives her one more hug, then grabs her bag and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Watch me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much to Los Angeles?</utterance>
   <speaker>TICKET BOOTH GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One way or round-trip?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're loving you tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're loving you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shucks, I just tell myself I'm writing for a big old drag queen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he heads off with her discarded costume:</context>
      <utterance>Eat me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess looks in a mirror. As she makes the necessary adjustments, VINCE SCALI appears. 35, scruffy-handsome.</context>
      <utterance>A big old foul-mouthed drag queen!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances up, sees him. Gets icy. Goes back to primping.</context>
      <utterance>Good show tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad the club's half-empty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half-full.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got another call from Marcus Gerber.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you told him we weren't selling.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess spins around, looking him in the eye for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>He wants to raise his offer. I told him we'd hear him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pivots away and sweeps into the club.</context>
      <utterance>Vince, I don't care what the number is; the only way Marcus Gerber will get this club from me is by prying it out of my cold, dead, heavily- jeweled fingers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>He drops her suitcase on the bed and stands there. Waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Good luck with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She digs into her purse. All she has is twenties. She peels one off and holds it out.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, hang on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But before she can finish, he pockets it, nods and leaves, closing the door behind him. To the closed door:</context>
      <utterance>If I could just get a little --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She pulls open the blinds, they fall off the wall with a CRASH! Ali stares at them. Then she opens the window. The SOUNDS OF HOLLYWOOD pour in. She digs out her cash, sticks it under the mattress. Then she reconsiders.</context>
      <utterance>-- change.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The cat curls up next to her. She checks his junk.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. I thought this was a single.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Typical. First guy I meet is neutered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't happen to know anyone in the music business, do you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALEXIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALEXIS, drag queen/door whore, also in full costume and make- up, TOSSES a GUY out the front door onto the street, then heads back inside-- Ali smiles to herself. Then turns back to look at COCO who disappears inside a BACK DOOR as...NIKKI walks out. Lights a ciggie. She has on full make-up. Lacquered lips. Lashes like peacock feathers. She sees Ali staring.</context>
      <utterance>Like I said, LOOK BUT DON'T TOUCH!</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't your Mama tell you it's not polite to stare?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, you're just -- so DAMN beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode>WARMING</mode>
      <context>Nikki strikes a pose, campy, showing Ali her best side. They both laugh.</context>
      <utterance>In that case, screw your Mama, stare away.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one would ever guess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki's face turns to stone. Her eyes widen in horror. Ali sees the mistake she made. She's mortified.</context>
      <utterance>That you're a dude.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Shit's" right, you little half-wit</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sean grabs her and drags her inside. As he does, a STRAND OF CRYSTAL BEADS comes off her costume, falls to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Bitch! You're on!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stage door slams shut. Ali picks up the strand of beads. Holds them up in the light, watching them shimmer. She goes to the front of club, where a smattering of L.A. HIPSTERS enter. There's a GLASS DISPLAY CASE full of photos of the acts. Ali looks at the pictures of the Girls in their elaborate costumes and provocative poses. She's unintentionally made her way to the front door. Black curtains obscure her view inside. She peers in. HEARS cool music emanating. The sounds of a nightclub. Intriguing. She ventures inside...</context>
      <utterance>I'm really sor--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this place? A strip club?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali looks back at the photos.</context>
      <utterance>Strip club? Honey, I ought to wash your mouth out with Jaegermeister. The only pole you'll find in here is Natasha the shot girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - IMPATIENT</mode>
      <context>Ali digs her ID out, hands it over. Alexis scans it --</context>
      <utterance>Babycakes, shit or get off the throne, I got a club to fill here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ali looks in her wallet. Sees one lone twenty inside. She hands it to Alexis. He nods for her to go ahead. Ali descends a staircase INTO THE CLUB... .and is BOMBARDED by: colors, chaos, laughter, scandal -- all shimmering, as if someone dunked the place in glitter. And over it all, an incredible mash-up of old music with a contemporary beat tying it all together. Ali ENTERS, rounds a pillar, staring out into the room as a SPOTLIGHT finds the stage where half a dozen OSTRICH FANS</context>
      <utterance>Twenty bucks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns. A bartender is watching her watch. JACK - 25, punky, dark hair, eyeliner, one arm half-sleeved with tats.</context>
      <utterance>Get you a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only if you're buying.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to L.A.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>DISAPPOINTED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it that obvious?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still have that new-car smell.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not brand new. But still under warranty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks back at the stage, mesmerized.</context>
      <utterance>Where you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Iowa.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah? Kentucky. We're practically related.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles. As Ali sips her free beer, Jack stacks drinks on a tray for a DITSY WAITRESS. He slides the tray to her. She doesn't notice. He barks at her:</context>
      <utterance>I thought you looked familiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey_. Go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>TO HERSELF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't build 'em like this in Iowa, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares up at the stage, marvels at the dancers.</context>
      <utterance>Hell no. I wouldn't have left.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So tell me -- who does a girl flirt with to get from here...  to there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this you flirting?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs. Points across the club to A DOOR leading backstage.</context>
      <utterance>With someone wearing more eyeliner than me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she heads off--</context>
      <utterance>Ask for Tess. She's your guy. Flirt away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He hands her a card. She looks at it:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Iowa-- use my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, slips it in her cleavage and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Jack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. I'm looking for Tess.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She switches to mascara. Sean, arms heavy with corsets, catches eyes with Ali, nods toward Tess: "that's her." Ali steps closer to Tess.</context>
      <utterance>So am I. And sometimes, when the lights are dim, and I squint my eyes ...I can still see her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm a friend of Jack's, and I'm-</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and I'm--</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking for a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and I--</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to perform here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess glances at Ali in the mirror. Then goes back to her mascara, unimpressed. Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a singer. A good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a dance show.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? You a professional?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a quick study.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess stands, a final check in the mirror. Ali sees her chance</context>
      <utterance>Not on my dime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I get that you're busy so I won't waste any more of your time-- but this place-- I've just never seen anything like it before and I know I belong here. So, how can I be a part of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess strides out, not looking back. Ali sees the Girls trading glances, amused. She turns and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty bucks at the door can make all your dreams come true.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at her, surprised. Impressed.</context>
      <utterance>One Dewar's neat, one shot of Patron, and get this, tough-guy in the hat? He wants a Cosmo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One night. If I'm not 20 times better than boobs-for-brains over there, you don't have to pay me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her leg went behind her head!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Coco's the real deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She used to dance with the Joffrey Ballet. Nikki sang opera. Eva performed with Cirque. Everyone here's a pro.  And you're on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she doing here?!</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode>POINTS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want that bitch out. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd she do to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stifled giggles from the girls.</context>
      <utterance>She thought I was a drag queen!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki is about to haul off on Sean when the CURTAIN OPENS, and WHOOMP!</context>
      <utterance>Can't be the first time THAT'S happened.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cat MEOWS and slinks out from behind the bed. Ali pulls the crystal beads out of her pocket</context>
      <utterance>When he kisses me I get a thrill...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when he does that wiggle I can't keep still</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>(ties the beads around the CAT'S NECK)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause he's a tough lover.. .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads back to the bar. As Jack loads her tray up, she stuffs her tips into her pocket-- SEES Sean, looking her up and down.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He ties her shirt up higher, undoes the top few buttons...</context>
      <utterance>Okay, girl, time for Sean to give you a real tip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got lips that could suck the chrome off a Peterbilt, but that matte is about as sexy as a bedpan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He heads off. While Eva performs onstage, Ali delivers the drinks to a table of SCENESTERS as Eva winds up her act in a flurry of fierce ballet moves, finishing to APPLAUSE as... Ali notices someone waving her over. MARCUS GERBER. 31, boyishly handsome in jeans and a ringer tee. Gold Rolex, status sneakers. Charming. Charismatic. When Ali gets to him:</context>
      <utterance>Now baby, go show 'em what you got.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali starts away, then--</context>
      <utterance>Dewar's on the rocks for me. Bottle of Dom for the table and--  --And tell Nikki I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh-kay. He smiles, wickedly handsome. Ali pivots and heads back to the bar. Before she can tell Jack the order:</context>
      <utterance>A member since 1991.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dewar's rocks, bottle of Dom, keep it coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Asshole's a regular?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus Gerber. Real estate guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's with Nikki?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince goes over to Marcus's table, shakes hands, joins him.</context>
      <utterance>This week.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack is about to lift the AmEx off the tray, when Sean swoops by and intercepts it.</context>
      <utterance>Technically your boss: Vince Scali. Tess's partner. And ex...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees Coco walking by, swipes the AmEx in her cleavage. She shudders, then turns around and tips her ass up at him. He swipes the card again.</context>
      <utterance>A black AmEx! The backstage pass to life!</utterance>
   <speaker>COCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Access denied!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack sees Ali laughing at their banter. She heads off with the tray of Dewar's and Dom as the "Prince Nez" number ends.</context>
      <utterance>Now there's a first!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what you said last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has no choice. We owe a balloon payment of 100 grand on the first, she took out a second to buy me out of the condo. And she just got turned down for another loan today.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a handful of these clubs around town, I could buy one of them tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it wouldn't be in the heart of the Sunset Strip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack gives Sean his drink. He walks off. MUSIC UP: An insanely cool version of Sly and Family Stone "Everybody Is A Star" mashed up with a Fosse-esque Burlesque rap.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. My lines. Our secret.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali enters with a tray of drinks. Nikki swipes one.</context>
      <utterance>Nikki, do you even own a watch? Or do you measure time in Patron shots?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki opens a bottle, pops 3 pills in her mouth, washes them down with the drink, and sets the empty glass on Ali's tray.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, no, that's for --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nikki turns to the mirror and starts getting to work. As Ali hands out the other drinks:</context>
      <utterance>You, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tess doesn't answer. But a slight glance at Ali in the mirror shows she's half-listening.</context>
      <utterance>Tess? Do you have a second?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking -- see, I grew up listening to all this music, I'd play the records over and over --</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fast-forward, babe. I gotta rebuild Rome in the next two minutes--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now see-- that's what I've been thinking about. There's one thing I don't get.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just one?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girls trade looks, knowing Ali's overstepping here. Ali doesn't feel the vibe-shift, surges ahead.</context>
      <utterance>It's the vocals. You have the girls lip-synching. which is fine, I guess, but wouldn't it be so much better if they actually sang?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Silence. Nobody moves. All eyes on Tess.</context>
      <utterance>I've been reading up on it, and back when burlesque started, that's what they did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess slowly spins around in her chair to face Ali. Peers at her with a supercilious gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no she didn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"When burlesque started"? Which was...when?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well... this book said it came after...</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali sees the Girls enjoying this dressing-down immensely. Tess stands, peers down her nose at Ali.</context>
      <utterance>Vaudeville -- is the word you're looking for. Derived from the 15th- century French expression "voix de ville" -- "voice of the city". Popular songs of the time that were strung together into stage shows. Which, over time, gave birth to another kind of show in which talented girls showing a bit more skin danced, did skits, and, _ yes, sang. In addition to being raunchier, these shows were funnier, hence the new name. "Burlesque": "comical" in French.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dance major. Juilliard. I did my thesis on Burlesque.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Ok. It's just-- It's just that ...I CAN sing and--</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sashays out leaving Ali standing there with what's left of her dignity and an empty cocktail tray. The Girls launch back into prepping for the show.</context>
      <utterance>We can all sing. But they don't come to hear us sing. They come to see the best dancers in town backed by the greatest singers in history.  But tell you what: when you find someone with better pipes than Sarah Vaughn, Billie Holiday and Etta James-- you let me know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FLUSH. The stall door opens. Georgia comes out shakily with mascara-smudged eyes, sweet as ever.</context>
      <utterance>Georgia? You okay in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rinses her mouth out at the sink.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know why they call it morning sickness when it hits at every freakin hour of the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Georgia turns sideways to the mirror, inspecting her bump.</context>
      <utterance>There aren't many women who could dance the Charleston on a chair at - - what are you, three months?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four. Can you believe my boyfriend hasn't noticed yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't told him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets to work wiping away her smudged mascara.</context>
      <utterance>I guess as long as he doesn't know, I can still imagine he'll be happy about it.  Oh my God, look what the cat dragged in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Georgia reaches into her corset, yanks one breast skyward, then does the same to the other.</context>
      <utterance>You look pretty hot to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coco enters carrying a glass of tonic for Georgia.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well -- you take what Mother Nature gave you and milk the hell out of it, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Coco.</utterance>
   <speaker>COCO</speaker>
      <mode>TO ALI</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't you be on the floor?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to pee. Is that okay with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali sees she's in the way. As she steps aside:</context>
      <utterance>Not when you're blocking my mirror it's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>COCO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's us. You okay, or are you gonna puke on me during the number?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coco drags her out, leaving Ali alone. Ali looks at herself in the mirror. Reaches into her shirt and does the boob-hoist that Georgia did. Looks again. Better.</context>
      <utterance>I can't make any promises.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They tear past her. She shakes her head, reaches her landing, heads down the hall toward her room, then sees: HER HOTEL ROOM DOOR, ajar. The lock broken.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She runs down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>No. No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks out the window, SEES the ROBBERS running off, disappearing down the street. She kicks the trash can. It flies across the room.</context>
      <utterance>No!!! God damn it!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She sees the cat watching her from behind the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it! Damn it, damn it, damn it, damn it, damn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The cat creeps out, slinks around her legs. Ali plunks on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>A lotta help you were.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Then she sees, on the floor, the PHOTO she took from Nanna's. She picks it up. The glass has cracked, tearing the picture.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to speak, but can't -- so she just nods.</context>
      <utterance>Ali? What's wrong? You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Cause, in my experience-- when you're on someone's doorstep surrounded by everything you own, there's usually a not-so-good story</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. No way!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sobs--trying to talk, with high-pitched SQUEAKS only heard by birds. Jack winces, trying to follow--</context>
      <utterance>Came in -- busted the lock-- and stole all my MO-NEY-EY-EY-EY!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She reaches in her pocket, pulls out a card. It's Jack's that he gave her in the club. It has his address on it.</context>
      <utterance>And there's no way I-- sleep there-- with-- like that-- the manager said- - not till Monday-- and I don't-- anyone else-- but then-- so I remembered I had...but it went straight to...so I...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a seat. I'll get us BOTH a drink. Here -- He hands her his phone. She looks at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- call whoever you want, long- distance, whatever--</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her chin starts quivering all over again.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you can. Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I.. .don't ...have anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To call.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No parents?  Siblings? Aunts? Uncles?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>NO AGAIN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>THROUGH TEARS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one! No one, okay? Do I have to spell it out for you? I am -- completely -- alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>40.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack susses out the situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>REALIZING</mode>
      <context>She starts to cry again.</context>
      <utterance>So...you're not here to use my phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She nods. He grabs a bottle of Tequila and a couple of glasses. Pours them a couple. They both take a drink.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Wait. No, stop, stop, stop, it's okay, it's fine. You'll crash here. No problem. Just, please -- no more crying.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She nods.</context>
      <utterance>Better?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She wipes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just for one night, I swear. Just till it's light outside and I can figure out my next move.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she opens her small bag and the cat strolls out.</context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa, you didn't say anything about a cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It slinks around his leg. He shakes it off.</context>
      <utterance>What? You don't like cats?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate cats.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you hate a cat?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cat bolts into the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>It's easy, I'll show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's it going? If that thing pees on my bed --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the window. The cat scurries back in, leaps onto the ledge. Ali pets him. Looks at Jack, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>He goes outside. We just have to open a window. He's very independent.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>It purrs. Jack eyes it warily.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have a name for him yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One night?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you play at the club?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make more money bartending.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You in a band?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was... Guitarist moved to Reno, Drummer went to med school, bassist is in rehab. I'm subbing around town till I regroup. This is for a punk fusion band -- their keyboardist is a flake, so they call me a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>SARCASTIC</mode>
      <context>HIGH ANGLE, seeing both of them on either side of a wall. Her listening, him playing. After a few measures:</context>
      <utterance>A flaky punk-rock-fusion keyboardist? No way. He smiles. Continues playing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He stops playing again.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you leave Kentucky?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you leave Iowa?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause I looked around and realized there wasn't one person whose life I wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Then as he starts playing again:</context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops again.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I'm really glad I'm not alone tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get some sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>43.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He continues playing. She closes her eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurls the cat away and bolts out of bed, disgusted.</context>
      <utterance>Aauuuugggghh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning. Coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>NODS</mode>
      <context>She pours him a cup. Sees a picture of a BEAUTIFUL GIRL on his fridge.</context>
      <utterance>Black. Like my soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's pretty. Your sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My fiancee. Natalie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fiancee? You're straight?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I'm straight. You thought I was gay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, the...make-up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A straight look.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the floral couch...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI/JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ali realizes she's barely dressed in front of a straight guy.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should put on pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bolts out to the living room, starts digging through her bag, bent over. She's in the doorway, so from the kitchen, all he can see is her cute little ass sticking out.</context>
      <utterance>Probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New York. Doing a play.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For how long?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't find pants. She shifts, so now her ass is facing him directly. He tries not to look--</context>
      <utterance>Six more weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>KEEPS DIGGING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, now I feel bad about this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Now that you're straight and engaged, it feels weird that I came here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aha! Pants. She pulls them out, starts putting them on. He looks out. Her foot is caught in the pants leg. As she hops around, trying to untangle it--</context>
      <utterance>Well, you did, and it was fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She tumbles out of view, thumps against some furniture. She appears in the doorway, pants on, pulling on a sweater. She slips her feet into her shoes.</context>
      <utterance>Or at least it will be as soon as you get dressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alrighty then-- I'll get outta your hair now...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, where're you headed?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She zips the cat into the bag he came in.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't worry about me. I've got a plan.  Come on, cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang on, let me at least spot you some cash. I'm a little strapped, but I could --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm good, if you could just She nods at the door. He opens it for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>eyeliner.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. For everything. You are my knight in shining...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see you at the club.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves. He closes the door behind her. Stands there.</context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, this plan of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.was to sit here at the bus stop and come up with a plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Jack, I--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pouring!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only water for chrissakes--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In ONE MOVE he SCOOPS HER up as she lets out a WHOOOOP!</context>
      <utterance>Jack-- you've done enough and--</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He grabs her bags and carries her back across the street--</context>
      <utterance>Jack-- No! Stop it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you have nowhere to go, I have a couch. You may as well stay here for a few days.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll be fine --</context>
      <utterance>You really don't need to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be homeless. You always have this much trouble saying yes when someone is trying to help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cat jumps up on the back of a chair, all wet, and SHAKES, splattering them with wet cat smell.</context>
      <utterance>It's never happened before.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK/ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As his PHONE RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Aaaaargh!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a towel in the bathroom-- dry yourself and that damn cat off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk off stage, dismissed. Tess turns to Sean.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, front row, thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to all the great dancers in L.A?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HALF A DOZEN DANCERS move to the stage. Ali watches from behind the bar, thinking. Then, on her face, we see: an idea forming. ON THE FLOOR, Tess and Sean check their clipboards, organizing for this next set. They look up and start in:</context>
      <utterance>They're busy "Dancing with the Stars."  Last group, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There, in the back row, is Ali, in her white platform shoes.</context>
      <utterance>All right, ladies, and five, six, seven -- whoa.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Coco and Georgia ENTER-- surprised to see Ali on stage.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell do you think you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trying out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tess, I've been singing and dancing my whole life and--</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girls here have years of training and experience. This stage is for serious and professional</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sean's eyebrows reach for the ceiling as Nikki enters, SEES Ali on stage.</context>
      <utterance>Hey_. This is your club and you can be as rude as you want--but don't you dare tell me I'm not serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I may not have been to a professional dance school, but I have a lot of talent and I came to this town to do something with it. And the only reason I've been putting up with all the bullshit "attitude" I get from you is cause I want to do it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Everyone in the club just stands there. Jaws dropped. Tess just looks at her, blinks, incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>For the first time in my life, I don't want to be someplace else. So you're gonna give me MY shot. Right here. Right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One song. You don't like it, I'll quit and do us both a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Sean, eyes big as saucers, looks from Ali to Tess, then back</context>
      <utterance>Your call, lady. I know every number in the show.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>DOUBTFUL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know every number.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess looks at her in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Which one do you wanna see?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ali just stares at her. Calling her bluff, Tess yells up to DAVE in the sound booth--</context>
      <utterance>I said, which one do you wanna see?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess plops down in a booth-- crosses her arms indignantly. ON STAGE, the music starts. Ali readies herself, starts to dance. Behind a beat to two. She's got the steps right, but it isn't clicking. She's thinking too hard. No personality. After a few measures, Tess has seen enough.</context>
      <utterance>Tough Lover!</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay then, next?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Dave resets the music. Ali regroups: takes her hair down and shakes it loose. Nikki ENTERS, SEES Ali on stage--</context>
      <utterance>Hang on.  Start it again, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode>TO GEORGIA</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>COCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On stage, Ali takes a beat; inhales, breathing in attitude. Then she looks up at the booth again.</context>
      <utterance>Shhhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MUSIC starts in again. And this time, Ali comes alive. She may not have perfect technique or the best extension, but she exudes an ambition and sexuality no one has seen from her before. It's like she becomes a woman before our eyes. She misses a step or two, but who the hell cares? On the floor, Sean gapes, eyes popping. Tess is poker-faced. Coco and Georgia's expressions turn from dubious to respectful. Nikki's eyes narrow. At the bar, Jack freezes, a huge rack of glasses in his arms - - unable to tear his eyes away.</context>
      <utterance>Anytime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are so you happy about, that's your replacement.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess and Ali are in a stare down.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but she's really good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want so badly to say something bitchy, but nothing's coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess sighs, not wanting to give Ali any props.</context>
      <utterance>There's a first.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were off the whole second half.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess narrows her eyes at Ali. Then looks over at Nikki, Coco and Georgia. Georgia gives an effusive THUMBS UP-- then suddenly becomes overcome by nausea, covers her mouth and RUNS to the bathroom to puke-- Tess rolls her eyes, looks back at Ali.</context>
      <utterance>So, I was spot on the first half?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali tries hard not to beam--</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're gonna be such a pain in my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have the job, or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not great. What you are is lucky. Because I need someone tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Tess turns and leaves--</context>
      <utterance>And I know all the routines.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even in those shoes that time forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki watches Tess go-- turns and pours herself a shot.</context>
      <utterance>Theeeere's bitchy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sean jumps up on the stage.</context>
      <utterance>Well-- this totally sucks ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations. The last time someone showed Tess balls like that, she married him.  You look like a checker at a Mal Wart in Wichita. Just tripled your salary. Get a new look.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I happen to like the way I look.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then what happens?</context>
      <utterance>Really? That's a fascinating story.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>ALL BUSINESS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Backstage in five.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>WALKING OFF</mode>
      <context>Ali jumps off the stage, runs to the bar, where Jack is still standing, slack-jawed. She throws her arms around him.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the family.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She squeezes him tight-- then heads backstage leaving him standing there, really turned on.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry for the short notice, I quit!  But hey-- with my raise I'll be off your couch in a week.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She catches the clothes. He dumps shoes on top of them, holding them up as he tells her what they go with:</context>
      <utterance>First number, second number, third number...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the sequined bustier. With the shorts and garters. With the beaded number. And those --  I never want to see again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>REMEMBERING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! And -- He hands her a prop GOLD MACHINE GUN.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ali pulls the trigger. BOOM -- GLITTER SPLATS all over Sean.</context>
      <utterance>For "Miss Otis Regrets". Just be sure you don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull the trigger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess meets his eye, then walks away. The number ends. The girls rush offstage and peel their costumes off.</context>
      <utterance>Admit it. You like her. It kills you, but you like her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My tits are up around my ears, my thong's about a mile up up ass, this corset is so tight, I haven't breathed since Tuesday and these lashes are thick enough to kick up a stiff wind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fun being a girl, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>BIG SMILE</mode>
      <context>She hands him the last bits of her costume. FOLLOW Ali as she heads to the dressing room. As she grabs her T-shirt and jeans:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FOLLOW Ali to the bathroom as she throws on her clothes and washes off her make-up, humming "Rich Man's Frug" to herself. She heads back out to the dressing room to find: EVERYONE IS GONE. She looks around. Feels like an fool. She plunks down in a chair. Drops her bag on the floor. Looks at herself in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>I'm starving, who wants to go grab some pizza before the next show? A general chorus of "Yeah?" and "I'm in."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She turns and sees Tess in the doorway. Tess comes over, takes Ali's brush. Looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>Your brush is for shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She chucks it in the trash.</context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get this, the 99 cent store?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make-up is like wine. The good stuff costs a fortune but is worth every penny. Where is everyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the girls went out for pizza.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you one of the girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess reads her like a book. Knows what went down. She turns to leave, then pauses at the door. Turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Apparently not.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali meets her eyes in the mirror. Then Tess grabs a brush from her own station, tosses it to Ali.</context>
      <utterance>Don't take it personally. Their love's the kind you gotta earn.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She leaves Ali alone.</context>
      <utterance>Dip it in water first, or you'll never get a clean line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your stupid cat peed in the tub!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...?  You closed the window, what do you expect?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali scoops the cat up.</context>
      <utterance>Your cat pees in the house, and it's my_ fault?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awwww. Poor guy, you must have been desperate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He GRABS the newspaper and tosses it in front of her-- she glares at him, then glances at the paper--</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn cat. And you used my towel again.  How's that apartment hunting coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>EYES WIDENING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A thousand bucks for a studio?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you really put a price on privacy? Freedom? Your own bathroom? With clean towels?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His cell phone rings. As he checks who's calling:</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Jack-- I get it--</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads into the bedroom, closes the door. Ali shakes her head, begins to peruse the classifieds.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie.  Hey, baby, how are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She scans the ads some more. Finds a good one.</context>
      <utterance>Guest studio, Hollywood, $900, with a yard, and -- oh. No pets.  Screw them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack walks in. Looks like he's got something on his mind.</context>
      <utterance>Ooh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Where's Pomona?</context>
      <utterance>I think I found my new place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to Hell, turn left, it's three miles down on the right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. How's Beachwood Canyon?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, if you have a car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truth is, you should get a car first. This is L.A. You don't exist without a car. Plus, you can't really afford a decent place yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>THINKING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She looks at him, curious.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna suck it up and let you stay here a little longer. Just throw in a little something for rent.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the "God damn" cat?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I don't like the cat. And I don't like my towel being wet. I don't like the lack of privacy. But you're in a jam -- and I'm the kind of guy, if a friend's in trouble, I help. It's just who I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>SUSPICIOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did Natalie have to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She narrows her eyes at him. He concedes.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing, you know just... hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And...her play got extended three more months, so since she has to pay rent there, she can't also keep up her part of the rent here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-hah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if you could stick around and chip in, it would --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Save your ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali looks down at his shoes.</context>
      <utterance>-- help.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, will you look at that? The shoe, on the other foot!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just -- yes or no?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at her-- realizes he's screwed.</context>
      <utterance>What's the proposal, exactly?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bedroom, with private bathroom access, for 600 a month, including utilities.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Closet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali picks up the paper, reads an ad.</context>
      <utterance>Half .</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooh, look! Hot tub!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She weighs it. Makes him suffer. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Fine. The closet, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>MOCKING HIM</mode>
      <context>We HEAR an AUDIENCE laugh O.S. as we...</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm the kind of girl, if a friend's in trouble, I help. That's just who I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd laughs. Tess points to a woman who isn't laughing.</context>
      <utterance>But you can bet your sweet ass I'm better ONCE than I ever was...</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The crowd chuckles as the Bumper Band kicks in and the harem scene evolves into a sexy tongue-in-cheek silhouetted dance.</context>
      <utterance>Drink up, sister! You're a tad behind.  Be a dear and bring Mommy over there another scotch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The distributor's holding back the booze unless we cut him a check.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ply him with drinks, send Scarlett over to flirt, and try to finagle him down to a half.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He produces a check, all filled-out, for her to sign.</context>
      <utterance>How's a third?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have I told you lately that I love you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got any brothers?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drinking already?</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mommie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But I'm working on it. Nikki totters a little. Tess looks her over.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pulling you from this number. Go home, wring yourself out, and come back tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess SPOTS Ali heading for the dressing room--</context>
      <utterance>You can't pull me--</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ali! Take Nikki's spot.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WHAT?! That bitch can't dance my part!</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali looks at Nikki-- who GLARES at her--</context>
      <utterance>Ali-- get dressed NOW!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess looks at her-- she's really had it with these girls--</context>
      <utterance>But, wait-- Tess-- that's always been Nikki's number.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali looks between the two of them, Nikki glaring at her--</context>
      <utterance>But this is MY club, and now it's your number.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a problem? You said you know the whole show.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CHALLENGING HER</mode>
      <context>Tess just looks at Ali. Nikki stares at Tess, livid, then storms off.</context>
      <utterance>You can do anything, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tess needs you. She said it was urgent.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't leave here now --</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, but don't say I didn't warn you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close the Goddman curtain!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali starts to sing again, her version, slow, and sexy...</context>
      <utterance>Hold on...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tess spots a TATTOOED BAND GUY in the door.</context>
      <utterance>I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you boys know all the music?</utterance>
   <speaker>TATTOOED BAND GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki wanders in, drink in hand. Tess looks at them all. Plants her hands on her hips.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali can't keep from beaming as she shakes her head, no!</context>
      <utterance>Okay, then. Tomorrow night, Ali sings lead, everyone else is back- up. Questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Girls file into the dressing room. Tess heads out, past Nikki.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"People don't come to hear us sing."</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves. Nikki scowls. Sean grabs Ali.</context>
      <utterance>No. But they'll come to hear her sing. Dry out and maybe you can back her up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads off to the dressing room, too, leaving Nikki and Ali alone together. Their eyes meet.</context>
      <utterance>Bitch, you SANG that damn song!</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tosses her glass in the trash and leaves Ali alone.</context>
      <utterance>One of us has clearly underestimated the other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns. Marcus is there. Handsome, charming and devious as ever.</context>
      <utterance>Where'd you learn to sing like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't learn to sing like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're too good to be singing here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shrugs, "but, you are" then--</context>
      <utterance>I just got into the show and suddenly I'm too good for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Jack's at the bar. Tell him I sent you. It's on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE BAR - Jack looks up, SEES Ali and Marcus talking. BACK ON MARCUS who looks Ali up and down.</context>
      <utterance>But I hate lines.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seriously. You sound even better than you look. Which is saying a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, amused, and heads away from him, toward the bar. He watches her go. Tess intercepts Ali.</context>
      <utterance>Talk about a "line."</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ali heads off. Tess glances back at Marcus, mistrustful.</context>
      <utterance>Directions to the bar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knew any white chick could sing like that? You channeled that shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell do you do that, girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's in my hands, my feet, my gut,</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I can't explain it. It's like -- I start singing, and something starts to move inside me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>and it just builds and builds till I feel like I'm gonna explode.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hops off the stool and scurries to the back. Coco stands, to leave. Looks at Ali.</context>
      <utterance>Trust me, I know what that feels like. I have to pee. Again.</utterance>
   <speaker>COCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali looks back at Coco -- validated. Accepted. At last.</context>
      <utterance>Wanna grab something to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali moves off. Coco goes to get her coat. Sean sees Jack still watching Ali as she walks across the room.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Lemme get my bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, will you look at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You looking at that girl the way I looked at you all those years. Only difference: you actually stand a chance with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a fiancee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three thousand miles away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We talk every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack shoots him a glare.</context>
      <utterance>Let me guess what about: her, her and...oh! Her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ali comes back, ready to go. Feels them stop talking and look at her.</context>
      <utterance>All I'm saying is, this one's beautiful on the inside too. And she won't be on the shelf forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack grabs a trash bag and takes it out back. Sean looks at Ali more closely. He brushes her hair out of her face. Then he holds it off her shoulders and raises that gay eyebrow. - INT. SALON - DAY - Ali sits in front of a mirror while Sean gives the HAIRDRESSER very specific instructions. - INT. JACK'S APARTMENT, AT HIS KEYBOARD, Jack plays a high- energy style piano which runs over a QUICK SEQUENCE: It's the instrumental music to: "BUT I'M A GOOD GIRL." - INT. BURLESQUE LOUNGE - The Burlesque Girls dance on stage, performing a high-energy tap dance, coupled with a European slap-dance, with the slapping of each other's bodies and faces integrated with tapping and music. It's very cabaret, but modernized with contemporary STEPPING. CARRY MUSIC: - INT. SALON - LATER - The HAIRDRESSER spins the chair around. Ali's her hair is platinum blonde, with bangs and a Louise Brooks bob that frames her face beautifully. Her smoky eyes pop like never before. Ali studies herself:</context>
      <utterance>I was just explaining to Jack that even opportunity has a shelf life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have I been all my life?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She spins herself around on a bar stool, so he can see all angles. Jack likes plenty. Way too much.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya, big boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>FLUSTERED</mode>
      <context>Not the reaction she was looking for.</context>
      <utterance>It's...I think-you look...I mean, yeah... do you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack. It's okay for you to think I look hot. We're friends for chrissakes. It's not like we're brother and sister.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>TO HIMSELF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. We certainly are not.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali -- sexy, sophisticated, gorgeous -- enters.</context>
      <utterance>Why the hell is everyone having a conniption over her? She's just a tacky, pushy girl from a --</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ali pretends she didn't hear. She sits at her mirror. The girls stare at her, mouths agape. Ali picks up her mascara wand, looks down the mirror at Nikki's reflection.</context>
      <utterance>-- fly-over state.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>FAUX INNOCENT</mode>
      <context>Ali takes a deft stroke of her wand over her lashes, then bats them at Nikki. Nikki walks out. Coco smiles with appreciation. Whistles long and low. The girls all laugh.</context>
      <utterance>What's a fly-over state?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess looks up from the contract, squints at Marcus.</context>
      <utterance>It's very simple. I buy you out and pay you a million off the top.  Five hundred grand each.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you want this club so badly?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best view on the Sunset Strip.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what you could do with that money, Tess?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what you can do with that money, Vince?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be reasonable. We're rolling vendors ninety days out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess looks at Vince, betrayed.</context>
      <utterance>The club's not even worth what you paid for it. You've got a second mortgage, you can't get a third.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you also tell him about the tattoo on my ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's business, Tess. Not personal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My business. Which I built from the ground up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna get another opportunity like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at a photo on her wall: the Burlesque Girls, in all their glory.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She gets up, opens the door, ushering them out. Marcus shoots Vince an angry look as they head downstairs. IN THE STAIRWELL, Vince reassures Marcus:</context>
      <utterance>Which is why I'll never let it go.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN TESS'S OFFICE, Tess stands in the doorway, having heard. Then she walks back to her desk and sits, dejected. Head in her hands. For the first time ever, looking worried and defeated. Something she'd never show anyone. A beat. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. The balloon payment's due on the first. She doesn't have the money. She has to sell.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up. Sean is in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Well. We've had a pretty good run.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tess's eyes go steely with determination.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's time to just.. .hang it up. Let it go. Call it a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You cannot say that to me. I can eat these "sky is falling" dipshits for breakfast, lunch, and dinner, but not YOU. You cannot be that person. I've scoured dirty flea markets for costumes, stayed up all night sewing till my fingers bled, painted and repainted every goddamn wall of this place myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sean looks at her...a wry smile.</context>
      <utterance>I choreographed every step of every number. I've played nursemaid, sister, mother and shrink to every girl who's ever danced here. I've hocked every keepsake I've ever owned to keep this place afloat. Because this club is the last of it's kind, and if it goes away, one day there won't be anything like it- - and THAT would be a tragedy. So you cannot say that to me. Because now someone's gotta believe in me, Goddamnit. And I need that person to be you. So don't you ever let me hear you say that again. I will never let this club go. Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess just looks at him, and smiles. He grabs a boa, throws it around his neck and exits. When he's gone, Tess's smile fades. IN THE CLUB, the place is empty. Jack is wiping down the bar cleaning up. He starts stacking some chairs in the house as..SEAN CROSSES the floor.</context>
      <utterance>There she is. Thought I'd lost you for a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Night, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sean EXITS as Jack carries a stack of chairs to the side of the room, sets them down near the piano. STOPS, grabs a chair for himself and sits down. Begins to play an original song. ACROSS THE ROOM, Ali ENTERS from backstage. Her dance bag over her shoulder. She HEARS the piano, peers around a column, SEES Jack playing. She stays in the shadows and watches as he sings and plays a beautiful song. (TBD) The song ends. Ali applauds slowly. Impressed. Jack looks up, surprised that she is there.</context>
      <utterance>Night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beautiful. You write that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just some sentimental crap. Ready?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack zips back to the door, opens it quietly, then SLAMS it.</context>
      <utterance>Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali grabs a dress from her bed, slips into it.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Just got home!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a nanosecond-- Jack enters the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>In here! Can you zip me up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Where you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he zips up the back of her dress, he sees the PHOTO propped against the lamp on the bedside table.</context>
      <utterance>Rehearsing. I'm playing a late show tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She picks up the picture. Looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>Who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She died just a few weeks later.</context>
      <utterance>Me and my mom on my 7th birthday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was so young.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>24. There was so much she never got to do. Sometimes I feel like, if I make the most of my life, part of her will get to live a little more, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the photo down. Turns back to him. They're close.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. You must miss her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every single day, something happens I want to tell her about.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Their eyes connect.</context>
      <utterance>What was today's?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand there, close to each other. Jack sees a strand of hair caught in the earring. He pulls it away, freeing it. His fingers move through her hair. She closes her eyes, feeling his fingers against her neck. Then she opens her eyes, looks at him. He looks back, unable to look away. Until: His CELL PHONE RINGS. Breaking the mood. He pulls it from his pocket. Checks who's calling. Looks back at Ali.</context>
      <utterance>Don't know. Hasn't happened yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali steps away from him, disappointed. He answers the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I should... it's... Natalie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ali watches him walk away from her, falling into the conversation with Natalie.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, babe, how are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, she's still here-What do you want me to do, it's not like you're here helping out, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>78.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC UP: An incredibly sexy saxophone which takes us to: FULL CLOSE UP: ALI steps into frame, starts singing.</context>
      <utterance>Ali grabs her bag and jacket, heads for the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- when can you cut out? I'm about to fall asleep standing up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have that gig, remember? In fact, I gotta head out or I'm gonna be late.  I can maybe swing you home before.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs his jacket from under the bar. As he heads out:</context>
      <utterance>No, that's okay, you go. I'll grab a ride with Coco.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the way -- you killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll drop you off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>She realizes he was listening to her conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Coco left five minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry-- I was coming to talk to you and caught the end of your conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk to me about...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swoops down and GRABS her dance bag and purse, turns and heads out.</context>
      <utterance>Dinner. With me. Gimmie that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - WALKING AWAY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you ever expect to see this bag alive again... you'll come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey...! Come back here...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you-- to dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dinner? What about Nikki-- What's up with you and Nikki?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where I'm from friends don't chew each other's earlobes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you glad you left?  Oh, damn!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just remembered I have to make a quick appearance at a party.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just remembered.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten minutes, tops. Do you mind?</context>
      <utterance>It's on the way. We'll be quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns off Sunset and heads up into the hills.</context>
      <utterance>Then you've been kidnapped.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Nice house.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTY GUEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marcus --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes the guy's hand and moves on through the party. Someone else calls out to him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, how you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER GUEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, let me get a drink, I'll be</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna throw us out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kicks open a back door.</context>
      <utterance>Not if we sneak out first, come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts up some steps to an outdoor gazebo. Ali follows. They pass AN INCREDIBLY WELL-DRESSED COUPLE coming down.</context>
      <utterance>Up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marcus --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exchange hellos. Ali notices:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Guys. Greg, Marla, this is Ali.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooh. Killer shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't they? Louboutins.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali stares at Marcus. He smiles, takes her hand, keeps leading her up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Glad you could come.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had to make an appearance at your own party?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali glances back at Marla again, locks in on her shoes.</context>
      <utterance>Would've been rude not to, right? You'd like those guys. Greg's the entertainment editor at the Times, and Marla's a designer.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna dream about those shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thousand dollars a pop.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Who can afford that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs as they reach the top of the stairs and a BREATHTAKING PANORAMIC VIEW OF THE ENTIRE CITY is revealed. Ali pauses, taking in the glittering, massive view of L.A.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I saw them first.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. L.A. looks one hell of a lot prettier from up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It should. That view cost me three times what the house did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>POINTING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See that strip mall down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You own that too?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I own everything above it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is nothing above it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You own...air?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Air rights. The guy who owns the strip mall was having money issues and almost had to sell. Whoever he sold to would have put in a huge tower. So I bought the air rights. Now no one can ever build above one story.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you the sly puss.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mall guy gets to keep his property. I get to keep the second best view in L.A.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gazes at her. She rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What's the first?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many girls have you used that on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles. Looks at her. Then...</context>
      <utterance>None who ever called me on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want, Ali? In life. Girl like you, gives up everything, gets on a bus heading for total uncertainty-- she's got a dream. I want to know what it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. She thinks about it. Looks him in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Because you're talented enough to get whatever you want. And I'm smart enough to help make it happen. So? What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be the best singer I can be. I want to give as much joy as I get when I perform. And I want to die knowing I made the most of every opportunity life gave me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's ...so beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes narrow.</context>
      <utterance>There wasn't a dry eye in the house when I said it at the Grundy County Junior Miss Talent Show.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you women always take advantage of nice boys?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki picks one up -- checking their authenticity.</context>
      <utterance>Ooh. Faboo.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes turn to Ali. She's saved by Tess entering.</context>
      <utterance>Who's the sucker?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coco-puff, shake a leg, you're on in five, Georgie-Girl, Ali-Cat -- move, move, move -- Tess exits.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh. My Nanna used to call me her Ali-Cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yet another fascinating story.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why doesn't Tess have a nickname for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>COCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A knowing look amongst the girls.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, she does.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She never uses it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure she does.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki gives him the finger and walks out. A beat. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Just after you leave the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLS TOGETHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They crack up. CUE MUSIC: "STRANGE THINGS HAPPENING"</context>
      <utterance>Coke-whore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were out late last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a ride home with that guy-- Marcus-- we went to a party. It was fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus the Asshole?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads past him, toward the kitchen. He notices:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Turns out he's not so bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New shoes?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's only one reason a man buys a woman shoes, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what if I'm getting a little male attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get a lot more than a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not from anyone who matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CLEARLY IRRITATED</mode>
      <context>Ali stops in front of him. Hands on her hips.</context>
      <utterance>I just think that you should be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I just think that -- if you really feel the need to tell a girl what she should and shouldn't do, you should pick up the phone and call your fiancee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Have you seen this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali wanders out of the bathroom, brushing her teeth. He shows her the paper. She SCREAMS.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCARLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That's major.</utterance>
   <speaker>COCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali reads the card: "To the best view in L.A. - M". Sean shoves her down in her seat, pulls her coat off.</context>
      <utterance>From Monsieur Louboutin, I presume.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shake your tail, Alicat, you still got a show to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm starting to think you'll go to any length.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>INNOCENTLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just made a call to Greg at the Times.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well-- I appreciate the kudos.  And Tess appreciates the business.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is about you. And me.</context>
      <utterance>This has NOTHING to do with Tess.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs-- takes her arm--</context>
      <utterance>You are so full of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees HAROLD SAINT sitting in the booth. He's in his 60's, still dressing like Robert Evans in his heyday.</context>
      <utterance>I've got another friend I want you to meet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ali Rose, Harold Saint.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>SHOCKED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harold Saint? Shut up. You worked with Etta James.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her, she chewed me up and spat me out, that one. But with her voice, I forgive her everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a set of pipes on you, too, little girl. I like your sound.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>SMILES</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever recorded?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands. Turns to Marcus.</context>
      <utterance>We should do something about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He points his finger, gun-style, which would seem cheesy, but he's old school, so instead it's weirdly cool. He leaves.</context>
      <utterance>See you round, kiddo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE BAR, Jack watches Ali and Marcus talking excitedly. Not liking what he sees. Sean breezes by, grabs a drink.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit. Harold Saint.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You snooze, you lose, pretty boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dumps the costumes in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Can you believe this crowd?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess walks off with the armful of clothes, so happy, humming to herself, passes her OFFICE-- OPENS the door to SEE-- VINCE is sitting at her desk. He flinches at the sight of her-</context>
      <utterance>'bout time. These poor babies are begging for your glue-gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops in her tracks, spotting Vince's PANTS on the FLOOR, and a TRAIL OF WOMEN'S CLOTHES to... THE NEW COCKTAIL WAITRESS, peering out, half-dressed, from behind the curtains--</context>
      <utterance>Can you believe the crowd out there? Never thought I'd see-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess rolls her eyes, doesn't slow.</context>
      <utterance>Tess. We need to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now, Nikki.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, now. I've been here since the beginning. We built this club together. And then some girl shows up out of nowhere-- who hasn't even paid her dues--</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get her to write a check tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And suddenly it's her show?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's not her show. It's my show. But people want to hear her sing. She's bringing them in off the streets. You better believe I'm building a show around her!</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can sing too! And you know it. But you don't give a shit. You always say this is a dance troupe, now suddenly it's not?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you expect me to dance behind a girl who struts in with a new pair of shoes she got for sleeping with Marcus Gerber?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nikki, you're wasted. Go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess hurls the costumes in the trunk of her car, furious.</context>
      <utterance>I won't be upstaged by some slut with mutant lungs!</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So don't be! Leave! If you don't want to be a part of what's happening here, then I don't want you around.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode>AGHASST</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd destroy our friendship and break up the group over some girl you barely know?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki just looks at her--</context>
      <utterance>Since when do you care about friendship? Or this group? You're a trainwreck, Nikki! You put tequila on your breakfast cereal! I'm struggling to survive here, and you show up too drunk to dance! You call that loyalty?</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki stomps off. Tess sighs --</context>
      <utterance>Okay, then. I quit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus says you're losing the club anyway!</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode>MOCKING HER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"They don't come to hear us sing"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - SOTTO</mode>
      <context>Nikki flips her off and keeps walking. Then turns once more:</context>
      <utterance>Stupid bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tess's eyes narrow. She grabs a HIGH-HEELED PUMP and HURLS it. It flies through the air and hits Nikki in the back of the head. Nikki SCREAMS, whips around, incredulous, to see: TESS, running right at her. Nikki bolts, heading for her car. She jumps in, locks the door just as Tess SMASHES her fist on the window and KICKS the door. Nikki starts the car.</context>
      <utterance>By the way: I slept with Vince the day after your honeymoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nikki screeches off, leaving Tess alone in the parking lot. Tess stands there a moment, then HEADS back into the club.</context>
      <utterance>You crazy bitch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Tess looks up, Dave is closing up the sound booth.</context>
      <utterance>Night, Tess.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dave FLIPS a big lever, and almost all the lights go OUT, leaving one shaft of light across the stage. We HEAR Dave leave, as the street door closes shut. Tess alone on stage.</context>
      <utterance>Night, Dave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns, sees her.</context>
      <utterance>You really need to do that at 6 in the morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little overdressed for breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which was occupied.</context>
      <utterance>My pajamas were in my bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack grinds the coffee beans again. Ali winces.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you're never here so... it's stupid for me to crash on the couch every night when there's a perfectly good empty bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is that what you're saying?</context>
      <utterance>So -- you want the bedroom back?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bed should be used by someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm home every night. Maybe not when you think I should be, but last I checked, you were my roommate, not my mother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>However, since it's an issue, what the hell, take the bed, I'll sleep on the sofa. I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have to move all your shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I realize that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause the room's a total mess --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll move my stuff, God --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clothes, make-up, shoes, hair things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Jack, what is your problem? Ever since I started hanging out with Marcus, you've been acting like a class-A prick. Is there something you want to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No. What do I care? You're ambitious, he can make things happen, go ahead, make a deal with the devil, what's it to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First of all: He's not the devil. He's a smart businessman. And oddly enough-- a gentleman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>JACK SCOFFS</mode>
      <context>She storms out of the kitchen, tripping over the cat-- a LOUD MEOW! as the cat scurries away, Jack intercepting him--</context>
      <utterance>Second: I'm gonna take the couch, and you're gonna 86 the attitude. Or I'm finding another place to live.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And try not to kill the cat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack looks across the terrace at Ali. Moonlight on her shoulders. A breeze in her hair.</context>
      <utterance>.why does every conversation we have end up being about YOUR future...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack hangs up with finality and marches toward the bar-- His cell phone immediately rings again.</context>
      <utterance>.you know what, you're right. We both should be thinking about our futures. And I might just be looking at mine right now. Break a leg baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess Natalie's not coming after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE BAR - LATER - Jack drains one drink and orders another, getting very drunk. Ali sidles up to the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, please, that girl? Show up at a party where she's not the center of attention?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>TO BARTENDER</mode>
      <context>Jack raises his brow. Ali drinks the shot, and without looking at him--</context>
      <utterance>Shot of Patron.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lookin' kinda lonely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>BOOZEY</mode>
      <context>He raises his glass-- she rolls her eyes, walks off-- he follows her, playfully PUSHING her from behind.</context>
      <utterance>No. Not lonely. Liberated, yes. Libated, absolutely. But never lonely. Cheers, baby--</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey-- what're we, in junior high?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to say something as-- THE SHIRELLES start to sing "BABY IT'S YOU"-- Jack turns to the DJ, points both fingers at him and YELLS:</context>
      <utterance>You still mad at me, Iowa? C'mon. Bring it on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.Many many many nights go by, I sit alone, at home and cry, over you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks her in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you're quite the crooner.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali smiles, surprised at his candor. He breathes a sigh of relief.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry for being a class A prick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>(bleary look at his watch,</context>
      <utterance>And as of about...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAN'T FOCUS)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.some time ago, I am officially a single man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and Natalie split up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That we did. So. That explains what I'm doing here all alone. What are you doing here all alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share a look. Then he spins her around in his arms. She laughs. AT THE BAR, tipsy Sean and Coco stand side-by-side. Coco is watching the DJ spin. The DJ glances down at them.</context>
      <utterance>Do I look alone to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That DJ's hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think?</utterance>
   <speaker>COCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coco smiles up at him, flirty. The DJ smiles back.</context>
      <utterance>He keeps looking at me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to find Jack and Ali, drunk, staring at the keys on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Whoopsie daisy --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoopsie daisy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Nanna used to say that all the time. That and upsie jumpsie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Upsie jumpsie?  Upsie jumpsie, whoopsie daisy, upsie jumpsie, whoopsie daisy, upsie jumpsie --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>ABRUPTLY STOPS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When would she say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When she wanted her dog to get on the bed with her. That is --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>DRUNKEN WHISPER</mode>
      <context>Their eyes meet. A connection. Then, staring into her eyes:</context>
      <utterance>when she was alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali bursts out laughing. So does Jack, as he pushes the door open, and they fall into the apartment.</context>
      <utterance>The dog, or Nanna?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack gets the lamp to standing, then grabs one of Ali's boots, slides it off, dumps it. Then he tries the second -- it sticks -- he pulls harder -- the boot pops off and he careens backwards, crashing into the lamp, knocking it over again. Ali cracks up. He turns to the lamp.</context>
      <utterance>Help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to Ali, regains composure, bows</context>
      <utterance>Stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He backs away, into the bedroom. Ali looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Jack disappears into the bedroom and closes the door. Ali stares at it, surprised. Then resigned. Oh, well. She undoes her bra, threads it through her top and out the arms. Then Jack's door opens. He stands in the doorway in matching "Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer" pajamas, leaning against the doorframe like Hugh Hefner in his finest silk smoking jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cute jammies.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A gift from my mother. Never worn them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack walks past Ali, toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Go figure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgot to lock up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>HE DOES</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks back into the bedroom and once gain shuts the door. Ali smiles to herself, plumps her pillow. The door flies open again -- Jack's there in just the pants, no top.</context>
      <utterance>Night again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stumbles past Ali to the kitchen, drinks from the tap. After a moment he returns to the bedroom, nodding to Ali.</context>
      <utterance>Water. No hangover.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ali just nods. He closes the door. Ali smiles, waiting. After a beat, the door opens again. Jack is there, in boxers.</context>
      <utterance>Night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He walks past her to the kitchen, opens a box of cereal, pours it into his mouth. Grabs some milk from the fridge, pours it into his mouth, too. Returns to the bedroom, crunching. He closes the door. Then -- very quickly -- he opens it again and walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I forgot something else, but I just can't remember what...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>TO HIMSELF</mode>
      <context>He wanders out into the room, past Ali, and we see from behind he is butt-ass naked. She cracks up.</context>
      <utterance>Door locked, water, food...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She covers her face. He glances down.</context>
      <utterance>What's so funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He strides back to the bedroom, shutting the door. After a moment, he comes back out dressed in an old, flowered bathrobe and fur-lined orange hunting cap.</context>
      <utterance>Well I never!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remembered what I forgot to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>SERIOUS</mode>
      <context>He crosses to her, takes her in his arms, and kisses her. She kisses back, making up for all their lost time. MUSIC UP: "PRISONER" a big, soulful ballad.</context>
      <utterance>Kiss you goodnight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK'S APARTMENT - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack and Ali in bed, in post-coital bliss.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's official.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at her, drunk with lust. CAMERA PANS UP AND OFF OF</context>
      <utterance>You are definitely not gay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cocks an eyebrow at him.</context>
      <utterance>I've been wanting to do this since you first walked in the club.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at her.</context>
      <utterance>Sure got a funny way of showing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He disappears under the sheets. She SQUEALS, starts laughing hysterically. CAMERA PANS UP AND OFF OF THEM THEN DRIFTS</context>
      <utterance>I'll show you an even funnier way -- you ready?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what about Natalie...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali smiles. Rolls the stocking up over her shapely thigh, then slowly takes it off. Looks at Jack. He strikes his chest, struck by cupid--</context>
      <utterance>Natalie who?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She giggles, repeats the sexy act for him. CAMERA PANS UP AND</context>
      <utterance>Do it again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali blinks awake. Confused.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack scrambles for something to put on.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YOU are a LIAR. You're a sneaky, pathetic LI-AR!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What 's she doing here:</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know!</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I LIVE HERE, you bleached out tramp, what the hell are YOU doing here?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>TO JACK</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were engaged to this woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nat, can we talk about this in the living room --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't BELIEVE I bought your bullshit: "It's nothing, she's just this chick from work, she's nothing."</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode>TO ALI</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what he called you. "Nothing. She's not even pretty.  Well, at least you were honest about one thing--</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said that? No, I didn't --</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE  JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He most certainly did! Nat-- shut the fu--</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ali grabs for a shirt--</context>
      <utterance>Jack?!? Don't even say his name!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Ali-- let me just-- would you mind --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Giving us a little privacy?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL I</speaker>
      <mode>OFFENDED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you! I'm the fiancee. You're a booty call. You go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali grabs some pants from the floor, pulls them on.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie, Jesus, STOP IT!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, I'm out of here--  You said you split up!</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In one phone call? Please, you don't dump a girl like me on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ali quickly grabs a few things--</context>
      <utterance>Both of you-- STOP IT!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ali-- I'm really sorry-- I--</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gathers up more things, really pissed--</context>
      <utterance>So am I.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali stifles him with an incredulous glare-- can't believe how this is going down. She looks at him, so incredibly hurt. Grabs her suitcase and brushes past him, stuffing her belongings into it. Jack goes after her--</context>
      <utterance>Wait-- do you need money for a Motel or...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ali, wait a second-- don't--  --go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Jack looks at Natalie. She folds her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. I'm sorry. I think I have the wrong apartment. I'm looking for Sean?  Brown hair? 5'10n? Early 30's?</utterance>
   <speaker>DJ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's asleep. Come in.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Sean! I thought he said John.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DJ</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ali nods. Sean's eyes pop open, confused to see her.</context>
      <utterance>That him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sean notices the guy in the blanket.</context>
      <utterance>Long story.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ali, this is Mike.</utterance>
   <speaker>DJ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark???</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Anyone want coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make it. You two get acquainted.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>OVER PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey gorgeous.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Marcus.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>WANDERING IN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the coffee ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>OVER PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark. Or Mike. Jury's still out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>OVER PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I be jealous?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only if you had your eye on Sean.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>OVER PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay? You sound down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm. Maybe a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>OVER PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know just the cure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>OVER PHONE</mode>
      <context>She thinks for a moment. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Me. But you turned me down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't you heard? No is the new yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark turns, heads down the stairs as Jack rushes up, calling:</context>
      <utterance>You... Take care. Sean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Ali here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark continues down. Jack whips around, looks at him, then up at Sean, who nods.</context>
      <utterance>Just left.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd she go?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With Marcus.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack burns, frustrated, then heads slowly down the stairs. Sean shakes his head and turns to go back inside. Then pauses, noticing: Mark, looking up at Sean's apartment, hesitating. Then he opens his car to get in. Sean stands there, realizing he's doing the same thing. He steps onto the stairwell. Calls out:</context>
      <utterance>I told you, opportunity doesn't knock forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>LOOKS UP</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Mark's smile:</context>
      <utterance>Mark. You wanna have breakfast?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the fridge and pulls out a bottle of CHAMPAGNE.</context>
      <utterance>My mother always said there's only one thing to do when you're feeling blue...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was a poet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali smiles. Marcus pops the cork, fills two glasses, hands her one. Clinks.</context>
      <utterance>And a drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To your new place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What new place?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All yours.  Unpack. Move in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus, I can't just--</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus plops her suitcase on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unpack. You're home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not even on the bus route.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, that is the first and last time the term "bus route" will be spoken in this house.  Four cars. Which do you want?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>SMILES</mode>
      <context>She looks out at a giant billboard at eye level.</context>
      <utterance>Better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna be on one of those someday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sooner than you think, too. Harold Saint called me today. You made quite an impression on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to make a demo with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you serious? When??</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He found a little studio time on Tuesday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Tuesday?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too soon?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're amazing.</context>
      <utterance>No! Oh my god, no, that's amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes meet. He pushes some hair out of her face.</context>
      <utterance>I like making you happy. Your whole face lights up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're way too nice to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's a problem because...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches her face, their chemistry palpable.</context>
      <utterance>I've had a lot to drink. And my judgment is off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>vulnerable.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm a gentleman. Which means I'd never kiss a lady when she's...</utterance>
   <speaker>118.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looks at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans in and impulsively pulls him into a kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Liar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees a Warhol-esque PRINT OF MARCUS on the wall. She raises her brows then sees her disheveled reflection in a huge mirror: smeared mascara, hair askew.</context>
      <utterance>Where am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She sees her and Marcus's clothes in a trail on the floor and bites her lip, remembering last night.</context>
      <utterance>Who am I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>119.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He comes up behind her, nuzzles her neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now it's a model. But when it grows up, it'll be a mixed-use space: retail and residential.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus shrugs, dries his hair.</context>
      <utterance>This is the address of the Burlesque Lounge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best view on the Sunset Strip, with no windows. When I'm done with it, it'll have a thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't tear down the club.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about the history? That place is a landmark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not according to the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does Tess know about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Tess knows and doesn't know isn't a big concern of mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think she would ever sell the Lounge?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has no choice. She's going under.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that club is her life!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on, you get this. It's business. It's not personal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not personal? It's pretty god damn personal for Tess! And Coco and Sean and Alexis. And what about Jesse? And Dave the lighting guy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>And what about me? It's pretty God damn personal to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She marches out of the room, resolute--</context>
      <utterance>To the club. Where I work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the door she turns back and looks at him. As he starts to speak, she SLAMS the door shut as we HEAR "THAT'S LIFE".</context>
      <utterance>Ali-- wait!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE FRONT DOORS OPEN, and Ali ENTERS, spots Tess, rushes over to her.</context>
      <utterance>Right now? Get really drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess keeps walking.</context>
      <utterance>Tess! I have to talk to you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tess stops. Slowly turns and stares at Ali, who's suddenly embarrassed to admit...</context>
      <utterance>Marcus Gerber is trying to buy the lounge, and he's gonna tear it down and build a twenty-story skyscraper!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tess looks at Ali. Stunned. Ali stands there, breathless, waiting for her reaction. But Tess just turns, continues up to her office, and shuts the door. Ali turns to Sean-- then starts after her--</context>
      <utterance>I just saw the plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has to do something! She can't just let him --</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>STOPPING HER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let it go, girl. She just got turned down for another loan. It's either foreclose, or sell to Marcus.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's it? It's over?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The circle of life, baby. All good things must come to an end.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she can't just give up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali sits on a barstool, in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>She's not giving up. She's going down with her ship. With dignity.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He pulls out the photo of Ali with her mother. It's in a new frame.</context>
      <utterance>I've got something for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack. He dropped it off on his way to the airport.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's he going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New York on the red-eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To be with Natalie?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pedal faster, baby, he and Natalie are over. You're the one he's been looking high and low for.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>TOUCHED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a -- Sean tosses her his CAR KEYS.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ali catches the keys and TAKES OFF. - EXT. PARKING LOT - NIGHT - Ali (in a Prius) peels out of the lot, weaving through traffic as she lifts her cell. - INT. AIRPORT - NIGHT - CLOSE SHOT: a CELL PHONE in a plastic bowl moves through a security X-ray machine.</context>
      <utterance>American to JFK. Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FIND Jack on the other side, as his belongings come down the conveyor belt. He grabs them, turns off his cell. - EXT. STREET - NIGHT - ALI skids through a light, veers past cars. - INT. CONCOURSE - NIGHT Jack reaches gate 43, sees a long line. Gets in back. - INT. AIRPORT TERMINAL - NIGHT - Ali bolts through the front door, frantically checks the DEPARTURES MONITOR. Finds: NEW YORK JFK, GATE 43: NOW BOARDING. - INT. TERMINAL - NIGHT - Ali races up the escalator, approaching SECURITY.</context>
      <utterance>This is Jack. Leave me a message.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boarding pass?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to talk to someone, he's --</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's allowed past this point without a boarding pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I have to speak to him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, miss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sean told me you're going to New York. Please don't go!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to. I got an offer from that band -- the Punk Fusion group. They want me to tour with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They finally had it with the flaky keyboardist. I'll be back in five weeks. Will you be here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Yes. Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Marcus?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share a smile, separated by the ropes.</context>
      <utterance>.Marcus who?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to figure out if I should kiss you now, or make you wait five weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five weeks?! That's forever!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up his bags. It's killing Ali.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go, that's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They smile again. Neither wanting this moment to end. She waves. He nods. Then he turns and walks off to board. Ali watches him go. ON JACK, walking back to the gate-then -- he stops. Turns back to see Ali, but she's gone.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call you when I get there. Take care of Miles Davis.  Our cat. I named him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at her, then quickly turns to walk past the Male Security Guard.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, you get out there and kiss that girl! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead-- but you're gonna have to come back through Security again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But then I'll miss my flight!</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin looks at Jack. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Martin! Don't you dare keep that boy from kissing his girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack drops his bag, takes a running JUMP over the ROPES and RUNS through the crowded concourse -- startling everyone. ON ALI, as she walks through the concourse, reliving her last sight of Jack. As she's about to get on the escalator:</context>
      <utterance>Ah, hell. Go ahead. Bag stays here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tess!</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could knock-- this is still my office--at least for another 48</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this is really, really -- Tess holds up a hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not. Now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said -- NOT --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time someone silences Tess. Ali takes a breath.</context>
      <utterance>Yes now! God damn, you are one stubborn mule of a woman. Anyone else in their right mind would have figured out by now, when I have something to tell you, you listen! I told you I could dance, did you listen? No. Big mistake. I told you I could sing, did you listen? No. Big. mistake. This time you are going to hear what I have to say if I have to tie you up with your corset strings and scream it in your God damn ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever heard of air rights?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode>INTO PHONE</mode>
      <context>Assistant scurries out. Businessman turns to Tess.</context>
      <utterance>Jim -- Jim -- hang on, I'm gonna have to call you back -- Jim! Damnit, Nancy, get him back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back with more noise complaints?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You offered to buy my club a few years back. I said no.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now you've changed your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess smiles at him. Looks at Ali, who's not smiling. She elbows her. Ali starts smiling. Tess walks up to the desk and sits herself down. Ali does the same.</context>
      <utterance>Not exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go with me, there's a good ending, I promise. How much will these condos you're building sell for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They start at one million and go up, depending on the view.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if I told you a twenty-story high-rise was going up where my club is?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>TO ALI</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would twenty stories block his view?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten stories would. Twenty would decimate them. Leaving behind a lot of angry homeowners staring across the street at fluorescent light bulbs and dirty windows.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. Mr. ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anderson.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Anderson. Your pretty million- dollar ocean views are going away because I'm selling my building to a developer tomorrow who'll have his twenty stories all framed up by the time you start selling --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trying to sell--</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trying to sell these condos.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or. I can put you in a position where your buyers could be guaranteed their million-dollar views forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As am I. As long as you're telling me you'll have a check to me by 5:00 today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>COCKTAIL WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, baby, they cut you off at the bar. Said you have to pay cash.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I co-own this goddamn place--</utterance>
   <speaker>131.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tess comes up behind him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore you don't. I'm buying you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, according to page 4 of our contract, I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode>SCOFFING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the next 48 hours?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a CASHIER'S CHECK. Vince stares at it.</context>
      <utterance>Why postpone joy?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at it, stunned.Then at her.</context>
      <utterance>I realize it's been a while since you've seen one, but it's called a check.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not your business anymore. And neither is the lounge.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>POINTS</mode>
      <context>Tess turns and goes over to the bar, where Ali spins around on her barstool, having heard the whole thing.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you know where the door is. It used to be half yours.  And take HER with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd that feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not half bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And they crack up again. Then...</context>
      <utterance>It felt pretty God damn awesome!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And to think, you didn't even want me around.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus, here it comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.What was it you said to me that first night? "Twenty bucks at the door will make all your dreams come true." That was sweet of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you finished?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kinda ironic, when you think about it. I started off begging you to make my dreams come true, and here we are --</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>All right already! You want me to say it, I'll say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place is the love of my life. The only dream I've ever had. I don't know what I would have done if I had lost it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>HEARTFELT NOW</mode>
      <context>A moment between them... as Tess SPOTS NIKKI ENTER the club carrying her dance bag--a little fresher than we've seen her before, and sober. Nikki looks over at Tess... then approaches. Ali turns away on her bar stool, respectfully.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode>SHEEPISH</mode>
      <context>Tess crosses her arms, and with a smirk on her face--</context>
      <utterance>I crossed the line.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again, and I wanna come home--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, again! Did you fill my spot or what...?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess and Nikki share a look.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nikki smiles, hikes her dance bag over her shoulder and heads</context>
      <utterance>Curtain's up in 20. Shake a leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I had a dollar for every time she's quit...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all fight. Bitch. Love and hate. And then make up. Just like sisters.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never had a sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me neither. THANK GOD.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now get your cute little ass and big ole' voice up on stage, cause this is Burlesque, baby girl, where the women are always on top, and the men like it that way. Like I've always said --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALI/TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't keep a good girl down.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
