<movie id="119" title="Cast Away">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RUSSIAN WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pretty. Who is it from?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMERICAN MAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We stay with the Driver as he ambles back toward the truck.</context>
      <utterance>My wife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My guess is we're talking fuel filters here, Fernando. The gas is dirty, these jitneys get in the mountains, their engines cut out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERNANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That could lose us half an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His beeper goes off.</context>
      <utterance>Easy. Each way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck hesitates for a moment, then looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>So it finally turned up...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll catch the sweep tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It took this test package thirty-two hours to get from Seattle to St. Petersburg, a distance of nine thousand miles. And then it took forty-one hours to get from our warehouse in St. Petersburg to here, a distance of, what --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEKSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six kilometers. Four miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a muttered chorus of answers.</context>
      <utterance>So how are we going to get this place shaped up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck leads his team through the sorting area. Yuri squeezes right next to him, ostentatiously carrying a clipboard. Chuck stops.</context>
      <utterance>There's only one way. We have to work together. Every one of us depends on everyone else. If one package is late, we are all late. If one truck misses the deadline, we all miss the deadline. Let's start by taking a look around.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hefts the package, as if trying to guess what's inside.</context>
      <utterance>Here, this table is too far from the wall. Packages can slip down...like...  ...this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sorter shoves the table against the wall. Yuri says something to the Translator.</context>
      <utterance>What could be in here? Let's say one of you sent it. Could be the closing papers on your dacha, could be a toy for your grandson's birthday, could be a kidney to keep your mother alive. I don't think you want your mother's kidney to end up behind a table.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSLATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wrong answer: Chuck glances sharply at Yuri. Aleksei appears with a cellular phone.</context>
      <utterance>He says they have been very busy. It is hard to get good employees. He is sure you understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEKSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck takes the phone, opening his BAG as he does so.</context>
      <utterance>Phone call. Malaysia.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out a set of blueprints and tacks them to a bulletin board as he talks.</context>
      <utterance>Kamal? Right. I'm getting them.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck keeps an eye on what is going on in the warehouse. Then he notices something over by one of the trucks.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking at the blueprints of K.L. right now. The belts are too small for the sorters. Yeah, sometimes you never see what's right in front of your face. Look, it's --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up the phone. He turns to the crew.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it! Hazardous material needs its own container!  -- three in the afternoon there, right? That gives you five hours until the sweep comes through. Do the sort by hand tonight, then put in a new feeder belt, say a twenty-four incher. Yes, overtime is authorized.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crew disperses back to work. Chuck and Aleksei walk toward the office. They've done this before. Chuck lets a corner of his command persona slip.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going out on every route, I'm going to work every job here, until I know enough to help you. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEKSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worse than Warsaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEKSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody remembers that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The failures they remember. It's the successes they forget.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sorted your packages before you left. None of the other drivers did. The Translator and Lev exchange a few words.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSLATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck looks at Lev with respect. Right answer.</context>
      <utterance>He says he wants to be organized. Do packages in order.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Translator asks Lev, who looks at him as if he is crazy, then snorts an answer. The Translator blushes.</context>
      <utterance>So how come the other drivers haven't left yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSLATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says -- he is a very rude fellow --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me exactly what he said.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSLATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck grins. Lev shrugs and says something else.</context>
      <utterance>He says why don't his farts smell sweet?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSLATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says that's just the way it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lev -- it's Lev, right? Listen, this is FedEx. We don't have to accept the way it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>No, keep trying. A circuit's bound to open up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waits. We hear an ANSWERING MACHINE.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Great. Try it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>This is not what Chuck wanted to hear.</context>
      <utterance>This is Kelly, leave me a message and I'll call you back soon as I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's stumbling over whether to say I love you.</context>
      <utterance>Kelly, damn, look, this is Chuck. I'm going to be a little late. Well, more than a little. I had to go to Russia. Couldn't be helped. Could you call and cancel the trip? Look, we'll sail the Keys in March. It's better then anyway. I'll be back before Christmas. I promise. I think. I mean, I will. I, uh --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gently hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I miss you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chucks looks at the clock.</context>
      <utterance>We've never got all the trucks in on time. Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one still left?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aleksei points at the big semi.</context>
      <utterance>Route six.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEKSEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pressure in on. Chuck looks around at his team.</context>
      <utterance>If we don't send it now we may miss the connection in Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it five minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures at a closed container.</context>
      <utterance>That's Bermuda. Bermuda is in the Memphis thru container. No, Azores is Europe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck is everywhere, setting the example. The whole office is energized, working together.</context>
      <utterance>The Paris container. Africa too. Japan goes to Memphis.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LEV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did it. All of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've heard this before. Lev holds up his hand just before Chuck does.</context>
      <utterance>Great job, everyone. Remember, work together. We are like a hand...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This makes Chuck smile.</context>
      <utterance>One finger, weak. All fingers working together, strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I absolutely, positively, have to get to Memphis overnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't help you. Try UPS.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack -- gotta be something wrong with our physicals, you keep getting certified to fly. Gwen, aren't you worried?</utterance>
   <speaker>GWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terrified.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on time, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck hands Jack and Gwen small packages.</context>
      <utterance>On time, Chuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another FedEx Road Warrior named STAN gets on. He and Chuck are obviously old hands at this.</context>
      <utterance>Little present from the emerging republics.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What connects the world? What makes it one?  We do. FedEx.</utterance>
   <speaker>GWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are such a lifer.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you expect, from the guy who stole a kid's bicycle when his truck broke down?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two of them strap in.</context>
      <utterance>Borrowed. I borrowed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd it go?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's finished a tough job. He's relaxed and on his way home. But Stan's his boss, and Stan's got bad news.</context>
      <utterance>Great. Terrific. The good guys won one for a change.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>I had to bump your plane last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You what?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The plane begins to taxi.</context>
      <utterance>It was fifteen minutes late.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I checked the weather, you had the jet stream, you could have made it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I might not have.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. I got it working... You have no idea how hard it was... They're finally a team...</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm touched.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fucked us over.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The point of FedEx, as I understand it, is to make the damn connection.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was making a point.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Let Paris hold its plane? Let Memphis take care of it? Let somebody down the line clean up your mess?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every person counts, every package counts, that's my point.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what your problem is? You just see the packages in front of you. You don't see the big picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baloney. I do see the damn "big picture."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know we had sailboats.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a ketch Kelly and I had chartered.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck doesn't look up.</context>
      <utterance>For all those vacation days you got coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And never take.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm sorry about your plane. But I couldn't risk being late into Memphis.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know General McLelland, he wouldn't attack unless he had everything just right. Finally Abe Lincoln came to him and said, General, if you're not going to use my army, could I borrow it for a while? So he gave it to Grant and Grant just said, let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm from Arkansas. Tell me a story with Robert E. Lee in it and maybe I'll pay attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're warriors, not desk jockeys. We've got to be bold. You always want all your ducks lined up. But nothing's 100 percent. It's always 60-40, maybe 51-49. Hell, I'd take 40-60. Then roll the dice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why you're a gambling man.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I'm running foreign and you're not. That's why you're not married and I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the third time.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan is so outrageous, Chuck can't help but laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Take the plunge, admit your mistakes, move on to tomorrow. That's FedEx, that's women, that's life.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are one sick fucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to help you here. There's Warsaw, there's this --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was nothing like Warsaw. I held the truck then minutes, it's not that big a deal. But apparently it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck reaches in his pocket, pulls out a bill.</context>
      <utterance>Look, that kids' bike, that's a guy who'll do what it takes to get there on time. Live up to your legend, that's all I'm saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hundred rubles St. Petersburg hits 95 percent in a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ninety five percent? Just give me the money now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk is cheap. Are we on or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck closes the PowerBook.</context>
      <utterance>We're on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both take out their Valium -- the price they pay for being such road warriors.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go off-line.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan puts on his Walkman.</context>
      <utterance>Two Valium...</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's their ritual. Chuck puts headphones from his Walkman over his ears, puts a mask over his eyes and leans his head back onto the headrest. We hear the Rolling Stones.</context>
      <utterance>And the Stones. Got to be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck pulls off the mask, takes out the earplugs. He manages a groggy grin.</context>
      <utterance>Chuck. Wake up Chuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta do your own delivery from here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But for a couple of fish floating on top of the tank it's too late. Chuck gets out his scoop and slowly skims them off.</context>
      <utterance>Damn thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I'm really sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of them gestures toward a door.</context>
      <utterance>You seen Kelly Frears?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Xerox machine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sonofabitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, be nice to it, it'll be nice to you. Surprised, Kelly turns to greet Chuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaps into his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Chuck! You're back!</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your eyes are puffy. Did you take Valium again?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks over at the Xerox.</context>
      <utterance>You smell like formaldehyde.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My last chapter's in there, and the damn machine's jammed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts up the cover.</context>
      <utterance>Let's take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was Russia?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't overwhelm me with details, you know how I hate that. Did you get it fixed?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pries up one feeder, then another.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got to follow the paper path here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Chuck doesn't want to talk. He's focused on the machine.</context>
      <utterance>Chuck, forget the Xerox. So Russia didn't turn out well?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls him out of the machine. He has toner on his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Used to you could fix these yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to say? That I thought I'd done a great job but it all turned to shit? That I might as well have gone sailing for all the good I did?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He suddenly looks really tired.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, tell me. Tell me all of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to the Xerox in frustration.</context>
      <utterance>You don't even know what time it is. What day it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>And I can't fix this damn machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She licks the last bit of toner off his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>We're on the deck of the ketch, the air's soft, the water's clear as crystal...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She ignores that, stays with the fantasy.</context>
      <utterance>That's carcinogenic.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she comes closer to him.</context>
      <utterance>We're covered with suntan lotion and sweat. Our skin is so hot, it's glowing...</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's really close now.</context>
      <utterance>We could take a swim.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They squiggle themselves onto the desk.</context>
      <utterance>On the other hand we could not take a swim...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why was Milan late, Colin?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colin continues as Chuck, out of breath, slips under the screen and heads for the one remaining vacant seat -- across from Stan. Next to Stan is MAYNARD GRAHAM, an MBA systems man. Becca addresses a question over to Stan.</context>
      <utterance>One of the race horses coming from Ireland got colic and had to be off- loaded in Brussels. That put the Jumbo 15, six hours late into Charles De Gaulle. Customs had difficulty locating the dutiable items...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stan, can we get P&amp;A down to work with Milan customs?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're already on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colin disappears. A red light goes on. Becca pushes a button. Another face comes on the screen. "Oakland" appears under the face.</context>
      <utterance>Good. And let's look at our live animal policy. I don't think the income stream justifies delaying IP product, especially at Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand by, Benson, we're still wrapping up foreign. She turns pointedly to Chuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck swallows nervously, tries to talk matter-of-factly.</context>
      <utterance>Chuck, thanks for joining us. Status?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Becca, as you know St. Petersburg was consistently running late by six to ten hours -- sometimes a full day or more. I replaced the station manager. We identified inefficiencies and worked out a quality improvement plan I believe can be met.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You replaced the station manager with a driver. A local with no knowledge of our systems.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't you have brought in someone from Memphis? Russia is priority one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The process is being ripped out of Chuck's hands. He struggles to get an answer.</context>
      <utterance>James Pottinger is available.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan is doing his best to back up Chuck.</context>
      <utterance>He's a numbers cruncher. Chuck's done all the right things here...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim's a terrific financial man, no question. But we can't always parachute in from Memphis. We've got to build up our local staff.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maynard knows how to go for the jugular. Everyone looks at Chuck.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to improve foreign on-time, that's what we've got to do. If this new guy's so good, how come the very first plane he sent missed the connection in Paris?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're building a new team here. We got every package on the truck for the first time ever. Success is the best teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't call missing the plane a success. Everyone looks at Chuck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas eve.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if you work for FedEx.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the b.g. one of the packages by the Christmas tree is starting to shake on its own.</context>
      <utterance>You break four million packages last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four four. A record.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't seem too happy about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, the staff meeting could have gone better.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck's attention goes to the tree.</context>
      <utterance>Let me guess, Russia came up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The package turns over, something darts out. It's a puppy, with a bow around its neck.</context>
      <utterance>One of those packages just moved.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck bends down to see the puppy.</context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A baby, she wants to say, but that's going a little fast so she catches herself. Chuck picks the puppy up.</context>
      <utterance>I figure, if we could take care of a puppy, we could, you know, take care of --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is a cute thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's your cute thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't even keep fish alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A puppy's got a little more personality than a fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And for you -- Chuck hands over his present.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly opens Chuck's present -- a very large box. It's a piece of luggage.</context>
      <utterance>So do good things come in large packages?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, for when you travel.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't believe it. It's the exact opposite of what she wanted.</context>
      <utterance>For when I travel?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck is flummoxed. Women read so much into things.</context>
      <utterance>You should have got me something that shows you want us to be together, not apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck's beeper goes off.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't sending a message. I though you'd like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He checks the number.</context>
      <utterance>You should have got me a ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go. I'm on call for overflow down at the Hub.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A ring. I wanted a ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. What to do?</context>
      <utterance>You did?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I love the puppy. I love you. But I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck picks up the puppy.</context>
      <utterance>You want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly is having one of those moments when everything comes clear.</context>
      <utterance>What should we call him? Or is it her? How about Jango?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't working out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're a little emotional here. It's Christmas, maybe we're over-reacting.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"We're" not over-reacting.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you watch Jango?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her the puppy.</context>
      <utterance>I can't take him to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is not a happy woman he is leaving behind.</context>
      <utterance>We'll talk about it when I come back. It'll all be fine. Really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to your pants?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck displays the puppy.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, meet Jango.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck hesitates just a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Chuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless us O Lord, and these thy gifts, which we are about to receive, from thou bounty, through Christ the Lord. Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's eat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's Kelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought you were going to bring her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So did I.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seemed like she had such a good time last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothing you did, Mom, believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jennifer's still down at the post office. And she's still got that crush on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she's still got those --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is an old, sore subject.</context>
      <utterance>You should have stuck around.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I help take care of the place. You got my check, didn't you Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That new roof, that's your doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops the turkey giblets into the trash.</context>
      <utterance>You're just allergic to farming, that's what dad said. Can't stand to be alone. Can't stand to be in one place. Can't stand the sight of...blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck can't believe this.</context>
      <utterance>Roger's going to put chickens in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mom goes to the freezer and takes out some frozen strawberries.</context>
      <utterance>Come on Roger, this is dad all over again. You already did beefalo, chinchillas, and what was that, ostrich? They chased Mom around the yard, sprained her hip.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't that bad, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't make a living out of this place. We tried.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But chickens?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty three pounds consumed per capita, up from twenty seven in 1960. Going to pass beef. Chicken's global. No religious taboos. You don't see your Hindus and your Muslims boycotting poultry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True enough. No sacred chickens nowhere, so far as I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mom mashes the block of frozen strawberries with a fork to separate the strawberries from the ice.</context>
      <utterance>Roger's working at Tyson's now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on down to the plant. It's state of the art. We're doing for chickens what FedEx did for the delivery business.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger grins at him. This is just how they are.</context>
      <utterance>Just don't count 'em before they hatch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try to remember that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all sit down. Mom brings the slushy frozen strawberries to the table, squirts on some Reddi-whip. Looks pointedly at Chuck.</context>
      <utterance>Dessert.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not a timely topic with Chuck.</context>
      <utterance>Speaking of hatching, I could sure use some more grandchildren.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, this is a farm. We've got real strawberries growing outside, we've got real cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck takes a bite, winces a little as the cold strawberries hit his teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no, the prodigal son's home. We bring out the store bought.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should take a few days off. Roger's working now, you could use some help around here...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you even think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The place is falling apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks pointedly at Chuck.</context>
      <utterance>I'm doing fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doing great, Mom, don't worry about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck finishes the drain pipe. Gives it a thunk with his finger.</context>
      <utterance>There's settled folks, and there's nomads. You're just not a settled folk. You never belonged here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on inside, Mom. You've had a long day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need the latest PDRs on St. Petersburg.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how was your Christmas?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, used to this.</context>
      <utterance>Terrific. Yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And get me in to the dentist. My tooth's acting up. Stan enters.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Malaysia's tanking. We're meeting in ten in operations.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.  Get me everything on Indonesia, New Guinea, all the way to Australia.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The box squawks. The TV screen rolls an imperfect image.</context>
      <utterance>Kamal? Kamal? Can you hear us?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Technician is fiddling with the TV set.</context>
      <utterance>Can't we get this working?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kamal, you're breaking up. Can you hear us?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>SQUAWK BOX</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kamal is not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this? Where is Kamal?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>SQUAWK BOX</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is Ibrim, I, I am a sorter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>SQUAWK BOX</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kamal is not here. We are very defused.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The squawk box hums and crackles. Nothing. Chuck turns to the Technician.</context>
      <utterance>Who's in charge then, where is Chinn?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got Telex, e-mail?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck turns to Leslie.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Just not getting any answers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's the next Jumbo?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The regular flight is scheduled for oh three hundred tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a sweep leaving Memphis in an hour, goes through Sydney.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should get your ducks lined up first. Chuck looks over at Stan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Stan is impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Call Operations. Get me on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's your dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's our dog. It belongs to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There isn't any us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly can't stay mad.</context>
      <utterance>Yes there is.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about the presents. I got a little carried away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it was great. Maybe a little overkill --</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's half-laughing, half-wanting-to-cry.</context>
      <utterance>I burned the Christmas tree.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you come over, get mad at me, tell me what a stupid bitch I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I hadn't thought through how I felt.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you were going to come over the next day all calm and say, Kelly that really made me mad? Don't tell me you're mad. Be mad. Be who you are right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, we'll do our trip as soon as I get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then it hits her.</context>
      <utterance>Don't even start.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get back? From where?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him for a long moment, then at the puppy.</context>
      <utterance>Malaysia. They're holding the sweep.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her the dog.</context>
      <utterance>Give him to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chuck, you're breaking my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A week, max. Okay? Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses the puppy.</context>
      <utterance>Go on. We'll be fine. I'll feed Jango to the frogs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Al -- gotta be something wrong with our physicals, you keep getting certified to fly. John, aren't you worried?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck settles into his seat.</context>
      <utterance>I disconnected his controls. He only thinks he's flying.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al has an Australian accent.</context>
      <utterance>You're on your way home, Al?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Down home, down under.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on time, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On time, Chuck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CONTROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jumbo 14 is overdue in Sector K.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another CONTROLLER tracks a giant computer screen.</context>
      <utterance>Where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONTROLLER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The signal flashes, but is strangely still compared to the others, which are moving.</context>
      <utterance>Somewhere east of Port Moresby. Guam is getting a signal but no location. Maybe the GPS is out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But now he is really thirsty. We WALK with Chuck up the beach. Beneath the palms he sees a couple of coconuts. He picks one of them up and studies it. It's heavy, almost the size of a volleyball. How to get in it? He throws it down on a rock. The coconut just bounces off. He wedges the coconut between two rocks, then throws a rock down on it. It bounces off. He throws down a bigger rock. It smashes on the rocks and chips. Chuck picks up the rock. OW! Where the rock had chipped the edge is sharp. It cuts him.</context>
      <utterance>Where the fuck are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blood stains the rock a bright red. Chuck sucks on his finger, then he gets an idea -- the same idea primitive man first got when he discovered stone tools. He picks up the rock, test the edge. Sharp -- really sharp. He throws another rock down, but it doesn't break. He picks up another rock and strikes the first one. Then again, harder. And again. A large flake shoots off. This edge is even sharper. He has a knife.</context>
      <utterance>Sonofabitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rotating a nut along its axis and carefully moving his fingers out of the way, he SMASHES the nut again. The shell splits! The precious liquid splashes out. Left inside is a swallow or two, which Chuck laps up eagerly. The milky white liquid dribbles down his face.</context>
      <utterance>That was smart, really smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clouds scud in front of the sun. Beyond the reef the waves are high and churning. Chuck can see them pound onto the reef.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe the GPS malfunctioned. That Korean airliner did.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, do the math. Maybe they know where you are within, say 500 miles. That's a circle with an area of, uh, pi r squared. So, uh, 250,000 times three point one four, that's about 800,000 square miles. Three times the size of Texas. This sinks in. Then Chuck gets an idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But even that doesn't give him much hope.</context>
      <utterance>They could use a satellite.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That sinks in.</context>
      <utterance>Say each satellite photo is 30 feet square, that's uh...fuck it...billions and billions of photos.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, someone will come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wants to say more, can't. He scoops some sand over the body.</context>
      <utterance>Got to cover Al up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scoops in some more sand. It's eerily like burying the tropical fish in his back yard.</context>
      <utterance>Got to cover Al up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks back, but that seems even scarier.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at the ocean beneath him, closes his eyes, and jumps. It's only a few feet, but he's breathing hard when he lands on the other side. He hugs the rocks, getting his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Got to get there. Got to see. C'mon... c'mon. Don't be such a wuss. Be bold.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck stares out to sea in every direction. Nothing.</context>
      <utterance>No way on. No way off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The last rays of sun hit his face. The ocean turns a deep reddish gold.</context>
      <utterance>This is bad. Really, really bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With his last strength he opens a coconut on the stick. He bangs hard on the shell and gulps down the milk. He stares at the stack of FedEx boxes. What could be inside? He reaches out and touches one.</context>
      <utterance>Got to drink. Got to drink something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Responsibility gets the better of necessity, and he takes his hand away.</context>
      <utterance>They don't belong to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With his finger, he prods around in the mucous-like meat, then tilts up the shell and we see the gooey gray stuff slide off the shell into his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Don't leave home without it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to spit it out. Tries to make himself like it.</context>
      <utterance>Yuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he swallow it.</context>
      <utterance>Yumm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Covered in sweat, desperate and exhausted, he throws down his wooden spade.</context>
      <utterance>Water, water, everywhere, water, water everywhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lies on his back, breathing hard. Pulls his hat over his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the water on this fucking island?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just rest a minute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He freezes, holding his spear motionless. Then he jabs at the crab -- misses! The crab scurries away toward the rocks.</context>
      <utterance>A crab, it's a crab.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck splashes after it, stabbing as he goes, falling, getting up, stabbing again. Suddenly one stab feels different. Chuck carefully lifts up the spear. On the end is a squirming crab.</context>
      <utterance>Dammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks carefully with it to the beach. Lowering the spear, he lets the crab slip off. It darts toward the water. Chuck heads it off, trying to avoid the snapping claws. He kicks it back toward the beach, then slams a rock down on it. He twists off a crab claw, expecting to see flaky white meat. But a crab has an exoskeleton. The flesh simply pours out, like mucous.</context>
      <utterance>I did it. I did it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is too much. He needs the next step, from the raw to the cooked. The crucial next step from primitive man to the beginnings of civilization.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He quits, exhausted. He looks at his hands. They are raw and blistered. He feels like Job.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid fucking thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what I did, God, but whatever is was, I am really, really sorry. You hear me? Really sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to rub again. He breathes hard, sweat pours off his face. He is really going for it, what the hell! A tiny wisp of smoke appears! Chuck saws with even more energy.</context>
      <utterance>Sonofabitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The smoke increases. Chuck rips away the bamboo, grabs the nest of shavings, and blows on it frantically. The smoke flickers and dies. Chuck can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No. No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gently places the nest of shavings in the kindling, then blows on it with utmost care, as if he were holding life itself. He shreds his money and business cards over the tiny flame. Suddenly, the evening breeze lifts the nest out of the kindling. Desperate, Chuck grabs it. Trying to shield it with his body, he grabs some palm fronds and jams them into the sand, trying to make a windbreak. They rustle and shake and blow over. The wind blows harder. Chuck jams some rocks in a circle to make an eddy. But the fire is out. No words now, just a loud, primal groan of pure despair. And then, into his vision floats...smoke. Chuck looks down. A wisp of smoke curls up from the nest of tinder! Chuck blows on it gently. Suddenly a tiny tongue of flame flickers and catches on the kindling!</context>
      <utterance>Careful now, careful...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He feeds in some more twigs, more tinder. The flames lick out, catch, grow.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! Yes! Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I ever forgot to thank you God, and I am sure I did, thank you now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck stares at them, stares until the ocean darkens and he can see them no more. It's late now. Leaving, he takes one last look, as he always does. And another remarkable sight greets his eyes. There, on the horizon, just below the evening star, is a...LIGHT. He stares at it, fixed.</context>
      <utterance>Beautiful. So beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But then he stares at it really hard.</context>
      <utterance>A star. It's a star.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...then slowly falls with a CRASH!</context>
      <utterance>Timberrr!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck holds his surgeon's saw over the stump. He walks to another tree and begins to saw his way into the trunk.</context>
      <utterance>I heard that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck sews several designer dresses together with needle and suturing thread for a sail.</context>
      <utterance>No more waiting. Take action.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cuts bamboo for the mast. He carves driftwood for an oar. He fills gourds with water, stores breadfruit and coconut as he sings "Fly Me to the Moon" to himself. He ties the sail to the mast and extends it with a bamboo boom lashed on with palm fiber and video tape. He ties on the doctor's kit and the FedEx box with the angel wings. He examines his handiwork: a finished raft. He brings out his old life preserver and puts it on, then grabs hold of one corner of the raft to pull it down to the beach. It doesn't budge. He tries to pull it again. Nothing. He leans his back into it and pushes with his legs. Nothing. He collapses on the beach, his breath coming in heaves.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. Take action.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bangs himself on the head, over and over.</context>
      <utterance>How could I be so stupid?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stupid, stupid, stupid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck's shoulders begin to shake, as he is racked with deep sobs of despair. And then he throws his head back and lets forth, from deep inside himself, a SCREAM of rage and anger and pain. The Scream pierces the indifferent natural sounds of the island, the rustling of the breeze, the lulling rhythm of the waves. It is powerful, disturbing, primal. The breeze picks up. Behind Chuck, the palm trees begin to sway. The tide is reaching up toward the beach. The waves crash louder. The palm trees sway even more. Chuck picks up some wet sand and rubs it on his body.</context>
      <utterance>You're too low in the water. Too damn low.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few DROPS OF RAIN begin to fall, splashing on Chuck and sizzling in the fire. Chuck looks up: clouds have obscured the sun. The wind blows harder. The rain falls harder, streaking the sand Chuck had rubbed on his body. STEAM sizzles out of the fire. Chuck looks up, disbelieving. The bottom falls out of the heavens -- monsoon rain, more rain than you have ever seen before. A long wave rolls up, its frothy fingers reaching for the fire. Forget the raft! Forget despair! The fire could go out! This is disaster!</context>
      <utterance>Dust thou art -- that's for damned sure -- and unto dust shalt thou return.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He springs into action. Chuck grabs an empty FedEx box. With his wooden shovel he frantically SCOOPS SOME COALS out of the fire as the rain HISSES and POUNDS at them. He slides the coals into the FedEx box, grabs some sticks of driftwood and sets off on a run.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stomps on the driftwood and saws at it with his knife. He places this kindling on the coals. They sputter and sizzle. Barely catch. He fans them with the box. A tiny flicker catches, then starts to grow.</context>
      <utterance>Please...please...please...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Firewood. I need firewood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His deepest instinct was to survive. And that is what he is going to do.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly he pulls himself back from the edge.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on. Just hang on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Wilson declines.</context>
      <utterance>Chips? Dip?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a big crunchy bite.</context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK as the sun goes down and Chuck reaches into the bowl again and dips an eel skin chip in the dip.</context>
      <utterance>Another fucking day in paradise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHUCK'S POV - SAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A SAIL is moving steadily away from the island.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Throws down the spear and waves his arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs into the water and starts to swim. He is so weak, however, he can only make a few strokes. He tries to yell as he swims...</context>
      <utterance>No! Wait! Come back!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Choking and weak, he turns back and drags himself up on the beach. In the b.g., the sail dwindles into the distance.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Wait!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes some charcoal out of his fire and draws eyebrows on the ball. Then, he mashes some berries, dips his fingers in the juice, and makes lips. He sticks shells on with clay for eyes. Then he looks at the face.</context>
      <utterance>You old airhead, you need a makeover.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits back and regards his companion. He gestures around the cave at the new paintings.</context>
      <utterance>Wilson, you bad!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Wilson doesn't have an opinion.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Idly Chuck takes down the Angel Box.</context>
      <utterance>You don't share much, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a long time he studies the wings on it. With a stick, he tries to draw a similar wing on the dusty floor of the cave. Dissatisfied, he wipes it away. He looks at the Angel Box. Casually he reaches over and cuts it open with a stone knife. Inside he finds two bottles of green salsa. And a letter. He reads over it.</context>
      <utterance>I guess I know how Kelly felt.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Visibly moved, Chuck puts down the letter.</context>
      <utterance>You said our life was a prison. Dull. Boring. Empty. I can't begin to tell you how much that hurt. I don't want to lose you. I'm enclosing some salsa, the verde you like. Use it on your sticky rice and think of home. Then come home -- to me. We'll find the spice in our lives again. Together. I love you. Always. Bettina.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I'm hoping that if this is airtight I'll get condensation down here, a cup or so a day. If I'm careful it should be enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I never return, know that here lived Chuck Noland for four years. I drew these paintings. I made these marks. And then I took my fate in my own hands and set forth to save myself, God willing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wilson, my main man. Time to go. And he gently leads the raft into the lagoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps onto the raft, begins to paddle out toward where the surf crashes onto the reef.</context>
      <utterance>Wonder what odds Stan would give me on this. I'd say 90-10. Against.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exhausted, he sinks back to the raft. Two Dorados leap into the air ahead of him. Chuck tries to stare again into the water. He spots another fish, a flash of silver under the surface. Chuck struggles to his feet, raises his spear. SPLAT! Something strikes him in the chest, almost knocking him into the water. On the raft we see flashes of silver and green and blue. A FLYING FISH. Chuck dives at it, catches it, loses it.</context>
      <utterance>Slow down, damn you!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He catches it again just as it almost flops over the side.</context>
      <utterance>Catch it catch it catch it --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Save some for tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BadChuck wins. Chuck keeps eating. He stares up at the sun, which beats down unmercifully.</context>
      <utterance>Catch another fish tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! Shit! Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay calm, identify the problem. Problem, rope fraying. Solution, fix rope.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With what? There's nothing to fix it with. This rope comes undone, you're going to drown.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOOD CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just get up and fix it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feels so good to lie here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck comes to his knees. Then sinks back down.</context>
      <utterance>Get up, damn you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't. Need water.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've had today's water.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirsty.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, shape up, get going, you can do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck tries another tack. Sweet reason.</context>
      <utterance>No water, no work.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay look, I know you're tired, I know you're thirsty, but give it one more shot, you've just got to do a little more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do too much, I'll die.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do too little you'll die.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That stops GoodChuck for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Going to die anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the pathetic little jar with its few teaspoons of murky water.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, look have an extra swallow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more water, you said.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it, damn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly Chuck gets up, lifts up the water jar, and takes a swallow. Then another.</context>
      <utterance>Wilson, do you believe this? Take the damn water.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then another.</context>
      <utterance>Stop. Enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets an idea, starts to pull the signal kite in.</context>
      <utterance>Think. Got to use something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they can't see you, what's the point?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kite rope is much thinner than the rope he had used to tie the logs, but it's all he has. He ties the log with the kite rope. Exhausted, he lies back down.</context>
      <utterance>Survive today, that's the point.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Polaris, where are you? Maybe I'm too far south.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know where you are. You missed the shipping lanes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the fraying sound again.</context>
      <utterance>Moon's too bright.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're putting off the inevitable.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the deteriorating rope, at the rotting sail.</context>
      <utterance>I'm putting it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck pushes the outer log away, then takes the loose rope and begins to lash it around the center logs.</context>
      <utterance>That's what's happening to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The raft is rocking. The waves are stronger. It's hard to tie the logs together. Rain falls like a sheet on Chuck.</context>
      <utterance>You're rotting away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get water!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fix raft first.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck works frantically in the rain, trying to tie the rope. Finally he does. Then he scrambles for his water collecting funnel, struggles to pull it up. One corner is stuck and collapses. Desperately he rights it, pulls the funnel up. Drops begin to run down the sides and collect in the jar. Soaked, Chuck stares at the water as it rises. Then the rain stops. We see the line of rain recede away from Chuck, spattering the ocean. But all around him the ocean is calm again. And out comes the sun.</context>
      <utterance>Water water water --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Very slowly it drifts along with the raft.</context>
      <utterance>You like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We look right into the whale's eye. Beneath the surface we can see the huge jaws open and close.</context>
      <utterance>Lost your mate?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're beautiful. Marry me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Very slowly the whale moves ahead of the raft, its vast body passing Chuck.</context>
      <utterance>You idiot, if he dives, he'll capsize the raft.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck rips a fillet off the line and throws it in front of the whale, which ignores it.</context>
      <utterance>No, don't go. Look, I've got fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whale slowly sinks, then suddenly arches its huge back and heads straight for the bottom. For a moment, all that remains are the flukes, black and vertical against the dark blue sky. With one swoop, those flukes could destroy Chuck and his raft. But they don't do anything except slowly sink. Then it is gone. We are on Chuck's face as he stares at where the whale had been, the surface marked only by a ring of concentric ripples that reach out and gently rock the raft.</context>
      <utterance>Please don't dive. Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't kill another one. Can't. Can't kill my friends anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fucking bleeding heart, you kill or you die.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do they have to die for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck listens. Doesn't hear anything.</context>
      <utterance>They'd eat you if they could. They're laughing at you. Listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck picks up the spear, stabs it, misses. Suddenly he has a fish on the end of the spear. It struggles, he scoops it onto the raft, brutally pounds on its head, twists the stone knife into its spine. The struggling stops. Chuck looks at the dead fish and begins to sob.</context>
      <utterance>Got to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cries uncontrollably. As he cries he cuts off the head, pulls out the eyeballs, and eats each one. Then he sucks the marrow out of the head. Then takes the heart and eats that. Then eats the liver. As he is chewing, he cuts the meat into strips. When he is done, he takes the backbone, breaks it, and sucks on it. Fish scales shine in his hair, blood covers his chest.</context>
      <utterance>I am so sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he sees other lights. A ship. A ship is out there. And he hears it, a humming in deep register. He waves his hands. He yells.</context>
      <utterance>I'm an angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice cracks, we can barely hear it over the ocean. The lights move on.</context>
      <utterance>Here! Here!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His raft is rocked by the wake, rocked hard. Chuck is thrown into the water! He comes to the surface, sputtering. Where is the raft? He looks one way, then another. Darkness. This is the worst. He turns again in the water. There, dimly, he can see the glow from the fish he killed. The glow saves his life. He swims toward it. He pulls himself back on the raft. He lies there exhausted, the glow from the phosphorescence casting a greenish light on his face.</context>
      <utterance>No...no...no...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his oar and begins beating the water. The killing continues.</context>
      <utterance>Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the water is still. One dolphin sticks its head out of the water and stares at Chuck, squeaking. Another dolphin lifts its head up, then another. They squeak to each other, clearly communicating and talking about Chuck.</context>
      <utterance>You fucking murderers!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dive, then jump into the air, squeaking as they go.</context>
      <utterance>I know you're talking about me! He splashes the water with his oar.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're gone.</context>
      <utterance>Take me with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Why me? Why me, God?</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to this, Wilson.  Because you piss me off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tries to do another pushup. Can't.</context>
      <utterance>You're falling apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First you eat your fat, then you eat your muscle. He rolls over.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the ocean. They're in a line of garbage, a thick slick of debris dumped off of ships.</context>
      <utterance>Then you eat your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes his eyes. After a minute they come open.</context>
      <utterance>Roll on you deep and dark blue ocean roll.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm late, I'm late, for a very important date. They slowly close again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm lost. Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes come open again.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, just slip off the raft. The ocean would feel so good, the water's so soft and warm. Take a little swim. Sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You quitter you quitter you quitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sea is lovely, dark and deep.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I have promises to keep.  And miles to go before I sleep.  And miles to go before I sleep.  Got to fix the sea anchor. Use the sail.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Use the sail for a sea anchor and you won't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I don't have a sea anchor I'll capsize.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hums Beethoven's fifth. BA BA BA BUM.</context>
      <utterance>Die tomorrow or die today.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's death knocking, knocking on your door. Crazy little woman come knocking, knocking at my front door...</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grow up, stop being such a baby. Other people get through a lot worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hums to himself, begins to sing, Beatles.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls in the loose sea anchor rope, which is covered with barnacles. He scrapes the barnacle off the rope into the water jug, then sips it. The sun is setting, huge rays shoot out across the sky. Out of the empty ocean the Dorados suddenly appear, leaping flashes of silver right by the raft. One Dorado swims right by the raft, broadside. Chuck looks at it, uncomprehending. Then slowly reaches for his spear.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so tired, my mind is on the blink...</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carefully he comes to his feet, then shoots the spear into the fish. Flapping and struggling, it lands on the deck. Chuck pounces on it.</context>
      <utterance>What? Are you sacrificing yourself for me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The banging continues.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it! I had to do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He concentrates on his work, then sits back on his heels in amazement. There's another fish inside. He holds that fish up, stares at it, then cuts it open. There's a smaller fish inside it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pops out an eyeball, then another, and crunches them between his teeth. He takes the heart and liver, starts to eat, then stops.</context>
      <utterance>I know there's a moral here, God, but right now I'm just going to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He struggles to remember.</context>
      <utterance>Forgot to say grace. Sorry Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless us O Lord, and these thy gifts and Christ and the bounty about to receive, or something...amen. He eats them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck picks up the smallest fish. It's half digested. He washes it in the ocean, trigger fish come up and nibble at his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Please don't leak. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cuts the small fish and hangs it on the stays.</context>
      <utterance>Don't look at me. It was that Dorado.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Wilson, every now and then we should say thank you. Thank you God.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly something bumps the raft. Hard. Then again.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for fucking up my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fins cut the water. SHARKS. A big hammerhead bumps the raft. BadChuck hums the theme from "Jaws." Chuck takes his spear stabs at the shark.</context>
      <utterance>Not again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another one circles in, bumps the raft.</context>
      <utterance>He's going to get you, going to get you...</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The shark circles again, that big hammerhead like a nightmare.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from me!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stabs at it with his spear. He might as well have stabbed concrete. The shark circle, Chuck stabs again. But the shark is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Get him get him get him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stabs again and again at the empty ocean.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you? Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck kneels, wavering, on the raft. The ocean is calm. Suddenly, BUMP. The raft tilts. Chuck hangs on. Then a shark appears, just out of spear range. Its lifeless black eyes seem to stare right through Chuck. If the Dorado was a gift from God, this is a message from Hell. Then the shark is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! You're using energy. Move slowly. Be patient.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you smiling about? They'll be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at the thought.</context>
      <utterance>I'm dancing on the roof of the Peabody Hotel. With Kelly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The music ends. We go back to the table. The waiters have brought dinner. New York Strip with Bordelaise Sauce. Mushrooms in brown gravy. Roasted potatoes with garlic and rosemary. Green Beans with almonds. Fresh biscuits and cornbread, dripping with butter. A nice salad with ranch dressing. A jumbo shrimp cocktail. Thinks about that, it spoils the picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes his eyes. This is the greatest fantasy.</context>
      <utterance>No shrimp.  We eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck thinks over the options, thinking of each one.</context>
      <utterance>For dessert, we have pecan pie a la mode, we have a double chocolate cake with creme anglaise, we have a nice pear torte, fresh key lime pie, or perhaps if you care to wait a few minutes, a grand marnier souffle?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rolls over. There, square in his vision, is a ship, its form coming in and out of a low haze. Chuck jumps to his feet. Waves. Screams.</context>
      <utterance>Why, bring them all, bring them all.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ship moves on. We can see the decks the rigging, the vastness of it. Chuck realizes he is naked. Struggles to pull on the remains of his pants finally holds them like a diaper with one hand as he continues to wave. On the ship no one is to be seen. It is a spooky sight. The big tanker moves on. We are on Chuck's face. Passed up again. Then he realizes what is about to happen. He throws out the sea anchor. He throws himself onto the raft and grips it as tight as he can, wiggles his feet into the ropes.</context>
      <utterance>Here! Over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then comes the wake of the ship. It rocks the raft like a piece of flotsam. The raft rides high up on the wave, then shoots down it, but the sea anchor holds, and the raft slows and rides along with the wave. And then the sea is calm again. Slowly Chuck sinks to his knees. His hand lets loose his pants. He lies down on the raft and imagines the conversation with the ship's captain.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shiiiittt!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Permission to come aboard, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK/CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Permission granted.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I ask, where are you bound?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK/CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>San Francisco. And you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As it happens, I'm headed for Frisco myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK/CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you do us the honor of joining us? We're just sitting down at mess. Pork chops and gravy, cranberries, baked potatoes with all the trimmings, fresh- baked bread, apple pie...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The depression comes back again.</context>
      <utterance>No please, join me. Some sundried fish strips, a few eyeballs, some gills to munch on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're never going to see you. You're just another piece of trash in the ocean.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're on autopilot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're always on autopilot. Or else it's night, or you're in the sun, or you're in the trough of a wave. They'll never see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck picks up Wilson.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it! Don't be so negative!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds Wilson close to his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Wilson, what's your story?</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I float. You sink. End of story.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. I'm always going on about me, me, me. Enough about me. Your turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a fucking soccer ball, you idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We move up until we see --</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. He lies on the raft and holds Wilson close.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the other Chuck begins to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Don't shirk, don't procrastinate, don't be lazy. We're okay today. We're okay today.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The laughter goes on.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands up and checks the horizon.</context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up! I mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so damn funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Chuck sees something on the horizon. A bank of clouds. A cone of -- land. He squints, stares again. The clouds part. It looks like -- his island. Chuck doesn't know whether to feel joy or despair.</context>
      <utterance>You are.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck squints.</context>
      <utterance>Look again, asshole. It's a mirage.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's real.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing out there but ocean.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck picks up the soccer ball, holds it up, and stares out at...ocean.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get a second opinion. Wilson? What do you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits back, looks at the mock headstone.</context>
      <utterance>Chuck Noland. Born October 8, 1958. Died -- pick a date -- July 11, 1998. And now the epitaph. Met deadlines. Kept appointments. Lost without a trace.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did it matter if FedEx was five minutes late one day? The next day we just start over again.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It matters. We do the best we can, that's all we have.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes on writing.</context>
      <utterance>Then we've just got shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am writing this to remind myself to live a better life. If I am lost, perhaps you who find this will be instructed to live a better live yourself. Live each day. Love your children. Don't take anyone for granted.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waves begin to grow, the ocean turns a slate gray. Far above him, great frigate birds circle. Suddenly one dives on a booby which has caught a fish. The great frigate bird swoops all around the booby until, panicked, it drops the fish, which plummets toward the sea. With a graceful dive, the huge bird grabs the fish and then soars up on a thermal, high into the sky. Lightning flashes back and forth across the horizon, which is turning black and dark. Thunder rolls.</context>
      <utterance>Is that it? Life is a fucking Disney movie?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BADCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODCHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up. I don't feel like dying today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he dives in to the water! Swims frantically after Wilson. Wilson floats away from him. He swims, but he's so weak. Finally he gets to Wilson. He reaches out, but only pushes the ball farther away. It bobs on the waves. Chuck treads water, exhausted. Where is the raft?</context>
      <utterance>Please, no sharks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he turns back the other way. The raft has drifted by him. He can go after Wilson, or he can go after the raft.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Jesus. Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swims toward the raft, barely moving. No matter how hard he swims, the raft seems to recede from him. Finally he reaches it, hangs on the side, breathing hard, choking, crying. He struggles to pull himself on board. But he is weak, so weak. He can't do it. Summoning some primitive reserve of strength, he tries again. This time he slides on. He lies on the raft, panting. Then with all his strength he pulls himself to his feet, holds on to the mast, scans the ocean for Wilson.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! Wilson!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is too much. Chuck starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Wilson! Nothing but waves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My favorite doctor. What's the verdict?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He checks his blood work records.</context>
      <utterance>Under the circumstances your overall health is good. Those salt water boils you picked up on the raft are ulcerated, but they're healing nicely.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck has been trying not to laugh. Now he can't stop himself.</context>
      <utterance>Hemoglobin's 10.8 -- you're anemic, that's why we're giving you iron. Potassium's low -- we're giving you an electrolyte solution with your IV. Sodium's over 150, way too high. You may experience swelling in your extremities as you rehydrate and discharge the salt. In spite of your dietary deficiencies there's no sign of mental deterioration.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck can't seem to help laughing at everything.</context>
      <utterance>What's so funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry...sorry... Why do my joints still ache?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dehydration. Vitamin deficiency. Protein deficiency. Any or all of the above.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I ate was fish. That's solid protein.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Protein digestion is very costly in water usage.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which I didn't have.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck laughs again.</context>
      <utterance>And fish are very low in fat, which is energy inefficient. So you're going to burn up your own cells no matter how much you eat. Luckily you ate the eyes and pancreas, which contain some Vitamin C, so you didn't get scurvy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am one lucky guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your body chemistry and your exposure to the elements would normally lead to irritability, depression, anxiety, periods of self-reproach. It's almost like schizophrenia. Different sides of your personality might come to life, speak out, act out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to laugh again.</context>
      <utterance>But all that's behind me. I'm fine now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you say you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I most definitely say I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck stifles his laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Hegel tells me he discussed the Vietnam POW syndrome with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are aware of the potential disruptiveness on your loved ones when you return to your old life?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The laughter again. Unsettling.</context>
      <utterance>Not to mention on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you don't want some counseling? Chuck gives his biggest smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc, I'm not on the island. I'm not on the raft. I'm alive. I'm so glad to be back, I can't tell you. I just want out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, when that IV runs out, you're through with us. Just the dentist tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Chuck is overcome for a moment, can't say a word.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>For some reason he can't keep himself from laughing. He covers the mouthpiece and laughs. And then we hear a dial tone, harsh, mechanical, final.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The laughter again.</context>
      <utterance>Stan, it's Chuck...Chuck Noland...</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever you are, you are one sick fucker. And again we hear the dial tone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a long silence. Then we hear Stan's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Two Valium and the Rolling Stones. That ring a bell?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God damn! God damn! Chuck, it's you!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're fucking dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck begins to laugh, a little too loud, a little too shrill. He's on a high.</context>
      <utterance>I'm most definitely not dead. And as I recall, you're the sick fucker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck shakes his head: no. She scrapes behind his front teeth.</context>
      <utterance>You sure you don't want to have the implant done here? We do quite good work.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck opens his mouth even further. The technician talks on in the self-absorbed way dental technicians sometimes do, that constant babble of human contact which Chuck has not heard for four years.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmm, you do have such a lot of tarter behind these front incisors. A little wider, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck nods. I follow you.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway, so the second prosthetic foot worked better, but he still couldn't drive his new Cortina, it being a standard shift, if you follow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck does. Stan bursts into the room.</context>
      <utterance>But would he hear of me driving him around? Not on your bloody life. Rinse please.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck struggles out of the chair.</context>
      <utterance>Chuck! God damn!</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are both almost overcome. Stan holds Chuck by the shoulders and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>God damn. God damn. God damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck laughs, thrilled to see Stan.</context>
      <utterance>You're alive, you're fucking alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beat the odds!</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You beat 'em to shit, pal! Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan notices the technician.</context>
      <utterance>I still need to floss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He says this with an absolute straight face, holding back the laughter with great effort. Instantly there's this connection again between him and Stan.</context>
      <utterance>This is Amber. Her boyfriend lost his foot in a shark attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ex-boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he and Chuck make eye contact and we see a glimpse of their shared unspoken irony.</context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck stares sharply at him. Kelly? Stan nods, but there's something he wants to say.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, there's somebody out here who wants to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's not all Stan wants to say. But Chuck is limping out the door.</context>
      <utterance>She thought you were dead. We all did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck is happy, he's still riding the high.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...hey...it's okay!</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, maybe a little, but who cares? He hasn't been hugged or barely touched in so long.</context>
      <utterance>You're so thin. Am I hurting you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She disengages, looks at him with that old smile.</context>
      <utterance>No...no...feels good...</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right back, you said you'd be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He meets her gaze, looks her over with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>A few things came up. Or went down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He notices the ring on her hand.</context>
      <utterance>You look...wonderful. I like your hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got married.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you might have.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would never --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'd known you were alive --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His responses come so quick. Chuck seems blissfully sure of himself.</context>
      <utterance>I would have done the same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to. It just happened. One day Gary was there. He took care of everything. He took care of me. I was a mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly nods.</context>
      <utterance>You have any children?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly fishes for a photo, shows it to Chuck. It's a little girl with a dog.</context>
      <utterance>Got a picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her name's Hannah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Jango?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, this is Jack. Jango was hit by a UPS truck. Can you believe it? Chuck laughs. It is funny, sort of.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan appears, takes in the scene. The few patients waiting are edged into the corners, trying to look occupied with something else.</context>
      <utterance>Life's just one big joke after another.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about we go somewhere else?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to see my raft?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="47">
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This stinks really bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan examines the ropes around the logs.</context>
      <utterance>You should have smelled me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool ropes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I braided them.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must have taken a hell of a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly points at something on the raft.</context>
      <utterance>Time I had lots of.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's not feeling sorry for himself. It's just a fact.</context>
      <utterance>That's my sea anchor. My second one. Made it out of part of the sail. It keeps you from capsizing in a storm. In theory.  And this, this I used to collect water. About half a cup a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were how long on this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at the tiny raft. It speaks for itself.</context>
      <utterance>Forty-three days.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All that time I waited to go on a cruise, and you went without me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly notices the sail, sees the writing on it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well...couldn't be helped.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that, written on the sail?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly reads it to herself. Her eyes are moist.</context>
      <utterance>My epitaph.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he seems really to believe it.</context>
      <utterance>Bad body chemistry. Made me a little morbid. But I'm all over that now.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be at the car.  Take you to the airport.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This interests Chuck to no end.</context>
      <utterance>I buried you, Chuck. They had to pry my fingers off your coffin.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a coffin?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, coffin, headstone, the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your calendar, your cell phone, your whoo pig sooey hat, some pictures of that ketch you wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That about sums it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe now's when you tell me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plane went down. My friends died. I washed up on an island. Then I found these barrels, built the raft, and here I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The tide came in, the tide went out. I survived. That's the headline. I survived.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to put it into words, isn't quite sure how.</context>
      <utterance>Don't overwhelm me with the details.  You know how I hate that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Try.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Live each day like it's your last.</context>
      <utterance>Cliches, mainly. Don't take anyone for granted. Don't sweat the small stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So simple to say, so hard to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks down at the raft. It's so small.</context>
      <utterance>Not when you have no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hated being alone. Couldn't stand it. Busy every minute. Always plugged into something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has something more to say. She waits.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't know what really being alone was. No one back here does.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's the point, isn't it? We are social animals. No man is an island.</context>
      <utterance>We're not meant to be alone. Not like that. Share life, that's what came to me out there. Be with someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is so unfair.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the laughter comes again. Kelly grins, embarrassed, a little worried.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I told the fish I caught. But I ate them anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at his face, reaches out, touches it again, this time with great tenderness. He nods, her touch feels so good. A wave of emotion comes over her: pity? love?</context>
      <utterance>Great. Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What will you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a distant beep-beep, discrete as a car horn can be.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I really don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah's babysitter has finals.</context>
      <utterance>I've got to get back to Memphis.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means a lot...that you came.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to come. To be sure you were okay. They hold each other. For a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Chuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck grins.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad you're alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she heads for the waiting car. Chuck stands by his raft, watching her go.</context>
      <utterance>You too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I first showed up, I thought you'd lost your fucking marbles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan pulls a flask out of his bag.</context>
      <utterance>I never thought it would end. Then it did. It was so great to be saved, I couldn't stop laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan takes two glasses from his bag, rests them on a FedEx container, and pours the whiskey.</context>
      <utterance>You need a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan hoists his glass.</context>
      <utterance>For years my only drinking buddy was a soccer ball. Wilson.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To Wilson.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now's when Stan gets to the question he's been wanting to ask, that Kelly wanted to know, that we all want to know.</context>
      <utterance>To Wilson.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>So, what's it all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been over the line and you came back. You've been saved, hallelujah!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan looks over at him.</context>
      <utterance>Hallelujah.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. The burning bush, the big picture, the words in neon...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it all about? It's about being so thirsty you'd crush a fish's backbone to suck out the spinal fluid -- that's what it's about. Stan sits back, repulsed but relieved.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours another drink.</context>
      <utterance>Do what it takes. That's what I always told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To life. Fuck 'em if they can't take a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To life.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all there is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a sip of his drink, just savoring it, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>Believe me I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All those things Stan used to tell him.</context>
      <utterance>But it's not being bold or being in the game or rolling the dice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was going crazy, on the raft, I'd argue with myself about everything. Because everything had a price. To get anything -- a sip of water, a little corner of shade, an hour's sleep -- I had to let go of something else. And then I could never get it back. He thinks some more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't win or lose. You win and lose. He looks out the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Chuck has. Big time.</context>
      <utterance>You win and lose.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Chuck waves. He's overwhelmed by all the input. Stan steers Chuck down the steps as the cheers continue. At the bottom of the steps Roger steps forward. The two brothers embrace each other. After a moment Roger disengages. Mary gives Chuck a hug.</context>
      <utterance>Wave.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Chuck --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waiting for you. At the farm. This was too much -- He looks around at the crowds.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan nudges Chuck. Time to go to the podium.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan and Chuck head for the podium. All the loaders and operators and package scanners begin to applaud. Chuck smiles, then laughs, getting into the emotion. He keeps up an almost indecipherable babble underneath the cheering. Occasionally he sees someone he knows.</context>
      <utterance>Glad you made it, big brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Thank you. Great. Thank you. Hey, Rasheed, how you doing? Thank you all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps to the microphone and addresses the SuperHub.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome home.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is an extraordinary moment. And it should be marked in an extraordinary way. With something we have never done since this company was founded.  Stop the line!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STEELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he talks, we stay on Chuck, who is taking in this amazing scene, not really listening.</context>
      <utterance>Four years ago we placed this plaque in honor of Charles Noland, and two just like it in honor of Al Morris and John Durham, the two brave pilots who went down with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the plaque to Chuck. Chuck acknowledges the cheers of the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Chuck endured years of hardship and loneliness. Like Lazarus, Chuck has come back from the dead. Chuck, this is your family, all of us. So it gives me great pleasure...to take this plaque...and to present it to our long lost son. Welcome home.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone applauds.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Thank you very much...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs, a short brittle laugh, composes himself.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a minute. I've spent four years looking out at an empty ocean.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over at the hub.</context>
      <utterance>It's all so -- big. You never think you'll miss -- all this. But I did. I really, really did. And I missed all of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points at some high tech equipment on the edge of the shed.</context>
      <utterance>You've added some new belts, and what's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Digital laser readers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around at everyone, doesn't know what else to say.</context>
      <utterance>Digital laser readers. Wow. Terrific.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tension is broken. Everyone laughs. Phil Steele motions with his hand. Let it be done.</context>
      <utterance>I've never heard it this quiet. Shouldn't you all be getting back to work?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what it's about.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swerves into another lane.</context>
      <utterance>Being patient. Don't rush things. I get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Live it.</context>
      <utterance>Not just that. Take your time. Use it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins, cuts across to the exit.</context>
      <utterance>Deep, real deep.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck stares at him. Are you kidding?</context>
      <utterance>So where to? The office? The hotel? The beach?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deliver this package. Then, I dunno.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want that delivered, we'll deliver it. That's what we do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right.</context>
      <utterance>Finish what you started. You haven't changed, Chuck. It's still you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to help, help me find the woman who sent this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. After three years the PTR reverts to tape storage, which is okay because we access it through the CPC. Here it is.  Ten packages from the same sender. Baku. Delhi. St. Petersburg. The guy was a real road warrior. This package was Kuala Lampur. No activity in his account after this package. No forwarding addresses after K.L.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the sender?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He works some keys, waits.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Bettina Peterson. Marfa, Texas. Let's run a current check.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. Durango, Colorado; Asheville, North Carolina, then...canceled her account.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you find her?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking at a Level III search. For your Level III, you gotta have E-4 authorization. I don't have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out a badge.</context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to pull up the data.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's let it rip.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. For everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sweat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress sets a plate down in front of Chuck, turns to watch. On the TV we see an Australian correspondent standing on Chuck's beach.</context>
      <utterance>And here's more from Dingo Dodd, our Australian correspondent, on the extraordinary story of Chuck Noland, the modern Robinson Crusoe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DINGO DODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck is staring at the screen, seeing his cave, seeing all those years.</context>
      <utterance>Shark infested waters! A deserted island! Surrounded by reefs! Accessible only by helicopter! For four years Chuck Noland survived here alone, eating fish, coconuts and clams, his only companion a soccer ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>DINGO DODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress looks over at Chuck. The other clients look at him too.</context>
      <utterance>I'm now in Chuck's cave where he passed the lonely nights, painting on the walls like some prehistoric caveman. What did Chuck feel? These paintings tell the story, but only Chuck knows what they mean. And he's not talking. On the screen we see a photograph of Chuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress comes over.</context>
      <utterance>Check, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck looks down at his doodling. Hesitates. Then signs his name.</context>
      <utterance>No charge, honey. But could you just sign that place mat for me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When'd you start working here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger got me on. I wasn't doing anything, and -- but you're back, you're really back. I would have come to Memphis, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to come here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck gestures, no, I'm full. She puts down the spoon.</context>
      <utterance>Have some more potato salad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around the house, everything in its place. His mother has been here for forty years. There's a big crack running down from the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>That was great, Mom, just great.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got all this back pay coming. Why don't you let me get you a place in town?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She studies him for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>This is my home. I'm part of the wallpaper.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does, but that's not it entirely.</context>
      <utterance>You miss it, don't you? You miss that island.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him. She knows her boy.</context>
      <utterance>Miss that island? Mom, come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a journey you've had. It seems more than a person should have to bear.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, thinks about this.</context>
      <utterance>The tide saved me, Mom. I lived by it. I'm just wondering where it will take me next.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember the family motto. In time. It will come to you, in time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman stares in disbelief at the package she hasn't seen in years and never expected to see again.</context>
      <utterance>FedEx for Bettina Peterson.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck displays a FedEx badge.</context>
      <utterance>Where did you get that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bettina notices Chuck's bicycle.</context>
      <utterance>Charles Noland. FedEx Special Projects.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came on a bicycle? No wonder it's so late.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bettina stares at the package, her own memories coming back.</context>
      <utterance>There was an unavoidable delay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I have to say, I'm impressed. You never gave up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds the box and studies him for a long moment. Something -- the look on his face, the extraordinary reappearance of this long-lost package -- makes her curious.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what happened to this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As much as anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to come in? Get dry for a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lets Chuck in the door.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smile awkwardly at each other. She starts to open it.</context>
      <utterance>It's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. Feels like it might have gotten wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Possible. So you did those wings?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. A long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're harder to do than they look.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? You've tried?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's opened the package. She pulls out the bottles of salsa and the letter.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I do a little drawing --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our apologies that it never made it to the recipient.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment where neither knows what to say.</context>
      <utterance>He was a sorry sonofabitch, and I'm sorry I ever married him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes start to register recognition. She glances at the magazine with Chuck's picture on it. She picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>You look familiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truly.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe this. I -- I -- They are... You're a gifted artist. You're into something very powerful. Primal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, not really, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck thinks about that. After a moment, he grins.</context>
      <utterance>You are. Yes you are.  What gave you the idea to paint on that cave?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To tell you the truth -- you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you...have any more packages to deliver?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. that was the last one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuck sits back on the couch, taking in the sight of the ocean in the light rain. He looks over at all the canvases, the easel, the palettes. The wind rustles the palm trees around the house. The surf crashes and rustles. Familiar sounds. Island sounds. He relaxes a little. Maybe the package with the wings was a sign, he kept it all these years precisely for this. Then there's a sound of a truck in the driveway. The engine cuts off. There are steps on the porch. The door opens. A tanned muscular MAN in neatly kept work clothes comes in, hangs a tool belt on a hook by the door. He looks at Chuck with a relaxed, even stare, as if seeing a man in a FedEx uniform sitting on his couch is not an unusual occurrence.</context>
      <utterance>Just sit here, I'll get us some lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Man nods at Chuck, goes into the kitchen. We are on Chuck's face. Who's this? We hear muffled laughter from inside.</context>
      <utterance>In here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't even have to bring us a package.</context>
      <utterance>Come back anytime. Coffee's always on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bettina hands Chuck a sheet of paper.</context>
      <utterance>That was my last one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The list of paints and brushes I did for you. He takes it, not exactly sure he wants it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep painting. Promise me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need some help?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet I do. High tide comes right up to this road.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, thanks. I'd never have got that out by myself. Looks at his uniform. At the bike.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not out of Pascagoula, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where is he from, anyway?</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to drive one of those. A long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, once a driver, always a driver. You want a lift? I've just got one more pickup.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up his bike.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Chuck Noland.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER/ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robinson Crusoe.</context>
      <utterance>I knew it! You're a legend! Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smile at each other. Then she smiles a little more.</context>
      <utterance>I knew I recognized you. My name's Erica.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you really steal a crippled kid's bicycle to make your deliveries, or is that just some bullshit story?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't steal it, and he wasn't crippled.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that makes Chuck laugh, really laugh, for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Otherwise it's completely true.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks over at him with a grin.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, completely.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What brings you out to the sticks?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had a package to deliver.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You? Personally?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had it on the island with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a connection building here, effortlessly.</context>
      <utterance>Must be a story there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, a long one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got lots of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The truck goes down the beach and then turns inland, away from the ocean. Away from all that.</context>
      <utterance>So do I.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>And we pull back, taking in the sweep of the beach, the estuaries, and the green forest stretching back into America. The end is the beginning.</context>
      <utterance>So do I.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
