<movie id="133" title="Cobb">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON PIPE IN ASHTRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smoke curls. A man's hand picks it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON MAN'S HAT AND COAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>on a coat rack.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON WASTE BASKET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Overflowing with crunched-up paper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sighs, and turns.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The muse has not descended, Lucille.  The muse has not descended.  God damn it, Lucille, you hear me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The muse has not descended.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucille is a longsuffering saint.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! The muse has left me stranded here like a beached whale -- only one phrase, one word, from finishing the greatest essay I've ever written! One word, the right word -- Flaubert called it 'le mot juste' -- I ever tell you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Le mot juste' -- the exact right word the writer needs to tell his story. Yessir, you've mentioned it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hemingway, Faulkner, Joyce -- they all searched for 'le mot juste' until they cried, until they bled...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yessir.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this essay about again?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fishing.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean what is it really about?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said it was about the quote unquote primal issues of survival, man against nature, etcetera -- that's what you said.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohyeah... so... we end the essay with...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Lucille types it out.</context>
      <utterance>'The tarpon leaps shimmering into the late cross light of the keys, a primeval moment frozen in...  ... frozen in'...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shimmering tarpon -- very good, Mr. Stump...  ... 'frozen in' what?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PHONE RINGS -- Lucille answers it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Lucille, that's what the Muse will tell me if she ever descends.  ... 'frozen in'...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump's cavalier attitude stops cold. He starts to reach for the phone, then stops.</context>
      <utterance>Yes? Yes? Just a minute, I'll see if he's available.  It's your wife -- are you and she speaking again?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. How does she sound?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump is suddenly a nervous wreck. He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Don't ask me to interpret.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her... tell her... I'll talk... no... tell her I'm out -- I'll call her later...  God damn it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up. The mood has shifted.</context>
      <utterance>Apparently he's out, Mrs. Stump -- I'll have him call you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump?</context>
      <utterance>What about 'le mot juste,' Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck 'le mot juste,' Lucille! Finish the damn thing yourself. 'The primeval moment is frozen in' whatever the hell you want it to be. Did you know that James Joyce let his secretary -- none other than Samuel Beckett -- revise and edit Molly's solliloquy in Ulysses? You're my Beckett -- I give you 'le mot juste!' Just get the damn thing in the mail so I can get paid.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump reaches for a beat-up pogo stick which leans against the wall in his office.</context>
      <utterance>Problems with the Mrs.?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs his hat and coat and we begin hearing the number one hit song of 1960, PERCY FAITH'S schmaltzy recording of "A Summer Place."</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I need a drink.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump addresses the sportswriters at the table as if they were a small audience in a lounge.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Stumpy...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright, awright... how do you get five old ladies to say 'fuck?'</utterance>
   <speaker>CRONIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, I dunno, how? Etc...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump laughs. The others groan. REYNALDO, 40's, black, speaks up. He's one of the regulars.</context>
      <utterance>Yell 'bingo.'</utterance>
   <speaker>REYNALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I got one --  A drunk is taking a piss in front of a bar, a bus drives by, real fast right along the curb, and knocks his thing off. Drunk picks up his thing, puts it in his pocket, goes into a bar, reaches into his pocket and puts his thing on the bar. 'Look't that,' he says, 'bus knocked my thing off.' Bartender says, 'that ain't your thing -- that's a cigar butt.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>REYNALDO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Everyone roars, even Stump. But Frank, as usual, is hyper serious and never quite gets into the revelry.</context>
      <utterance>Drunk reaches into his other pocket and slaps another thing on the bar. 'There,' he says, 'bus knocked my thing off.' Bartender says, 'you're drunk and that ain't your thing either. That's another cigar butt.'  Drunk looks down at both cigar butts and back up at the bartender and says, 'God damn it, I mushta smoked my dick.'</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amidst this levity, gentlemen, I have some real concerns. Mark my words, people will look back on this year and say that 1960 was the year that Western Civilization began its downward trajectory.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need to get laid, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys, guys, c'mon... do you really think things are as good as they used to be? You think Jack Kennedy is qualified to be President?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kennedy may not be qualified, but -- Jackie's a babe -- and that's good enough for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>REYNALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Every man nods in solemn agreement.</context>
      <utterance>They're a happily married couple and that oughta stand for something these days...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speaking of being happily married, Al, are you and your old lady still having problems?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, the wife and I are all patched up -- doin' fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRONIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good to hear... awright... way to go, Stumpy...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean look at us -- we call ourselves writers but we just watch ballgames and get drunk a lot. You call that writing?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the department store of life, sports is the toy department -- so what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, besides, Alan here's writing a serious novel, aren't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well I haven't started yet but I'm gonna. I've been busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are pathetic. Ya write for one reason -- a paycheck.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More art was created for money than for passion. Take your platitudes and shove 'em, Frank. I'm gonna write a novel too, someday.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Great American Novel, I suppose?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could come from my pen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a barbershop writer, Al -- you write sugar-coated pieces for guys to skim when they're waiting for a haircut!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump raises his fists as if to fight; Frank responds.</context>
      <utterance>Awright, that's it! Let's go! Settle this right here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A scuffle breaks out, a lot of posturing, feinting, but they're all too chicken to do anything. Nobody wants to fight. A PHONE RINGS at the bar. The bartender answers the phone, shouts at the obnoxious sportwriters.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>REYNALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump goes to the phone, interrupting his own "fight."</context>
      <utterance>Stump! For you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump grabs the phone, covering an ear to hear better.</context>
      <utterance>Phone call saved your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... yeah... who?... no... you're kidding?... when? Stump hangs up the phone and turns. His face registers shock, or more precisely, bewilderment and wonder.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They do, and give Stump their ruffled attention.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...  Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cobb wants to see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cobb who?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This news instantly sobers the room.</context>
      <utterance>Ty Cobb! How many Cobbs are there?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ty Cobb? I thought he was dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet. He said he wants to tell me the real story of his life before he croaks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were just talking to Ty Cobb?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This impresses the hell out of everyone in the room. Even Stump is still a little dazed.</context>
      <utterance>The Georgia Peach himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say Cobb is crazy. The meanest sonofabitch who ever lived.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard he killed a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe so, but -- he was the greatest baseball player of them all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRONIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank suddenly is cautionary, concerned, paternal.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, the best, no one close, etc...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Al, be careful --</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't gettin' my ass shot, don't worry...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not that -- the story.  This is like Ivan the Terrible inviting somebody into the Czar's palace before he died.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except Ivan was a nicer guy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let Cobb bullshit you. This is your shot. This is all our shot.  When does he want to see you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Immediately.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NEWSREEL NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Onscreen (B&amp;W) -- Cobb as a young ballplayer followed by images of Cobb's famous batting stance, Cobb clowning, etc.</context>
      <utterance>This 1905 cameo of an 18-year-old youth shows a peaches-and-cream complexion and the piercing eyes of a lad who would become, etc...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His reputation as being difficult at best, psychotic at worst, preceded him. But if there was one thing I knew after all my years as a journalist covering politicians, celebrities, and sports heroes, it was this --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Onscreen (B&amp;W) -- Cobb in action -- His demon fury gives way to the fierce joy of his playing. He slashes a ball up the alley, turns first and never hesitates at second, and as the relay comes into third --</context>
      <utterance>The 'facts' -- and public perception of those 'facts' -- frequently bear little resemblance.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Cobb slides with spikes high and a cloud of dust. There is something thrilling and terrifying in the image.</context>
      <utterance>One thing was beyond argument -- he was the most brilliant athlete of his time... perhaps of any time.  I was determined to find out who was the real Ty Cobb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>First drops of rain begin hitting the windshield -- Stump hits the wiper button and the floppy blades begin ineffectively wiping the windshield. Stump struggles with his vision.</context>
      <utterance>Driving into the Sierras at night with winter coming on wasn't the smartest decision I'd ever made but it seemed better than being late for my first meeting with Cobb.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fill it up and replace the wiper blades.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colder than a witch's tit, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I hate skiing.</context>
      <utterance>It's just starting. We got three- four feet of snow another thousand feet up. Where ya going? Skiing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I'm going to meet Ty Cobb.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cobb?! He stopped here for gas once, I asked him for an autograph for my boy and he told me to shove it where the sun don't shine.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump heads to a pay phone as the attendant replaces the wiper blades. Stump's breath hangs heavy in the air. It's cold. Freezing. He drops a set of coins in the call box. He blows on his hands and pulls up his collar -- he wasn't prepared for the weather to be this cold. He comes to life when he hears a voice on the other end -- a voice we never hear.</context>
      <utterance>I hear he's got a way with kids...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a CLICK.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, baby, it's me...  Al... your husband...  I'm up in the woods somewhere on assignment...  Listen, sweetheart, listen -- nobody can love you the way I love you and I want you to take me back. I made a mistake.  Okay, lots of mistakes. I know I'm not worthy.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flicks the receiver hook several times. She's gone.</context>
      <utterance>Honey? Sweetheart? Baby?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man whirls and is shocked to see Stump standing there with his own suitcase.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, Mr. Cobb, I have too much dignity to spend another moment with you. I hope you die before the sun comes up and may you rot in hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie bursts out into crazed laughter, as if the world of Cobb was finally too absurd. Cobb and a writer? In this weather? In any weather? And the man walks through the rain, laughing, heading on foot down off the mountain as Stump just stares. Stump turns and steps into the open doorway.</context>
      <utterance>You mean he actually found somebody to take the job?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man looks at Stump and points upstairs without speaking. More CRASHING sounds from upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Cobb?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The silence is shattered by a SCRATCH, then VIOLIN MUSIC from upstairs. STATIC suggests a record is playing.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Cobb?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GUNSHOT RINGS OUT -- Ripping through the door. Stump is terrified -- he gasps for air.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Mr. Cobb?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump turns and creeps back toward the stairs, but -- ANOTHER GUNSHOT RINGS OUT -- SHATTERING a hanging LAMP. Stump freeses one more time. Silence. Then the voice --</context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much, Mr. Cobb, but I don't need this job that bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Stump -- you do need this job that bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you are a hopeless romantic and only a moderate success.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I am the most successful sportswriter in America and not merely a 'moderate success.'</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.  Give me those pills over there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an invitation to a testimonial dinner at the Baseball Hall of Fame in Cooperstown, New York. You're taking me there -- when is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the great ones will be there -- The great Mickey Cochrane will be there! Hornsby, Sisler, Ott, the Waner Brothers... we used to have some parties, Stump, I'll tell ya that right now...  We can't forget.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't forget.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at me closely, Al...  Lie after lie has been written about me -- my whole life I've been misunderstood.  You're gonna tell the real story of Ty Cobb.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb climbs slowly out of bed. His words are reasoned and not without passion.</context>
      <utterance>What's the 'real' story?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why you're here.  See, there's two kinds of writers. The kind that spin endless yarns about small subjects... that's you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or... there's the kind with one great subject that consumes them forever.  That could be you. Because I am that subject. Cobb hobbles to a table in front of a window. The table is covered with pills, bottles, needles, and booze.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmmmm...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a small oil company near Bakersfield called Honolulu Oil, sitting near the Elk Hills Reserve...  I want you to buy all the stock you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honolulu Oil?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump crosses and stands behind Cobb, sharing the view.</context>
      <utterance>Getty is expanding in the west, looking for companies like that. I got a hunch...  Stumpy, c'mere... Cobb picks up the revolver and holds it lovingly.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can take that buck. What'ya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb smiles and loads the revolver. He pushes the window which swings slowly open.</context>
      <utterance>With a pistol? No way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like hell you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right behind the ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're full of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jameson?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Mr. Cobb said he got him, then he got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb stumbles back into bed, somewhat exhausted by the ordeal.</context>
      <utterance>You have no vision, Stump. A writer without vision is a waste of my time. I think I picked the wrong man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Jameson exits the room.</context>
      <utterance>And I think I better get back to San Francisco before the storm hits. I'll take care of these transactions, Mr. Cobb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'll be leaving as well, sir, since you think I'm the wrong man for the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Stump -- we both know that I'm your meal ticket.  We need each other.  And we start in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb reaches over and defiantly turns UP the MUSIC so that the room is overwhelmed with Kreisler's violin. Stump stares back at this decrepit, overpowering figure. Cobb gradually slips into sleep, buried in the music, the booze, the pills, the pain...</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready, Mr. Cobb.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chapter one, Page one...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Know ye that a prince and a great man has fallen this day.' Stump types it out, then stops.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what Robert E. Lee said at the burial of my grandfather who was a Confederate General killed at Fredricksburg.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'm taking notes?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell no. That's the first line of my autobiography.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't writing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's horseshit. It's a third person comment about someone who's already dead. An autobiography has to be in the first person -- plus it can't come from the other side of the God damn grave.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My story can come from any damn place I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not to mention you can't call yourself 'a prince and great man' -- that's for the world to decide.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of a fucking writer you call yourself -- all tied up in rules and regulations. What's the point being a writer if you can't say what you want to?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM! A SHOT RINGS OUT -- Stump types quickly, hunting and pecking with two fingers, reading aloud.</context>
      <utterance>You're not treating me like a writer -- you're treating me like a stenographer.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know ye that a prince and a great man has fallen this day...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has a certain ring to it...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it does.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb checks the tape and suddenly is deep in thought over some information coming across. Stump types.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you might like it. It's yours, a gift from me.  'Cobb, a prince among men, misunderstood in his genius, as genius always is' -  This is the second line from what will be the greatest biography of a great man ever written -- type it!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb grabs a phone and dials -- Then barks into the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Bethlehem Steel's about to dive.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb slams down the phone, momentarily lost in finance.</context>
      <utterance>Jameson. Bethlehem's going in the toilet. Dump it all!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a stock tip for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... buy Coca-Cola. We're about to go out in cans.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb just stares back in disdain. Then, suddenly -- Cobb starts coughing terribly. He clutches his torso as if it were about to fall into pieces.</context>
      <utterance>Coke in cans? I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what's wrong with Ty Cobb?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every disease known to man -- I got 'em all! And they'll never get me in a hospital -- never!  My heart leaks -- the doctors who are nothin' but a buncha hacksaw artists give me Digoxin to keep it pumping... Cobb grabs a bottle of Digoxin pills and flings it across the room in a rage. He flings bottles of pills as he recites his ailments.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb grabs a hypodermic needle and awkwardly pours from a bottle into the chamber. Insulin spills as he does.</context>
      <utterance>They give me Darvon for the cancer in my back, they give me Tace for something eatin' up my stomach, Fleets Compound for an infection in my bowels, Librium for my tension, insulin for my diabetes...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jams the needle wildly into his arm without hesitation.</context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' insulin...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PHONE RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>And if all that wasn't enough, it's been two years since I got my pecker in the air...  The South may not rise again but my dick will.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump answers the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't here!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cobb's residence... hello.  He's not here -- who's calling? Ernie? Ernie who?  My God...  It's Ernest Hemingway... for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump covers the receiver nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him to go to hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, Ty, this is the great American writer -- this is the man who inspired me to become a writer!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him to go to hell anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Him and me used to be pals but we went on a hunting trip once and he hired a shitty guide.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb looks at Stump with a fierceness that is so over- whelming, so physical, that Stump melts.</context>
      <utterance>That's it? You didn't like a guide he hired?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump is terrified. He reluctantly uncovers the receiver.</context>
      <utterance>You tell him to go fuck himself or I'll kick your Yankee ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb settles into a chair, letting the drugs and pills and booze work their way into his thick body.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hemingway? Mr. Cobb says... to go to hell.  By the way I'm a big fan of yours -- CLICK, a hang up.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb rubs his head -- The drugs are taking effect.</context>
      <utterance>Hemingway isn't a bullfighter -- he wrote about bullfighting. What the hell is that?!  Bullshit... Damn painkillers...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ty, you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll pass...  Stumpy, listen to me -- you know what I need?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a woman.  A woman is definitely what I need...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Stump lights a pipe as he walks up a trail, away from the lodge, toward a ridge, all covered with snow. The flurries of snow are getting thicker now.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't be around the man for long without needing a break, which his painkillers gracefully provided.  My sanity would soon depend upon a frequent breath of fresh air, a walk in the woods -- any escape from what one sportswriter had called 'Cobb's brooding soul that bubbled with violence.'</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Stump stops at the ridge and looks down at the partially frozen Lake Tahoe in the lingering light.</context>
      <utterance>I knew most of the Cobb stories -- first man elected to the Hall of Fame, ahead of the incomparable Babe Ruth. Statistics that haven't been approached in three-quarters of a century.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'd known boxing champions and football players -- they were gentle souls outside the arena.  How much of Cobb was an act, a lifetime of theatrical intimidation to preserve his own legend?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Stump continues walking down a crest of snow, through a stand of snow-covered pines. The light is dark, purple, eerie, and Stump is lost in thought, until, suddenly, he sees: A trail of blood in the snow. He follows it down a slope, past a tree, growing deeper, thicker. And there it is -- The buck lies dead in the snow in a pool of blood. Stump stops in fear, then approaches, leans down and examines --</context>
      <utterance>Legends grow in time. Tough guys are tougher, women more beautiful, routine acts of self-preservation become heroic.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The buck's head has a hole blasted behind the ear. Stump rises quickly to his feet and looks around. The woods are silent. Snow falls from a branch. And... He hurries back through the woods up the ridge, momen- tarily lost as the snow swirls, he finally spots the lodge.</context>
      <utterance>My God...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to Reno. I want a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a blizzard out there!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When a man wants a woman, a man wants a woman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just put on some soup, build a fire, and we can work on the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't let it out of your sight.</context>
      <utterance>How cozy.  I got 25 thousand in cash and negotiable securities in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Ty, the roads are impassable.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lead, I'll follow.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not driving in this stuff!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a woman!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump is caught between fear and rage.</context>
      <utterance>Get off the road -- ya can't drive any faster?! Move it!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you! I ain't dying in this God damn ice cube!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump plows his way on foot down the embankment, fighting bad footing and snowdrifts, until -- He arrives at the car -- Surely nobody could survive this. With difficulty, he makes his way to the back door of the huge car and wrestles it open. Stump sticks the top half of his body into the car.</context>
      <utterance>Cobb!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb lies upside down, ass in the air, his face buried under the dash of the car. There's blood on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Cobb?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about fucking time you got here!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb struggles to right himself, twisting and turning free.</context>
      <utterance>You've alive?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump helps Cobb back out of the car. It is an awkward, clumsy, difficult task.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't call it living but it'll do. Help me outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's blood!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course there's blood! I just put my head through the windshield of a car, what the hell ya think, ya big fucking jerk.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ty Cobb can't die like this! They'll bury me and nobody'll know who it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump drags Cobb awkwardly through the snowbank back up to the highway. When they get to the edge of the high- way, Cobb stops to stare at the tire tracks leaving the road.</context>
      <utterance>I said shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look't that! No guard rail! I'm suing the State Highway Commission, I'm suing the Governor, I'm suing every God damn body!  I coulda been killed!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blizzard swirls around the two men, now at Stump's car on the highway.</context>
      <utterance>God damn it, shut up and get in the car!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme your keys, I'm driving.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm driving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hell, no! I'm driving.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know how to get to Reno?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb pulls a gun from his overcoat pocket and aims it right at Stump's head.</context>
      <utterance>Over my dead body!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your call.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb smiles. He loves it when someone stands up to him. He thrives on confrontation.</context>
      <utterance>You miserable son of a bitch. You coward, you pathetic, frightened, desperate old man -- you can't do anything without that gun and frankly it doesn't impress me to keep flashing it because I know you're not gonna shoot me 'cause you need me worse than I need you. What, you're gonna kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've killed a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb hands the gun to Stump.</context>
      <utterance>Fine, then put me outta my fuckin' misery. I'm freezing.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump holds the gun awkwardly, not knowing what to do.</context>
      <utterance>Here ya go, Stumpy. I like a man who stands up to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now give me the keys. I'm driving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only another hour -- plenty of time to tell you my story before we find us some women.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Women? Plural?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some for you, some for me. We'll have a helluva time. The broads're probably lining up right now, waiting for ol' Ty and his buddy Stump.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Cobb launches in as he accelerates down the mountain, every curve risking death. He seems at peace with the world -- in the driver's seat, literally, on the edge of being utterly out of control.</context>
      <utterance>Dear God...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose you want to know about my childhood. Writers usually do.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of this 'know ye that a prince and great man has fallen' stuff --</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Cobb drifts into a story of his youth. He's suddenly so relaxed that he pays little attention to the road.</context>
      <utterance>My philosophy is simply this -- Life is too short to be diplomatic. A man's friends shouldn't mind what he does or says, and those who are not his friends, well, to hell with 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was born in a small town in Georgia, of course... my sweet sister Florence still lives there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother was the most beautiful woman in the county... she married my father when she was twelve which was the way they used to do it.  And she taught me to believe in the hymns we sang... I especially liked the bloody ones...  'And sinners plunged beneath that flood, Lose all their guilty stains...'</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember after I was baptized and I was walking home with my pals...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The boys skip rocks and start across a trestle bridge.</context>
      <utterance>I was feeling very Christian, ready to live the good life -- my father didn't drink, smoke, gamble or chase women -- and I wasn't going to either --</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... when all of a sudden a train was coming at us.</utterance>
   <speaker>POV SHOT - TRAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>headed right for the boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There I was, a newly baptized child of God who hadn't hardly sinned, and I was gonna die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father died in a terrible accident, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't, really...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you do your research on me before you came up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't have time... I mean, I knew the basics.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you've read that I'm the meanest bastard of them all?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People have said that, yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care what people think.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why do you care what I write?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am who I tell you I am! Why are you making things so complicated?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what writers do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well writers oughta make things simple! Everything's complicated enough as it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you're right!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I'm right! Stump suddenly looks up and shouts in terror.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A snow-covered truck in the middle of the road, broken down and abandoned, is on top of us.</context>
      <utterance>Ty!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb spins the wheel -- The car spins out of control, just missing the truck, and hurtling on down the icy highway.</context>
      <utterance>Godddddddd!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump is in sheer terror by this time.</context>
      <utterance>Don't shout like that, Stumpy -- it just increases my tension. I saw that truck all along -- you think I'm gonna hit a truck when I'm getting close to finding me some women?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father was murdered, y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father was murdered?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean that's the sort of thing you're looking for, isn't it?  Murdered on the balcony of his own house... the house I grew up in...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father was murdered? How come nobody knows about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The oldtimers in Royston know about it. Nobody else's business. It happened when I was 17, a few days before Detroit called me up.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this helps explain why -- He catches himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why I'm such a prick? Ha!  That's too easy -- you're a better writer than that --</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was the killer ever caught?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was an arrest, a trial, and an acquittal. Nobody was ever convicted.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Single to left, steal second, steal third, steal home...</utterance>
   <speaker>GAMBLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAMBLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb tosses some money on the pile, and climbs up the dugout steps, shouting.</context>
      <utterance>You're on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell ever signed you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAMMATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb laughs -- He seems to feed on these exchanges, and he stands in at the plate, addressing the UMPIRE.</context>
      <utterance>Go to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Cyclops, you're missing a good game.</utterance>
   <speaker>UMPIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Cobb digs in, he reaches into his back pocket and drops something on home plate, in front of the CATCHER.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Cobb.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Catcher holds up a pair of women's panties.</context>
      <utterance>Here ya go...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your old lady left 'em in my car last night -- I thought you could give 'em back to her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going down, Cobb.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pitcher delivers a fastball right at Cobb's head -- He hits the dirt just before the pitch arrives (and this is long before players wore protective headgear). Cobb rises, laughing defiantly.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Cobb shouts at the shortstop, a large German-American athlete, the great HONUS WAGNER.</context>
      <utterance>That's as hard as you can throw?! Shit, it that was my fastball I'd wear a dress!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wagner doesn't budge, comfortable in his position, not drawn into Cobb's taunts. Stoic, implacable -- far from Cobb.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Wagner! I'd shade me a little up the middle if I was you!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You try to take my head off then you throw a sinker away, in and out, same old shit -- sinker away...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Krauthead, I'm coming down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON WAGNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just nods.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PITCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Here comes Cobb with a recklessness beyond reason. And as the pitch arrives in the Catcher's hands, the Catcher digs in to take on Cobb -- Cobb slides spikes high, flying above the earth, his back leg slashing his spikes like knives. It is a slide of utter defiance and violence, a slide intended to harm. A vicious collision between Cobb and the catcher -- blood and dust. The ball rolls free. Safe. Cobb and the catcher immediately start punching and in seconds, a brawl breaks out, both benches clearing. As the police rush out to break up the brawl...</context>
      <utterance>nods, winds up, and as he does --</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In those days you didn't hold hands and dance with the men on the other teams. They were the enemy -- you fought with 'em.  And I was the most hated man in baseball.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb tips his hat and speaks easily to the fan.</context>
      <utterance>I hate your guts, Cobb!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The police escort Cobb to right field -- the roar of the vitriolic crowd increases.</context>
      <utterance>A good day to you, too, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Cobb in right with the cops -- the crowd on its feet, booing so loudly that the air is all one giant, wailing moan of hatred.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know what it's like to be booed like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It feels wonderful! They couldn't live without me! They came to the ballpark to see me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON MAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb puffs on a cigar defiantly as he reads his hate mail.</context>
      <utterance>Cut-out letters read: "COBB - YOU'RE DEAD"</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty thousand fans trying to kill me everywhere I went!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I loved it. Only great men are booed. Captains of industry and presidents. I knew 'em all...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After World War Two, General Patton asked me for an autograph -- he said he patterned himself after me!  Are you getting this?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why aren't you writing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb's tone changes suddenly -- he questions Stump with- out guile or anger, as if his answer is obvious.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause I'm trying to have a good grip on things when this car goes over the next cliff! I ain't ready to die yet!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb stares at Stump, waiting for an answer, and forgets about the road. Stump looks up in fear and points at the road.</context>
      <utterance>But neither am I.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb swerves wildly back onto the road, such as it exists in the blizzard.</context>
      <utterance>Ty!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said I'm not ready to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then watch the fucking road.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're not listening to me! I may have every God damn disease known to man but I am never going to check into a hospital because I am alive and I am going to get laid in Reno!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna get laid, too, Stumpy!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I don't wanta get laid!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You queer?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm married.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were divorced.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>problem. We're talking.</context>
      <utterance>We're in the middle of a...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talking my ass! Quit hanging on -- get a divorce. Is that why you don't wanta get laid in Reno? 'Cause you're feeling loyal to a woman you're divorcing? That's really stupid, Stumpy...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not getting a divorce. I'm being loyal.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump is nailed.</context>
      <utterance>Is that why you used to wine and dine that little brunette who had an office across the courtyard from you in Santa Barbara?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know about her?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do my homework, Stumpy. I know where the bodies are buried.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't last long!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, no need to defend yourself. When it comes to women I'm a total shit -- the difference is, Stumpy, that I know I'm a shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody knows about the brunette.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our little secret, huh?  And that part about me being a shit with women? That ain't gonna be in the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta put your family in my book.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your book?! My book! And nothing about my ex-wives or children are gonna be in it. My book is about baseball!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My book is about Cobb!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cobb is baseball!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb brakes -- the car spins to a stop some distance past the figure standing knee-deep in snow.</context>
      <utterance>Stop the car!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever it is he's gotta be pretty stupid to be out in this shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Stump climbs out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>We're out in this shit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FIGURE IN SNOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help me. Please help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is Willie, the black man who Cobb fired the day before.</context>
      <utterance>My God... it's you. Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode>FIGURE IN SNOW</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you found me...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me help you to the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you that you'd only last one day with the bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie stops trudging toward the car.</context>
      <utterance>Cobb's in the car. He's driving.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Cobb's in the car?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'm not getting in the car with that son of a bitch. I'd rather take my chances out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Stump drags Willie to the car, though the man is re- luctant the whole way, he is in no condition to resist.</context>
      <utterance>You're coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hates me. He hates black people...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He fucking hates everybody. Don't give him the pleasure of dying out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get to the car -- Stump opens the back door to help the nearly-frozen man into the car. Cobb grumbles.</context>
      <utterance>If dying out here gives him pleasure then I won't die out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ty, it's Willie. We can give him a lift to town.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit! I ain't givin' no nigger a ride nowhere!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up and give him a ride!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump hands the gun to Willie.....</context>
      <utterance>Now who's the coward! You won't shoot me! You need me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie climbs into the back seat with the gun. Cobb is livid.</context>
      <utterance>No. But I'm sure Willie would take great pleasure in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll pay for this, Stumpy...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, Willie, you a baseball fan?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yessir...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the greatest ballplayer of all time, in your opinion?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Willie Mays, no doubt about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That nigger couldn't hold my jock!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Mr. Cobb, the man is speaking...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'd say the second greatest player of all time is Jackie Robinson... or maybe Josh Gibson...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And of course, the greatest base runner of all time isn't riding in this car -- the fastest baseball player of all time was Cool Papa Bell -- Cool Papa would've easily broke all your stolen base records --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noooooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool Papa was so fast that when he entered a hotel room and flipped the light switch off, he'd be asleep in bed before it got dark...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then there's Satchel Paige...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, Satchel Paige could throw a porkchop past a wolf, Mr. Cobb, ol' Satchel woulda had you eatin' outta his hand, he woulda had you hittin' .220 and kissin' his black ass to boot...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut this man up!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man with the gun does the talking, you wretched, old prick...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WOMAN IN WIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand back, you old farts. I'm in the middle of something --  The heat's on the blink and the mattress is lumpy -- I want a discount.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, c'mon, you always want a discount, Mona.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode>WOMAN</mode>
      <context>Cobb pulls out a bottle of pills and washes a handful down with a deep swig from a pint bottle of whiskey. The Clerk looks on with alarm.</context>
      <utterance>Ra-mona... and the mattress is always lumpy --</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, I've gotta get him checked in. He's very sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whirls and leaves the lobby, leaving the three men.</context>
      <utterance>We're all sick in the eyes of God -- but some of us still have manners.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two rooms, next to each other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb reaches into his pouch and pulls out a bundle of cash and security notes, tied neatly with a string.</context>
      <utterance>His face looks terrible, drawn, drained.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My money...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your money's okay, Ty, right here...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My gun...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Stump hands Cobb his beloved pistol, which Cobb takes with great affection and comfort. Stump helps Cobb into bed, covering him with a blanket. The gun and the money sit on the pillow next to his head. Cobb speaks with great pain just before he passes out from pain, drugs, and exhaustion.</context>
      <utterance>Your gun's okay, too... right here...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We haven't missed the testimonial dinner, have we?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we haven't missed the dinner...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb manages a small, pained smile before drifting off into sleep. Stump turns off the light and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Good, good...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours another drink, and sits down to his typewriter.</context>
      <utterance>Omigod, what can I say? I feel terrible -- no, it's not okay, jeez... When I get off the road we'll do something special -- a late birthday, eh? Maybe you can go to spring training or something with me, eh? Yeah...  Listen, is your mother there?  I know she doesn't want to speak to me, but I want to speak to her.  Okay, okay -- I feel terrible about the birthday... I'll call you real soon. And tell your mother I'm not drinking anymore. Okay... 'bye, 'bye... Stump hangs up the phone -- Takes a deep breath, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump is hunkered over his typewriter pounding away. His VOICE OVER indicates what he is writing.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck it...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was a fool for thinking Cobb's brilliance might be what I needed at this moment of my life... Ty Cobb was the last thing I needed.  He was not misunderstood -- he was understood perfectly well. He hated blacks, he hated Jews, he hated Catholics -- he hated everything except himself and his own view of the world...  At times it seemed like he would drop dead in front of me...  ... and other times he seemed indestructible...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump awakens slowly, disoriented, amidst a shattered bottle.</context>
      <utterance>'Pathetic, paranoid, lost in the past!' What is this shit?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are my notes! You can't look at my notes!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're notes -- my life! You're gonna betray me, you son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want the truth? I'm gonna tell the truth!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose truth?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine, for crissakes, I'm the writer!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm the legend and legends are not pathetic!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are just notes...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you understand anything about 'greatness'?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should find another writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This frank admission momentarily stops Stump.</context>
      <utterance>There's not enough time left.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm entitled to my opinions --</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's pathetic. Who gives a good God damn about the opinions of Al Stump?! What people want to know about is Ty Cobb! And they don't want to know who he hates 'cause everybody hates somebody! They don't wanta know if he had two wives or ten! They don't wanta know if he hit women or if they hit him!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think they wanta know how to steal second base?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Precisely!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I don't!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, oh, oh... I get it. You're one of them college psychology type guys. You wanta find the missing piece to finish the puzzle known as the Madman Cobb -- you think you're the next Hemingway but you're just a moderate success in a moderate-sized pond.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, Cobb! I'm much more than a moderate success!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it, now you're showing some life. You want psychology? I'll give you some fucking psychology!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father was a great man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father told my mother he was going out of town for the weekend on business. But he didn't go. He came back 'cause he thought she was being unfaithful...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why he thought it -- 'cause my mother was a wonderful woman -- but he thought it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN'S POV</speaker>
      <mode>B&amp;W</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The window. It starts to open.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father had high standards... the highest. He believed in quality... he believed in education... he believed in God... he believed in me... he believed in my mother... But on that night he seemed like a prowler... and so --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb spits on the papers of Stump's text.</context>
      <utterance>How's that? A pretty God damn good piece of psychology, eh? That what you're looking for? The childhood incident that explans me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Stump is shaken by this story.</context>
      <utterance>Well I was a prick before it happened and a bigger prick after it happened so stick that up your Sigmund Freud ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mother killed your father?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you ain't printing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if I say so. I don't think you understand something -- I have final editorial approval of the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I do. I always have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you read your contract?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my standard contract. I just signed. I would never have agreed to this if you had final approval.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump quickly dials and gets an answer.</context>
      <utterance>Call your agent.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb smiles and hangs the phone back up for Stump who reaches for the bottle on the nightstand and pours himself a morning drink of vodka.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Charlie? Al... I'm in Reno... yeah... things are fine...  Yeah, listen... I'm just checking... did we give away final editorial approval on this Cobb book?  We did? Cobb has it? Jesus... Stump listens long and hard -- his face sinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you were pretty stupid to give up approval, weren't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, Cobb?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck me? Why me?  Why you mad at me? Your agent made the deal, your lawyer, your publisher, you didn't even read the contract because you trusted them! Who the hell ever trusted a lawyer or an agent?! If I was Al Stump, the guy I'd be pissed off at would be Al Stump!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, you son of a bitch -- if you die before the book is finished, I'll write the story I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I ain't dying first.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll write slow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb lights a big cigar -- and sets fire to Stump's pages. Both men watch them go up in smoke.</context>
      <utterance>I'll die slow.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump just stares back -- exhausted and overmatched.</context>
      <utterance>Now get dressed so we can go find some women...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOUIS PRIMA AND GROUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cigarette girl works the room at a nearby table. She's all legs and fishnet stockings... and wig.</context>
      <utterance>'That old black magic has me in its spell, That old black magic that you weave so well..' Cobb and Stump at a table drinking and eating.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cigarette girl turns and we recognize her.</context>
      <utterance>Look't that -- hundred bucks says I get in her pants before dawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramona is a vision in this outfit as she approaches them.</context>
      <utterance>My God -- it's Mona... Ra-mona... We met her at the hotel...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramona arrives at their table.</context>
      <utterance>I don't remember...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cigarettes, gentlemen? Cigars? We stockpiled some Havanas before Senor Castro did his little number.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coupla Monte Cristos, Ramona, number twos.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have we met?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the hotel -- checking in.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb is suddenly gallant, gentlemanly, even charming.</context>
      <utterance>Ohyeah, you were the asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramona delivers the cigars and collects the money. Stump is a bit chagrined and caught off guard by this Cobb.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, young lady, I must apologize for the behavior of my friend -- he has a crude side.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I accept.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ramona... Spanish name... lovely... it means 'moonlit garden of the gods'...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually it's German and means 'wise protectoress' but thanks for the thought...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOUIS PRIMA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Stump has been left out of the exchange, and mumbles.</context>
      <utterance>... so let's give a Harrah's Casino warm welcome to the greatest baseball player of all time, the one and only Ty Cobb! The spotlight flies to Cobb who kisses Ramona's hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience stands to applaud Cobb -- Full and genuine. Cobb graciously waves to the crowd, bowing, basking.</context>
      <utterance>'Moonlit garden of the gods'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK ONSTAGE - LOUIS PRIMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>motions to his band.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS PRIMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They break into "Sweet Georgia Brown."</context>
      <utterance>And this one's for the Georgia Peach!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS PRIMA/KEELY SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb breaks into a little dance with Ramona at the table, much to Stump's (and Ramona's) amazement. For a moment, at least, there is great footwork and lightness in his movement -- we get a glimpse of the great athlete he once was.</context>
      <utterance>No gal made has got a shade on Sweet Georgia Brown, Two left feet but oh so sweet is Sweet Georgia Brown...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS PRIMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The great Ty Cobb! C'mon up here!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want you, Ty --</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Cobb heads for the stage, walking better but not without effort, a walk enhanced by drugs and booze. As he does, Ramona turns to Stump.</context>
      <utterance>Of course they want me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The greatest baseball player of all time.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she's off with her trayful of tobacco to the cocktail lounge.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know baseball from shmaseball but I know a nice man when I see one and I also know it's time for my coffee break. Hasta luego.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK ONSTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As Cobb arrives...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS PRIMA AND GROUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fellas, she can't get, are fellas, she ain't met, Georgia made her, Georgia claimed her, Sweet Georgia Brown. Louis Prima welcomes Cobb to the mike to thunderous applause.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS PRIMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My great pleasure, sir --  I've always wanted to ask you something, Mr. Cobb, with all the great ballplayers playing right now -- how well do you think you'd do against today's players?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I figure against today's pitchers I'd only hit about .275,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb grabs the mike and takes over.</context>
      <utterance>Because I'm 72 fucking years old, that's why, God damn it. Give me that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Prima and his cohorts are aghast. They cling to the hope that this is some put-on, some joke. They force a small, unnatural laugh. Stump winces and leaves the room, heading for the bar.</context>
      <utterance>First of all I wanta thank you for that song, 'Sweet Georgia Brown... it's a great song about my home state and I appreciate it...  That song has become the theme song for the Harlem Globetrotters...  It's too bad such a fine song had to be stole by a buncha niggers playing a faggot game in their underwear...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A disaster. Prima tries gamely to seize the mike back.</context>
      <utterance>'Course the Globetrotters are owned by a Jew named Saperstein so whadda you expect?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS PRIMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much. Another round of applause for the Georgia Peach, Ty Cobb!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb turns to the crowd which, even in it's drunken state, is appalled and in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>I got the mike, Dago -- gimme a God damn minute. Nobody's got respect for their elders any more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb grabs a clarinet from a member of Prima's band.</context>
      <utterance>Now let me explain to you how to hit a baseball. It's a lost art. Ever since that half-nigger Ruth started hitting home runs, the skill, the art, and the science have been lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, say this is a bat...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CASINO MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just haul him off --</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Ty Cobb! He'll fucking kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, the bat is like a wand, a magic wand... it should be caressed, held like a woman... like a woman who's really in need of a man...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFSTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Casino Manager winces and consults.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASINO MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, here we go...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Cobb starts demonstrating hitting techniques to the bewildered audience and casino staff. He strikes that familiar, strange stance -- choked up on the bat, a split grip, the bat held parallel to the ground...</context>
      <utterance>Hitting a baseball is really very easy... you can't force it... you can't overpower it... you go with the pitch... you let the bat do the work... it's all rhythm and flow...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You again? You could learn some manners from your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try harder.  You're a beautiful woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramona pulls the wig off her head revealing a sea of bobby pins and hair pins tying her natural brown hair to her head. She sets the wig on the counter and scratches her natural scalp.</context>
      <utterance>It's the wig.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump scratches the back of her scalp, somewhat embar- rassed and somewhat aroused.</context>
      <utterance>The damn thing itches but it's good for tips. Give me a scratch, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn you on? Hey, Harvey, another round. On him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramona slaps the wig back on her head. Slightly akilter. She doesn't care. Harvey delivers another round.</context>
      <utterance>Vodka and grapefruit juice.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your wig's crooked.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it bother you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no... I was just --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanta go to bed with me, right? Stump is so taken aback that he doesn't know how to answer. Flustered, he looks around, then takes a deep hit on his drink. He is very unsure.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want money?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a whore! I don't screw for money?! Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I didn't know. I mean I'm not good at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just divorced, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramona lets out a loud, hearty laugh without inhibition.</context>
      <utterance>It's written all over ya. Giant letters right across the forehead. D-I-V-O-R-C-E. Ha! Plain as day.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's obvious, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obvious.  So, if ya wanta pay me to screw, I won't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screw or pay?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whichever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So ya don't wanta screw?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump, completely befuddled, lets down completely. He doesn't care about getting laid or drunk or anything for the moment, except having someone to talk to -- the some- one is Ramona.</context>
      <utterance>All this ambiguity -- I see why she's divorcing ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what I'm saying or doing anymore... I'm trying to speak my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told my wife I wanted a divorce. She said 'okay' -- then I realized maybe I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then go back to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then quit crying. You want a divorce, you don't want a divorce, you're asking marital advice from a woman you're trying to get in the sack -- Jeez Louise!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sigh. Stump is lost. He motions to the bartender.</context>
      <utterance>Who is?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another round, Harvey.  This assignment has me befuddled. I'm supposed to tell the world that a monster is really a prince. I'm supposed to lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You being paid?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it's not a lie. It's a job. Quit agonizing -- take the money, do what you gotta do, and get it over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump has to think about this for a while.</context>
      <utterance>For godsakes why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him like he's crazy.</context>
      <utterance>He knows greatness. I'm in the presence of greatness. I want to learn about greatness.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greatness is overrated.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you're right, maybe you're right...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump drinks deeply -- his heart needs alcoholic reinforcement.</context>
      <utterance>So what do you want?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be in someone's arms tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh that. Why do men have such a hard time saying what they want?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, wait... don't drink too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya think I won't be able to screw if I'm too drunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs a hearty laugh, letting it all out.</context>
      <utterance>Screwed, stewed, and tattooed!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mere... I want to hold you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're so thoughtful -- the others are trying to get me drunk and you're trying to keep me sober. You'd be good husband material.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so fast --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean --</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a whore.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of quiet, simple bliss -- when: The door bursts open -- the LOCK SPLINTERS with a CRASH, and: Cobb bursts into the room -- Full of rage.</context>
      <utterance>Shh, shh... I know, I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two-timing bastard! You God damn Judas Iscariot! You stealing my girl! I'll kill you!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Cobb lashes out at Stump -- Stump tries to block the blow, but Cobb is relentless, and Cobb hits him again. Stump falls backwards -- His head hits a corner of the table.</context>
      <utterance>She's not 'your' girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Cobb backhands Ramona across the face, knocking her down. Stump lies on the floor only half conscious. He grabs his head. Blood. The room swirls in front of him as -- Cobb grabs Ramona, pulling his everpresent gun from his pocket as he does.</context>
      <utterance>What're you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're coming with me!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb jams the pistol into her jaw.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does -- The wig sits at a funny angle.</context>
      <utterance>Put it back on.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's better.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you again?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the Georgia Peach. I have 4,191 base hits in 11,429 at- bats, 920 stolen bases, 2,244 runs scored, and 92 batting records...  And I want you to undress.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb clicks the hammer of his gun with icy calm.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That don't scare me 'cause if you kill me I'll be dead and you ain't gonna screw a dead lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. You might.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramona removes her top -- her breasts are jammed into a classic 50's push-up bra.</context>
      <utterance>Take your clothes off.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got big tits. I like big tits.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They aren't so big. They're average, actually -- but these bras are great. Push 'em right up there. I owe a lot to the bras and wigs. A girl needs what she needs --</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does. And covers her breasts with her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. Take it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramona gets on the bed -- Cobb circles the bed continuously.</context>
      <utterance>Shy, huh? Get on the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rolls on her face, propping herself on her elbows.</context>
      <utterance>You're a beauty. Roll over.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON HER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terror and tears.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Cobb, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His eyes are full of fury and lust.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I coulda done with you in my prime...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you --</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want from me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terrified, she does.</context>
      <utterance>Roll over.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to do exactly what I say...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out the money for her.</context>
      <utterance>A thousand dollars...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Cobb takes a big, sloppy hit from a bottle, throwing in a few pills for good measure.</context>
      <utterance>Do what you gotta do and get it over with, Mr. Cobb.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to tell everyone you meet that you fucked me and I was the best fuck you ever had.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out and straightens her wig which is pretty crooked by now. She lets him. Then he falls apart, vio- lently grabbing his crotch.</context>
      <utterance>For a thousand bucks? Hell yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb grabs his crotch with the violence he does everything.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking at the most beautiful woman in the world, do you hear me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb lashes out at Ramona -- a vicious right hand. She ducks as his fist slams through the headboard.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm dead down here! Dead! Nothing! And it's been like that for over two years! Nothing! Now get outta here before I hit you!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Georgia Peach my ass -- Georgia trash is what you are!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was a great piece of ass, Stumpy, best I ever had...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, good...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have we missed the Testimonial Dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump tucks Cobb in his bed as the old man drifts into sleep, turns off the light, and heads back to his own room.</context>
      <utterance>No we haven't, Ty... now get some sleep...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Stump sits on his bed smoking his pipe and writing in longhand on pieces of paper of all sizes.</context>
      <utterance>It was a baseball book and I kept it in the typewriter for him to discover and amend...  It was a book I never planned to publish.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The second version, my version, was written on legal pads and hotel stationery and cocktail napkins and anything I could scrape together without drawing his attention...  I kept my version in a box at the bottom of my suitcase --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The door flies open and Cobb bursts in -- full of vim and vigor, a fresh set of clothes on, fire in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>The whole thing had become an agonizing death watch, and most days I couldn't believe the son of a bitch wouldn't die...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing like a cigarette girl and thirty hours of sleep to invigorate a man, Stumpy! You look like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb goes straight for the typewriter and yanks out a page, grabbing the stack of typed pages as well.</context>
      <utterance>Been writing, Ty...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb reads the pages with utter seriousness. Stump watches.</context>
      <utterance>Well let's see how we're doing...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb rushes to Stump and embraces him, almost like a child. His eyes are wet with tears.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, God damn it, Stumpy, yes! Now you're getting it! None of this Sigmund Freud bullshit! Baseball, Stumpy, baseball! Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump stares back. And nods.</context>
      <utterance>You understand! People are no damn good but you're different! You're okay, Stumpy, you get it!  And I can trust you...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now let's go roll us some dice, Alimony, I feel a hot hand coming on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arriving at a craps table, Cobb barges right in.</context>
      <utterance>Y'see how it works, Stumpy... they boo ya your whole career, then when you're about to kiss off, they put ya on a pedestal. That's what being a legend's all about.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The croupier pushes the dice to Cobb who places a bet, as do the others. Cobb rolls the dice -- but he sees something. Somebody.</context>
      <utterance>Send the dice to the Peach, boys, and belly up to the bar...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stumpy, what is that?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My girl went for the nigger?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think they're just next to each other by accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb's voice silences the tables. Ramona looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Mona! You with that nigger!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Willie! Is she with you?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my man, Mr. Cobb, and he's all man.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My girl with my nigger!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb pulls his gun and tries to climb across the table.</context>
      <utterance>She's not your girl and he's not your --</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got a gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Cobb!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb on the table with a gun as Stump and police officers scramble to grab his gun hand. Customers hit the deck.</context>
      <utterance>Get down!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM, BLAM, BLAM -- the gun is FIRED REPEATEDLY into the ceiling fixtures, into the mirrors above the tables. Cobb is wrestled to the table by several men, including Stump. And it takes all of them to escort the struggling Cobb out of the casino into the lobby.</context>
      <utterance>What is the world coming to?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're leaving, we're leaving! There's no reason to press charges!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know who I am?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a crazy old fool, that's who you are!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back off, God damn it! We're leaving!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump hesitates, chaos swirls around them. Cobb is out of control, we hear threats of arrest -- when...</context>
      <utterance>Where we going, Stumpy, I wanta find us some more women!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ty, Ty, Ty, calm down. It's time for the testimonial dinner! This stops Cobb cold. He's immediately sober.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know something, Alimony, I believe you're the best friend I ever had.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swear on a Bible, Stumpy -- I feel I can trust you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>deeply alarmed by this confession.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Cobb talks into a tape recorder sitting on his lap, enjoying the hand microphone.</context>
      <utterance>I was disturbed, to say the least, that he felt we were friends -- but at least for the moment it made things bearable.  And he started talking -- the world according to Ty Cobb...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then this fat ass named Babe Ruth came into the league and damn near destroyed the game of baseball... We all thought he was gonna eat and fuck his way outta the league but he hung around for a few years --</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Hung around'? He was --  -- next to you -- the greatest player of all time. He hit 714 home runs?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody can hit home runs. Now excuse me, I got work to do...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Ty -- And Cobb resumes into the tape recorder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>An O.S. RUMBLE -- Stump quickly hides the manuscript as: Cobb thunders in with the typewritten version, the ver- sion written for Cobb's approval.</context>
      <utterance>I was drinking like a fish, smoking cigarettes again, and now lying about the hidden manuscript.  And by writing two versions without telling him, I was becoming something Cobb was not.  I was becoming a liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fabulous stuff, Stumpy, just brilliant. You're a genius.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Ty...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb takes a swig of booze. Some routine outside noise drifts in, young people LAUGHING and CARRYING ON.</context>
      <utterance>I love reading about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb hurries outside, drawing his pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it, who's out there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as Stump helps him shoot up.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I also became expert at finding his veins...  Which always revived him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somewhere along the way I'd gone from biographer to stenographer to chauffeur to nurse... I was the only thing keeping the bastard alive... and I kept hoping he'd die.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb grabs the recorder mike and launches in again.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know, Stumpy, with a friend like you, I just might go on forever...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were we -- ohyeah -- then, at the age of 42, I batted .323 which was an embarrassment to me but would be a career for anyone else...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until, by the grace of God, we arrived -- days, weeks, months later, I don't know -- in Cooperstown, New York, for his beloved testimonial dinner...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna meet great athletes, great warriors, great men at this Hall of Fame dinner, Stumpy. None of this modern, pansy bullshit --</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been looking forward to this for a long time --</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fucking liar. You've been hoping I'd die first.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got me wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump squirms. A KNOCK at the door. Stump answers it. A beat-up 70-YEAR-OLD MAN stands there -- looking like a lost bum.</context>
      <utterance>I got you right. But it's okay 'cause I need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cobb here?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Mickey Cochrane.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump lets Cochrane in the door. Ty stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Ty, it's Mickey Cochrane.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your tux?</utterance>
   <speaker>COCHRANE</speaker>
      <mode>MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have one.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sent you money for it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COCHRANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't arrive.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You drank it, you mean. You can't go to the Hall of Fame like that. I won't allow it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COCHRANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things have been rough, Ty.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb peels some cash from his roll of dough and throws it at Cochrane.</context>
      <utterance>There's two things a man should never do -- complain or explain.  Now go buy a God damn tux!</utterance>
   <speaker>COCHRANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The stores are closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb grabs the phone and dials impatiently.</context>
      <utterance>How could you be so good behind the plate and so bad everywhere else!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb thrusts the card into Cochrane's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Operator? What's the best men's shop in town. Who owns it? Jack who? Gimme his home number. Better yet, ring him up for me.  Jack?! This is Ty Cobb. Go down to your shop and open it up and sell a tux to the great Mickey Cochrane. And sell him a cumberbund and a shirt and a bow tie and some God damn cologne. He smells like shit. What's the address?  He'll be there in twenty minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God damn it, Mickey, ya gotta give a better effort.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>COCHRANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Cochrane exits, leaving Cobb with Stump once again.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Ty.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's lost, Stumpy, the poor man's been lost ever since he took a fastball in the ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take care of him?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For years -- but that ain't goin' in the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Ty, why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb winces as he tries to rise, almost falling.</context>
      <utterance>Because it would embarrass him.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanta take the cane tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to have your cane.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb poses in his tux -- proudly, unsurely.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have to have anything -- if you stay near me... in case I wobble or something... just a firm hand right here...  That'll keep me upright. I'd appreciate it. Now how do I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look like the greatest ballplayer of all time. You going to be okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be okay when I hear the crowd.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>P.A. ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lanky Carl Hubbell, 50's, waves to the crowd and cameras as he enters to applause from the locals gathered.</context>
      <utterance>The great left-handed pitcher from the New York Giants, who struck out five men in a row in the 19-- All-Star game -- Carl Hubbell.</utterance>
   <speaker>P.A. ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pie Traynor, 60's, struggles to the entrance using a cane.</context>
      <utterance>The great third baseman from the Chicago Cubs, Harold Joseph 'Pie' Traynor...</utterance>
   <speaker>P.A. ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waner Brothers, 60's, jauntily wave and enter.</context>
      <utterance>Paul and Lloyd Waner, the Waner brothers -- Big Poison and Little Poison -- from the Pittsburgh Pirates...</utterance>
   <speaker>P.A. ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barrel-chested Jimmy Foxx, 60, gets out and waves.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty-eight home runs in a season -- Mr. Double-X -- the great Jimmy Foxx!</utterance>
   <speaker>P.A. ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb gets out, followed by Stump. Cobb walks into the building, past the cameras, utterly erect and upright, stretching his full six feet one inch. The applause is the most enthusiastic yet.</context>
      <utterance>And ladies and gentlemen, the highest lifetime batting average of all time, first man elected to the Hall of Fame, retired with over 90 batting records, the one and only Georgia Peach, Ty Cobb!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump slips his hand to Cobb's lower back just as they arrive at the door, and the two men enter together.</context>
      <utterance>Your hand, Stumpy, your hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Cobb is met by the Hall of Fame director, CHARLES, 50, who shakes his hand and shows him in.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, my friend...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they head inside.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Cobb, good to see you again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam Crawford, Ty, Long time no see.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good to see you, Sam. You doin' okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm alive, Ty, I'm alive...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boys'll get together later and have a little party, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be some parties tonight, Peach...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stumpy, meet Rogers Hornsby, next to me the greatest hitter of all time --</utterance>
   <speaker>HORNSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How d'ya do. You're looking good, Ty...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look like shit and you know it. We'll have a real smoker later, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HORNSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The EMCEE raps a fork on a glass, bringing the dinner to order.</context>
      <utterance>Ohyeah... we'll tear it up good...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASEBALL M.C.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The spotlight moves around the room and each man waves, half rising from his chair.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Cooperstown, ladies and gentlemen. We're here to acknowledge the greatest ballplayers of all time, those men still gracing our presence who were among the earliest inductees into the Hall of Fame.  Waner, Hubbell, Foxx, Cochrane, Hornsby, Traynor -- these are the giants, the Old Masters of our craft...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASEBALL M.C.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A spotlight hits Cobb, who rises and waves to the crowd as the lights dim.</context>
      <utterance>But the greatest of all is with us tonight -- simply put, the best ballplayer ever -- Tyrus Raymond Cobb.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASEBALL M.C.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>lights, please...</context>
      <utterance>We have gathered from the archives some film on Mr. Cobb...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FILM NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This rare footage of Ty Cobb reflects his love of children, and they admired him by the thousands...</utterance>
   <speaker>FILM - COBB</speaker>
      <mode>B&amp;W</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>posing with kids in uniforms. He clowns with them, tousling their hair, knocking off their caps.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILM NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On another occasion he partakes in a Donkey Baseball game, showing his not-so-well-known lighter side...</utterance>
   <speaker>FILM - COBB</speaker>
      <mode>B&amp;W</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>on a donkey in a Donkey Baseball game.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILM NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And here's Cobb with two other immortals, Babe Ruth and Tris Speaker...</utterance>
   <speaker>FILM NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cobb and Speaker were great friends off the field, and of course were accused of fixing some games by pitcher Dutch Leonard...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FILM NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cobb and Speaker were clearly involved with unsavory gamblers, but finally were acquitted by Judge Landis, though many questions remain unanswered --</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a great film --</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me and Speaker and the fix?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think the medication's getting to you, Ty -- I'm watching you run the bases.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FILM NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His ruthless competitive spirit has sometimes been called psychopathic...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Al, what are you seeing?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your batting stroke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FILM NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In an infamous incident on August xx, 19xx, Cobb attacked a heckler who turned out to have no arms or legs, and was briefly suspended for the incident...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stumpy, what's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ty, I think you're not well -- I'll take you back to the motel.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you seeing?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and Connie Mack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crawford and Foxx have something cooking in Room 212 --</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over here, Ty.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never partied with these boys but they had a reputation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROOM 212</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They knock. JIMMY FOXX opens the door a crack.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOXX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ty.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got some booze?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOXX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.  Who's in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOXX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, Sam and Pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got any women in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOXX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb lights up.</context>
      <utterance>Sure do.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me and Stumpy want some action.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOXX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanta meet some great broads?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Jimmy Foxx opens the door letting in Cobb and Stump.</context>
      <utterance>We're ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ty. You know my wife, Lillian?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAYNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is Mrs. Traynor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOXX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pearl, meet Ty Cobb and --</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Al Stump.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foxx pulls Cobb aside and whispers discreetly.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, ladies.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOXX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hornsby's got something on the third floor -- maybe more what you're looking for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you're up for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb takes a hit on his flask and they knock at the door. Hornsby answers the door -- we can see a party behind him, full of old players, booze, cigars -- and even some women, though the whole thing is infinitely tamer than the smokers Cobb remembers.</context>
      <utterance>I've never been readier!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rajah!</utterance>
   <speaker>HORNSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't comin' in, Ty.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb starts pushing on the door. Hornsby holds firm.</context>
      <utterance>It's me! An' Stumpy here!</utterance>
   <speaker>HORNSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a bastard and you ain't coming to our party.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's in there?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HORNSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me and Mickey an' a coupla broads.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hornsby signals to Cochrane who comes over to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Let me talk to Mickey.</utterance>
   <speaker>COCHRANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ty...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya look good in that tux, Mick.</utterance>
   <speaker>COCHRANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't let ya in, Ty. It's Rogers' party. I'm an invited guest.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb tries to break into the party but Hornsby rushes over and shoves the door in his face, leaving Ty and Stump alone.</context>
      <utterance>God damn it, let me in!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Presidents of the United States of America used to invite me to the White House to drink their Scotch and smoke their cigars and fuck their women.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb heads down the hallway pounding on every door -- he's ready to explode.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go to the motel, Ty...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me in, God damn it! I invented this game! Let me in!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go home, Ty, this isn't a good place to be...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fought for players' rights and salary increases and unions while all you crawled around on your knees begging massa' for bread crumbs just thankful for a job!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cobb grabs Stump and pulls his face close.</context>
      <utterance>Open up, God damn it! Ballplayers can make big money but they're too stupid! You're all too stupid! The hell with ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take me back to the Hall!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate your coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb is silent. He and Stump enter.</context>
      <utterance>For Mr. Cobb, no problem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you see on that film tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw Ty Cobb playing baseball.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was raised in the Baptist Church but I know that Heaven is just the ol' oskefagus -- the change-up. You swing from your ass 'cause you think life is a fastball down the middle and after your bat has crossed the plate and you're all off balance and looking stupid, the ball just kinda flutters across home, slow and juicy and hittable, and as it crosses the plate, the ball looks at you and smiles a nasty smile and laughs its way into the catcher's mitt...  We don't just lose -- we're made fools of.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Save the romance for the book...  ... and take me home to Georgia.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cobb parted with some of his hard- earned money and rented a limo in order to make what he called a 'grand re-entrance to his beloved home town of Royston...' Cobb marks the margin of the manuscript.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He loved the manuscript, as well he should -- it made him out to be a saint -- Cobb looks up from the manuscript.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greatest biography ever written --</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The book, like Cobb, was almost finished. But he was dying slower than I was writing, and like everything else, he viewed it as a competition that he was not going to lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweating, pale, hanging on. A grim smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To me, we weren't riding to Georgia in a limo...  We were riding in a hearse...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAR POV - OLD WOODEN SIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paint chipped and faded.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The sign reads: "WELCOME TO ROYSTON, GEORGIA</context>
      <utterance>We're here. And the fuckin' sign needs paint.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They look kinda the same...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's the last time you saw her?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About fifteen years ago. But she understands me...  There! No... damn....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe she moved.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There! I think...</utterance>
   <speaker>POV - HOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>like the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>stops nearby.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump gets out of the car and heads up the walk.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see if it's her. Wait here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLORENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have your brother in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyrus?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. And he'd like to see you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLORENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wish to see him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's not well.</context>
      <utterance>It's been a long time, he said.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have nothing to say to him, and wish to hear nothing he has to say to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know there's been problems, but the family is very important to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Young man, the family he talks about never existed.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He loved his father.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump hesitates. He doesn't have a ready answer.</context>
      <utterance>If his father, if my father, was such a great man, why did Tyrus turn out to be so evil?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dying. He just wants to see you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't your sister. The woman in the house said your sister moved a long time ago... she doesn't know where.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Stump, at last, goes off --</context>
      <utterance>You cocksucking liar. My sister doesn't want to see me and you're lying.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liar?! A cocksucking liar?! Of course I'm a liar! That's what I'm paid to do, isn't it?! Lie about Ty Cobb?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you didn't like the job, why didn't you quit?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who would take care of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give me the sob-sister routine.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I listen to your bullshit, I interpret and shape and find words for your bullshit and you give me nothing but grief!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You love being this close to greatness!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car stops. Stump climbs out, searching for room and for air to breathe. The skies are overcast and dark.</context>
      <utterance>Stop the car!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you'd die!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb is out of the car on his cane -- following Stump.</context>
      <utterance>I will, Stumpy, I will...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A line of lightning signals a storm in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>And go to hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look up -- The entrance to the Royston Cemetery. A casually-maintained slope of several acres up a hill.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll do that, too.  And look how convenient you've made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was your sister alright, and she didn't want anything to do with you either!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump walks into the cemetery to escape Cobb, who follows nonetheless with a cool resolution. Stump laughs at Cobb's comment.</context>
      <utterance>I forgive her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You forgive her?! That's rich!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgiveness is crucial to human maturity and religious growth.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Religious growth?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all need to forgive more, Al... you oughta try it. You're too angry. You're all pent up.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the cemetery they keep walking, up a long hill full of tombstones and shrines and sprays of dead and dying flowers and gaudy plastic bouquets. Cobb following steadily along with his cane, several paces behind Stump. THUNDER shakes the ground. And more lightning.</context>
      <utterance>I'm angry?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you angry because I discovered you were a whore? Is that it, Alimony?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm angry?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it the divorce? You gotta let go of it...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love her! I don't want a divorce!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump whirls near the top of the hill to face Cobb who continues making his way along, slowly and surely.</context>
      <utterance>Sure ya do. You're just so used to accommodating people that you don't know what you want anymore. I accommodate nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you have no friends!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A mausoleum looms behind Stump, bigger than anything in the cemetery, classical, outsized, monumental, even elegant. One simple word is above the door, carved in granite: COBB.</context>
      <utterance>Do you? Who are they?! Those drunken hacks you hang out with who all think they're gonna write the great American novel but all they're gonna ever do is bitch and moan and write lousy leads about high school football games? How about the brunette in the courtyard? Is she your friend? I heard she fucks everybody -- she must be everybody's friend!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump turns to see the mausoleum, and the word COBB.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad we're here -- I was gonna bring you here anyway sooner or later --</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several beats as the men take it all in. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Which Cobb of Georgia is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And rain suddenly falls from the skies, threatening to soak the two men. Cobb heads for the mausoleum -- Stump follows.</context>
      <utterance>That is me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump is still fuming, angry and cynical.</context>
      <utterance>When I die, my mother and father will be moved in here and, in time, my dear sister, Florence will join us as well.  The family will be together again.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under one roof? That's romantic! You want that in the book? Ty Cobb brings the family together at last to enter the gates of Heaven whole!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb grabs Stump by the throat and stares him in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>You mock my family -- you mock me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father was a great man!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why are you such a bastard?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Being a bastard is a small price to pay for greatness. I, too, am a great man.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me go!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother didn't kill my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb's fist clinches Stump's throat, forcing him to hear. Outside the mausoleum, RAIN pours down now, a Southern spring thunderstorm unleashing torrents.</context>
      <utterance>What're you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father told my mother he was leaving town for the weekend but he came back to the edge of the woods where he tied up his horse...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>His mother hands the shotgun to a naked man climbing from bed.</context>
      <utterance>Because my mother did not kill my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Cobb's father raises the winow -- KABLAM! The lover FIRES into his stomach. Cobb's father lurches onto his back.</context>
      <utterance>My mother's lover killed my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON COBB'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode>B&amp;W</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>on his back staring up at his mother's lover.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The lover unloads the second shell -- blowing his head off.</context>
      <utterance>The last thing my father saw was the face of the man fucking his wife!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb quietly takes a hit on his flask from the doorway of the mausoleum, watching Stump rant and rave in the rain.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be your friend! I don't want to feel sorry for you! So your mother's lover blew your father's head off! I don't care. You were a prick before it happened, you were a prick after it happened, you've been a prick ever since, and you're a prick now!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Public relations are overrated.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb holds out his flask for Stump.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell're you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb motions for the limo to pull up the slope towards them.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck the drink!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump stands in the rain screaming at Cobb who stands out of the rain, calm, centered, drinking, dying.</context>
      <utterance>You're too angry, Al, you just gotta learn to let it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna tell the truth about you, Cobb! I'm gonna tell the world you hate women, Jews, and niggers!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't use the word 'nigger', Stumpy, it's racist and demeaning. And I don't hate women -- I'm just not very good with 'em, which puts me in the same boat with you and every other man I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb comes out into the rain toward Stump.</context>
      <utterance>You treat people like dirt!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb takes him by the arm and tries to lead him to the limo.</context>
      <utterance>The children of America need heroes, Al, you know that...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your hands off me!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Cobb helps Stump into the limo, which pulls out of the cemetery still being drenched by rain.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Al...  You're making a fool of yourself out here. It's not dignified...  Come in out of the rain...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump just shrugs and takes another hit.</context>
      <utterance>Either my father was... inadequate ... for my mother... he was not the man I thought he was... not a great man... not even a good man...  ... or my mother was... trash... a common whore...  It's that simple, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump drinks deeply once again.</context>
      <utterance>As a boy I stood in court next to her because suddenly I was the man of the house but as I stood there steadfastly by her side and heard the jury say 'not guilty' I knew she'd been with another man the night of the killing.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Or am I a fool?</context>
      <utterance>A man must defend his mother at all times, isn't that right, Al?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man must defend his mother at all times.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the two men sit there silently, rocking slightly, trying to stay warm, when there is -- Suddenly a KNOCK at the door -- They stare at each other. Cobb puts down the gun, struggles to the door and answers it. A MAN stands in the rain, carrying a briefcase, trying vainly to keep dry.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I thought...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH BRIEFCASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Al Stump?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MAN WITH BRIEFCASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump nods as he swigs on the bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Al Stump?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH BRIEFCASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been chasing you all over the country --  -- I'm here to serve you papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papers?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I know this routine.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid it's divorce, Stumpy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH BRIEFCASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're being sued for divorce.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But my wife and I are still talking?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and what she's saying is 'fuck you.'</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump reaches for the gun and aims it at the man.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck me? Well fuck her. No, fuck him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man is frozen with terror as Stump rises from the chair -- drunk and crazed, aiming the shaky gun.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't serving me no papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH BRIEFCASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just doing a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all loved our wives, Al, that's got nothing to do with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAN WITH BRIEFCASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll find somebody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KABLAM! Stump FIRES at the man but the shot goes wild. He's drunk, he's not experienced with guns, he's shaking.</context>
      <utterance>There's a million broads out there, Stumpy -- put down the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not going to accommodate this man, Tyrus.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all mixed up. Give me the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man drops to his knees, begging for his life.</context>
      <utterance>You're absolutely right, Tyrus, I've been accommodating people my whole life and it stops right here.  You've killed a man. I'll kill a man. KABLAM! KABLAM! He misses again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH BRIEFCASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Please, dear God! I have a family, too!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump tries to hold the gun with two hands, approaching the man, to nearly point-blank range.</context>
      <utterance>Don't give me that sob-sister stuff!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump looks crazed, a bathrobe falling open, his feet bare and wet, his hair awry from the rainstorm. He aims the gun at the man's head, looks at Cobb with wild glee.</context>
      <utterance>Al... no... Al... Al...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life is too short to be diplomatic. A man's friends don't care what he says or does. You're my friend, Ty, right? You're my friend!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump pulls the TRIGGER -- CLICK. Empty. As the Man looks up, realizing he's alive, Stump strikes him across the face with the gun, drawing blood. The Man scrambles to his feet and races from the room, grabbing his briefcase, and running to the door.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH BRIEFCASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the Man runs into the rainy night, leaving Cobb and Stump. Stump's head collapses in his hands -- Bewildered, exhausted. The two men sit alone for several beats before Stump speaks. He is completely lost.</context>
      <utterance>You're crazy! No wonder she wants to divorce you! You're crazy!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I almost killed a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little drunken excess...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I put a gun to a man's head and pulled the trigger. I wanted to kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's forgotten already. I saw nothing. Nothing happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it did.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Al, listen to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I was hired to write a biography of the greatest sportswriter of our time -- a biography of Al Stump -- would I include what happened tonight? Attorneys are pigs -- divorce attorneys are lower than pigs. What happened tonight was private. An intimacy. Your own business. Our own business. Nobody else's. It wouldn't belong in a book about greatness.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's gonna write my biography.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump looks up at Cobb but says nothing. He picks up a nearly-empty bottle off the floor and takes a hit.</context>
      <utterance>And when the brunette in the courtyard brushed against you, I know what happened, Al. A warm summer breeze, the smell of jasmine, her black hair against a white blouse -- you came to life again, you got hard -- and when you saw her naked it was more than you could bear... it's okay, Al, it's okay...  The brunette ain't gonna be in the book either...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump raises his hand, motioning Cobb to stop.</context>
      <utterance>And the drinking? Well, they used to say ol' Ty had a drinking problem but you can booze me right under the table right now... no problem... and nobody's God damn business, either...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment. A look.</context>
      <utterance>I get it... I get it...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then get some sleep. You look pathetic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oblivious in a drunken sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rage is in his eyes. He cocks the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's crying. He shakes his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb puts the gun into his own mouth -- He clears his throat, as if to make room for the gun barrel. He gags slightly and closes his eyes, he thinks for the last time.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have a point of view, Stumpy, you ain't worth killing...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON HIS FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb removes the gun momentarily and looks at it. He sees that the gun barrel is covered with blood.</context>
      <utterance>Something's not right.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear God...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as he stares into the mirror.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb coughs again -- More blood covers his chin. He touches his chin, touches the blood, smears it around a little, looks at his hands now covered with blood.</context>
      <utterance>No... no... no... this can't be... Absolutely not... This is not right...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb moves around the tiny bathroom like a caged animal. He falls to his knees in prayer in front of the sink.</context>
      <utterance>Stumpy?! No...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb rises to his feet and looks in the mirror again. He grabs a hand towel and daubs his face with it. A bit more blood trickles from his mouth. And gradually a deep calm seems to settle over him.</context>
      <utterance>Our Father, which art in heaven, hallowed by Thy name. Thy kingdom come, Thy will be done, on Earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread, and forgive us our trespasses, as we forgive --  Aw, fuck it... little late for that sob sister stuff...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... so this is what it feels like...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump struggles to his elbow to find Cobb.</context>
      <utterance>Ty.  Tyrus.  Peach...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP'S POV - COBB'S BED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>is empty and still neatly made.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUMP'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three holes of broken plaster and mirror.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Dear Alimony, you lying S.O.B. -- I'm checking myself into the hospital. I think the end is near. Your Pal, Ty.'</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deeply alarmed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the hell outta here! You call this a hospital?! You call this food?! You know who I am?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Mr. Cobb.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful. He's got a gun and we haven't been able to get it away from him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump hurries down the hall to the source of the noise. A small group of doctors, orderlies and NURSES are gathered outside Cobb's door, afraid to enter. Also there are two civilians in business suits.</context>
      <utterance>I know, I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump ignores the advice and enters the room.</context>
      <utterance>He doesn't want visitors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NURSE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir, but I need to draw some more blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put a bucket under my chin and I'll cough up a couple pints for ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to do it this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out his arm for her. She begins drawing blood.</context>
      <utterance>Well don't poke around too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a nice piece of ass, eh, Stumpy?  You come back later and climb on the big fella?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's against regulations, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you read the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, God damn it, I thought I could trust you -- I used to be able to figure out people better.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That book is the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another NURSE enters and announces.</context>
      <utterance>You're a God damn romantic! The truth is a whore! Just like you and just like my mother!</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Mr. Barton is here to see you. He says he's the chairman of the board of Coca Cola.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell the son of a bitch to go downstairs and have a Pepsi -- I got no time for business.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>YOUNG DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to take your blood pressure, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's high. What else you need to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young doctor wraps Cobb's arm with the device and begins pumping. Another OLDER DOCTOR enters and addresses Cobb head on.</context>
      <utterance>I have to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb picks up the gun and aims it at the doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Cobb. We cannot allow you to have a gun in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Older Doctor turns and leaves. Stump enjoys the show.</context>
      <utterance>Come and get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Younger Doctor completes his task and slips away.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know, Stumpy, my oldest son was a doctor -- a hacksaw artist, that's all they are --  He died of a brain tumor when he was forty -- hadn't spoke to me in fifteen years 'cause I was such a rotten father -- put that in your God damn book!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad, ain't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know which version of your life I'm going to publish. I really don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb waves his gun just as some more doctors enter.</context>
      <utterance>There ya go again! Accommodating me and you don't have to! I died faster than you could write!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room clears -- leaving only Cobb and Stump.</context>
      <utterance>Get the hell outta here! Everybody but Stumpy! Out!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fooled me, Stumpy, nobody ever fooled me but you pulled it off! I thought we were pals!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know what I was getting into with this job.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quit explaining yourself! Stand by your convictions! You beat the great Ty Cobb! I respect that! But if you print it -- print it all!  My second son weighed 300 pounds and he died of a heart attack in the arms of a hooker in Paso Robles. My other son I lost all track of and my two daughters won't speak to me and my two ex- wives won't and my siter you know won't! Print it all!  And Ty Cobb can't get it up anymore! Print that too!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all... confusing...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump nods and pulls a pint of whiskey from his coat pocket. He goes up to Cobb and tucks the whiskey under the blanket.</context>
      <utterance>It's not! It's simple! You won! Tell the world that the greatest ballplayer who ever lived was also the biggest bastard! Who cares now?! I give you permission and my blessing! From here on it's your story!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb nods in appreciation.</context>
      <utterance>Here's a little something might help.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's my money?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb grabs Stump's hand for one last word.</context>
      <utterance>Right here, Peach... next to your gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump places Cobb's hand on his money, nods, and -- Stump leaves the room without looking back at --</context>
      <utterance>Stumpy, there's nothing wrong with wanting glory.  Now get the hell outta here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLDER DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the gun? Did you get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Stump leaves the hospital, passing the Coke Executive. As he does he looks back over his shoulder to see:</context>
      <utterance>Naw, I didn't get the gun...</utterance>
   <speaker>POV SHOT - DOCTORS, ET AL.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sounds of CRASHING, BROKEN GLASS, and COBB'S thunderous VOICE. Stump smiles slightly and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>rushing back into Cobb's room. And --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PAN OVER ACROSS the sign -- to the adjacent cemetery as -- A hearse enters the cemetery grounds followed by three cars. A very humble ceremony. And the voice of a country gospel singer can be heard.</context>
      <utterance>And on July 17, 1961... Ty Cobb died quietly in his sleep. I don't believe it was quiet, nothing he did was quiet, but that's what the newspaper writer said who wrote the lead and we all know that writers never lie...</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNTRY GOSPEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'There is a fountain filled with blood, Drawn from Emmanuel's veins...'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody hired a singer...</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNTRY GOSPEL SINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'And sinners plunged beneath that flood, Lose all their guilty stains...'</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Stump stands in the distance, at the back of the cemetery, watching the simple, empty service.</context>
      <utterance>... but it was the grimmest damn funeral service I'd ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He left all his money to his family, though no members of it managed to attend the funeral, and with the rest he founded a hospital in his own name and an educational trust fund for poor Georgia children.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>POV SHOT - THREE OLD MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>in dark suits drop flowers on the coffin.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only three ballplayers attended the service -- three oldtimers who he'd been supporting financially for many years, a fact he didn't want made public.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Bored laughter and another hit on their everpresent drinks. And Stump enters for the first time in nearly a year.</context>
      <utterance>An' the drunk says, 'I know, I was talking to the duck.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump enters comfortably, happy to see his cronies at last. Frank and the others come over from the bar, quickly gathering around Stump.</context>
      <utterance>Al!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump settles in at the table.</context>
      <utterance>Stranger! Another round on me!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRONIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long time no see, etc...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good to see you guys... how's it goin'? Alan, how's that novel coming? Must be about done by now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, actually, I haven't started it yet... been kinda busy...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all been busy...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know how it is...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We read that Cobb died.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... finally gave up the ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? What was he like?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were the stories true or were they exaggerated?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>REYNALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell us the truth, man, was he a monster?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump looks at the faces of his buddies, eagerly awaiting his judgement as if it is final wisdom. He stirs his drink.</context>
      <utterance>Or was he just one of the guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truth?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRONIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohyeah, the absolute truth, no bullshit, give it to us straight, etc...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stump takes a drink and looks his friends in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>The truth?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murmurs of deep satisfaction from the Cronies. Affirmation.</context>
      <utterance>A prince and a great man has fallen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRONIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>etc...</context>
      <utterance>Yes, awright, we knew it...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helluva guy, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Stump starts lying to his enraptured audience, we PULL BACK AND UP, going FROM the intimate center of the table TO a cool distance, and --</context>
      <utterance>A helluva guy, a great man, a misunderstood artist, a fierce competitor but a sweet man at heart... a gentle soul...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
