<movie id="135" title="Cold Mountain">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SWIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...This is your path. There is no other. That's a curse you can use on the Yankee before battle.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that works?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to say it in Cherokee.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this, Monroe and Ada have arrived, escorted by SALLY SWANGER, a local woman, middle-aged, kindly, and her husband, ESCO, a glorious curmudgeon. The Monroes are introduced to various locals. Inamn watches them, on the other side of the crowd. The Reverend Monroe, his daughter Ada. Up from Charleston, bringing God's word to you heathens! Is Esco's preferred introduction. Building a church. Inman watches Ada, moves his head to keep her in view as Swimmer stitches, and winces with pain.</context>
      <utterance>You said it to me in Cherokee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sally collects plates for the Monroes. Hands them to Ada and her father, who wait, patiently, for silverware. Esco takes a plate, picks up a skewer of meat, bites on it. Monroe pluckily follows suit.</context>
      <utterance>So keep your head still.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, there won't be any war. And if there is, they say it won't last a week.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUTCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fresh breakfast. Shoot him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butcher chases after the rabbit, Rourke in raucous support.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not firing, start the damn war off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUTCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WOUNDED BLACK SOLDIER sits up as Butcher celebrates. Butcher runs over, but can't find a charge for his musket. He looks around in the stack of corpses, pulling out weapons, tries one: not loaded, throws it down, tries another: not loaded. The wounded man can't get up, tries to drag himself like a crab away from Butcher. Inman yells at him, appalled.</context>
      <utterance>That was something! That's hell and we've been there! Kicked old Nick's asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up another musket. It fires. The wounded Federal slumps back, dead.</context>
      <utterance>You got a charge?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He examines his fiddle for damage. Some orderlies pass, lifting OAKLEY away on a gurney. Oakley's pale as a maiden, the life leaking from him. Inman walks a way with him. Oakley looks up, desperate to be brave.</context>
      <utterance>That's gold in his mouth he got no need for.  We take his boots.</utterance>
   <speaker>OAKLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a few. You saw?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>OAKLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman flicks his eyes to the Orderly, whose look confirms the boy's wounds are certainly mortal.</context>
      <utterance>I know you don't recognise me. I'm Mo Oakley's boy.  It's okay. I was thirteen when you all left. Am I going to die?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Bonaparte's Retreat? That's one I play.</utterance>
   <speaker>OAKLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stobrod looks at Inman, confused.</context>
      <utterance>Play me something sweet. Like a girl's waiting for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OAKLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Play me something like there's nothing to fear from a merciful Lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only know a couple of tunes.</utterance>
   <speaker>OAKLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman glares at Stobrod. And Stobrod starts to play. Hesitant, then with gathering confidence, improvising, increasingly expansive, as if he's as surprised as everyone else. Oakley's lips move. A whisper. Inman leans in.</context>
      <utterance>Like when you're thirsty up at Bishop's Creek and the water is so cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>OAKLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stobrod plays. It's wrenching. Oakley stills. Inman abruptly puts his hand on the neck of the fiddle, stopping Stobrod. The boy is dead. Inman gets to his feet and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>I'm reaching Cold Mountain before you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get up, soldier. You are mentioned tonight in my report. You are a credit to the Highlands, to North Carolina and to the Cause.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have news, sir, on my application for transfer?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. A bloody day. It's what our General said: Good thing war is so terrible else a man might end up liking it too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir. It was my understanding the medical corps was desperate for volunteers.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now, soldier, it's me who is in need of volunteers. There's a dozen Yankees in that stand of trees between us. Stuck there from the retreat. Come daylight they can shoot us down for sport.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ada, how are you settling in? Are you liking the farm?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very much. It's beautiful country.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So listen -- if you would say hello to one of these fools, I'll get a field cleared this weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone? Like a forfeit?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UP ON THE ROOFBEAMS OF THE CHAPEL, the men are preoccupied with talk of secession from the Union.</context>
      <utterance>No. Him in particular, up in the rafters. Been pressing me all morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I call this nail: Northern Aggression.  I call this nail: a free nigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show some respect -- these nails are making a church.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman swings down. He feels the other men staring, burning a hole in his head.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Ada Monroe.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Inman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inman?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>W. P. Inman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>W. P. Inman.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Repeating a thing doesn't improve it.  People call me Inman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you were to take a glass of lemonade your friends might stop staring. Inman.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops down to ground level, takes the lemonade, scowls at the other guys. They're breaking for lunch and as they make their way to the trestle tables -- they enjoy jostling Inman.</context>
      <utterance>They're not my friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I work wood. Got a piece of land. Mostly work wood.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clear fields?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can clear a field.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, was there something in particular you wished to say to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he turns and joins the other men gathering round the tables for lunch. Ada watches him, intrigued. Rourke and co. approach ESCO SWANGER, a known sympathizer with the North, to give him a bad time.</context>
      <utterance>Not that comes to me.  I'll say thank you for the lemonade.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Esco loves the Yankees.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman arrives just as Rourke points a warning finger at Esco. He pushes the finger down to get by. Esco continues:</context>
      <utterance>I prefer a Yankee to a halfwit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it you think you'd be fighting for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The South.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esco's sons, ELLIS AND ACTON, who're working at the other end of the building, have now arrived at the table.</context>
      <utterance>And what's that when it's at home?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pop, you causing trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That means yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cut the wood, you carry the water for good old King Cotton. Now you want to fight for him. Somebody has to explain it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others are desperate to tease Inman.</context>
      <utterance>Don't even try.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada, at the lemonade stand again, watches them laughing at Inman, who keeps his head fixed on the table.</context>
      <utterance>How's the lemonade? Sweet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a fine looking thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been missing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, by the way.  Inman's down in the bottom field, clearing his debt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh dear. And then he had nothing to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are men so different in Charleston?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Men? I don't know. I don't even know what a woman should be like. In Charleston I was called a thistle, twice, by two different men. Both of them -- they were hunting for a simile, what was I like -- and thistle came right to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're saying you might like him, why not go down and say hello.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Esco, our friends there --  -- they helped build the Chapel?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Teague and his boys. I'd recommend you kick them out except a man don't kick a snake. One time the Teague family owned the whole of Cold Mountain. My farm, your farm, all belonged to his grand-daddy. Teague wanted this place bad. You got it. He's here sniffing out an advantage.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Teague raises his glass across the room.</context>
      <utterance>There's no advantage here, but to celebrate a job well done. Cheers --  -- and thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you planning to come inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm wetter than a fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a good fire going.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody said you were enlisting.  Are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's a war we'll all fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's a mountain we'll all climb, if there's an ocean we'll all drown.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call a thing a war makes it a challenge to some men.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get a picture made?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A tintype, with your gun and your courage on display.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're laughing at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're always carrying a tray.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking a drink over to the negroes in the barn.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes into the night rain. She watches him.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do that. I can't get much wetter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Inman.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman hovers, awkward. Ada appears, awkward.</context>
      <utterance>What can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada comes forward, takes the package.</context>
      <utterance>I have some sheet music. Belonged to my father. No use to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should probably get along.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Inman is more comfortable outdoors. Perhaps we might take a walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A splendid idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to get sheep into this field. A big field doesn't look right without sheep. You're a lucky fellow, Mr. Inman, you've had this view all your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada walking behind, comes alongside the two men, threading her arm into her father's but, by so doing, also arriving next to Inman.</context>
      <utterance>It's a special view. I dragged my poor daughter to Cold Mountain from Charleston because of my Doctors -- they say my heart is weak -- so the air's meant to do me good. But it's the view I think heals.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman looks at Ada. No word.</context>
      <utterance>I have to get on my visits. Can I offer you a ride back into town?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TEAGUE AND HIS MEN COME RIDING UP THE STREET, their horses clearing a path amongst the celebrating crowd. Teague reins in his horse and rides it up against Esco Swanger.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you have your war.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman steps between Esco and Teague, holding the reins of Teague's horse, easy and dangerous.</context>
      <utterance>Those who follow Lincoln, or preach abolition, best keep one eye open when they're sleeping, Old Bogey Man might get you!</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Teague produces a document, which he waves in the air.</context>
      <utterance>Are you the law all of a sudden?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he spurs on his horse, his fellow Home Guard falling in behind, riding on over the ridge. Inman walks to Ada.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, son. Home Guard for Haywood County. I'm the law from today. You all go fight now. We'll watch your sweethearts.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might be safer back in Charleston.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts a hand on his arm for a second. They both want to get to the point of declaration but don't know how. They stand, people noisy around them, those about to leave, those about to be left.</context>
      <utterance>But then who'll be waiting for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he does so, making his meaning clear for her to follow.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to walk back inside the Chapel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the door opens again and it's Ada. She's dismayed to see her father.</context>
      <utterance>Did you want a quiet word?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just some quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He indicates they should both leave. Inman sits at a bench.</context>
      <utterance>Of course Ada.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll daresay Dr. O'Brien'll want to do a test or two.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monroe smiles in acknowledgement, gets back in the trap. Ada heads into the store.</context>
      <utterance>And then there'll be a coffee or two, a brandy or two...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has something else. Wrapped in paper.</context>
      <utterance>I found you this book. William Bartram. They tell me it's good. I think he writes about these parts, the author, so... Inman takes it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this...  I'm not smiling in it. I don't know how to do that, hold a smile, so now I'm solemn...</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ada...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HE KISSES HER, pressing into her, his arm circling her waist. Below them the sound of a MARCHING BAND. It's the RECRUITMENT PARADE and brings Rourke and Butcher racing down the stairs. Inman pulls away from Ada as the boys hurtle for the front door.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Says he ain't about to die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My condolences to you all.  Keep an eye on the negro. They want what the white man got -- all of you watch out your brave boys give their lives to war and meantime your slaves carry murder, rape and arson to your firesides.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only slaves within twenty miles labor on my farm. They're good Christians and I'll vouchsafe for them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking -- at this moment, I don't know why -- you're looking exactly like your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every time you see the doctor you get melancholy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He listens to my heart and I get emotional.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She squeezes his arm.</context>
      <utterance>He gives you alcohol and you get emotional.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We commiserate about the folly of this terrible war.  Do you worry when there's no word from him?  From Mr. Inman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then they see THE FAMILY OF SLAVES turn off the road as their cabriolet approaches, running away into the fields.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. But then I've tried counting the number of words which passed between Mr. Inman and me.  Is that a bonfire? So close to the barns.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monroe gets out of the cabriolet and runs into the fields after the retreating family, who are carrying bundles, chairs, personal items, all loaded up. Ada has already taken the reins and has driven up to the house. THE BARN IN WHICH THE SLAVE FAMILY HAD LIVED IS ON FIRE. Monroe catches one of the women, remonstrates with her. She's upset, distressed, one of her sons comes back, pushes Monroe to the ground. They hurry away. Monroe gets up, hurries to the fire.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Stop there! Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure swings round. IT'S AN EFFIGY, A GROTESQUE</context>
      <utterance>No, Daddy, it's not real.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada turns and runs off.</context>
      <utterance>What is wrong with us all?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monroe stands and considers the flames. Ada turns back once more to see him -- a small man silhouetted against the blaze.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get help.  Keep away from the flames.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women try to process this, the attitude.</context>
      <utterance>Most of these men will be dead by the morning or, if they're stubborn, by nightfall. I have other men outside in the quadrangle waiting for the beds.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, any kind word will be a blessing. One woman is overpowered by the stench, gags.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women begin to approach the beds.</context>
      <utterance>It's the heat. I'm sorry. They rot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MRS. MORGAN, nervous, decent, sits next to INMAN. His mouth is moving. She doesn't know what he's saying.</context>
      <utterance>Don't pray. If they're not God fearing you can stir up a hornet's nest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bends to him again. His voice is a faint croak.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, you want water?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor is on his exit, stops at the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Pigeon River. Little East Fork.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I don't know what he's saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They ramble. Names of loved ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This man is dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.  For your Providence, Oh lord, we thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amen. That was the last of the ham.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was delicious.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to learn how to cook.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was going to say something in Chapel. Perhaps some of the womenfolk will volunteer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't have people coming here and cooking for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my fault. I should have raised you less like a companion and more like a young woman. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sorry, but I don't know how we'll get through another winter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONROE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada takes the dishes away. He gets out his papers, his pen and ink.</context>
      <utterance>Will you play me something? Something peaceful while I look over my sermon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are various dates, which she decodes.</context>
      <utterance>It's come to you by way of Virginia.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not too recent -- written this past winter. I'm afraid I can't read who it's from. Dear Mr. Inman,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman is very still. Then, eyes glinting with determination, gives a TINY NOD.</context>
      <utterance>-- at the end of my wits, so now I say to you, plain as I can, come back to me. Come back to me is my request.  Then something I can't read, something, come back to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By order of Zebulon Vance, Governor of this great state of North Carolina: any soldier turned deserter is guilty of treason and shall be hunted down like a dog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Official is flanked by Teague, Bosey and the twins, puffed up with self-importance. Ada has to walk around him to enter the store.</context>
      <utterance>-- Any man takes in a deserter is likewise guilty of treason.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Home Guard is powered to enter any place it sees fit, without notice or constraint. Names of all deserters will be posted in every town, published in every newspaper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a letter for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CASTLEREAGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go to the back of the store, to a screened-off area. Mrs. Castlereagh hands her over a packet of material. There's another, more furtive, transaction to take place. Mrs Castlereagh hands over a second parcel as if it were narcotics. Ada tears at the wrapping. It's a parcel of books.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing -- we're getting no post through at all -- although if you slip out back the material you ordered has arrived.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CASTLEREAGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If folks knew I was taking deliveries from the North.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Thank you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CASTLEREAGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sooner we lose this war the better. Already one boy gone, another with his leg took off at the knee. That's enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CASTLEREAGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I know is they say not one boy in ten from these mountains is coming home again and most of them are deserters.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's taken me too long, but I've come to pay my respects.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada takes them. She is very queasy with these dead animals.</context>
      <utterance>I reckoned you might need fattening up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This house must bring bad luck. Killed my granddaddy to lose it, then my daddy died on account of not having it, then your daddy died on account of getting it. We should burn it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't somebody try?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lot to manage without help. Need a hand with that pump?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm happy to volunteer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not to volunteer for the war?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The war? I wanted to go. But you know: too old, too literate. Plus I got no spleen. Lost it from a horse's kick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got no spleen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the thing about an organ. You don't know you need it till you lost it.  I want to clear this path. I can just as soon do it and talk as stand around and talk. Then you can say men beat a path to your door.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd really prefer it if you didn't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you rather I did my job?  See if there's any material I should confiscate. For the war effort.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was raised in the good manners of the South where a gentleman doesn't enter a house with a woman alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good manners didn't quite make it to these mountains. If it don't yield meat, or you can't sit on it, or suck on it...  And you're sleeping all right? These cold dark nights?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sleeping fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and stops at the gate, runs his hands through his hair and uses the grease to ease the hinge. Then steps up onto his horse, and rides away. Ada watches him. Shudders.</context>
      <utterance>It's going to be a long hard winter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're seen from ground level, through a boxwood, as their feet patrol the ground, turn away from the door, and then retreat, their voices drifting away. Ada is there, crouching in her hidey-hole, a blanket on the ground, her book. She wants to reveal herself, but is too embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Ada! Ada, It's Sally.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you look at the state of this place!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this a ROOSTER, black and gold, struts into the boxwood. As the rooster approaches, Ada shudders, tries to shoo it away without alerting her presence. Ada peers through the boxwood as Sally and Esco close the gate and recede. The rooster comes at her again. She rises up, kicking out at it, while he flares his wings, spurs flaying at her. Ada runs from the boxwood, tormented by the triumphant rooster, which continues to fly and scratch, driving her into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Poor soul. She's got nobody and nothing and three hundred acres of misery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BLIND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting better all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLIND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't hurry. War's almost done.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you take your wound?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLIND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's shoveling some peanuts into a twist of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Before I was born. Never saw a thing in this world, not a tree a gun or a woman. Though I put my hand on all three. Couple of things I felt back there I'd sure liked to have had a long look at.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would you give for that? To have your eyeballs back for ten minutes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLIND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten minutes! Wouldn't give an Indian head cent. I fear it might turn me hateful.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's sure what seeing's done to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLIND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't the way I meant it. You said ten minutes. It's having a thing and then the loss I'm talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we don't agree. There's not much I wouldn't give for ten minutes of someplace.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLIND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someplace or someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLIND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You watch yourself. They're shooting men who take themselves a walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman settles in the seat. The Barber contemplates his scraggy beard, the livid, scabbed wound on his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Next.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll cut your hair, but I ain't about to shave you. That thing opens up, your head's liable to falloff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Sally Swanger calls out from the field. She's concerned at Ada's gaunt, ragged appearance. Ada waits for her approach.</context>
      <utterance>Ada...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're skinny as a whippet, girl -- you're coming indoors with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. I'm not -- I need to clean some clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she folds her arm into Ada's. They walk up the lane.</context>
      <utterance>Great God, you ever looked at my husband! I can't get him to wear decent Church clothes Christmas morning. Hang on to me, the wind'll blow you over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go back to that dark house. There's a bed here, least till our boys get home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That your daddy's coat?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was saying to Sally, I wasn't expecting to be visiting, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to chuckle, then Ada, too, then Sally.</context>
      <utterance>Don't suit you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get up to your place this week.  She's mad at me --</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't expect -</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- more than I can do to keep this place half-managed. I'm ready-to stop, I tell you. I just want to sit on my porch with Sal, watch my boys in the field, holler good job! every hour or so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about your people in Charleston?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no people. And no money. My father had some bonds and investments. They're worthless now, of course, the war has... they're not worth anything.  I love it here. In spite of everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look from Sally.</context>
      <utterance>And waiting on a feller.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look down our well.  She should! Look down our well with a mirror, you'll see the future. S'what they say.  You do it! Don't make that face.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it ain't rightly Christian, but it's what folks do, like when they dangle a needle over the belly to see if you're carrying a boy or a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of mirror?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The image is clearer. The trees sharpen, the figure walking, the steep incline of the corridor, all fiercely black and white as if it were a carpet of snow and black hieroglyphs of trees, and crows flying. The trick of the glass and the watery disc of the well surface. A buzzing in Ada's ears, something like a distant music. Then the figure seems to suddenly pitch forwards, but at that moment, Ada -- canted over, getting dizzy has to move and the image flies away, replaced with the sky, the flash of the setting sun.</context>
      <utterance>I tried many a time, never saw a dickybird.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada's faint. She sits up, blank, a little shaken.</context>
      <utterance>You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesterday I found myself crouched over a well like a mad woman, which I suppose I have become</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- or wished I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ada looks up from her writing with a start. She covers her letter, guiltily, instinctively. In front of her, at the gate, is A YOUNG RAWBONED, FERAL WOMAN, OF INDETERMINATE ORIGINS. She is barefoot, and dressed in a hand-dye_ shift of blue. Her name is RUBY.</context>
      <utterance>That cow wants milking.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that letter ain't urgent, the cow is -- is what I'm saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada is instantly defensive, intimidated.</context>
      <utterance>Old Lady Swanger says you need some help. Here I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need help, I need, I do need help, but I need a laborer -- there's plowing and rough work and -- I think there's been a misunderstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the rake for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rake?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't for gardening, that's for sure. Number one -- you got a horse I can plow all day. I'm a worker. Number two there's no man better than me cause there's no man around who ain't old or full of mischief. I know your plight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My plight?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I hard to hear cause you keep repeating everything. I'm not looking for money, never cared for it and now it ain't worth nothing. I expect to board and eat at the same table. I'm not a servant. Do you get my meaning?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not a servant.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People'll have to empty their own night jars, that's my point.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm not planning to work while you watch neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a yes or a no?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's half the day yet. Let's make a start. My name's Ruby. I know your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rake: there's a rooster devil, I'm sure of it. He's Lucifer himself. I go near him he's at me with his spurs.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada gets up, nods to the corner of the yard. Ruby goes over. The Rooster gathers himself up for a new opponent.</context>
      <utterance>I despise a flogging rooster. Where is he?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at him, then continue on their way.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!  I'd pay a dollar for an egg. A piece of cheese.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ada? Ada? You up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.  It's still dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell the cows that. It's late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to eat something.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you have to get up earlier.  What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A novel.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to carry a book carry one you can write in --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks back at Ada for a reaction.</context>
      <utterance>-- we got our own story. Called Black Cove Farm: a catastrophe.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're heading for the stable.</context>
      <utterance>I can spell it, too. C-a-t-a-s-t-r-o- phe. Learned the same place you did, in the schoolroom. That's one of the first words they taught me. Ruby Thewes, you are a ca-t-a-s-t-r-o-p-h- e...</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada half-asleep, obedient, stunned by this energy.</context>
      <utterance>You mucking out?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three years I was in school before my daddy -- saying God rest his soul is like wishing him what he had in life, cause he lived to rest, he was born tired -- before my daddy decided there was better use for my backside than have it sat all day in front of a blackboard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada scribbles, walks, scribbles.</context>
      <utterance>Number One -- layout a winter garden for cool season crops: turnips, onions, cabbage, greens.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number Two: patch the shingles on the barn roof. Do we have a maul and froe?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maul?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>M-a-u-l.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clear and turn this field. No harm done letting it go fallow, now we'll do well.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number fifteen</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number sixteen: let's get a martin colony going in the Gourd House. Keep away crows. You got one thing in abundance on this farm and that's crows.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a Gourd House?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's survival. On them trees.  You got a cider press or would that be wishing on a blessing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruby whoops, jogs away. Ada, exhausted takes a bite of an apple, watches her.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, yes, I think we do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let go. Just back up, nice and steady, do this all in reverse, you're going to end up with her draped back over your animal.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't pull that trigger. I am a man of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've killed several of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean I am God's minister.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What part of God's business is throwing a woman down a gorge.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's retreating, on his way back to the horse.</context>
      <utterance>A slave woman, can you see that in this light? She's black as a bucket of tar.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has the girl back on the horse. Inman brings the torch up to his face. It's tear-stained.</context>
      <utterance>Drugged her. Like you would a butterfly. And I care for her, that's the heartbreak of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's got my bastard in her belly. What kind of pistol is that I never saw the like of it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm begging you. It's better you blowout my brains than return me to this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where does she live?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In our house. She sleeps in our kitchen. You don't know me, friend, but the good Lord punished me with want. I am all appetite. That's all I do all day is want: food, the female parts...</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're in the town's main drag now. There's a Chapel and next to it, a small house.</context>
      <utterance>Shut your mouth. I don't want a sermon every time I ask a question.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This your place?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear God of misery.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to put her back where she sleeps.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do that the Members will lynch me. Consorting with a nigger, adultery, siring a bastard while serving as their preacher. We're a strict congregation we've churched men for picking up a fiddle on the sabbath.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disgusted, Inman approaches the front door of the house.</context>
      <utterance>So you reckoned to kill her.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he leads Inman down a side path.</context>
      <utterance>There's a back door. Have pity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks longing at the girl as he puts the blanket around her shoulders. He turns to Inman.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I was going to do a grievous wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>VESEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman is incredulous that he thinks he can just go to bed...</context>
      <utterance>You tasted dark meat? Sweet as liquorice. I think I should go back up to my wife. She wakes at the slightest noise.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You find me some paper and a pen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman has pulled a handkerchief from Veasey's jacket. He stuffs it into his mouth, cutting this diatribe short. And then he walks away leaving Veasey tied to the tree, cursing through the handkerchief.</context>
      <utterance>You're not entitled to judge me! You're nothing but an outlier, plain as daylight!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning. Pigs: you have any loose in the woods?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. What? No. We bought our hams.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up some discarded laundry, contemplates the overflowing laundry basket.</context>
      <utterance>There's a world more to a hog than the two hams! Lard, for example, we'll need plenty --</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The catastrophe of Ada Monroe's laundry.  I can feel you shutting your eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this wood?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Locust?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's North?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>North is, North is --</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name me three herbs growing wild on this farm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't! I can't! All right? I can talk about farming in Latin. Will that do? I can read French. I know Harmony and Counterpoint. I know my Bible. I can name the principal rivers of Europe, but don't ask me to name one stream in this county. I can embroider, but I can't darn, I can arrange cut flowers, but I can't grow them. If a thing has a function, if I might do something with it, it wasn't considered suitable.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They manage to get the first line of rail set down.</context>
      <utterance>Ruby, you could ask why? about pretty much everything to do with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This fence is about the first thing I've ever done that'll produce an actual result.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An old-fashioned look from Ada...</context>
      <utterance>So you never wrapped your legs around this Inman?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>FERRYGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For five dollars I wouldn't give a parched man a dipper of this riverwater.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sign says ferry, five dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRYGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This look like a ferry? My Daddy's dead, or gone off to the Federals, don't matter which. I'm the way across now.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the name of this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRYGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dog barks in the distance. Getting closer. Inman turns to the sound. The Ferrygirl is well aware of her leverage.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing but the mighty Cape Fear River, is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRYGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody crosses this water unless they're running from someplace. Some cross one way, some the other: makes no difference, they're all running. You want to wait for your friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can give you thirty dollars script.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRYGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Inman is astonished to see VEASEY stumble out of the trees. His head is shaved, his face bruised and swollen, his clothes castoffs and ill-fitting, cinched at the waist with rope. He stumbles towards Inman, urging him to get on with the journey.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Hey! Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets straight into the canoe.</context>
      <utterance>Keep going. We're both in trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Homeguard. Made me tell them all about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shouts, more barking. Inman jumps in the canoe, and they're off. The Ferrygirl turns the boat around, rows them away from the jetty with the grace of someone doing something for the thousandth time.</context>
      <utterance>I should have shot you when I had the chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not looking for revenge, by the way. For what you did to me. No, I'm a Pilgrim now, like you, traveling the road, paying our dues, relying on the kindness of strangers.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're nothing like me and the last thing I want right now is a conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You recall Job in the scriptures? I will give free utterance to my complaint. I will speak in the bitterness of my soul. That's our friend here...  They cut off my hair. Which was hard. I was vain about my hair.  I had good curls. But I deserved it. I'm the Reverend Veasey. Have I seen you in church? Inman sits, scouring the bank for sign of his pursuers. The sun is sinking fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRYGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has no love for the river. Another gurgle of viscous bubbles around the canoe.</context>
      <utterance>I'm saving for a cowhide, and when I get it I aim to get a saddle made, and when I get me a saddle I'll save for a horse, and when I got a horse I'll throw on the saddle, and then you won't see my sorry ass round this swamp again.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRYGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catfish. 'gator. Keep your hand in the boat. Already looks like some critter chewed his neck.  Thirty more dollars, we can go to the cabin. I'll pull this dress over my head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman nods, coughs. And Veasey AIMS A KICK at Inman's head, knocking him back into the mud.</context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, god!</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figure that righteous, given our history. Otherwise I'd bear a grudge on our journey.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nowhere I'm going with you except to Hellfire!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agricola poetis viam non monstrat.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which means?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The farmer does not point out the road to a poet.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which means? Should be the other way round</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which means, I suppose, which means the poet should know where he's going.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's no wonder you're helpless and hopeless if it takes this long to fix your hair.  Say some more.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terra mutata non mutat mores.  It's appalling what's in my head.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's appalling what's in my head?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it means: A change of place does not change a character.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that's surely true even in English.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can keep those earrings.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't keep anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to keep the bangles. They were my mother's.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that's all. The rest is for trading. Else they can bury you in your finery.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a small mirror on a stand. It has Inman's picture stuck in it. She picks it up, removing the tintype, and holding it up for Ruby to see her hairstyle.</context>
      <utterance>You're done.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the mirror and shows Ada her simple plait.</context>
      <utterance>Good God! Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the earrings back in the pile.</context>
      <utterance>Takes two minutes. That's what I like.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much do you love that piano?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're careful we'll get through the winter now. I made old man Roy give me ten of those sheep on account of I said they were so small put together they were no bigger than six proper sheep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father always wanted sheep on this land.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're working as they talk, taking the sacks into the larder, putting out stuff for the evening meal.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry you had to lose your piano. I cut off my hair once, for money. My daddy got two dollars for it. Made a wig for a rich feller in Raleigh.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stobrod called himself a musician -- my daddy -- he could play six tune on a fiddle. Got himself shot dead at Petersburg. I was like his goat or some creature tethered to a post. He left me once, up the mountains. I was eight. He was gone over two weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Ruby.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was all right! He'd walk forty miles for liquor and not forty inches for kindness.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a pause. Ruby not easy with her emotions. Abruptly she jumps up.</context>
      <utterance>Never met her. We're the same in that regard. He said she was -- he told me a thousand stories -- she was a wolf or an indian or a donkey. Don't say much for him, except you know he'd be fast to work up a sweat on a tree if he thought there was pleasure in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's cows to milk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Look at this!  This is a good saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not yours. You take it, you make us another enemy. You're a Christian -- don' t you know your commandments?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman is vexed, walks away. Veasey follows, experimenting with the saw's music when flexed. Inman stalks on.</context>
      <utterance>You'll find the good Lord very flexible on the subject of property. We could do a lot with this saw...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman suddenly stops, scowling, puts up a hand, listens. Inman carefully scouts the track then, with great caution, edges towards the river bank. A HEAVY SET MAN labours in the water. He's contemplating THE HUGE BLACK CARCASS OF A BULL which has slipped into the ford and died. The man is wet and exasperated.</context>
      <utterance>Why you in such a hurry the whole time?  Hurry or slow the destination is always the same. It's only the journey that is different. That's either in the Good Book or I made it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man turns, his spirit evidently lifted by the prospect of help. His name is JUNIOR. He's working on roping the animal.</context>
      <utterance>Good day to you!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Veasey is immediately an authority on bull removal.</context>
      <utterance>My old bull, wandered off and died in this here creek. Fouled up our water is how I found it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three men contemplate the carcass, swatting away the swarms of flies. Junior offers a swig from a jug of liquor. Inman refuses, Veasey takes a long pull, shudders happily.</context>
      <utterance>This is a tricky one.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name for the Bull's member is a tassel. I learned that and never forgot it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reckon I need a train of mules.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting an idea. My saw is the remedy. Let's saw up some wood and make levers.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks into the wood.</context>
      <utterance>Lever him out. This'll work!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you two sports heading?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know where he's heading. I'm going down the road. And I got a good way to go before nightfall.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charitable of you to make a stop. Ain't for me to be curious.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you work this damn thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the saw, walks to the bull, gets on one side, indicates Junior should go to the other.</context>
      <utterance>Give me that saw.  Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they begin to SAW OFF THE BULL'S NECK. LATER, and they're in A VILE STEW OF BLOOD AND INNARDS. The stomach opens and its contents gush into the creek. Veasey is disgusted, draws back. The two other men haul up the rest of the animal onto the banks. They're exhausted.</context>
      <utterance>Let's do this in chapters.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might want to leave off that water for a day or two.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There'll be a tang, I'd imagine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's my place. Hope you can stomach a yard chock-full of females. Brought my woman home, she showed up with her three so-called sisters and their brats. The noise in that place is something awful. It's why I go hunting.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks a bit crooked.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is on a bit of a tilt. Them females. They all roll down one end each night!</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Roll me over!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- In the clover</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They guffaw, delighted in the alcohol haze. Veasey suddenly exclaims, hand in the air, rushes into the bushes.</context>
      <utterance>One good fart -- that'll tip over!</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God of my God! Hallelujah! Hallelujah!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Israelites! The tribes of Israel are about to flee from the banks of Egypt! Hallelujah!</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got a shit coming on. It's overdue.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he's a Preacher? Like a Christian?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a Christian.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women consider the men, then disappear back inside.</context>
      <utterance>These two boys is stopping for supper. They're on the road to Atonement.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Atonement is not a place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what is it when it's at home?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are fine examples of the female.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take them all and leave the saw. Be a sight more use.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHYLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they want to get in a tub there's an hour before food.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They love to scrub a man.  Put the water on the boil.  It's my liquor, gets their titties swinging.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God damn!  I was right about sheep droppings those stools -- like rock hard. Quite astonishing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHYLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's battered flesh.  I could work a finger in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a hero. Took that wound at Petersburg.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't know what I am.  Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHYLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's shy, ain't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait up a few minutes, I'll be in that tub, then we'll see who's a shy one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHYLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A second woman comes to the door. Dolly.</context>
      <utterance>I want to poke my thumb in his holes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lila says supper's up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>LILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior grins, looks over at Inman, then nudges Veasey.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gone now. Look! His eyes have gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dolly?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>S'me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dolly, Lila, Shyla and Mae. That's a poem. That's a poem. He begins to recite, has a verse in his mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dolly, Lila, Shyla and Mae  Da-da da-da da-da dae...  ...there's a poem there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving soon as I'm full.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a bunch of traps needs visiting. I'll be back tomorrow, before dark. You'll still be here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my fervent prayer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My house is your house.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like to wash their hands and pray.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say again?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dolly, Lila, Shyla and Mae.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman gets up suddenly, sways.</context>
      <utterance>That's Job. Don't say much but even liquored up there's a preacher in him.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he stumbles over to the fire where he instantly curls up.</context>
      <utterance>I'll say my goodbyes, got miles and miles to go before sunset.  I'll just quickly lie down.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up, wanders out of the door. Junior's eyes glint. He jerks his head towards the girls then in the direction of the smokehouse.</context>
      <utterance>I'm heading for that smokehouse and I'm ready to be washed clean of my dirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up his gun and leaves Dolly gathering up the children and herding them out.</context>
      <utterance>You go tend to him.  I'll be seeing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shyla stays, Mae having gone off after Veasey. Lila waits until the children have gone. They consider Inman supine by the fire.</context>
      <utterance>Come on you -- get!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lila shepherds Shyla out, shuts the door, swigs from the jug, walks over to Inman, then turns to the big table and pushes pots and plates way down to one end to make a playing field. Then she bends over the prostrate Inman.</context>
      <utterance>He's mine. You can go rub yourself off on the Preacher.  Gonna make him hug me till I grunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman stirs, glazed.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to see what Mamma's got for you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't move, except to sway, eyes glazed. She turns.</context>
      <utterance>You just get on and ride me all the way to China.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's kneeling now, her dress hunched up around her middle, working the front of Inman's pants. He's in a swoon, surrendering to her, getting aroused, his hand cupping her head. ON CUE, THE DOOR CRASHES OPEN AND HE'S STARING DOWN</context>
      <utterance>You shy? You need a hand?  Let's have a look see what we can muster.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ada Monroe and Ruby Thewes! Look at you both!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at us both what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a coupla scarecrows after a thunderstorm.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need a scarecrow, birds eating up half our winter garden.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sally's right. We should both stop toiling and stand a while with our arms stretch out. I'll volunteer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got something for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For all your kindness. Coffee. And a pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's real coffee. It ain't hickory and dirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you both.  Ruby, I look forward to this. We all do. Esco and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good God in Heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sally's strangely awkward, lingering at the door, staring at the gifts...</context>
      <utterance>I'm still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be getting along.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That strike you as odd?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stood at her front door?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sally?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number one -- I know that woman all my life. I never stood outside her house -- she'd invite a wolf inside if it knocked on the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps, I don't know, perhaps she was busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number two -- Old Man Swanger was inside that house: I could smell his pipe burning. Number three -- look at these fields.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She contemplated the stubble fields they're passing.</context>
      <utterance>What about them?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We came by here a week ago, they were waist high in hay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The horses plough on. Inman shouts to BROWN, the leader.</context>
      <utterance>He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody pays any attention. He has to drag the body.</context>
      <utterance>This man's dead!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Veasey looks at Inman.</context>
      <utterance>Am I so altered that they don't see me? Somebody walks by with a young child.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The child stops, looks without recognizing, is tugged away from the chain gang by his mother. One of the other prisoners, SHEFFIELD, leans in to Inman, his voice low.</context>
      <utterance>I christened that child.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEFFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking to get out of this. They drag us back to fight -- we're just target practice for the Federal boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You run, we're all running with you, the lame and the stupid, of which we number both.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEFFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either way we're fucked. Run or don't run.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GROUP OF SLAVES ARE WALKING BY, CARRYING SACKS. One of the women is pregnant. Veasey studies the group, sees the pregnant woman, recognizes her.</context>
      <utterance>Just give me some warning so I can tell the guard -- I'm not getting shot again for some cause I don't believe in.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mas?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it well with you?  I've been repenting for what I did. I've walked the road of atonement.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your curls is all gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rebecca, reluctant, rejoins the other slaves, walks away with them, but then turns back to look at Veasey. She clearly cares about him. And seeing her has somehow broken his heart. He turns away from Inman, towards Sheffield.</context>
      <utterance>God Bless you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEASEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm with you. I got a baby coming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's been in the corncrib.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a coon or possum. Scratched out a fist hole in the side. This place! I'm telling you -- we grow, others eat. I'll go into town, take the last of the cider and trade for a trap.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you looking to catch?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With that trap.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got some critter stealing our corn.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still but the two of you up there, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruby rides on. She rides around the bend -- she's not far from the Swanger farm.</context>
      <utterance>When we get a cold night, camped out, trying to keep the rule of law, protecting girls like you from Federals and deserters, that's a thought warms us  ain't it? -- the two of you up there on my Grand-daddy's farm, dressed in men's clothes. Warms us right up. What you got in the sacks?  Looks like human heads! Eh? Looks like a bunch of heads. We got competition!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ruby...</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not stopping, Sally. I'm not snooping neither. Just you should know Teague and his boys are lurking down by Pigeon River, the old mill.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She emerges, with a bowl of water, rags, washes his face, pushing back his hair to look at his wound, puts a finger to the gash on his neck professional in her appraisal. Inman is barely conscious, he groans, trying to defend himself.</context>
      <utterance>Mind that Billy, he's the jealous kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pay no attention to me. What happened to your head?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fighting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your neck?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Different fighting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the color of a cadaver. I'll fix you. I can fix you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister -- you could fix me I'd be in your everlasting debt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Debts, fighting -- them words don't mean much round here. For the record, I'm a female of the species.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruby gets off the horse, and they start unloading sacks.</context>
      <utterance>The hat's a nice touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cried for my Daddy. I dressed up the scarecrow in his suit and he came back, his arms out, said you never cried enough, you never cried enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well now you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruby opens the sacks.</context>
      <utterance>Then I thought, it's not my Daddy, it's my sweetheart. I saw him once that way, when I looked down Sally's well. So I dressed the scarecrow in the dress I wore the day he left. In case his spirit flies over looking out for me.  That looks terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cabbages.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bargained like Lucifer. We can make all kinds of good eating.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such as?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cabbage. Slaw, sauerkraut, cabbage soup, fried cabbage, stuffed cabbage...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The riders slowly fan out, almost as if choreographed.</context>
      <utterance>Afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't spread out. Why they spreading out?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esco comes over the rail fence, his gun loose in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not spreading out. I'm sitting here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never knew a man worked in his field with a shotgun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a war on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to fish out a tobacco pouch. Esco's gun swings up. Teague shows him the leather pouch, shrugs, starts to make a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Got to watch out for the Bogey Man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mo examines his breeches for a dust mark, wipes it off, retreating in a turkey walk of examining and dusting.</context>
      <utterance>Get off my land.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your boys come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't seen my boys in four years. They're fighting other boys, not old men and women.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He means us. He's referring there to us.  So you won't care if we take a look around?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I gotta give you? A chicken? A lamb?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right then.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thing is -- you got one barrel and there's five of us. Not a fair fight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mo backs away. Sally is screaming. She watches, helpless, as Esco dies in front of her, the sheet growing a darker red.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got your bait. Set it on the hook.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get this damn thing off her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Lord in heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada runs over. They struggle, can't lift it. Sally's lips are moving.</context>
      <utterance>Ada, I can't get this off her!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bends down, listens to her. Looks up at Ada.</context>
      <utterance>What darling? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's saying don't bother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs a thick log off the stack, staggers back and in a second they've inserted it into the fence and levered it up and away from Sally's hands. They fall back onto the dirt. Ruby cradles Sally. Ada nods towards the well.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruby looks over at the well, then at Ada.</context>
      <utterance>There's someone down there. I think it's Esco.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This world won't stand long. God won't let it stand this way long.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have I been sleeping?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not long enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stop here. I'm a deserter. They find me here things could be bad for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She calls over a little goat. It ambles over affectionately and nuzzles into her hand. She strokes it and scratches under the chin. The creature gets increasingly tranquil.</context>
      <utterance>What they going to do? Cut short my young life? Sit down before you fall down.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long you been up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What year are we? '63?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last time I checked it was '64.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd say twenty six years.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty six years!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's still stroking the goat. It looks as if it's asleep.</context>
      <utterance>I could move on anytime. I've seen most of the world anyway, Richmond in the North, south almost to Charleston. You're going somewhere or you are somewhere, what's the difference?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a single motion she has a knife in her hand and has SLIT THE THROAT OF THE GOAT, putting the bowl underneath its neck to catch the blood, still stroking the goat, which blinks as if it were only surprised and not dying.</context>
      <utterance>I've learned a person can survive off pretty much of a goat. I can't abide a chicken, but a goat gives you company and milk and cheese and then, when you need it, good meat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you've been fighting?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could be at killing for days sometimes, in the hand to hand, my feet against the feet of my enemy and I always killed him and he never killed me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gave it a try, to look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this she's shucked the skin off the goat with the authority of someone who's done this a thousand times.</context>
      <utterance>See I think there's a plan. There's a design. For each and every one of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the goat is now thin and pink, eyes bulging, a piece of meat.</context>
      <utterance>You look at nature, a bird flies somewhere, picks up a seed, shits the seed out, a plant grows. Bird's got a job, seed's got a job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman is circumspect, views the stub lozenge with suspicion.</context>
      <utterance>Take one of these now with your food.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman puts it in his mouth, gags at the taste of it. She hands him a beaker with milk to wash it down.</context>
      <utterance>Swallow it. If you die I'll give you your money back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts steaming the poppies.</context>
      <utterance>Our minds aren't made to hold on to the particulars of pain, the way we do bliss.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's true...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's her name?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ada.  -- Sometimes I think I'm crazy when I'm just hungry --  Ada Monroe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And is she waiting for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maddy pricks open the poppies and collects their opium, then hands Inman the liquid.</context>
      <utterance>She was. I don't know. Or if she'd know me. I'm like the boy who goes out in winter for firewood comes back in the spring with a whistle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drinks the laudanum she's made.</context>
      <utterance>Now drink this. It visits the pain. And you'll sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had to put myself in the way of people's kindness.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She dips a cloth in the steaming water, unbuttons his shirt. She has a crock of what looks like treacle and vaseline. She smears this salve over the neck wound and into his scalp. Inman surrenders to the drug.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you found it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The passenger pigeons fly south, the berries ripen. Whether I see them or not, whether a man dies, or a war is won.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He obliges. She grimaces at the state of it, where the chain has chewed into the flesh. Gets to work.</context>
      <utterance>That's the laudanum getting to you. That's good. Say something more.  Raise that up for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slides off the stool and lays on the floor. Maddy goes over to her cot and pulls off a blanket which she drapes over him.</context>
      <utterance>She gave me a book. Ada Monroe. Man by the name of Bartram. Wrote about his travels. I carried that book through every battle. I left it someplace, got to get it back. Sometimes just reading the name of a place near home -- Sorell Cove, Fire Scale Ridge -- was enough to bring me to tears. Thing is I've been thinking -- those places belonged to people before us, to the Indian -- and he had a different name. What did he call Sorell Cove? How can a name not even the real name break your heart? It's her, she's the place I'm heading. And I hardly know her. So how can a person who's maybe not even a real person -- I don't know what I'm talking about -- I have to close my eyes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raiding our corn. Got him in the trap. That's him yelping.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to shoot him!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want him to shoot me.  Can you fire this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head towards the corn crib, bundled up against the cold. A MAN IS KNEELING AT THE CORN CRIB, perfectly caught in the art of stealing, his head forced away from view. Ruby hands Ada the gun and approaches, warily.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen up -- you got a barrel trained on your rear-end.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me out of this dang thing. My fist's about to drop off.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a weapon?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No ma'am. I'm begging you. I'm already on my knees, otherwise I'd get down on them.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unbelievable! Stobrod Thewes.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ruby? God damn!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks up to him and KICKS HIM HARD AS SHE CAN ON HIS</context>
      <utterance>That's my daddy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just so's you know -- I can eat while she's doing this -- in case you're holding off.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just so's you know -- you're not eating inside. Number One -- they hang people round here for taking in deserters. Number two -- even if they gave out prizes -- you'd still eat outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're scarred.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm what?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your heart. Scarred. I did wrong to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be scarred. You'd be really scarred if I hadn't wrapped them trap teeth in sacking. Which was her idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good God!</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wrote fifty tunes with you in mind. Ruby this, Ruby that, Ruby with the eyes that sparkle.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Let's agree: you beat me, you abandoned me, you ignored me, you beat me some more -- all of that is better than Ruby with the eyes that sparkle!</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm changed. People change. War changes people something terrible.  Ruby's told you -- I've no doubt -- I wasn't always the best...</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were an asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't disagree with that. I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get him out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruby walks over with a crock, wrapped in a cloth.</context>
      <utterance>Music's changed me. I'm full of music, darling. I wish I'd brung my fiddle Hey Ruby! Got a new fiddle -- it's got a little snake's rattle in the body -- took it off a dead federal in Virginia. That's a beautiful fiddle. It's full of tunes, Ruby. Don't know if it's from that little rattle locked up in it, or from something untied my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all set.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Bless you both.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't you got a proper coat?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darling, I'm fine. And you just say the word, I won't come back neither. I don't want to put either you or your mistress here in any bother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not Ruby's employer.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay, who is?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody.  I'll make up food for you, you come Sundays before it's light, I'll leave it behind the Old Frazier Mill.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he's gone. Ruby scowls. FIDDLE MUSIC BEGINS.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know who really needs a coat, darling, is my partner, fat boy name of Pangle. We're hiding up in the caves and he feels the cold like a thin man, but ain't no coat'll fit him.  I love you, Ruby. In case the sky falls on our head. You're a good girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is so full of manure, that man, we could lay him on the dirt and grow another one just like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's Stobrod Thewes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is and that's the last you'll see of him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's medicine and goatmeat. You're sick of both.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him an ancient flintlock pistol.</context>
      <utterance>I have a deal to thank you for.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns, abruptly, mingles in with her goats. Inman nods, knows that she doesn't want a fuss, although he wants to make one, and turns himself, heads away from the caravan.</context>
      <utterance>And that's just for show, or -- if you can get close enough -- a wild turkey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- a source of little visible delight, But necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She ain't gonna marry Linton, is she? She said -- whatever our souls are made of his and mine are the same. You can't say that and then marry Linton.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not waiting until tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lies back in her bed. Ruby takes the book, lies across the bottom of the bed, as Ada goes to sleep.</context>
      <utterance>Ruby, I'm falling asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little visible delight, but necessary. I like that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Inman accepts this as a rebuttal, and trudges back towards the road.</context>
      <utterance>Can I at least sleep in the corn crib -- just for some shelter? I'll be on my way come morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Inman turns. A gap in the door appears, the figure barely seen.</context>
      <utterance>I've got a rifle.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The baby's crying behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Fair enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's some beans and corn pone, all I got. You better come in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman takes out his gun. She starts, terrified.</context>
      <utterance>I'm alone here, as you can see, with my baby. I need to believe you mean no harm.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns it handle forwards and offers it to her.</context>
      <utterance>No, I mean to give it to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want it. I had my way they'd take metal altogether out of this world. Every blade, every gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your baby sick?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She never once looks at him. Her eyes on the floor or the food or the baby.</context>
      <utterance>He cries. I don't know. He cries a lot. My man is dead. He took his wound at Fredericksburg. Never saw his boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a plate of steaming beans. An onion perched on top.</context>
      <utterance>It's pretty much what you'll get if you knock on any door of this war. Man dead, woman left.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes over to the bed and picks up her baby and starts the same business of walking him, singing the while, an odd lament. Inman eats, looks at her, at the child and the fire. He picks up the onion, bites into it. Sara looks across.</context>
      <utterance>It's mean food but it's hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no hunting on the road, just cress and -- He takes another bite. Sara picks up the baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman, embarrassed, turns his back to her. He sits finishing the food while she puts the baby to her breast, slipping the shoulder from her dress. While the baby feeds.</context>
      <utterance>I need to feed this man, if you could look away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Used to have a cow, few goats. Raiders took them. Made me kill our own dog on the porch. That poor creature watched over me. Nothing left now save a hog and couple of chickens to live off till spring. I'll have to kill that hog and make sense of the flesh and divisions which is something I never did.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could do that for you in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what I'd gladly do for you for what you're gladly doing for me. I'm Inman by the way. That's my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Sara. My baby's Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad to know you both.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a palpable attraction between them, so that every exchange seems to contain a promise, a sexual charge.</context>
      <utterance>You look about his size. He was another man straight up and down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even have a blanket.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a blanket.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By the dim light, Inman peels off his clothes, sets to work with the bar of soap and the cloth to scrub himself clean. He can be seen from the window and finds himself turning away to pull off his pants.</context>
      <utterance>I'll leave you the lamp.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They fit?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty much. These boots are good boots.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll say good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you do something for me? Do you think you could lie here, next to me, and not need to go further?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits on the bed as she slips under the covers, and then removes the boots, his shirt, gets under the covers. There's an electric space between them. Then Sara begins to cry, pulls his arm to open up so that she can be folded into him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I'll try.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go. I'll go, shall I?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lie, staring up at the ceiling, her tears falling. A</context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She don't speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can't speak. I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she feeble then?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts the tune of Wayfaring Stranger. Ruby groans.</context>
      <utterance>No.  Don't mind him.  Hey Ruby: what about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he starts up again, but this time GEORGIA BEGINS TO SING. He's like a pale angel and sings with a soft, true voice. Ruby finds herself taken by this boy's voice and by Stobrod's extraordinary invention as he takes the tune off on a wild journey. Ruby sits next to Ada, fiddles with her bracelets, slips one from Ada's wrist and slides it over her own.</context>
      <utterance>Don't make that face -- you listen: c'mon Georgia...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's snow in the air.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't sleep here.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's bitter, they could stop one night.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They stop one night, they'll want to stop two.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This coat's warm.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about next Sunday? That'll be the New Year. It's gonna be a better one.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The war's over in a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said that a month ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It started off being over in a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Ada. Merry Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas. Pangle. Georgia.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Night.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three women walk down the lane, the three men watch.</context>
      <utterance>'Night now.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my Ruby.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's an original.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think the Good Lord would forgive an old cold fool if he changed his mind? Ada said it herself it was bitter...</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of name's Georgia?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's where he comes from, it's not his name.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that's meant to be the ugliest state under the heavens.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you care what his name is?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that cluster of Stars?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Orion.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about them shaped like a wishbone?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Taurus the bull, and that's Gemini and that's Orion's big dog, Canis Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to her, Sal. She's turned into a highland girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all three have linked arms. Ada imitates Stobrod.</context>
      <utterance>I could always name the stars, Ruby, that was never my problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you darling. In case that big old sky falls on our heads. And I love you, too. Sal.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's sad, Sal. It's a c-a-t-a-s-t-r- o-p-h-e.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman surfaces from deep sleep.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of here, quick!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman is up, grabbing clothes, boots, his gun.</context>
      <utterance>Federals are coming. They find you here it'll go bad on all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can try and fight them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls up the window in back of the cabin. Inman throws things out into the freezing morning. He has his pants on, but is otherwise naked. He swings over the window and down onto the frosty ground.</context>
      <utterance>No, my baby. Please no! Just get.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PISTOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A third Federal, BARDOLPH, chases after the chickens, gathers them up.</context>
      <utterance>My baby's sick! Cover him up! He's shaking! Have some pity.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nym gets close to her, putting his rifle to her chest.</context>
      <utterance>I got nothing. I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't necessarily so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nym unties her. Pistol has a rope around the hog and now leads it towards the horses.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! Take me inside! Let's all go inside! Take my baby inside and then we'll do whatever you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's wailing, an unbearable ululation. NYM SLAPS HER, TWICE,</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing! You take that hog I'm as good as dead. Cover up my boy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BARDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is ready to get a fit going. It's shuddering. It's gone blue.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bardolph obeys, terrified. Sara runs out, collects Ethan, gives a little moan of anguish, runs back inside the cabin.</context>
      <utterance>Move away from the baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take off your boots.  Take off your pants, and your shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot me, please. We're starving. We haven't eaten.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd better get running before you catch your death of cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, thank you. I will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think he's dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This snow. Isn't it supposed to fall with bad news?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks past. Ada stares into the distance where</context>
      <utterance>Bad news is girls get working. I'm going to round up the animals.  This'll settle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you reckon? Think we could eat this?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cook something long enough you can eat anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's frozen. How long it been there for?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not very long.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pangle takes another stick, burns his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Edible.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't taste much like venison.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good. I think it's good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evening. Hope we didn't disturb you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name's Teague. Do I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Teague slides off his horse, approaches the fire.</context>
      <utterance>Thewes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a deserter? -- don't mind if I just warm up at your fire.  That your wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who? That's a he!</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He your wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're musicians. He picks the banjo, I got a fiddle.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look pretty romantic by the fire. Don't they?  Your boyfriend's got a nice bit of flesh on him. Close your eyes slip inside that shirt get two good handfuls -- dark enough I'd be willing. I'm just kidding.  Tell him, I'm just kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just kidding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you answer my question -- about your military status?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Discharged. Took a wound at Petersburg.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so like a hero's discharge.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your boyfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The military wouldn't take him. He can't fight. He's simple. He's got a mind no bigger'n a pickled walnut.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry -- he's fat, he's simple and got titties -- but you're insisting he ain't a woman. God damn! Don't that sausage smell outstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miqhty outstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mighty outstanding! There's a new phrase. Mighty outstanding. Listen, don't tell me -- you left your papers somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which papers?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your hero's discharge. For mighty outstanding valour.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're, they're, they're at my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where, where, where is your house?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down the mountain.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're up the mountain.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunting. Drinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On honeymoon.  I'm pretty fucking funny tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he going to play?  You gonna play that fiddle?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pangle surfaces, blinks, grins at everybody.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Sure.  Hey, wake up!</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evening, Mrs.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Georgia?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the trees, Georgia ducks, retches.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Georgia?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't know what he's saying. We were talking about Georgia early on -- maybe heading down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Georgia's like my armpit. Worse, it's like yours.  Want some sausage?</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. You is Home Guard?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You is Teague?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm known!</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't know what he's saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That bastard Teague.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad words. Folk always put the curse words in front of your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Teague wants us to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We heard there were deserters in these parts. Hiding out in a big cave.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not come to my ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know where this cave is?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do, Stobes! He means --</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, right! he means, there is a cave, right, it's up over the other side, big cave, we played some music up there, never occurred to me they were deserters. Near Bearpen Branch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't nowhere near Bearpen Branch! It's this side! He's always getting lost. That cave -- we live there! -- it's over on Big Stomp. Tell you how I always find it. There's a big old locust tree fell down across the path, that points straight at it, like a finger, always a dozen squirrels round that tree. You gets to the tree, sit on it, and there's your entrance, straight in front of you, tree points at it. Come right to your hand, them squirrels --  -- Chrrrpppp! Chrrrrppp!</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds good. Okay, let's eat, let's hear some music.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you make of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heartbreaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand over by that tree.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stobrod gets up, carrying his fiddle, heads over to a big old poplar. Nods at Pangle.</context>
      <utterance>Over by that tree. Over there. Take your boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pangle gets up, banjo in his hand. Puts his arm around Stobrod as if they were about to be photographed. The Home Guard gather around them. From the trees Georgia watches, helpless. Pangle grins at Teague.</context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quit smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He always smiles. He don't mean nothing by it. I told him this world's got nothing worth a smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put your hat over your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cover your face with your hat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told Georgia he can stop here, sleep in the barn. He's got nothing inside him. He'd walk out of here and die in the snow.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can milk the cows. I was worrying about that. It'll be dark in a couple of hours. I's ten hours climb from here. He's drawn a map.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know these fools stayed the night in the Mill? That's Stobrod -- he can't do one good thing without adding the bad. Left tracks in the snow all the way up for them Home Guards to follow. That's a sign says shoot me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada moves towards her, puts her arms around her. Ruby is rigid. Ada stops embracing her.</context>
      <utterance>Ruby, I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's tying up the kit. She doesn't know how to grieve.</context>
      <utterance>We should get going.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every piece of this is a man's bullshit. They call this a war a cloud over the land, but they made the weather. Then they stand in the rain and say: shit! It's raining!  If I cry one tear for my Daddy I stole it off a crocodile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada fishes out Pangle's banjo from the snow. It's broken and the strings hang slack.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe Teague's took him. They did that with the Swanger boys -- didn't, they? -- dragged them into town, then strung them up as warning... it's snowed since, so I can't read the story on the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LATER -- and RUBY FINISHES OFF THE GRAVE, hammering in a stone to mark the place. Ada walks away towards the creek, to wash her hands. She bends and rinses her face. As she looks up SHE SEES STOBROD ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE CREEK; half-in, half out of the water, slumped against a tree, blood everywhere, staining the crust of snow which covers him.</context>
      <utterance>Let's dig.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruby arrives at Ada, looks to where she's looking, walks straight into the creek, all her love contained in the urgency with which she hurtles to her father, oblivious to the freezing water. She puts a head to his chest, seeks out a pulse at his wrist. Calls back to Ada.</context>
      <utterance>Ruby! Ruby!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's still breathing!  God damn! Daddy; Daddy -- it's Ruby. Don't you die on me again.  He's still breathing!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cuts the skin and prises out a slug which she drops in the snow and rolls around to clean. Stobrod doesn't move. He could be dead. Ada loads the pan with snow.</context>
      <utterance>Pack a pan full of snow. I need good clean water, boiled up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get him home. We have herbs there and it's warm.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll die first. He's got hardly no blood left in him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll die lying here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada puts the snow-packed pan on the fire.</context>
      <utterance>There's a place further on up. Used to be. Old Cherokee place. There's good water right by it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruby picks up the blankets and provisions and goes back inside to her father. Ada takes the horse to another hut and, despite his great reluctance, pushes him inside.</context>
      <utterance>This horse is weary. He's ready to give up the ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada wouldn't even recognize this practical, hardy woman she's become. Stringy and of few words. She sets off towards the tree tunnel, passing Stobrod's hut.</context>
      <utterance>Good boy.  That's warmer, isn't it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting firewood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wood -- that sound when it burns that mean more snow?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it do, country girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman is bewildered by this woman's voice in a man's outfit, keeps walking, peering through the snow. Ada fires a warning shot. Inman, still some distance, suddenly understands.</context>
      <utterance>Turn round and go back where you came from.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ada? Ada Monroe?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After all this time, all this way, Inman could give up the ghost.</context>
      <utterance>I do not know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns, walks heavily away from her. Then he turns again, completely lost, without compass.</context>
      <utterance>Then I believe I made a mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I knew where to go I'd go there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. They don't know how to speak to each other, just stand awkwardly, some distance apart, the emotion stones in their throats. Eventually --</context>
      <utterance>Inman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, she starts to sob, and sob. VERY HIGH ANGLE: Inman walks towards Ada. They embrace.</context>
      <utterance>You'd better come with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruby digests this. Considers this ghost of a man.</context>
      <utterance>Ruby, this is Inman.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations, I should send you out with a shotgun more often. He looks as he needs sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I may need to.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be my guest. You shot or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hungry?  He woke up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stobrod?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Said -- your mommy's name was Grace then closed his eyes again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's asleep. They both are.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not surprised. Your man looks played out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw him. I realize now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saw him when?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Sally Swanger's well. A tunnel of trees. The man like a black smudge in the snow, the sun behind him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well there you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny thing is it wasn't the same. The image. It wasn't snowing. And in the well, he was, as if he were falling.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You probably don't remember it right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember it exactly. There were crows, these black crows flying towards me. I thought I was seeing him fall. Instead I was seeing him come back to me. All this while I've been packing ice around my heart. How will I make it melt?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better get a fire going.  I've got big plans for that farm. Got a vision in my mind of how that Cove needs to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you have.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's not a thing we can't do ourselves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I was trying to be quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I got no appetite left to be in a room with wounded men.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't see your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a face you recognised.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get my letters?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got three letters. Carried them in that book you gave me. The Bertram.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must have sent 100. Did you write to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whenever I could. If you never got them I can summarize.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's --</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I pray you're well. I pray I'm in your thoughts. You are all that keeps me from sliding into some dark place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how did I keep you? We barely knew each other. A few moments.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A thousand moments. They're like a bag of tiny diamonds glittering in a black heart. Don't matter if they're real or things I made up. The shape of your neck. The way you felt under my hands when I pulled you to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your boots, one polished, one not yet polished.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're playing a piano and I'm standing outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm playing a piano and you're standing outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That kiss -- which I've kissed again every day of my walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every day of my waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruby stomps out of the hut.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you can't see my face, but if you could see my inside, my whatever you want to name it, my spirit, that's the fear I have deeper than any gash on my neck. I think I'm ruined. They kept trying to put me in the ground, but I wasn't ready, no ma'am, no more ready than that scoundrel in there's not ready to die on us. But if I had goodness, I lost it. If I had anything tender in me I shot it dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's at the door to Stobrod's hut. She contemplates them.</context>
      <utterance>Number one -- shut this door, it's freezing.  Number two -- shut that door, it's freezing.  I'm laying on my back, with my fingers poked in my ears trying to shut out who's got a bag of diamonds and who's got boots needs polishing, If you want to get three feet up a bull's ass listen to what sweethearts whisper to each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that she enters Stobrod's hut, slamming the door.</context>
      <utterance>In fact, if you're going to wimble all night I'm going to sleep in with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pause.</context>
      <utterance>Now I can't see anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll say goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think Ruby's vacating my hut so that you can sleep in a different one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman enters. They don't know the rules for this.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever comes to pass between you and me, I want Ruby to stay in Black Cove.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as she wants. And if she never leaves I'll be glad.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More a question could she put up with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you understand she's my friend, she's not a hired hand and she doesn't empty a night jar unless it's her own.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This war's made some things pointless. It's hard to imagine a wedding. I think even my father would recognize that.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ada, I want to marry you. If you'll have me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't there's some religion where you just have to say I marry you, three times, and then you're man and wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada laughs, unsettling Inman.</context>
      <utterance>I marry you. I marry you. I marry you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's that funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I think it's I divorce you three times and then you're not married anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can wait for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they kiss, tentative, then more urgent.</context>
      <utterance>You waited enough. I certainly did. I marry you. I marry you. I marry you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about the way I look. In these clothes.  And there are so many buttons.  Will you turn your back?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands holding her clothes in front of her to cover herself. He takes them from her, drops them to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Not for all the gold dollars in the Federal Bank.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go ahead. I'll follow with the horse at a pace your daddy can tolerate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can all go together.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's safer this way. No one has quarrel with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get to you by nightfall.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her hand to his mouth which creases into a smile.</context>
      <utterance>You be safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Mr. Bartram speaks about some category of fly born on the hide of a cow. It flies up into a tree and waits and waits until it smells cow. It can wait a year, two years, I don't know, maybe longer. Then a cow comes along and it wakes up, flies down, lays its eggs on the cow. There's purpose for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And am I the fly in this story, or the cow?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come up the mountain for me, darling, I'd be dead otherwise, dead and gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd have found some other fool to rescue you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He coughs for a long time.</context>
      <utterance>He's sweet on you, that Georgia boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you say a thing and then cough it's a lie. Daddy, stay on that horse, and don't lose him or sell him. We'll need him on the farm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope that Georgia boy's been seeing to the animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were thinking on him!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was not. I was thinking on swollen udders -- and before you say same difference...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruby elbows her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm saying nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada elbows her back.</context>
      <utterance>Miss lovey-dovey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look round.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many men does he have?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There were five. You can't reason with that man.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inman opens his coat. Stobrod looks at the Lemats. They're at the edge of the trees.</context>
      <utterance>I got a conversation stopper.  Closer we get to that broken ground the better.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hold on tight, do you hear? When I say three, look round, nice and slow.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOBROD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stobrod looks round. Inman doesn't. Teague has some new bodies in his entourage but they're all dead. A SPARE HORSE HAS</context>
      <utterance>One, two, three.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir. Here's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just have to shoot the horse from under you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot her. She's not mine. You riding Mr Teague's mare?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope so.  Look, how old are you? Give me your gun and ride home, I'm done fighting. I'm sick of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I give you my gun you'll shoot me dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not shoot you, but nor am I walking down that mountain looking over my shoulder for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what they call a conundrum. I tell you what I've got on my side.</utterance>
   <speaker>INMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you got on your side?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And in that second HE PRODUCES HIS GUN AND FIRES. INMAN HAS</context>
      <utterance>The confidence of youth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has the skin off the lamb, which lies like a little pink cat on the ground. She approaches Grace, takes the live lamb from her arms, the girl resistant, frightened.</context>
      <utterance>He came out dead, love.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the skin and wraps it round Grace's lamb. Then puts the covered lamb into the pen with the dead lamb's mother. It goes to the sheep and, after a few false starts, starts to feed, accepted as a surrogate.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to kill him. But we have to try something or else he's going to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And A VOICE joins in with the fiddle and banjo.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that a small mercy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From behind her, Grace appears, carrying a jug of milk, puts it on the groaning board of the table. Grace has a full plate in front of her, picks up a fork to spear some meat.</context>
      <utterance>Hot hot hot hot hot!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The music stops. And there's quiet except for the sound of animals: lowing, barking, braying, bleating.</context>
      <utterance>Grace Inman, nobody said eat.  Mr. Thewes...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For good friends, good food, good family: for all our blessings -- Oh Lord we thank thee. Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they eat.</context>
      <utterance>Amen !</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
