<movie id="138" title="Confidence">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I think it's because of this redhead...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know who I am, Jake?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Anti-Christ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>There's the LOUD UNMISTAKABLE "CLICK" of a gun being cocked. The barrel of a gun slides gently along Jake's ear and comes to rest at the base of his skull. The voice and the gun belong to BUTCH (40's). With his suit and conservative looks, you'd make him out for a "Steve" or "Roger" more than a "Butch". BUTCH (cont' d) Things are probably going to end badly for you, Jake.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm not the Anti-Christ. Or the Prince of Darkness. I'm just a guy looking for some answers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee... What makes you say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your life flashing before your eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just the last three weeks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EXT . - BACK ALLEY- NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The same alley... The door of a building bursts open as LIONEL DOLBY (late 40's), dressed in a cheap suit, stumbles out breathing heavy. The dim light of a bare bulb glares off the sweat on his forehead. A moment later, Jake emerges from the same door carrying a large black revolver.</context>
      <utterance>Title: Three Weeks Ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost my head. I'm... Sorry. I don't know what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y-y-you fucking shot him! That's what happened!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lionel starts shaking his head spastically.</context>
      <utterance>I had to! That motherfucker was about to welch! You saw what he was doing, right? You heard him!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't be here! You understand? I can' t--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the distance, A POLICE SIREN WAILS, growing louder.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me! It went to shit. It happens sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake takes a tentative step forward. Lionel sees a BLOOD STAIN on Jake's shirt and recoils. The SIREN GROWS LOUDER, Jake turning his head towards it.</context>
      <utterance>LISTEN to me! We don't have much time. We can still get through this but you have to keep your head and trust me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What-- What do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake waves Lionel back through the door they came out of.</context>
      <utterance>Help me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lionel stands frozen. Jake, drops the dead guy's legs with a THUD.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Grab his arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The POLICE SIRENS grow LOUDER.</context>
      <utterance>Lionel... He's dead. Yeah, maybe you didn't pull the trigger, but you were standing right there and watched me do it. Help me. Grab his arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tick-tock...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you wanna help, then help. If not, shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miles non-chalantly pulls a sawed off shot gun frown under the bar. MILES (cont' d) You think this kinda shit hasn't happened here before? Given it's usually on Thursdays. And usually, I gotta tell the cops, "No, Officer... I didn't really get a good look at the shooters." Usually anyway.</context>
      <utterance>Oh please...</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't see nothing. And I swear if you let me go now, I won't say-</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The POLICE SIRENS sound like they're right outside.</context>
      <utterance>Relax, porkchop.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake cocks his gun, never taking his stare off Miles.</context>
      <utterance>I can't be here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lionel looks at the briefcases of bloodied money.</context>
      <utterance>Then go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about... The money?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lionel again looks at the briefcases; then the shotgun leveled at Jake; then at the direction of the POLICE SIRENS... He runs for the door without a second thought.</context>
      <utterance>What about this situation makes you think I can answer that question right now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, freeze you motherfucking, cocksucking, scumbags! The second middle aged cop, OFFICER RICHARD ROTTOVICH comes calmly down the stairs behind Sobozinski.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rottovich closes the door and locks it behind him.</context>
      <utterance>We're clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or I'll blow off every one of your fucking heads! Sobozinski lets out a bellowing LAUGH. We PAN OVER TO REVEAL Jake, Miles and BIG AL  sitting at the bar by the Dead Guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop waving that thing around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure we're clear?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guy looked like he was trying not to shit himself.  Nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dead Guy stirs-- GORDO, late 20's, dressed in a blood soaked suit stands up; wiping blood off his face.</context>
      <utterance>What took so fucking long?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAD GUY/GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been lying in this shit like half the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys were late. We had to go to a Mexican stand-off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake tosses the revolver on the bar.</context>
      <utterance>And you know I hate guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were fighting crime.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake starts taking the money out of the briefcases. Gordo strips out of the jacket and shirt, revealing a THIN WHITE VEST. A wire runs from a battery pack on his belt, up the center of the vest, ending at a scorched, bloody, explosive squib. Gordo drops the vest along with a plastic bag containing fake blood. A nasty bruise on his chest marks the spot where the squib was.</context>
      <utterance>Keeping the city streets safe for drug dealers and pedophiles everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, use less powder.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake removes the blood stained bills from the top of the pile.</context>
      <utterance>But you won't get that splatter effect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Al moves over to the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Then these go into your cut.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jake... When am I gonna get to play the Inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gordo plays the inside. You're the Shill.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but come on... All I get to do is cry and get insulted.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? You should get a fucking Academy Award for the Shill work you do.  We got it down cold, Al. You don't want to jinx it by changing something up, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I' m gonna go get eggrolls. Anyone want eggrolls? Al slaps Jake on the back and exits. Jake catches Gordo hawking over his shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I can feel you looking at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lot of cash. He came up with it pretty quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's done. He's not coming back.</context>
      <utterance>Probably some investment banker or convertible-bonds-broker-dickhead. Did you see how fast he ran out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess. I gotta drop a dime. Did anybody mess up the hoop?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordo disappears dawn the back hallway.</context>
      <utterance>It's clean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys got sack, I'll give you that much.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sobozinski and Rottovich head for the door with their newly padded pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Confidence. It's just confidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feels a little light, Jake. Next time we're in for twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty? My ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? Ten's standard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah Well, Sobo's kid needs braces.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any idea what those monks charge for that medieval torture?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got a good thing going here. You want to blow it over an overbite?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get me wrong, Jake. I like you boys. You guys are the steadiest business in town. But what can I say? Twenty percent's still better than what we give to any of the other criminals.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the shit we pulled with you and you're trying to shake us down? You guys got sack.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that a threat? Did I hear a threat?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grifters...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't all be model citizens such as yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all about the money, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it always?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what makes us run. And despite what they say, it can buy you love.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALL GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lets the overcoat fall open, revealing her lack of clothing.</context>
      <utterance>Are you ready for me, Ralph?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INT.- BIG AL'S APARTMENT- NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big Al has a cordless phone to his ear...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can erase all those things about you that you wish didn't exist.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Al picks up a CHINESE TAKE-OUT MENU and leafs through it while on the phone.</context>
      <utterance>It's Alfonse. I want to settle up. I haven't been ducking you. I told you I'd get it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake passes a group of well-dressed, well manicured people waiting in line outside of a trendy bar called "Wax." Among the hip and well dressed, he seems out of place at the moment. An outsider. An attractive blonde in her late twenties, LILY, bumps into Jake.</context>
      <utterance>It can make you think you're on top of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws Jake a smile he can't but help return. They stand for a second facing each other before she's whisked away by an OLDER MAN, dressed in an expensive suit.</context>
      <utterance>Oops.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANSWERING MACHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no new messages.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake stands his sparse little world, addressing the quiet before he fishes for his wallet, which he can't find.</context>
      <utterance>If you've got nothing, you've got nothing to lose. And when it comes to money, finding it and losing it, you always gotta remember how much of it's just luck...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode>V. O. </mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oops.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Dolby. King would like a word with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>R-r-right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. We have a car waiting. I apologize for the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better get over to Al's. Now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was supposed to meet him for breakfast. He likes that new IHOP they just opened, you know... He likes to order that thing. The Rutti-Tutti-Fresh and Fruity thing they got.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miles...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Al stares up at them with those bulging, vacant eyes, his mouth hanging open. Jake reaches down and grabs the remote control and turns the TV off.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I'm just... Look what they did to him. Right in the middle of his egg- foo-young.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big Al used to send money to his Father, some Vietnam Vet slowly losing his mind in a VA hospital in Cleveland. Al was like that. That's why Al never played the Inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They just pulled him out of the East River.</context>
      <utterance>Seems Lionel Dolby came down with a sudden case of drowning last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this is just fucking great...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordo throws Jake a hard look, letting the news sink in. Jake can only slump back into the booth.</context>
      <utterance>It gets worse. Now I know why he was such a good rope. X mean, cash.... That much and we never had to put him on the "Send?" Turns out this ducking Moe was an accountant for the King Pin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cash we fleeced off of him was collection money. He was supposed to take that money and give it to the King earlier yesterday like he does every Thursday. `Cept this time, he figured he could make a little something for himself off us and still get the King's money back before any body says "boo."</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordo looks to Jake, but can see that he's still processing the information.</context>
      <utterance>What's a King Pin?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Currently, the King Pin is a very large- type pole stuck up our asses.</utterance>
   <speaker>MTLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mob?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Independant. Same shit, just independant. They call him the King Pin because he looks like that guy from the comic book... Big. Fat. Bald.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what? We hide, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you? New? Let me tell you how good this guy is. Last night, Al calls this bookie to settle up. Apparently he's been ducking him for like a month. So the guy asks him where he's got all this money all of a sudden, right? What does Al do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're pissed we didn't get credit?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that was the only semi-fucking smart thing he said! Except anybody that's ever met Big A1 knows that the only thing he's comfortable doing alone is eating. This guys tells this guy, that guy tells some other guy, eventually it works it's way back to someone who works for the King and--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Big Al's eyes grow huge as we hear a LOUD BALM!!!</context>
      <utterance>Shazaam.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO THE DINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>GORDO  Big Al gets whacked mid-egg foo young. The whole thing took about two and a half hours. That's how good he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We sure Big Al threw him to us?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All three of them turn their attention out the window. They watch the bustle of people walking past wondering if any one of them is looking back.</context>
      <utterance>Come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordo and Miles exchange a look, unsure of how to respond.</context>
      <utterance>A bird flew into my house last night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just an idea, but let's just fucking split. We'll meet up anywhere. Akron or Austin or Atlanta. Anywhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll find us. We go talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to give him the money back?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what we're doing with the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what about Big Al?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WAITRESS approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Leave him. Someone's going to find him eventually. Then they'll start looking for us, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I get you guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake turns his attention out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Coffee. And a valium.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Gordo and Miles start unloading the same neat stacks of money from their pockets. It's not as much as Jake put in.</context>
      <utterance>Gordo fleeced the deed off some idiot in a card game. We used it every now and then for a rag, but mostly it was our office. Our Power Point.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES/GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shaking his head, Jake seals the Fed--Ex box, then hands the form to Miles and. Picks up the phone. MILES (cont'd) Do we want insurance? (off their looks) I'm just asking...</context>
      <utterance>Bills.../Had that thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Just mail it to the hospital.  Mr. King, please. It's regarding an accounting problem. Yes... Correct... I know where it is. That will be fine. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight. Just me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck that. We're going too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake levels a stare at Gordo for a second.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, let's all put our dicks back in our pants for a second. Is this the best thing to do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meet me at my place later.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know the King's going to let you walk?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake picks up the phone and dials another number.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting a ride.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The King, huh? Nice going.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I try.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake nods and approaches the door where Harlin and Lupus stand vigil. Lupus wears another loud sweatsuit.</context>
      <utterance>Don't dick around too long. And if he stabs you or shoots you or causes any other form of profuse bleeding, call a cab because you are not getting back in this car!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake takes a step towards the door, but is pushed up against The wall by Lupus who begins to roughly pat Jake down.</context>
      <utterance>We appreciate your punctuality. Mr. King is expecting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lupus!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harlin shakes his head and pushes Lupus out of the way.</context>
      <utterance>What? You said pat him down, I'm pattin' him down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake steps back and raises his arms.</context>
      <utterance>It only takes a moment to be polite. My apologies, Mr. Vig. If you wouldn't mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You the one that did it? You the one that got Al?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harlin gives the Officers Sobozinski and Rottovich a slight nod of acknowledgment.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. King prefers to farm out for that kind of work.  Please, after you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... Which one's the King Pin?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake nods and let's out a silent sigh of relief.</context>
      <utterance>He's in the back taking a steam.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This isn't so bad. Jake almost has to stifle a laugh. KING PIN (cont'd) Every time, you get the pinkie and I get a hang nail. ( to Jake) You Jake? Jake nods and the King motions for the manicurist to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Ow! Watch the pinkie!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grifter huh? Where have you been on the grift? Couldn't been here long 'cause I would have heard of you, Skippy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jake. You can call me Jake. Here and there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here and there, Scooter? Here and there like Boston, Chicago, Houston? The bay area? Some action in London, `til it turned nickel and dime. Or how about that little stint down in Miami? Heard you actually got into some trouble with the Feds down there. You guy's pretty good?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a good crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake visibly bristles...</context>
      <utterance>Minus one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Minus one.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, back in the day, grafting was considered a gentleman's racket. Good suits, good food... The Underworld of the Underworld. A grifter had to survive on his wits, his instincts... I like that. I like the idea of that. These days, things being what they are, guys like me gotta stay low.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it lacks a certain style.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, your line of work's only as good as the people you find.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't cheat an honest man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't cheat an honest man. But a man like Lionel Dolby...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King picks up a long, metal nail file.</context>
      <utterance>I apologize for the inconvenience.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honest mistake. Just give me the money back and all will be forgiven.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me rephrase-- I won`t do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me repeat-- Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you killed one of my crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buddy, that was business. Besides, you have more crew. Then there's you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get the money back, plus interest. I go on the grift for you. You get a cat, I get a cut. And we get square.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucking grifters! I love it! You got balls, I'll give you that much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King Pin stands up and moves over to Jake.</context>
      <utterance>No. Just confidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I' ll be honest with you, Kid. A grifter comes in here with a fifteen hundred dollar D-K-fucking-N-Y suit, cooler than an Eskimo in winter and tells me he wants to grift for me? First thing I have to ask myself is, is he playing for me or is he just plain playing me? You tried it once.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With surprising speed, the King Pin grabs Jake by the neck.</context>
      <utterance>We got caught. So you know it won't happen again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few pained CHOKES from Jake as his knees buckle.</context>
      <utterance>I know it won't happen because you're going to feel like a Prom Queen who just got gang fucked by the wrestling team!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King loosens his grip and let's Jake fall.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Vig arrived with an escort. NYPD.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus snaps to attention.</context>
      <utterance>Grifters... Always working an angle. Alright. I can see you got some vision. But I give you the Mark. I tell you the who and you give me the how. Lupus go with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake begins to speak, but is silenced with a look.</context>
      <utterance>Consider him part of your crew. Consider him a part of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He goes. Now let me see your hands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake turns to find Lupus and Harlin on either side of him. They take him by the wrists and hold his hands up for the King. KING PIN (cont' d) I don't like to ask things more than once, Junior. I want you to know how much that irks me. The King begins to gently trace between Jake's fingers with the nail file. Jake remains rigid against Lupus and Harlin as the nail file scrapes along the soft, fleshy webbing between his fingers. Jake shuts his eyes... Then opens them to find the King now gently stroking his hands-- Almost a loving caress.</context>
      <utterance>You ask a lot of questions. Come on.  Let me see `em.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King continues to stroke Jake's hands with his own meaty paws.</context>
      <utterance>You have incredibly soft hands. Good cuticles . They' re like a baby's hands. Grifters with rough hands... You know that they're probably not that good. Means they've had to do some hard labor to make ends meet. But you... Smooth... Supple.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you insinuating that the King Pin is of an alternative lifestyle?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a tip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we gonna do with this stuff anyway? Heroin? What the hell do you do with heroin?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sell it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be an idiot. How hard do you think it is to sell one drug dealer's drugs to another drug dealer? If Vig's right, we might be looking at a hundred, maybe a hundred fifty grand...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think this is a good idea? We never did this kinda shit before.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hooded figure turns a corner onto the street, heading for the Cigar Shop. He wears a knapsack slung over his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>What's he going to do? File a missing drugs report? If it works out, this guy might be good for a few more turns.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One fifty! It's not even covered.</context>
      <utterance>Hope so. Those fucking orthodontist bills are killing me. One fifty every time they tighten those bitches up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cosmetic. They don't cover cosmetic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit it's cosmetic! My fucking tooth was cracked in half. I made the son of a bitch write it in as a cavity. The department's dental is for shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We HEAR the SOUNDS OF CAR DOORS OPENING, then SLAMMING</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa... There he is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know who we are?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The heat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you got in the bag?</context>
      <utterance>Alright. Put your hands dawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something for my Pops.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid hesitates for a second before handing the knapsack over. Rottovich opens it and pulls out TWO BRICKS OF HEROIN, wrapped in plastic. He nods to Sobozinski. The Kid stays rooted right where he is, looking up at the Detectives like a lost puppy.</context>
      <utterance>I see. Well, your Pops has been making you carry around drugs for him. We're going to have to take them.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Pops is going to be mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sobozinski fishes in his pocket starts to peel off bills for the kid who then sprints away.</context>
      <utterance>Give the kid a twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rottovich and Sobozinski head off with the knapsack.</context>
      <utterance>What's the world coming to? Everybody's on the friggin' take...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never know when you can use a crooked cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep going. I want to know how you got Lionel Dolby.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you want to know how to play the Big Con.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch shoves the gun a little harder into Jake's head.</context>
      <utterance>In this case, you might say I want to know how not to play the Big Con.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake buys another round to the indifferent Slick.</context>
      <utterance>First thing about being on the grift.... You're only as good as your Mark. The Roper's the guy who finds them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>THE SCENE DOESN'T CHANGE--- Slick MORPHS into a FAT TEXAS BUSINESS MAN wearing a ten-gallon hat. He doesn't smile.</context>
      <utterance>They all have money one way or another. Some of them come from money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Fat Texan MORPHS into a WALL STREET-type suit, who remains stoic as Jake reaches over for another round of drinks.</context>
      <utterance>There's that saying-- Show me an honest man and I'll show you a natural born liar. There's always that little bit of bad no matter how much good. It's that little itch on the back of you neck. You may not even know it's there, but it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Euro-Trash MORPHS into an distinguished looking OLDER MAN as he takes a sip.</context>
      <utterance>It means that in fifteen minutes we're on good terms. Thirty, I'm your buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake punctuates some unheard point with a slap on his knee.</context>
      <utterance>In an hour, I'm your best friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake looks up as the OLDER MAN MORPHS into LIONEL DOLBY, the nervous mark from the earlier con.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a day and you'll let me do your wife and daughter at the same time. It's too late for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE-UP: Dolby's lips loosen in a wide SMILE. Jake smiles back. He puts his drink down, then takes the drink from Dolby. They remain talking as THE BACKGROUND--</context>
      <utterance>I have your confidence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Gordo pulls an envelope out of his coat and gives it to Dolby.</context>
      <utterance>The Insideman's the one with the know- How, the scoop, the angle. But maybe 'you' re the suspicious type . So I give you the "Convincer." We both put up a little and we get a little back. Just a taste.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake speaks quickly to Dolby who nods emphatically. He hands the envelope back to Gordo.</context>
      <utterance>Just enough that when I tell you we can make more off of it, you agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. </mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That`s when I put you on the "Send." You put in -a little, you got a little. Put in a lot... I "send" you out for mare. As much as you can get.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordo lying in a pool of blood...</context>
      <utterance>Frankie Suits always said, that what you have to understand about any confidence game, is that it's like putting on a play where everyone knows their part... The Roper, the Insideman, the Shills... Everyone except for the Mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Al sits cowering at a table...</context>
      <utterance>I've been shot. Oh. The humanity.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miles casually washing glasses...</context>
      <utterance>God. No. Please. Don't kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better hurry. The police will be here any second.  I don't really understand my motivation with this. Why am I washing glasses?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolby turns to Jake, eyes wide, lips trembling in fear.</context>
      <utterance>Now you're an accomplice in a homicide. Everything you thought you were in control of just flew out the window or is dripping down your leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should be running out the door, desperate to forget this ever happened, ready to repent your greedy ways!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOLBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about... The money?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then there it is again... That little itch. There's a guy holding a smoking gun, a guy bleeding all over the floor and still, all you can think about is the money. You twisted fuck. So we gotta give you the "Blow-off". We make sure that you never, ever want to look for us again. We get you off our backs. Forever. Jake stops for a second and listens... He points over his shoulder and on cue A POLICE SIREN WAILS in the distance.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolby bolts for the door without the money.</context>
      <utterance>And that's why you need the "Fix"...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EXT - BACK ALLEY- NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>PRESENT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Butch eases the gun off Jake's head.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how'd you get caught?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're working for the King.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a second... Who's the mope?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the King's eyes and ears. Just in case you decide to get cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we gotta short con our way out of a hundred and fifty grand? That could only take like, a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Big con. One rag. One rag and we get out from under all this. But we need another Shill.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we need another Shill for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Breasts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? You guys cops or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not cops.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta be kidding me. Her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, her. Where's my wallet?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake takes her bag and dumps the contents on the floor-- A few wallets, a watch, even a wedding ring. Jake picks up one of the wallets filled with cash. LILY (cont'd) That's not--</context>
      <utterance>Your what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily scoops up her bag and finds a cigarette, eyeing them all suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>You interested in a little work?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about your wallet, but if you think I'm going to suck dick over thirty seven dollars, a waxed out Visa and a bad fake I.D., you're fucking crazy.  Jake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a deep breath and count to ten. It's not that kind of work. You're Lily, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Says who?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily takes a second to look the guys over. Miles gives her a wink. Lily slowly raises her middle finger at him.</context>
      <utterance>You're working Daffy's block. He was going to break your kneecaps. Pick- pockets can be so bitchy sometimes. I told him you were with us, so that's two you owe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have work. It pays a lot. Unless you figure on getting rich lifting wallets while old guys feel you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily saunters to Jake with a seductive grin. Jake may be aware that he's stopped breathing. She puts her hands on Jake's chest and leans in a half inch more, her lips an eyelash away from his. She whispers... LILY (cont' d) Keep the wallet. We're even. Take a deep breath... Count to ten... And go fuck yourself. Lily pushes past Jake and heads out of the alley.</context>
      <utterance>Oooh. Sassy. What do you care who feels me up, Jake? Unless it kinda gotcha going. Did it, Jake? Getcha going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordo gives Jake a nod of approval and Jake takes off after Lily.</context>
      <utterance>Is it just me or is there something really hot about a girl telling you to go fuck yourself?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>EXT.- CITY SIDEWALK- NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lily down the street, Jake giving chase.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright! Hold up. You win. You got the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake catches up and blocks Lily's way.</context>
      <utterance>Gee thanks. Now I don't have to find that bridge to jump off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had to see what your deal was. I'm just a little superstitious.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's my deal-- Don't waste my time. What do you want me for anyway? You don't even know me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily studies Jake's face for any hint of sarcasm. None.</context>
      <utterance>I just have a good feeling about you. Haven't you ever had someone say they had a good feeling about you before?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  What's my cut?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get an equal cut.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I have to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily steps back and hails a cab.</context>
      <utterance>Just play a part. A little acting.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to a large digital clock hanging in a store window reading "11:11p".</context>
      <utterance>Make a wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eleven-eleven. If you're superstitious, make a wish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see why you liked her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was it. We had our crew. Now we needed the Mark.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordo and Miles both do their best to contain their disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Morgan Gillette.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because that's who the King Fin wants us to fleece. And Gillette's perfect...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much we going after?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miles lets out a whistle.</context>
      <utterance>Two million.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We only owe the King a hundred and fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake looks over at Lupus for confirmation.</context>
      <utterance>We get fifty percent. And we get clear of the King.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's worth it right there. You ask me, I don't think you can do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm with Jack LaLane. That guy's untouchable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why we don't go after him directly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A lone man, GRANT ASHBY, MATERIALIZES behind a desk on the empty floor and sits behind a computer terminal.</context>
      <utterance>We find a doable guy in Gillette's bank... Someone about mid-level. Not too high, not too low.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We meet him with corporate papers, inquiring about a corporate loan for start up capital. The corporate papers are in order, but we need things to happen fast. Our guy fudges numbers in the right places, moves our papers to the top of the pile or to the bottom, depending upon what we need.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that? He works for Gillette.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We pay better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake MATERIALIZES on the empty bank floor, walking confidently up to the Teller with a SILVER BRIEFCASE in hand.</context>
      <utterance>That same day, I show up in the Caymens with the proper I.D. and corporate papers to make a withdrawal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILE5</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILE5</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Two million in a briefcase?</context>
      <utterance>I'm just thinking out loud here, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake approaches the Teller, now wheeling a BLACK SUITCASE behind him by the handle. Jake presents the Teller with a series of papers and a photo I.D.</context>
      <utterance>Good point.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's bank policy not to release this money in cash because it's under a corporate account.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As we get closer to the Custom's Desk, a CUSTOMS OFFICER wearing a white short sleeve shirt and a badge MATERIALIZES behind it.</context>
      <utterance>Now, this is the most important part-- You can't just walk into the United States with a suitcase full of cash without evoking the words "cavity search".</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake approaches and slides the suitcase towards him. The Officer slides it back to Jake, revealing another envelope stuffed with cash under it.</context>
      <utterance>That's why you need someone on the inside at Customs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This might just be me, but that is hands down, the dumbest fucking idea I've ever heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People have tried this before, Jake. It's never worked. Teddy Fraiser and his crew went on vacation in Chicago for it. Last year, Mumps got pinched in L.A.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It never worked before because A, they didn't flush the bank enough; B, their corporate papers were for shit; C, they didn't have someone on the inside with Customs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, or D, it's a dumb fucking idea...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Run?</context>
      <utterance>Then what do you want to do, Miles?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We never had a problem with that before.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well we never had this kind of problem before.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? Yes we have. And we would have been beautiful about it. We would've had a bucket of chicken delivered to the King with a nice kiss my ass card attached to it. Then we woulda moved on `til the next local putz caught on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting a little old for running.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well we're still a little young for Albany State Prison. Are you pissed about Al? I'm pissed too, but I' m not like "twenty-five to life" pissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting clear of this. If you're not going to do it for the fucking principle, do it for the money. Gordo?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Whatever, Jake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silence falls over everyone.</context>
      <utterance>No, not "whatever." You're either in or you' re out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes stay on Jake as a smile grows across her face.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EXT.- PAY PHONE- DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jake dials a number...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agreed with Miles. It was, hands down, a dumb fucking idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there were other factors.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Factors that weren't clear to me until now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moonan quickly flashes a badge and his best Kodak smile.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen? Special Agent Gunther Moonan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Special Agent?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm looking for Jake Vig.</context>
      <utterance>You are Officer Richard Rottovich. And this would be Officer Walter Sobozinski.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been looking for this Jake Vig for some time now. Problem is, the guy's the invisible man. A spook, a spectre, a ghost. Then, like a gift, Jake's good buddy and member of his crew, Alfonse Moorely, is found the other day with a hole in his head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moonan takes out a microcassette recorder and hits PLAY.</context>
      <utterance>Look Special Agent Moonan... We don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLICK. Moonan kills the recorder.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be an idiot. How hard do you think it is to sell one drug dealer's drugs to another drug dealer? If Vig's right, we might be looking at a hundred, maybe a hundred fifty grand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officers look out the window to see TWO SERIOUS LOOKING MEN in suits.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, I almost forgot. The two serious looking gentlemen outside? Internal Affairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to know the first time I had a line on Vig? He sent me a birthday card.  Belated, but it's the thought, right? Oh, this prick's got a sense of humor. But, then again you guys probably know him better than I do. In fact, I've only met the guy once. But now, now I have you. The next best thing. His partners. His "Fix."</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You help me catch him. Whatever he's into next, I want you to be into. And what you're into, I'm into. If it all goes well, those two guys from IAD will never have to hear this tape. I'll clear you guys of anything you've ever done with Vig under the guise of some cross-departmental investigation. This prick's been on the wish list for so long, you'll probably get gold shields out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you get out of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peace of mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not everyone's on the take, Walter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you Feds are so hot for him, why don't we just bring him in right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want him for something big and to do that, we have to catch him in the act.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy must have been a real pain in your dick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rottovich and Sobozinski remain silent.</context>
      <utterance>Literally. It's not a bad deal, gentleman. I get peace of mind. You get Detective Sheilds. But this is the best part, Walter... Walter, your daughter will get to keep her braces and have that winning smile. Capice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. One more thing... You gotta give up the booty. I can't have you guys running around with heroin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just as crooked as the next guy. You'd think he'd have more important things to do with tax payer dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's getting cold.</context>
      <utterance>Cue the fucking violins. Come on...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I the only one who feels like we can't make a move with this guy on us?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should ditch him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus exits the restroom, heading back towards the booth.</context>
      <utterance>Just watch every thing you say around him. Every word, every move... It all goes back to the King Pin.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the hoop, superstar? Clean?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it with you and bathrooms?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't like using a bathroom unless he knows it's clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You laugh now, but wait until you need a clean place to powder. This is New York city, Sister. Public sanitation does not run very high on the city hall agenda. You know what you can get off a toilet or doorknob? Let's do the list... Hepatitis, influenza, the flesh eating disease-</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's what's going to happen. Gordo, we need to find a guy in Gillette's bank. Miles, we need papers, corporate, insurance...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it all fugasi?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, the corporate papers have to be legit. But you gotta score an I.D. A clean one. Talk to Suits. I gotta get us a Banker.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Customs?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll worry about Customs.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I' m not just along for the ride, so I don't want to hear any bullshit later about a smaller cut.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake rolls his eyes as Lily glares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Take a deep breath. You sound like you just broke up with your boyfriend or something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INT.- BULLDOG GYM- DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake and Lily stand in front of the King Pin, who's dressed in shorts and a t-shirt. He wears boxing gloves and headgear. Lupus and Harlin stand vigil by the sparring ring.</context>
      <utterance>Boxers at the bags, a jumping rope, etc...</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think two million.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you need from me? Permission? Go! If you can fleece him for two million, then do it, Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to stake me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stake you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to stake me. I can't do it without it. It's just a couple hundred grand. Taken out of our cut when we're done. King Pin eyes Jake suspiciously for a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What happens if you fuck this up?</context>
      <utterance>That's more than you already owe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing ventured, nothing gained.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Skippy? Do I have the word "chump" tattooed on my forehead?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr . King, I think---</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily just shrugs and rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I got it! Take some mental notes. You just might learn something here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Scooter---</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(beat)</context>
      <utterance>No, you listen. We're partners now and even though I'm running the show for you, I'm still running the show. That means I get a little respect. So I don't want to hear anymore of this Scooter, Buddy, Junior, Skippy, Tiger, bullshit. It's Jake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few of the BOXERS training around stop and turn. The King Pin lowers a glare at Jake.</context>
      <utterance>And I gotta tell you, for a guy who spends all his time in a gym, you could be in better shape.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake looks behind him to see Harlin looming.</context>
      <utterance>Take off your shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few more BOXERS stop and turn. Jake notices he's being watched. The King Pin takes a step towards Jake...</context>
      <utterance>I said take off your fucking shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake unbuttons his shirt and stands in front of the King Pin, arms crossed. It's getting weird.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. You want me to take it off, I'll take it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at you, you skinny prick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King smiles and begins to take off his shirt. Harlin and Lupus share an uncomfortable glance. The King strips down to the waist and reveals an incredibly large, incredibly round stomach which he SLAPS loudly.</context>
      <utterance>You're not going to bust out baby oil and start rubbing me down or anything, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come here. Feel this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks. I'm good.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King grabs Jake's hand and puts it on his stomach. It just got weirder. Now the whole gym has stopped, everyone focused on Jake and the King Pin.</context>
      <utterance>Come here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are freaking me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Punch it.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. Feel that? That's solid muscle. Not an ounce of fat. Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King starts to get that look again. Jake winds up and punches the King in the stomach. He shakes his fist in pain.</context>
      <utterance>I am not going--</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Harder.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I just broke my hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake's demeanor changes as he winds up and hits the King as hard as he can. The King just smiles. KING PIN (cont'd) All muscle. The King then hits Jake back in the gut with surprising speed. Jake falls to his knees, but the King's right there. With one arm he pulls Jake up and starts to pummel him in the stomach with an unbridled visciousness. Jake spits up blood as the King hurls him face first into the ring.</context>
      <utterance>Harder. Remember, I killed your buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harlin and Lupus lift Jake up. Lily looks at Jake with a pained expression.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's true. Maybe you can't cheat an honest man. Me? I'm about as dishonest as they come and that's the truth. But if you even think about trying to con me they'll find fucking pieces of you in each of the five boroughs. Pieces of you, pieces of her, pieces of your whole crew. Can't be any mare honest than that. I'll stake you, but that's three hundred fifty you're in the hole and consider the juice running. Now go make me proud.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got our stake. Now we need to find our guy in Gillett's bank.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you're looking for in a mark is someone who's weakness you can exploit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miles points out a woman crisply dressed in a suit, MICHELLE STRIGO. They follow her down the street.</context>
      <utterance>Michelle Strigo. Loan officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake watches as she hails a cab. A MAN, also hailing a cab goes for the same one. Michelle gets into a screaming match with the man. FREEZE FRAME ON MICHELLE--- A CGI SIGN appears over her head "Single, volatile, confrontational woman seeks "man" for economic security and house chores."</context>
      <utterance>Guy like me, with people like that... I'll tell you what you're looking for without even meeting you. It's like a personal ad you wear over your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miles points out ALICE TANNER, a mousy looking woman in a bad skirt. She gets to the intersection and waits for the light to change, even as hordes of others jaywalk the way New Yorkers do. FREEZE FRAME ON ALICE-- A CGI SIGN appears: "Single woman looking for opportunity. Plays by the rules and willing to claw her way up to middle management."</context>
      <utterance>Alice Tanner. Finance Director.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>newspaper from his coat. He opens it to the crossword-- Just like Jake would.</context>
      <utterance>What you're looking for in a mark is someone who's got nothing to lose. No friends, no family, no life. You're looking for a guy who doesn't own a rug. Jake watches as Ashby orders a drink and pulls a</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake watches Ashby do the crossword puzzle alone.</context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I' m sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're greeted by FRANKIE SUITS, an ancient rake-thin man, perfectly coiffed and exceptionally dressed.</context>
      <utterance>Now we had the con and the mark. We needed to look the part...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankie Suits was a legend in certain circles. He. Was on the grift since he was ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suits grabs Jake with a hug. It's a heartfelt one. The others exchange greetings with Suits who moves over to Lupus and studies his loud sweatsuit.</context>
      <utterance>Last of the red hot grifters.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back in the day, Suits made money running fight stores and the wire with a Fix so tight it was like a legit business. I never understood what the point was if grifting became like a regular job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need wardrobe. FRANKIE  So I see. In from Long Island? You fellas take a look around.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>eleven or twelve ounce Super 100 worsted? Miles gives him a look like he's speaking latin. Jake and Lily follow Suits into...</context>
      <utterance>Hey Suits? You got anything in like a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake takes out the papers and gives them the once over. He then puts an envelope thick with cash on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Corporate papers with the New York State seal, insurance documents with a proof of bonding and some fugasi financial records. There's also the I.D. you asked for. Corporate papers with the New York State seal, insurance documents with a proof of bonding and some fugasi financial records. There's also the I.D. you asked for.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aces, Suits.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not easy pickin's. Papers like these speak to larger issues. Sorry about Alfonse.  You into something big?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In over your head?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty much. Suits eyes Lily.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I speak to you in confidence?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suits gives Lily another suspicious look.</context>
      <utterance>Huh? Oh. She's alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try and keep up... You ask for the Advantage Goods, then you guys come in looking to be Bean Traps. So I gotta think you're either working the mace or playing the Jug Mob.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily watches in utter confusion.</context>
      <utterance>A little bit of both.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I been on the ramp all my life, so I got no problem with the way you help yourself, Jake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then who's the Banker?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dead look comes over Suits.</context>
      <utterance>The King.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The King? Jake, you play the heavy rackets like that... They put the lug on for nothing at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't doubt your talent. You looking for that place in the hall of fame?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not history.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to get out from under all this for good. And I want to fuck them all doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake considers those words for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Then I gotta say, in my opinion, you can't get what you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suits guages the seriousness in Jake's face and nods. The he gently rests his hands on the papers.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I can.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't do it Suits. I can't lay down for this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suits holds out his hand. Jake takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Here's the thing... You fall flat, you might not get anything short of stiffed. Then it's Blue River Land for everybody. Papers like these are dangerous because papers tend to multiply, then they start to take shape. Usually it's the shape of an arrow. I hate to do it, but after this, I gotta give you the blowoff. We Jake, Jake?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake, knowing it'll be the last time.</context>
      <utterance>We're Jake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's his problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake stops and turns to her, looking her up and down.</context>
      <utterance>It's just that I left my asshole decoder ring at home, so how do I know not to worry?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need to get a haircut.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And some new clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to rope this banker tomorrow and you gotta at least look classy, if not be classy. You gotta do this thing and I don't even know if you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just going to have to trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't trust anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then show me how.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SALESGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me read this back. One silver Cattier watch, engraved-- "To Carolyn, the Attorney at Law. Happy Graduation, Counselor. Love Mom and Dad."</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One bracelet, engraved "To Abby. Happy 25th Anniversary, Love Tom."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Salesgirl takes the order form and walks away. A change comes over Jake. It's subtle-- Posture, facial expressions, a slight tug of an accent-- but it's there.</context>
      <utterance>I' ll just go put this in, Mr. Lewis.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Lewis turns and looks at Jake. There's no real hint of recognition, but Jake's smiling up at him like an old friend.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Lewis?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake extends his hand.</context>
      <utterance>It is you. Hello!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Lewis seems to search for second, then extends his hand more in an effort not to appear rude.</context>
      <utterance>Jake. Jake Pearson. I go to lawschool with your daughter. Carolyn. We met once or twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Jake. Nice to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Here of all places! How is Mrs. Lewis?</context>
      <utterance>Well, it certainly is a coincidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Salesgirl returns.</context>
      <utterance>Great. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me? I believe you're holding something far me under Pearson.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a ticket?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, this is kind of embarassing, but my wallet was stolen yesterday and I'm afraid the ticket was in it. But the name's Pearson.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking advantage of the long weekend?</context>
      <utterance>While you're back there, could you make sure that Carolyn is spelled with a "y"? The Salesgirl nods and disappears again. MR. LEWIS  What brings you down from Boston, Jake?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind his back, Jake discreetly waves Lily over.</context>
      <utterance>My wife and I are just taking a little vacation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily approaches. When she does, Jake pulls her close and gives her a loving kiss on the lips. It throws Lily for a second.</context>
      <utterance>Carolyn's down this weekend too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... Everything okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily and Mr. Lewis exchange handshakes.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, this is Mr. Lewis. Carolyn Lewis's father. Mr. Lewis, this is my wife, Lily.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake taps Lily on the back with the hand wrapped around her waist.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, honey. I'm almost done.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake gives Lily another kiss before she leaves.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. I'll be looking for earrings.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Attractive girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Actually, it's our first anniversary this weekend. She thinks I'm here to pick up something for my mother, but it's actually a gift for her. Think I've fooled her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it from me, you never do. But congratulations. Nice to be married, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake smiles ear to ear, like the happy newlywed he's pretending to be. The Salesgirl returns.</context>
      <utterance>Very much so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake's smile dissolves as he grows a little anxious.</context>
      <utterance>We have Carolyn with a "y". I'm sorry, there's nothing under Pearson. If we had an invoice number--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake takes a nervous look over at Lily, who is drying on earrings with another Salesperson.</context>
      <utterance>I told you. My wallet was stolen. Please... Check again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Jake shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck. Congratulations again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir. You know, I hope this isn't too much of an inconvenience, but if Carolyn is coming down for the weekend, perhaps I could give you something for her? It's a check. We split the cost on a few books and I haven't had the chance to pay her back yet. Could you..?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake pulls out a checkbook and pen.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'd be a great help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SALESGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Nothing under Pearson.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure? This is... Just a complete disaster.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake quickley scans the jewelry in the glass case.</context>
      <utterance>What was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A ring for my wife. Alot like that one. In fact, it was that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's no problem. We have those in stock.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Sorry, I'm just a little anxious to give it to her. You take out of state checks?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With identification. Jake stops writing on the check and locks up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand that, but I had my wallet stolen last night. Is there any way..?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake's anxious look comes back.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>later...</context>
      <utterance>I know it's policy, but...  The thing is... It's our first anniversary and we're only in town for the weekend. It's a very, very special night for my wife and I. This ring is my gift to her and I think she's going to really love it. I can give you phone numbers to call for people who'll vouch. I can send you I.D.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SALESGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is embarrassing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake looks up and rips the check out from his book.</context>
      <utterance>Jake?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake seems to be lost. Mr. Lewis looks over at Lily, who gives him a friendly smile, then back to Jake.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir. Thank you very much for doing this. And please tell Carolyn hello for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unseen to Mr. Lewis, one corner of Jake's lip goes up in a grin.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you let me put the ring on the card and you can write me a check in return?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily takes the box and shakes her head, impressed. Jake Looks up to see Mr. Lewis watching them as he tries to hail a cab. Jake's demeanor quickly changes as he puts on a big smile.</context>
      <utterance>Happy anniversary.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily puts on a big smile while opening the box.</context>
      <utterance>Smile. You just got a present from the man of your dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we gotta give him a strong finish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta go get a haircut.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake watches as Lily walks away. She looks back at Jake once before disappearing around a corner.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INT.- SIXTEENTH PRECINT- DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moonan sits on a desk, ear to a phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was all in play. Everything...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rottovich and Sobozinski enter.</context>
      <utterance>It's Moonan... I'm in New York. Listen, I got Vig. He's here and I'm this close... Look, I understand that, but I'm telling you this time... Obsessive is a big word to use... Goddamn it, Lou! I'm telling you, this is it. Yeah... I figured you'd feel that way. So here's the deal... Call Kylie over at the Bureau. Tell him I got something that might interest him. A guy they call the King Pin. I think there may be a corruption case brewing here, too... That's right. So even if I don't get Vig, you'll still have something to show.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whaddya mean? We got dick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moonan kicks a chair across the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You guy's are not working with me here. I just got off the phone with my boss. After he got done ripping me a new Lincoln Tunnel size asshole, he let me know exactly how little I'm welcome back if we come up short. And now here you guys are, WASTING MY FUCKING TIME!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like we told you before, we think he's into something with the King Pin---</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moonan walks over to the fallen chair and picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm not a confrontational person by nature.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moonan kicks the chair down again, sending Rottovich and Sobozinski back a few steps.</context>
      <utterance>I need answers and the only two things you've given me are jack and shit. You gotta do better. You gotta do better or I swear on my sweet dead grandmother's grave, I'm gonna make you guys an I-A-fucking-D cautionary tale.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a superstitious fucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luck's a funny thing. Especially the bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Having a gun pointed at you for one. It's not like breaking a mirror bad luck, but it's bad. Three on a match, black cats... Believe it. Believe it all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if you wanna talk about bad luck...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, a KNOCK on the door. Jake opens the door to reveal Lily, dressed in an expensive business suit and sporting a sophisticated cut of new RED HAIR</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Redheads.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>INSERT SHOT- A RED HEADED WOMAN enters dark bedroom, carrying an axe...</context>
      <utterance>Top three all-time worst red-heads...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>INSERT SHOT- A dinner table for TWELVE MEN dressed in flowing robes. A RED HEADED MAN leans over to whisper in the ear of an important looking guy in the middle...</context>
      <utterance>Lizzie Borden... Axe murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>INSERT SHOT- A RED HEADED WOMAN, middle-aged with a bad haircut from the 70's carrying a suitcase leans down and tearfully kisses a SMALL BOY on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Judas... Betrayer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shirley Vig... Abandoner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO FREEZE FRAME OF LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The action resumes...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to see you too. Why are you getting so bent? She takes a step into the apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just put a mother of a jinx on us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lighten up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lily takes her jacket off revealing a delicate blouse, decorated with a design of flowers and a BIRD.</context>
      <utterance>But the fucking Grand Poo-Bah of all jinxes? A bird in your house...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means death.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake points to her hair.</context>
      <utterance>You have no idea what you've done do you? No idea! What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me to change my hair!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're dead!</context>
      <utterance>What about this? Do you have any idea what this means? You've killed us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I miss something?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The red hair... It's bad luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not like she's a real redhead, Jake...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily grabs her jacket and starts out the door, then turns back around to Jake.</context>
      <utterance>Like that matters! You can't fool bad luck! You can't get by on a technicality! You can't trick karma!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Jake can feel the eyes on him.</context>
      <utterance>So much for that good feeling, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake takes off after her.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody says a word I swear to God...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had you tempting fate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LILY steps out from behind Butch.</context>
      <utterance>My father used to play the same fucking lotto numbers with these other guys in the pharmacy. The same numbers everyday for sixteen years. One day he gets pissed off, tells them he's out and plays his own numbers. They hit the Lucky Seven for one point two million.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily looks down at Jake and the gun pointed at his head. There's not even a hint of sympathy.</context>
      <utterance>Guess he passed on that unlucky- asshole gene.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should have trusted me Jake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BLONDE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ashby turns to see an ATTRACTIVE BLONDE pointing to the empty seat next to him.</context>
      <utterance>Is this seat taken?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, no. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Blonde grabs the barstool and starts to walk off with it. A rejected look from Ashby.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Lily appears next to the Blonde. Ashby looks around to make sure she's talking to him.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm not that late. You didn't have to give away my seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't sure if you'd make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily takes the barstool back.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I didn't know you... Here. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blonde woman leaves as Lily sits down next to Ashby.</context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for playing along. I just have to sit for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tough day?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What are you drinking?</context>
      <utterance>Brutal day. They say the streets are lined with money down here, but I guess you have to know the secret handshake.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily signals the BARTENDER for two more drinks.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, Maker's Mark. Rocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name's Grant. Grant Ashby.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake, Ashby's demeanor brightening again.</context>
      <utterance>Oh god. I'm overbearing and rude. Lily. Lily Finn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's more like what aren't I doing. My partners and I are trying to secure start up capital for a small tech company. We tried the venture capitalist route in the Valley, but then again who hasn't up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silicon Valley?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The drinks arrive. Lily hands the bartender a twenty.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. So, brainiacs that we are, we thought we'd be innovative and relocate east. Try our luck with a straight corporate loan out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can---</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flashes a trademark smile as they CLINK glasses.</context>
      <utterance>On me. For the seat. Cheers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we've been meeting with banks all day. It's amazing how many ways they can say "no" without ever using the word.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily arches an eyebrow at Ashby.</context>
      <utterance>Well, typically, corporate loans are relatively simple matters, but you do need to demonstrate a capacity for gross fund recovery.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me you started a tech firm here before us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. Nothing like that. I work in a bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ashby reverts back to schlub mode.</context>
      <utterance>My partners are here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well, thanks for the drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome. I was just going to ask you if you'd like to join us. Ashby brightens again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all break out into LAUGHTER.</context>
      <utterance>So then Miles walks straight into the Creative Director's office and says "The code's fine, the program's for shit" and throws down like a thousand pages of code on the guy's desk!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this is our boss, right? He chases me and Miles out of his office and he's yelling and screaming, "You're fired! Your whole team's fired!" He starts looking for Lily, Lupus, Gordo--</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More LAUGHS.</context>
      <utterance>But the best part was that he couldn't find Gordo! He was in the bathroom. So he finally goes in there, kicks in a stall door and starts yelling! And there's Gordo, pants at the ankles, holding a PC World Magazine!</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't been able to use a public bathroom since.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus's non-sequitur brings the whole rhythm of the conversation to a grinding halt.</context>
      <utterance>Especially with the thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, right... And that was it. That's when we decided to start our own business. No more shithead bosses.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I envy you guys. Taking a chance like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Masters of our own destiny.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What bank are you with?</context>
      <utterance>So far, masters of our own demise.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>City Bank of Manhattan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's that Gillette guy, right?  You Like him? As a boss, I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's . . . He's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More LAUGHS.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you do over at your bank, Grant?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group exchanges Looks.</context>
      <utterance>What do I do? I'm the VP of Finance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. We haven't met with anyone your level yet. VP? So that means there's you, then the P.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you can help us understand what's so hard about getting a corporate loan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As long as you can demonstrate--</context>
      <utterance>Well, typically speaking, they're not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yeah, we got that part.</context>
      <utterance>A capacity for gross fund recovery.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. And tech firms... They 'tend to scare people off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Present company excluded of course.</context>
      <utterance>They scare people off because most people lack vision. Vision and balls.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Banks need to know how they're going to get their money back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know exactly how we're going to make The money back. There in lies the Catch-22</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An uncomfortable silence falls.</context>
      <utterance>I don't follow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jake...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws Ashby a flirty smile.</context>
      <utterance>It's alright. Grant's one of the good guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus casually punches Ashby in the arm. It's meant to be a friendly tap, but it's hard enough to jerk Ashby's head to the side. Ashby lets out an uncomfortable LAUGH as he rubs his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. He's our boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, what I'm about to tell you, I'm telling you in confidence, okay?  Have you ever heard of a company called Big.Com?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big.Com. That Internet thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. The guys who started that did what a lot of companies in the Valley do. They get a good idea, shop it around, raise some capital, then sell it off to a bigger company. Microsoft, Intel, Oracle, whatever. The beauty of it is, they've pretty much sold the company before they're even real. The bigger company is already set to buy it, all they want to do is make sure that the idea actually works. So they get some start up capital, make it work, then sell it for like five times the initial loan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort of like a letter of intent.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. But the Catch-22 is that you can't tell anyone about the offer, because if it's public, you could start a bidding war and that's considered a breach of etiquette. It could kill a deal. But, wait too long and you're not considered hot anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you have this letter of intent?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's why I wish there were guys willing to take a chance and live a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting down to the wire. Apparently another company has a similar product in R&amp;D right now. If they beat us to it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ashby considers for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Off the record, I'm this close to cutting someone in on the action if it'd help.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake and Lily share an almost imperceptible look.</context>
      <utterance>Should we get another round?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesus, I almost felt sorry for the guy.</context>
      <utterance>Poor bastard never knew what hit him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta work off some of this adrenaline. I got a line on this Pawn Shop guy over in Brooklyn. Anybody want in?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I' m going home</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go, Jake?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... No thanks. I'm not going all the way to Brooklyn for a hundred dollar pay-off.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake looks over at. Lily then nods. Gordo, Miles and Lupus start to head off.</context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lupus! Lupus turns and Jake moves closer. JAKE  When this is all over, you're going to tell me who the King put on Al.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to have the time?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus nods and heads off. Jake watches them go.</context>
      <utterance>I'11 find the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at you... You want to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what? A couple hundred bucks?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you'd do it for free. You' re almost drooling. You like the rush.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what I do. It's my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Your mother not breast feed you or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you asking me if I have something to prove?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have something to prove?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not in that repressed anger sort of way.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm your basic underachiever. Can't stand working and porn doesn't seem like a good option.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good quality porn has it's place in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever. But you... I get the feeling you could have bullshitted your way into anything. So why this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manipulating... I'm good at it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm good at it. Lying, cheating.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's more than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Intuition. It doesn't make you Yoda. Like tonight. You killed that guy tonight. But I knew you would.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that was my part? Smile and shake my ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You have another part? You'll know what to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know I will?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Intuition.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have really soft hands. Like a baby's.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They roll off the bed onto the floor, a naked tangle of arms and legs, their hands still entwined.</context>
      <utterance>Don't ruin this for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what it was, Jake? Was it love?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily looks away, her face softening for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>You know when the first con was ever played? It was when Adam fell for Eve in the Garden of Eden.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake continues to LAUGH...</context>
      <utterance>Then she fucked him over with an apple.  Redheads...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake resumes kissing Lily's neck, trying to rekindle some of last night's magic.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think we can do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily rolls away from Jake. Undaunted, Jake starts kissing her back.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Even if we don't, you'll be alright. You're not in the hole with the King.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who says you have to know the King to be in a whole? I actually did have a real job once. When I was in high school, I worked as a candy striper.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds respectable.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the way I did it. I was loaded half the time. I don't know how you could change bedpans sober.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake, kissing up the length of Lily's neck.</context>
      <utterance>You want to talk about an old boyfriend right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wasn't my boyfriend. I had a boyfriend at the time... What was his name? Anyway, Glenn was like thirty. I was only fifteen. But he was a nice guy. Real sweet. Liked to talk. We used to get loaded on pills from the nurses station and then listen to Morrisey or some stupid shit like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, the sensitive guy-thing never worked for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were friends. I trusted him. I should have known it was weird. But, then again I was weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake still kissing...</context>
      <utterance>You guys got busted. This is a great neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we never got busted. We were done with a shift one night, both a couple of Percocets down and I was telling Glenn about my boyfriend, about how we were thinking about doing it, you know? I was thinking about letting him be my first because I loved him.  What the hell was his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glenn talked you out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort of. I was telling him about this great love of my life who's name I don't remember, and I could see... He was getting pissed. I thought it was just because he was worried about me, but...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was looking out for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then he grabbed me and threw me down on the floor, that really cold linoleum tiled hospital floor and started ripping my uniform off.  He said he was going to "fuck some sense into me." Jake stops kissing Lily and looks up at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, what was that guy's name? I really liked him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lily... Jesus Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake slides off Lily.</context>
      <utterance>After Glenn was finished, he gave me a couple of valiums and I went home. The next day, I finished my shift and met him around back, like we always did. I stuck a number eight scalpel into his chest. Three or four times.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did, uh... Did you kill him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake considers for a second.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I packed up my shit and ran away. To this... So unlike you, I guess I do have something to prove, in a repressed anger sort of way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You trusted him... You were just getting square.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know why I told you that, Jake?  Because I trust you too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch lowers the gun down and looks over at Lily.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, honey. But I figure if we can't all share at a time like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got some issues, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch freezes as A POLICE SIREN WAILS in the BACKGROUND, growing CLOSER then FADING again. He puts the gun back to Jake's head.</context>
      <utterance>I can take care of myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had to finalize the deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything looks in order.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has to happen fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. It won't go unnoticed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake slides an envelope across the desk.</context>
      <utterance>There'll be red flags.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ashby leafs through the money in the envelope.</context>
      <utterance>You need some convincing. Consider it a convincer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just slow down for a second...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're worried about recouping the loan. I already told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ECU- A bead of sweat rolls down the back of Ashby's neck.</context>
      <utterance>No, I understand that. What I mean... What I'm trying to say... I was actually wondering about... Well, my cut.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then there it is. Ashby gets the itch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The standard ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten percent. Of how much?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two million.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three or four times over.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to make it back, Grant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a pause before Ashby smiles, then reaches around to scratch his neck.</context>
      <utterance>And all you need to do for your ten percent is put some paperwork through and push a button tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight A.M. flight.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calls?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass the glass partitioned conference room. Jake looks inside to see Morgan Gillette holding court with a bunch of SUITS. Butch stands behind Gillette. For a second, Butch and Jake's eyes meet.</context>
      <utterance>We'll use the Euc.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake turns just in time to catch Rottovich's fist square in the face. Jake staggers back and Sobozinski pushes him into an alley.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Jake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That tip not work-out for you fellas?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tip was fine, Jake. We were a little more curious about the Fed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sobozinski punches Jake in the stomach. Miles and Gordo lurch forward--</context>
      <utterance>Hey, listen... If you guys don't pay your taxes, that's your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want I should hold him down?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Special Agent Gunther Moonan. Ring a bell?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gunther? I think I'd remember a Gunther.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sobozinski punches Jake again.</context>
      <utterance>Ring it for him, Sobo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thanks.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Moonan. I remember now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well he's in town and he sure as shit remembers you. What are we going to do about this Jake? We can't afford to have a Fed onto us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rottovich punches Jake hard in the stomach, sending him GASPING to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't dream of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're into with the King Pin, but whatever it is we get a piece, understand? We get a big piece. If we find out you're keeping us out, I may suddenly develope a conscious and give you up to Moonan myself. Say something stupid if we got a deal, Jake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the cops exit, Lily, Miles and Gordo rush to Jake.</context>
      <utterance>And don't leave town!  I always wanted to say that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he buy it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so. What'd he ever do to you anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moonan calmly turns the page of the paper.</context>
      <utterance>Let's just say he burned me once.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's this guy so hard up for you? You're not exactly a threat to national security.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Through the crowd, we catch a glimpse of Moonan, in sunglasses, watching the guys.</context>
      <utterance>Turns out this local goon was being watched by the Feds, which means we were being watched by the Feds. One in particular.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Special Agent Gunther Moonan. Jake turns and catches Moonan looking at him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EXT.- RACETRACK/PARKING LOT- DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moonan walks over to a car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Moonan pulls a piece of paper off the windshield that reads: "La Scala 2night."</context>
      <utterance>He didn't really have anything on us, but I figure, maybe this guy's good for a Fix. So I ask him out to dinner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake nonchalantly slides a fat envelope over to Moonan. Moonan picks it up and finds a wad of cash.</context>
      <utterance>These guys we have now, sure, give them twenty bucks and they'll look the other way on a parking ticket. But a Fed... You get a guy like that as your Fix...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was probably a stupid idea. There I am, Armani and Rolex. There he is, JC Penny and Timex...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INT.- THE EUCLID- DAY</speaker>
      <mode>RESUMING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jake finishes the story to Lupus.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus nods, satisfied.</context>
      <utterance>And that's how Special Agent Gunther Moonan and I became friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moonan. Here. Shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake gets up, hard enough to knock the chair over.</context>
      <utterance>So what? We just stay clear of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus... Take it easy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not going to take it easy. You can't stay clear of this guy. He will be on this until the end of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do? We change the scam?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no scam! I've got a fucking sign on my back! I can't leave town now and come back with a suitcase full of money. You get it? It's over. We walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jake--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's it. The gig's up.</context>
      <utterance>What do I always tell you guys? Don't spend it all. Sooner or later we're going to run into some bad luck. Save some. Put it away, so when shit like this happens, you're not desperate.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can still do this!</context>
      <utterance>That's it? What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jake, I mean, come on--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no! Not this time. I am doing this for your own good! You guys have got to learn when to stop. You with the Armani! You with the hookers!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Escorts!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you even remember Al? Do you remember what he looked like sitting there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are such a raving pussy sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, we fucked once, honey. That hardly makes you a good judge of character. And don't think I didn't know you were working some angle with that either.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone's working an angle, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily looks around the room. No one seems to be backing her up.</context>
      <utterance>There are three people I trust-- him, him and a guy who got killed. I don't know who you are! You're like some stray doq that wandered into the house. So I'm telling you to cut loose of this. No one's looking for you, Not the King, not Moonan and not Gillette. Just go wherever it is you would go. It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake stops and levels a look at Lily.</context>
      <utterance>What about the money?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So there it is. You got that big itch you need to scratch. It's all about the fucking money. What do you want, an apology?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I want my cut!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to say this one last time for You, so take a deep breath and count to ten. There is no cut. Lily levels a look of utter contempt at Jake.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus sits quietly, taking it all in.</context>
      <utterance>You're an asshole. With that, she grabs her coat and leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>King ain't gonna like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I'll settle up with your boss. We haven't skipped town yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I'm saying is, is that the King ain't gonna care. See he had a real thing with getting this Gillette guy, If you ask me I think he's jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of what? They're both crooks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. `Cept this Gillette guy. He gets to walk around in three piece suits, hob knob with the Mayor, own a bank, that kinda shit. Meanwhile, the King sits holed up in the steam, afraid to even take a leak without me or Harlin watching the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My fucking heart bleeds.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your buddy. That fat guy. The King couldn't wait to have that guy whacked. He didn't even know who the guy was, but he was so pissed off at him, he gets him drilled. It ain't personal. It's business.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Point, Lupus. Give us a point.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus stares blankly at Jake.</context>
      <utterance>Point is, you don't go through with this, he's going to go after you next. And he don't even like you, Jake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was doing it for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BULLSHIT! You were scared, Jake! You - Lost your nerve! You lost your confidence! You weren't being noble. You weren't trying to save anybody but yourself! Admit it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake doesn't move. Butch grabs him by the hair and turns him towards Lily. BUTCH (cont'd) She trusted you and you sold her out! Be honest! Be a man! Tell her, Jake! Tell her that you loved her but the money meant more to you! Butch kicks Jake in the gut. BUTCH (cont'd) Grifters... Gentleman's racket... My ass. You're just any other lowlife stammer-- Looking out for number one. Jake shuts his eyes, maybe because Butch is right.</context>
      <utterance>Yes it is Jake! Yes it is! They were right there for you. She was right there for you! Look at her!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coupla things. They got this Fed , loo king around and the girl just split.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Fed? Is he close?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. Their Fix gave us the heads up and Jake's got a plan that'll probably keep him off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake looks up.</context>
      <utterance>But this girl, the redhead. She knows a lot. She could be a pain in the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus cups the phone.</context>
      <utterance>No. She won't. She's not going to be a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake reaches over and grabs the phone.</context>
      <utterance>He wants to talk to you.  Don't tell him I said he was jealous of Gillette, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh... Uh huh... Okay... I understand. Jake hangs up the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he said good luck.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know... Don't fuck this up. I'll kill you. I'll kill your family. I'll shoot your dog... All the usual.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were back on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After you cut her loose.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily pushes Butch aside and moves closer to Jake.</context>
      <utterance>She walked.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I walked? Let me tell you a story, asshole...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>Lily frantically rumages through drawers. She pulls a knife, but it's only a butter knife. She tosses it aside. Lily moves to the door and looks out the peep hole.</context>
      <utterance>Lily?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode>O. S.</mode>
      <context>Lily moves to the closet.</context>
      <utterance>.Jake sent me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More KNOCKING.</context>
      <utterance>Jake? Hold on. I just got out of the shower.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily, wide-eyed, stands frozen with the bat still cocked..</context>
      <utterance>The King would like to have a word with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily takes a swing. Harlin easily grabs the bat and backhands Lily. She goes flying back into the far wall, bounces off and lands with a THUD at Harlin's feet where she finds the butter knife. Harlin reaches down and pulls Lily up by the hair. The egg SIZZLES in the pan. Lily takes a stab at Harlin, but the knife just bounces off his coat. Harlin slaps Lily again, sending her flying into the stove. Smoke starts to rise from the burning egg. Harlin steps closer, but Lily throws her hands up in surrender. A spoon RATTLES in a cup as the RUMBLE of a subway train grows LOUDER.</context>
      <utterance>Please. I have a car waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I apologize for the--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I didn't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend, Big Al? It should have been you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alrlght, alrlght. What happened today?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today? Started off great...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake stares off into space, absentmindedly flipping a penny in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>He should be landing in the Caymens about now. The Custom's guy is ready right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feeling lucky today, Miles. Found a penny-- Heads up. There was an empty cab right outside my building. We hit every green light.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake considers...</context>
      <utterance>And we got rid of the red head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we got rid of the red head.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake just nods and continues flipping the penny. JAKE</context>
      <utterance>Jake? Customs?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say a good chess player can. See up to twenty moves deep. That means that in some games, you've calculated every possible move in your head... The game's over before it's even " really started.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same thing with playing a con. You have to be able to see that deep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT SHOT- ECU of Ashby's finger on the "Enter" key. ASHBY (coat' d) Now. Ashby hangs up and checks over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Jake? Right. Uh-huh... Uh-huh... Yeah, it's going through--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Gordo stands in front of a Teller. She reads off a paper then does a double take at Gordo, who smiles back.</context>
      <utterance>Gordo was making the withdrawal from the Grand Laymen's Bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V. O. </mode>
      <context>Gordo slides a folder of corporate papers along with his photo ID towards the Teller. We follow the teller as she hands the papers to the</context>
      <utterance>They check the papers...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then he had to bang it out across the street at the Bank of the Caymens...</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER TELLER looks at the check then back up at Gordo. GORDO (cont'd ) I also need to deduct a certain amount and deposit it into this account number. Gordo takes another piece of paper and slides it to the Teller.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like this cashed, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAR I E</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ashby watches the screen, as a big broad smile comes across his face.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Ashby? Mr. Thompson from International with a 34R on a corporate account.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASHBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ashby grabs his coat and strides confidently out.</context>
      <utterance>Probably just a new account marker.  Tell him I already left for lunch and that I'll call him later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BANK OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On a small table are neat piles of bundled money, shrink wrapped in plastic. Gordo seems in awe.</context>
      <utterance>We'll let you have a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Bank Official and Security Guard exit. Gordo holds up a Green Twinkie up to his nose and takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>We called them Green Twinkies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miles was on his way to the airport to wait for Gordo to land. I made the call.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's me. I need an escort. Not a ride, just an escort. You wanted in, this is in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about Moonan. We got him covered. When..?  It was him. There's a shipment coming through tonight. Kennedy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After Rottovich and Sobozinski exit, Moonan dials a number.</context>
      <utterance>Shipment of what?  Find two cars. And change into plain clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>International terminal. Come heavy.</context>
      <utterance>It's Moonan. Tonight. JFK.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's it, huh? You get the cops to give you a safe ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you something... You really think I'm going to come this close, this fucking close and let my guard down? I'll get square with your boss. I'll get square with whoever did Al. I'll get square with everybody. Then I'm going going to cash in my chips and be on my way to a new and better me far away from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus gets off the stool and we follow him into...</context>
      <utterance>You're a weasal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got pigs for an escort. You believe this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King struggles into a pair of pants, then turns around. KING PIN (cont' d) My ass look big in this? Harlin deliberately looks away.</context>
      <utterance>Always something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks fine, Boss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>INT.- UNMARKED POLICE CAR- SAME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sobozinski and Rottovich overlook the terminal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOSOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You trust this Moonan guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't trust anybody. You see how bad this guy wants Vig? It's like a sickness. I say we collar Vig ourselves. We got Vig, then we got leverage. And we trade; Vig for that tape. I want to see it right in front of my face.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just insurance.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm down! Sobozinski holds his hand up for a high five.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>High five.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's the CRACKLE from a walkie-talkie.</context>
      <utterance>Put your hand down. I don't high five.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys awake?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INT.- JET- SAME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gordo on the Air-Phone next to MRS. HEAVYSET...</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MR. HEAVYSET returns to his seat, drying his hands on his own shirt.</context>
      <utterance>I'm landing in about fifteen minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HEAVYSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Heavyset pats her husband's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Jeez... I tell ya, this airline food goes right through me every time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever use the bathroom in Kennedy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INT.- THE EUCLID- SAME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jake hangs up...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's wheeling around two million dollars in cash and he wants to stop to use the bathroom. You believe this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's got it right. Maybe we're all just looking for a safe place to shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus gets up and heads for the bathroom again.</context>
      <utterance>That was fucking deep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's landing. He's got a suitcase on wheels.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING PIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do half the other people in this place. How do I know which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it figured out... He's got this thing with bathrooms. If he makes it through Customs, he'll be heading for the john.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up with you? Bladder infection?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got my cell. Leave a message.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>It's me. It's Jake. Listen... It's happening. Gordo's landing right now. Meet me at the Euclid... For your cut, I mean. It's... I want you to have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's cool.</context>
      <utterance>You really like that bitch don't you? I gotta tell you, I was pretty convinced that the whole thing before was blowing her off for her cut. You know how it is, get her to do some shit for you, throw her a bang to keep her happy. But, if you're into her...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I like about you, Lupus. You're a free thinker. Don't let the King tell you different.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for nothing, Jake, but the guy who whacked your buddy? It was me. The King usually farms out for that kind of stuff, but I tell ya, he was so pissed off he couldn't wait for the regular guy. Fucker didn't even put down his Kung Pao Chicken.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Egg Foo Young.  Stand up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No offense, but I've seen you fight. You gotta be kidding m- Jake's sends a fist flying right into Lupus' mouth, knocking him over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said stand up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is probably about where you came in.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Now that's an exciting story. Butch, has anyone ever tried something like this before?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that I recall. What do you want us to do about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We double our money.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see... Let's suppose he gets to Customs and he gets caught. We get our money back, but then we have to deal with a criminal investigation. I don't much like that idea. Then again, let's suppose he actually gets through Customs. Now, that'll be something. We recover the money in cash and let the insurance cover the corporate fraud.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we go to the bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so. The airport's going to be crawling with police. Traffic will be a nightmare. Go down to the bar. If they pull it off, great. Have someone deal with Ashby.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll take care of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVEAL Lily sitting on the couch in front of them, cell phone in hand.</context>
      <utterance>And how much did you say you wanted for this... What did you call it? A finder's fee?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten? That seems a little high.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten is standard, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. But only if we recover the cash.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only if--? No way. I want something for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sounds like a good story.</context>
      <utterance>Have a little faith in him, honey. Butch, see if you can get him to tell you how he did it. Or almost did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillette picks up an APPLE from a bowl in his desk... The oldest con.</context>
      <utterance>I' ll ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apple?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INT.- CAR- SAME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rottovich and Sobozinski check their guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOONAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's headed towards the eastern most exit. Do not, under any circumstances approach. I want to follow this all the way down to Vig.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOBOZINSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sobozinski snorts a LAUGH as they get out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, we'll wait, jerk-off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eee Oott Auught!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus picks up the phone and dials another number... No answer.</context>
      <utterance>HE GOT CAUGHT! Your boss tried to pull a switch and he got us all fucking pinched!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus cocks the gun and crams it back into Jake's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus takes a newspaper off the bar and covers Jake's face with it. SLAM!!!-- Blood splatters across the front page of the Metro Section. The paper falls away revealing Jake, wide- eyed, the gun hanging from his mouth. Lupus lies in a heap at the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Aaaaiiit!!! Ooopusss!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we please all stop being so goddamnfucking-polite and get to the point?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch presses the gun against Jake's head. Jake turns and looks at Lily. They lock eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Where's the money, Jake?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you get, Lily? Finder's Fee? Because it is all about the money, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sold me out. You should have trusted me like I trusted you. You fucked up. You fucked up HUGE. Butch taps Jake on the head with the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where is it?</context>
      <utterance>Alright... Turn around. She doesn't get shit, unless I get that money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably safe in the hands of the Federal Government. Butch buttons his coat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jake. You disappoint me. And you just let Lily here down again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like putting on a play, where everyone knows their part except for the mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like putting on a play... Guess some people forgot their lines.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess so.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Butch continues to count, Jake slowly turns his head and looks at Lily. Butch, still counting, smiles at Lily's obvious contempt then slides the gun along the back of Jake's head.</context>
      <utterance>So why don't you take a deep breath, Jake, and I'll count to ten. One. Two. Three...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch turns back to Lily to see her reaching into her bag...</context>
      <utterance>I do trust you, Lily.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily pulls out a gun and... BLAM!!!</context>
      <utterance>Wha- Butch spins and aims at her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake lies face down in a puddle, the collected pool of water growing red with blood. POLICE SIRENS WAIL in the distance, growing closer.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ! Tell me before you do something like that!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch disappears down the dark alley. Lily stands for a moment and takes a final look at Jake's body. She then turns and runs back into the bar.</context>
      <utterance>You should leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'm dead...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell them the "Tale".</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want? An apology?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lupus watches quietly, taking it all in...</context>
      <utterance>No, I want my cut!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And like in a game of chess, you've played every possible move in your head...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were right. He's trying to fuck you. You want it, you gotta get it at the airport...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The King Pin and Harlin are bent over the hood handcuffed. Rottovich and Sobozinski lie on the ground, face down, their hands behind their heads.</context>
      <utterance>Then you give them the "Blow-off". You get them off your back. Forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROTTOVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Next to them, a Federal Agent opens the suitcase. Coffee beans spill out on the asphalt, followed by the two bricks of heroin. The TWO INTERNAL AFFAIRS officers from before emerge from the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>We're on the job! We're active in the one-six.</utterance>
   <speaker>IA OFFICER#1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second Internal Affairs officer holds up a</context>
      <utterance>Officers Rottovich and Sobozinski?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Custom Officer waves Gordo through. Gordo reaches down and picks up an IDENTICAL BLACK suitcase already lying on the table next to his and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Like Suits said, sooner or later someone's going to start asking the right questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Moonan walks over to the Customs Desk and takes the original black suitcase. He nods to the Customs Officer. Moonan turns and walks TOWARDS CAMERA, wheeling the suitcase behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Rottovich and Sobozinski would ask how the drugs got in that suitcase. The King and Gillette would ask where the money really went.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We CLOSE-IN ON THE BADGE hanging from Moonan's neck. On it is a number and the single word, "CUSTOMS".</context>
      <utterance>And all of them would ask what agency Special Agent Gunther Moonan worked for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A black car comes to a stop n front of him. The tinted glass slides down and Jake leans in.</context>
      <utterance>No one's going to ask me:</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside we see Moonan and Lily riding in the back, Miles and Gordo up front.</context>
      <utterance>Drop something?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles that smile.</context>
      <utterance>Oops.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jake gets in and the car pulls away, followed seconds later by two Police Cars SCREECHING to a stop in front of the Euclid.</context>
      <utterance>Redheads...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
