<movie id="141" title="Cowboys and Aliens">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WES CLAIBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howdy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WES CLAIBORNE</speaker>
      <mode>NO RESPONSE</mode>
      <context>The Man's got NO IDEA what he's talking about.</context>
      <utterance>We're riding towards Absolution. You know how far west we are?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE CLAIBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wes hops off his horse, right in The Man's face now --</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's a dummy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WES CLAIBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now, Mose nods to the BRACELET on The Man's wrist --</context>
      <utterance>There a reason you don't wanna answer my question, friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE CLAIBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wes, he's got iron on his wrist... and he's been shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE CLAIBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke spurs his horse behind him -- The Man's SURROUNDED.</context>
      <utterance>Bet he's a chain jumper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wes nods as he slides a SAWED-OFF DOUBLE-BARREL from his back scabbard. COCKS both barrels. The dog GROWLS --</context>
      <utterance>If he escaped, there'll be a bounty. Let's bring him with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>WES CLAIBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But The Man doesn't move. The Claibornes share glances. Wes steps forward -- RAISING HIS RIFLE --</context>
      <utterance>Not your lucky day, Stranger -- turn round and start walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>WES CLAIBORNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead or alive, no difference. I said</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog sits by the door as The Man enters -- EMPTY -- he's moving -- into a small kitchen area -- bottle of whiskey -- uncorks it with his teeth -- drinks -- pours some on the wound -- then A PISTOL COCKS behind him -- Meet MEACHAM, town preacher, a tough, wash-foot Baptist:</context>
      <utterance>Stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man freezes. Turns up his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Palms to heaven, Friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only two kinds of men get shot -- criminals and victims.  Which one're you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meacham hears the HONESTY in his voice. Knows a lost soul when he sees one. Lowers his gun, softening...</context>
      <utterance>don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a name, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know that either.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Meacham, INTRIGUED -- we CUT TO:</context>
      <utterance>... English.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man just stares. News to him. And now, as Meacham leans over the wound, the METAL CROSS around his neck begins to twitch... lifting ever so SLIGHTLX off his chest -- towards the strange BRACELET on the Man's wrist. Meacham reacts --</context>
      <utterance>Odd wound. Looks... cauterized.  Means somethin' burned it half closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Man looks at him -- "What the hell is a 'magnet'?!?" Meacham shrugs it off, readies the needle --</context>
      <utterance>Nice trick. That some kinds... magnet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He pokes the hot needle through the wound -- The Man winces slightly, but bears the pain.</context>
      <utterance>Try'n hold still.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you ride in from?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>West. Woke up in the desert. Looking up at the sun like I'd been dropped outta the sky.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems I remember a story about that happening once... fella by the name of Lucifer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>GRINS</mode>
      <context>But TheMan's distracted by his REFLECTION in a cracked mirror: his own face unfamiliar. Meacham nods towards The Man's HANDS --</context>
      <utterance>How 'bout I just call you "Luke," for short.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That blood yours or somebody else's?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three men rode up. Drew on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode>STILL CONFUSED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My hands... moved on their own.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>A BEAT</mode>
      <context>And The Man senses somehow that, ygg, there is... but:</context>
      <utterance>Anything else you wanna confess to while you got my attention?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything that happened before I woke up...  It's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meacham looks up, eyes twinkling. This is not a fire n' brimstone preacher. This is a guy who GETS IT --</context>
      <utterance>Well. Too bad. Can't absolve you for your sins if you don't recall 'em. That bein' said...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>it's yours.</context>
      <utterance>I seen bad men do good things and good men do bad things. Whether you end up in heaven or hell... it's not God's plan...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>The Man considers. Darkly --</context>
      <utterance>You just got to remember what it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if I don't want to remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT; GRINS</mode>
      <context>On cue -- SMASH!!! The stained glass window EXPLODES as a MOLOTOV COCKTAIL hurtles into the church. FIRE spreads around the pews -- MEACHAM ACTIVATES -- tears curtains off the confessional and uses them to STAMP OUT the fire --</context>
      <utterance>Then you're probl'y goin' to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>WHOOPS and HOLLERS and GUNSHOTS outside! The Man whirls to see A DOZEN MEN ON HORSEBACK, marauding through town --</context>
      <utterance>Dammit -- it's Dolarhyde's men!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Percy! N2t the saloon!</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the goddamn hell not?!</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something LOADED in the way he emphasizes "daddy." Percy GLARES -- strange RESENTMENT between them. With a growl, Percy GALLOPS OFF, chucks the flaming bottle onto the CHURCH STEPS:</context>
      <utterance>Cause your dady said so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meacham tosses The Man one of the blankets, nods across the street to the GENERAL STORE which is just STARTING to burn --</context>
      <utterance>All right, folks -- don't panic! Get inside and you'll be fine... C'mon...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ON THE MAN, not sure how he suddenly became the damn fire brigade, but HUSTLING across the street to --</context>
      <utterance>Put it out before it gets goin'!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can answer, HOOFBEATS behind them -- and here's PERCY. He yanks the reins, pulls his REVOLVER on our Man --</context>
      <utterance>Just tryin' to save the candy.  You one of my Pa's hired guns?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whatever the opposite of Love At First Sight is, THIS is it:</context>
      <utterance>Who the hell're yam?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid's scared. The Man ISN'T, despite the gun in his face:</context>
      <utterance>Nobody is right. You think you can just collect your fifty dollars and ride off? You signed up for the wrong side, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Man's eyes narrow --</context>
      <utterance>Tell you what. You get down on your knees and kiss my boot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do that and I'll let you run back to wherever the hell you came from so you can tell whoever you see...  Absolution belongs -tg..th-e- 1Dolar es.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Percy extends his boot just INCHES from The Man's face:</context>
      <utterance>You want me to kiss your boot?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THWIP! The Man YANKS Percy's boot off his foot in one quick move and KWHAM!!!1 WINGS IT RIGHT INTO PERCY'S FACE! Percy FLIES off the HORSE -- The Man grabbing his rifle -- the moment Percy lands, it's STICKING into his NECK:</context>
      <utterance>Tongue's just fine if you're feelin' amorous. Don't hold ba --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- but The Man yanks Percy up by his collar, using him as a SHIELD between himself and Colorado. Eerily calm --</context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit, Nat -- SHOOT HIM!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colorado knows he's dealing with a PROFESSIONAL. MORE GANG MEMBERS ride up, surprised -- a dirty outlaw, GREAVEY, barks:</context>
      <utterance>Wherever you came from? Go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheriff's right behind us, Nat!</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colorado -- DECISION -- doesn't take long -- glares at The Man --</context>
      <utterance>You goddamned shitheels! Don't you even THINK about leavin' me!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be seeing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Nat spurs his horse -- YA! The others follow him as he RIDES HARD out of town. Percy growls at The Man --</context>
      <utterance>Look forward to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DM! The Man's SMASHES Percy's skull with the gun, knocking him OUT COLD, as LAWMEN approach on horseback --</context>
      <utterance>You are a dead man. You hear me? So help me God I will kill you my--</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SHERIFF KYLE TAGGART rears up on his horse. Tall, dark and handsome despite a SADNESS in his eyes, already dismounting:</context>
      <utterance>FA! He caught Percy Dolarhyde!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid (now EMMETT) strides towards his father excitedly:</context>
      <utterance>Emmett -- you all right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man shakes Taggart's hand. A beat. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Pardon my boy, mister. He can be excitable.  Kyle Taggart.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>. Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man NODS -- Oh, RIGHT.</context>
      <utterance>Well I'm in your debt, Luke. Tune of fifty dollars, actually.  Our advert? The telegram?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could use a man like you in case any of 'em come back...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I'm just passing through.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man tips his hat, nods to Emmett (still STARSTRUCK), turns to go. Taggart furrows his brow as the DOG scampers after him.</context>
      <utterance>Fair enough. You don't mind spending the night, bank opens in the morning... I'll get you your money then.  Saloon's got rooms. You just tell Maria I sent you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Man stops. Intrigued. Turns back --</context>
      <utterance>You here with the prospector woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup. Real looker. Came into town yesterday with that there dog. She a friend of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>11.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ON THE MAN. His first real LEAD.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as The Man heads off, we HOLD ON TAGGART, his spidey-sense tingling that all is not RIGHT with this...</context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somethin' wrong, Kyle?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that French sayin' where you swear you seen someone before?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't speak French.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taggart takes one last look at The Man departing as we CUT TO:</context>
      <utterance>No... you sure's hell don't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RANCH HAND #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should take it easy there, Pal --</utterance>
   <speaker>RANCH HAND #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Dolarhyde don't like it when we drink on the job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RANCH HAND #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANCH HAND #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hear what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I know you are, don't lie to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many times do we have to do this, Arturo? J. love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him SQUARELY -- yes, some SECRET withheld. As The Man In Black reaches the bar, he's Maria's EXCUSE to end this:</context>
      <utterance>Really? Do you?!?  I found this in our bed! And I don't k3 Vg. a watch, Maria. I can't AfjQrd a watch because y insisted we buy this saloon!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And MOVES off. Doc stomps toward the exit -- sees EMMETT at the back of the bar stealing sips of BEER from left-behind glasses:</context>
      <utterance>We have customers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atticus grumbles and goes back to eating, but not before sweeping his duster aside to show the GUN in his holster. Maria rolls her eyes, sets a GLASS in front of The Man, who nods:</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Atticus. This is the man who took out Percy Dolarhyde.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures to the WHORES --</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes the PHOTO from inside his hat. The one of the WOMAN.</context>
      <utterance>This kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE MAN. Not exactly sure he WANTS to. But they CLINK glasses, knock 'em back. Maria pours him another:</context>
      <utterance>Never seen her before. But she is beautiful.  Here's to you finding her, Senor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have any idea what kind of mess you just stepped into?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria's eyes go down. Somehow GUILTY. But then:</context>
      <utterance>No. But I figured I'd be safe in here seein' as how that boy I tossed off his horse didn't wanna burn your saloon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not the boy you should worry about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode>OMINOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's his papa.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Our POV belongs to ROY CLANTON, the ranch hand from the cow abductions. TERRIFIED -- his arms and legs TIED TO THE SADDLES OF TWO HORSES, kicking dirt in front of Dolarhyde's RANCH HOUSE:</context>
      <utterance>You're Roy, right? Clanton, is it? Been working for me two weeks now, and I haven't had the pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Dolarhyde, I... I swear I didn't</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best not to interrupt me, Roy, makes the horses skittish.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You partial to history? Here's a primer,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Incoming HOOFBEATS -- Dolarhyde looks up to see COLORADO and the rest of the GANG returning from Absolution. A WOMAN emerges from the servant's quarters. APACHE. 50's. Beautiful. As the men REAR, Nat Colorado MEETS EYES with her. A relationship we don't understand yet as Dolar strides up --</context>
      <utterance>The sky. Opened up. And took my cows.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Percy?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolar darkens. Unsheathes a KNIFE. Looks down at Roy:</context>
      <utterance>Jail. Sheriff locked him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He STABS the knife down... SLICING the rope tethered to Roy's FEET. His lower body SLUMPS to the ground, he breathes a SIGH:</context>
      <utterance>When're these people gonna lgarn?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he MOVES OFF, Dolarhyde's eyes go to the Apache Woman. Something passes between them. She seems CONCERNED.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone saddle up. Got us a sheriff to kill.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That STOPS Dolarhyde. He turns back, face dark:</context>
      <utterance>Wasn't the sheriff, got him caught. It was a stranger.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... What stranger?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Usually a man gives off a scent. Where he's been. What he's done.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode>STILL SPOOKED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't have one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEPUTY CHARLIE WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Percy wouldn't've come in shooting without his daddy's say-so, Kyle. You best get ready for a war 'cause that's what's comin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taggart's on his feet, grabs his JACKET off the door --</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow we ride the little shit up Phoenix way, turn him over. Dolarhyde's got a beef, he can take it up with the 6th cavalry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He STOPS. Something catches his eye on the posting board. YANKS a piece of paper off, a mixture of CONFUSION and CONCERN</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn tired of this... fatass rancher scaring good people off their lan--</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>WHAT DOES HE SEE? Before we get a chance to KNOW --</context>
      <utterance>Sonofabitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You drink like a man who wants to forget.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog WHINES AGAIN for the steak. Atticus SLAMS down his silverware. Draws his GUN --</context>
      <utterance>Other way round.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ATTICUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got three seconds to get your dog outta here or I blow his balls off.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not my dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTICUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and just before "three"... CA-CLICK. Atticus FREEZES, because there's a RIFLE BARREL at the back of h,iS head now:</context>
      <utterance>Q=... two...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>RACK TO FIND the person holding the rifle is A WOMAN. Beautiful. EXOTIC. Dressed in leather. Meet ELLA SWENSON. ON THE MAN IN BLACK. Can't help himself. immediate and undeniable CHEMISTRY. But she pays him no mind -- makes a PSST sound and the dog snaps to her side. Atticus uncocks his gun, slowly slides it back in the holster --</context>
      <utterance>Give you odds you don't get to 'three.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTICUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just havin' some fun, Miss --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atticus HESITATES, angry at the humiliation. Ella PRESSES THE GUN HARDER against his neck, lowering him -- and his plate -- to the floor. Right in front of the dog, who GROWLS --</context>
      <utterance>Give- him, the steak.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now say you're sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTICUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm-- sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HappyBARES HIS TEETH. INCHES from Atticus' face</context>
      <utterance>His name's 'Happy.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTICUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... 'Happy.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright then.  You're right. That was fun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing with my dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping you could tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WRIST BRACELET. Surprise and REVELATION:</context>
      <utterance>The hell're you talking ab--?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Before he can answer, SHERIFF TAGGART enters, along with DEPUTY WADE (carrying a SHOTGUN), and 5 other deputies. They move cautiously to THE MAN, like he's a powder keg about to go off...</context>
      <utterance>Where... did you get that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey there, "Luke." Mind following me down to the office so we can have us a chat...?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONFUSED; ALERT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men LOCK EYES:</context>
      <utterance>All due respect, I'm the law, mister. That's what for.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what, Sheriff. How about you keep the fifty dollars you owe me and I just walk outta here like we. never met?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON ELLA. For reasons we're not sure of, the idea of The Man leaving ALARMS her. All the Gunslingers' hands are POISED by holsters. The Man stays preternaturally COOL:</context>
      <utterance>Because we did meet.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>L can't be accountable for what happens if they draw on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what's gonna happen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best you don't find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taggart gives a nod and the men start to CONVERGE --</context>
      <utterance>Now why'd you have to go and say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Charlie makes a MOVE and The Man SLAMS his head into a pole -- the NEXT GUNMAN reaches for his pistol -- The Man PUNCHES his THROAT -- SLAMS the third into a bench -- The FOURTH straight down on the Faro table -- TAGGART levels his REPEATER -- but The Man just GRABS the barrel as Taggart FIRES a ROUND into the ceiling -- now the rifle's in THE MAN'S HANDS and just before he PULLS THE TRIGGER on Taggart: HE SEES EMMETT AT THE WINDOW. About to watch his father's MURDER... and The Man LOWERS the gun:</context>
      <utterance>Don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN IN BLACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>CRACK! The butt of a PISTOL WHIPS the side of his SKULL! The Man DROPS as we REVEAL who just knocked his ass OUT: ELLA! Taggart draws a gun and pins The Man, whipping out that piece of paper he pulled from his office...</context>
      <utterance>I told you, I don't wanna hurt anyb--</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup -- looks just like him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake sits up. Woozy. Blinking back to reality.</context>
      <utterance>You're a dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jake moves LIGHTNING QUICK -- reaching through the bars, GRABBING PERCY'S COLLAR, YANKING FORWARDS -- SLAMMING Percy's head into the bars, KNOCKING hIM OUT COLD AGAIN. Percy DROPS.</context>
      <utterance>My daddy's comin' for me, Boy. You're gonna end up another dead shitheel under his spurs. I am gonna watch you suffer for a long, long --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake sits back on his cot, rubbing his still-throbbing head.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to see Lonergan. It's important.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And pushes PAST her, into the office with the men. HOLD on Ella -- dammit, she NEEDS to find a way in there.</context>
      <utterance>'Fraid not, Miss -- we're preppin' him for transport.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>DEADPAN</mode>
      <context>Taggart shakes his head as Charlie and a deputy unlock Percy's cell, CUFF HIM, drag him out. Taggart points to Jake:</context>
      <utterance>Man walked into a bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Step back against the wall there. Move and I shoot you dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should've let me go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I should've shot you in your knee. You put down six of my deputies.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six was all you had.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, they're gonna love you in Phoenix.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? What's in Phoenix?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taggart reaches into his shirt, pulls out a pair of GLASSES. Slips them on his nose. Takes out that WANTED poster and reads:</context>
      <utterance>What you got comin', Jake Lonergan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aggravated banditry, 17 counts, Forgery, Blackmail, Hijacking, injurious use of a cattle prod, Arson, Incitement of Whorehouse Riot, and Trespassing with intent to deflower. You're also leader of a gang of outlaws includin' Creek Johnson and Bull McCade, which makes you accessory to every law they broke too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That LANDS on Jake. Wondering if this is TRUE. Evenly --</context>
      <utterance>Saved the best for last... 'Murder.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It say who I killed?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taggart rises, removes Jake's BLACK STETSON from a hook on the wall, pulls that PHOTOGRAPH OF THE WOMAN from the inner brim:</context>
      <utterance>Prostitute outta Mojave, name of Alice Wills.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jake just stares, CONFUSED. SHAKEN.</context>
      <utterance>If I were a bettin' man, I'd say this would be Ms. Wills, would it not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>With that, a CLUE falls into place: SAGUARO PASS.</context>
      <utterance>They found her dead in a cabin round Saguaro Pass, twenty miles west of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He slips the photo back in the brim, tosses the hat to Jake:</context>
      <utterance>Deed was in your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>At gunpoint, Taggart PUSHES Jake out the door --</context>
      <utterance>Dead hooker with a hole in her chest, in your cabin, plus your sterling reputation equals guilty as goddamned sin.  And you're gonna hang for it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GREAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>blue light... Clanton said he saw blue light before the cows disappeared...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a storm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Dolar isn't listening. THROUGH HIS BINOCULARS: he sees PERCY being carried into the prison wagon. Followed by Jake.</context>
      <utterance>No storm I've ever seen... I say we wait 'til it passes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a HYA! he's OFF, the others FOLLOWING with reluctant looks -- still SPOOKED by that incoming STORM:</context>
      <utterance>No time, they put him in an iron coach.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DEPUTY WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake holds out his hands. Wade unlocks one wrist, freeing a cuff... then takes that cuff and LOCKS IT to Percy's wrist.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme your wrist.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you --?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best way to make a man stay put: chain him to his enemy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode>A GRIN</mode>
      <context>SLAM: the door CLOSES and LOCKS. Jake SIGHS and tries to sit back, but it's hard tethered to Percy's slumped form. Shit. Then QWW -- something starts to STING and he looks down: HIS BRACELET. Has started PULSING RED. And it's getting WARM. Jake stares -- ON EDGE -- what the hell's happening? As -- OUTSIDE, Taggart mounts the buckboard. EMMETT feeds the horses:</context>
      <utterance>You lovebirds have a nice trip now.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure he's a bad guy, Pa? He did give Percy a lickin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's bad enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>. can I come with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too dangerous.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dangerous to drive a damn coach? Why can't Charlie just take him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's my job, Emmett. That's what these people pay me to do. And your mother would kill me if I brought you. Emmett looks off, half sad, half angry --</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And turns without a goodbye. Taggart watches him leave, wishing he could connect. Takes the reins and looks up -- REACTS: THAT MASSIVE. FRIGHTENING CLOUD IN THE SKY -- roiling faster toward town. The scary BLUE FLASHES within grow more INTENSE. IN THE COACH -- WITH JAKE, looking at the BRACELET, the pulsing growing MORE FREQUENT -- and then, a VOICE:</context>
      <utterance>Good thing she's already dead then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me where you got that bracelet...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should'a asked before you knocked me out..</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please... I need to know. Just tell me where you got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And sits back as the coach starts to MOVE, leaving Ella in the dust. Some of the gunmen ride atop it; others on horseback cover the coach in a protective ring. Wade sees something incoming from the NORTH:</context>
      <utterance>Y dOli' .xBmbgX - - I don' t remember my name or where I've been or any of the things they said I done, so leave me the hell alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STRANGE STEEL RINGS fire from the speeders and mushroom out -- KA-CHING! -- SNAP OPEN and CLAMP around necks, arms, legs -- and from these steel collars, CABLES LASH OUT, whip-snapping back to the speeders and TETHERING MAGNETICALLY to them --</context>
      <utterance>Jesus God!!</utterance>
   <speaker>26.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah-these are HIGH-TECH LASSOS:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MOANS, WAILS... desperate cries as people search for loved ones. JAKE'S BLASTER -- RETRACTS, folding in on itself -- shrinks down to size, reverting back into a BRACELET. He's stunned. So are the remaining townsfolk. DOLARHYDE is first to speak:</context>
      <utterance>Maria -- oh God-- they t-took her-- What just...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell're ?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolarhyde starts MOVING toward Jake -- wild killer eyes --</context>
      <utterance>He's the one who caged Percy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatwere__tho_se__thinae?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolarhyde GRIPS Jake's arm -- THE BRACELET:</context>
      <utterance>-- why're you asking me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This! Where'd you get this?! It was shooting the same light beams they were --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go of my wrist.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KA-LLLANG!! Suddenly that CHURCH BELL comes HURTLING out of the church wreckage, PLOWS through debris. People scatter. And out of the church stumbles... AN ALIEN. 8 FT. TALL. Standing upright, limbs inverted -- limbs that DRAG, wounded, as people SCREAM and RUN and Jake and Dolarhyde can only stare, jaws dropped, and the monster LUNGES: WHUPWHUP -- something SPINNING through the air -- A HATCHET ---</context>
      <utterance>-- I'm not lettin' go of nothin' til you tell me what the he--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake KICKS the alien. It doesn't move. Happy BARKS --</context>
      <utterance>Is it... dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>. The hell j,,a it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They all turn to see MEACHAM. TERRIFIED.</context>
      <utterance>A demon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Revelations 16:14: "For there are spirits of demons, showing signs."  Escaped from hell itself.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indeed, there on the creature's wrist is an IDENTICAL BRACELET. ON JAKE. Mind tumbling. He meets eyes with ELLA. Her face as EAGER as his to understand this and now... BEEP. BEEP. BEEP. What's that SOUND? Everyone looks at each other. Colorado bends closer to the corpse... SCARED...</context>
      <utterance>Lookit its wrist! It's got one'a those bracelet things too!</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People look at each other: WHAT NOW? Trying to control the near- hysteria they all feel. Finally, Dolarhyde takes a BREATH -- more BRAVADO than actual courage:</context>
      <utterance>I think... it's comin' from somewhere inside it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one way to find out. We need to cut it open.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>TO DOC</mode>
      <context>DOC snaps out of his stupor, looks up, FREAKED --</context>
      <utterance>You're a doctor. Got a bone saw?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(looks to them all)</context>
      <utterance>. Are you... serious?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That LANDS on all of them. A long beat. Doc looks down at the thing, ORANGE GOO dribbling around the AXE in its head...</context>
      <utterance>Well this one here's our only chance of findin' where they went.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you got a bone saw or don't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolar brings up his COLT -- so does COLORADO --</context>
      <utterance>Stay outside. You're not welcome in here!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARRYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ella steps between them, BAD ASS --</context>
      <utterance>I own more of this town than any man in it so I'll go wherever the hell I damn please. And for the record? You ain't welcome in my country, Mexican.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc and Dolar never take eyes off each other. or their GUNS. Finally... Dolar LOWERS his. So does Doc. People BREATHE. Meacham slips on a pair of GLASSES, studying eerie veins and muscles through the creature's viscous outer layers. Doc turns his focus to the alien too. Picks up his PUMP-OPERATED BONE SAW. Presses his boot on the bellows, it turns with a WHIR... SHAKING as he brings the SPINNING BLADE to the alien's CHEST. Looks at Meacham, AFRAID --</context>
      <utterance>Whatever troubles you had don't mean a damn thing against the ones we got now. We wanna see our way through 'em, your guns better start pointing in the same direction, Goddammit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it 'mss a demon, and I cut it open... am I going to burn for it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON DOC. Little relief. BROW SWEATING, he brings the spinning blade down toward the disgusting ALIEN -- VRRRRZZ -- HESITATES --</context>
      <utterance>That should cover ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>B GH! He PUKES on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc wipes his mouth with a handkerchief, slightly DEFIANT --</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Doc!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not normal. I'm entitled to vomit. We should XU be vomiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc GLARES... with a still-shakitig hand, gets back to business --</context>
      <utterance>Just cut, Lardass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senor? A hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode>TO DOLARHYDE</mode>
      <context>The men all grip the chest plate and PULL -- A DISGUSTING CRACK. Everyone turns away, scowling, Emmett wafting the air:</context>
      <utterance>You too, maricon.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn! Smells like a dead dog's ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Emmett.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc covers his face with his handkerchief as he explores...</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chet wall's partially collapsed... no familiar organs of any kind...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'course they're not familiar. Just look at this th--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And GRINS at Dolar's pain. But Meacham NOTICES something around Dolar's neck where the alien pinned him, like a ring of DUST:</context>
      <utterance>Spinal reflex.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meacham sweeps a little off Dolar's neck, rubs it between thumb and forefinger. The dust GLINTS under the kerosene lamp:</context>
      <utterance>Something on your neck. Hold still.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They check the creature's hand talons: GOLD FLAKES underneath 'em, and Lots of it. Colorado checks its taloned feet:</context>
      <utterance>I'll be damned... gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That LANDS on everyone. but most especially ELLA. Who looks up to see Jake READING her in this moment.</context>
      <utterance>Down here too.  This much ore... could only have come from a digging in a mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In MACRO CU, DOC CUTS INTO THE EYE, WET SQUISHY SOUNDS as he pulls it from its socket, attached to a STRINGY OPTIC NERVE dripping with juice. Clamped to the nerve is a METALLIC ORB: -- he takes hold of the blinking orb. It FLARES to life, the light coalescing into a 3-D ARROW-LIKE HOLOGRAM. Confusion. Doc REMOVES it from the optic nerve and the hologram DISAPPEARS:</context>
      <utterance>Gimme my scalpel.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd it go? The hell'd you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reconnects it to the optic nerve, the hologram REAPPEARS:</context>
      <utterance>Nothing, just pulled it off --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Colorado moves closer... rainbow light flickering across his face...</context>
      <utterance>Only works when it's touching the creature.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think... it's a compass. Look:  No matter how you move it, it points in the same direction.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Compasses point north. That's west.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. Another puzzle piece falling into place.</context>
      <utterance>West's where 141 came from.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're right, what's it pointing to?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rest of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be my guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He SNAPS his PISTOL open, loading bullets:</context>
      <utterance>Then that's where I'm goin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of my ranchers said my herd disappeared into the sky. 'Til about ten minutes ago, I figured him for a liar.  Nobody takes my cattle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FLASH of something from Dolarhyde -- could that be EMOTION? But just as fast, it's GONE. Almost a THROWAWAY:</context>
      <utterance>Your b was taken too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I noticed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if they're already dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid's right. If all they wanted was to kill us, they would've.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looked to me like... they were ropin' people.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>His eyes flash to Nat: "C'mon." And they EXIT. Everyone looks at each other, working up the courage to face what they know they must. Doc grabs his SHOTGUN, starts gathering shells:</context>
      <utterance>Means they need 'em for something. Whatever it is, we can either stand here guessin'... or go find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she's alive -- if there's even a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As one by one, they turn... to JAKE. Who until this point has been mostly SILENT. Observing. But now -- he's gone from enemy to potential savior in a heartbeat.</context>
      <utterance>Lord hates a coward... but our bullets were useless against those things. Other than his wrist gizmo, we're outgunned and outnumbered.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, I got nothing to do with this --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got everything to do with it. If you can remember where you got that thing --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember you all wantin' me on the end of a damned rope. Whatever's happenin' here's got nothin' to do with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He LOOKS at her. No, he isn't. But he sure as hell won't stay to debate it -- turns to go --</context>
      <utterance>You sure. about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The EMOTION in the boy's voice STOPS Jake at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Lonergan? Sir?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it? You're just gonna run away?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Sister. I'm walking away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he keeps on walking, Ella picks up a ROCK, wings it at the back of his HEAD -- WHAMI Jake stumbles forward, TURNS AROUND --</context>
      <utterance>Well s w.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ella strides forward, picking up another rock on the move --</context>
      <utterance>SONOVA-- -- I told you to gyp.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your damn problem?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're comin' with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not coming anywhere. And you throw that rock I swear I'll-- WHAM! The rock glances off his shoulder --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That PENETRATES as Jake realizes he doesn't really KNOW. And that's the last thing he's gonna admit --</context>
      <utterance>If you're walkin' away from here, what the hell're you walking tsQ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- now it's her turn to pause. Cryptically:</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you walkin' to, Lady? 'Cause if I heard right, it sounds like suicide to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... just wanna help these people.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the fact that he's BUSTED her gets Ella's hackles up --</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. You wanna help yourself. Saw your face light up the minute you knew that thing might lead you to gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not gold I want, you dumb sonofabitch, it's what it'll buy me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whatever that means, it's a deep, painful LONGING in her. She stares at him, DEAD ON:</context>
      <utterance>Remange.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>With that, Ella turns and STRIDES OFF as we HOLD ON JAKE, face knotted in conflict. As her words RESONATE.</context>
      <utterance>And lookin' at you? I'd bet a silver dollar... its what you want, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Though BURNING EMBERS, Emmett helps a LITTLE GIRL pull her half- burnt DOLL from the rubble...</context>
      <utterance>Was the Devil come to Absolution... come to drag our town down to hell... SERIES OF SHOTS - AS DUSK TAI .t $. TQ .NIGItT:</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ella and Doc tend to WOUNDED PEOPLE in a triage area as... Meacham finds his overturned PULPIT. Determination in his eyes, he pushes it UPRIGHT:</context>
      <utterance>but our town's not just a buncha buildings, Brothers and Sisters -- Nossir. Our town is fie. Good, God- fearing souls. Pure and hopeful. And the devil can't never take that away...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>SUNRISE: Pistol chambers SPINNNN -- rifles are COCKED --</context>
      <utterance>In times of darkness, God asks that we come together so we may stand and fight. So we're goin' after our kin. Any of you aren't able or prepared, no shame in it. Head up to Fort Huachuca, join up with the garrison there and pray... Rest of us ride out at sun-up to recover that which we have lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Lo and behold, most of the town survivors are just too damn scared. They form an EXODUS LINE, heading off toward the fort. Dolarhyde, Colorado and his REMAINING MEN (6) load the ALIEN CORPSE onto the back of a WAGON. Some of them trade glances -- DAMN WORRIED about staying. Dolarhyde sees it:</context>
      <utterance>Thy will be done, Lord, and there's an amen behind it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His withering GLARE keeps them from speaking up. Doc and Meacham climb onto the wagon:</context>
      <utterance>Somebody got something to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode>THE ALIEN</mode>
      <context>Doc nods as he TWISTS the forceps in the Alien's eye, the COMPASS HOLOGRAM flickering to life before them:</context>
      <utterance>Sure we need to bring that thing along?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emmett appears leading a PONY, a BOW and quiver of ARROWS slung around his back:</context>
      <utterance>If this arrow points me back to Maria? Yeah -- J'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't come, Emmett, too dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can protect myself -- shoot, I'm the only master bowman in my archery club. Won the county tournament by shootin' a flipped nickel at 50 paces.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somethin' tells me these things don't carry nickels, son. Answers's no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's the truth. Meacham sighs, no choice... finally:</context>
      <utterance>You want me to ride off with the chickenshits, then double back, be happy to. But let's just skip that part and get to it, Padre.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He SLAPS the reins and the wagon rides off. Emmett GRINS and mounts the pony, then sees... JAKE riding past. ANGRY EYES from Ella as she heels her horse and TROTS OFF angrily:</context>
      <utterance>Go fill your canteen, dammit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But HAPPY remains, torn between them, tail wagging and looking up at Jake as if to say: PLEASE COME?</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suppressing GUILT, he rides on toward the hills -- as Dolarhyde VEERS his horse in front of Jake, cutting him off:</context>
      <utterance>Oh shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was ridin' into town to kill you for what you done to my son. You owe me your life, Boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>His hand rests on his nickel-plated .38. Eyes gleaming cruelly.</context>
      <utterance>Ride with us, we'll call it square.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You that fast?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a DAZZLING TWIRL, Jake slaps it back in his holster. Point made, he RIDES ON. Dolarhyde, burning mad at having been out- drawn, turns to CULOBAI)U -- speaks LOW:</context>
      <utterance>Now you owe me y.Q= life. We're square.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Follow him. Soon as he's got his back turned... kill him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Figure out which way you're headed yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>West. Saguaro Pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The inference LANDS on Jake. But he's in no mood. GALLOPS off. Meacham watches Jake go... MUSIC RISES AS WE DISSOLVE THROUGH:</context>
      <utterance>That's not what I meant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns, drops the flowers into the vase as we see she's talking to JAKE.</context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't have.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got you somethin' else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman looks to the pouch -- Picks up one of the coins. TORN. Jake moves behind her. Close. An INTIMACY here.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. Dark. But DETERMINED:</context>
      <utterance>Your boys '11 come after you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to him, their eyes HOLD... and they KISS. Soft. Tender. Soulful. But then -- a THUNDERCRACK turns their attention to the window: A STORM CLOUD on the horizon. Same kind that consumed the town. The cabin starts to VIBRATE like a tuning fork. The pouch slides off the table... THE GOLD COINS SPILL OUT and --</context>
      <utterance>Let 'em come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GREAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... what's a pretty lady like y--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc, sipping from his canteen, does a SPIT TAKE. Ella's eyes DRILL Greavey. Cut down a peg, he tips his hat, red-faced:</context>
      <utterance>-- you finish that sentence, I shoot you in your beef whistle.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And rides past her, taking us to EMMETT and DOLARHYDE:</context>
      <utterance>Ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me somethin', Kid... why didn't your father just take my money?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode>CONFUSED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What money?</utterance>
   <speaker>UOLARHY DE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And this just BURNS Emmett. A beat; then:</context>
      <utterance>offered him a thousand dollars to leave town. He could's taken you outta harm's way, relocated... found you a new momma.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something FLASHES in Dolarhyde. But he's contained:</context>
      <utterance>Is it true Percy's momma died givin' birth to him, Mister Dolarhyde?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emmett HOLDS his look against Dolarhyde's. Brave and UNFLINCHING. Doc can't help but grin at the kid's moxie... but it's short-lived as his face suddenly falls:</context>
      <utterance>Then maybe you should use that thousand dollars to buy yourself a new wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And we PAN AROUND, dropping over his shoulder to see what he's reacting to -- AN ENORMOUS CRATER. ACRES WIDE... TWENTY FEET DEEP. Even Dolarhyde looks nervous now:</context>
      <utterance>Madre Dios...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARYHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the... hell is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn to see Meacham, brushing the DUST off a WOODEN SIGN: Holds it UP. " Winfield's Landing... Population 133." ON GREAVEY AND THE MEN. Shit. He doesn't mean...?</context>
      <utterance>It was Winfield's Landing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And suddenly a weird CRACK shakes the canyon -- like the SOUND BARRIER BREAKING -- everyone's look goes UP where: SWIRLING, DARK CLOUDS LOOM. The same clouds that dropped the tornado on Absolution. And that appeared in Jake's MEMORIES at the cabin. But this time, something's SHOT OUT from them --</context>
      <utterance>You tryin' to tell me those... things pulled the whole damn town into the sky?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The plummeting object HITS a distant dune, kicking up a SAND</context>
      <utterance>That can't be good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we... open it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we open it? Hell NO we shouldn--</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and now we find Emmett's already POKING it with a stick, a Small TEAR in the cocoon's outer embryonic layer -- GOO leaks -- then it RUPTURES, EXPLODING as the horses REAR away, WHINNYING the goo spreads across the desert floor, thinning out. BEAT. Everyone wipes blue shit off their clothes as they come FACE-TO-FACE with the object inside, lying there on the ground:</context>
      <utterance>-- oops --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GREAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolarhyde's eyes NARROW. Emmett looks at Doc, SCARED:</context>
      <utterance>Boss... it's one'a yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc dismounts. Moves to the cow's mouth and PULLS OUT THAT TUBE with a wet SQUISHING sound. Thinking it through:</context>
      <utterance>Is-- is this what happened to my Pa?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Doc's eyes aren't sure. Meacham looks back to the sky:</context>
      <utterance>This was stuck down its throat... to help it breathe. That means they wanted to keep it alive, Emmett.  I'm sure your father is fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd they dump it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever they needed from it, they must've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>She does. The others FOLLOW in a chilled daze. The last is DOLARHYDE, glancing back at his dead cow with angry eyes...</context>
      <utterance>Gonna get dark soon, need to keep moving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Colorado Queen."</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>But Ella doesn't seem as impressed as the rest of them. In fact, her attention is drawn BEHIND them, to something coming up over the DUNES... the barest flicker of a smile --</context>
      <utterance>The river's two hundred miles from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IT'S JAKE ON HORSEBACK. Followed by another horse, with COLORADO in the saddle. Wrists tied but ALIVE. As Jake rides to a stop, he PUSHES Colorado off the horse -- the indian HITS the ground with a THUD as Jake levels Dolarhyde with HARD EYES:</context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your man got it in his head that he was s'posed to kill me. I'm holding onto his ear 'til he says sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake's hard-as-nails. DRIVEN now --</context>
      <utterance>Why'd you let him live?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rides past Dolar to Ella. Stops. Says, simply:</context>
      <utterance>Gonna need him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice boat.  What's that smell?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He realizes her shirt's caked in the BLUE GOO from the cow.</context>
      <utterance>That'd be me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why're you blue?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>DRYLY</mode>
      <context>Their look HOLDS. A MOMENT. Something REAL between them.</context>
      <utterance>Cause I missed ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A THUNDERCRACK. On the horizon, sheets of RAIN.</context>
      <utterance>We better keep movin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Storm's comin'. I say we dig in here til it passes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>(to Colorado; fucking WITH HIM)</mode>
      <context>Nat BURNS. Dolar feels his AUTHORITY being undermined:</context>
      <utterance>How's that sound, Nat?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colorado finally turns to Uolarhyde. DEFIANT:</context>
      <utterance>Storm or no storm, I say we keep movin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too hard tracking anything in the rain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolar pours some whiskey on a BANDANA, leans towards Colorado --</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolarhyde backs away. Colorado GLARES.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme clean it for you or it'll get -- -- I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolar's eyes flash. A mixture of anger and PAIN. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Is Percy worth dyin' for?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>POINTED</mode>
      <context>ON COLORADO as that lands. Clearly, there's something here... a bond that seems to go deeper than just boss and employee. But WHAT? Finally Nat just gets up and LEAVES. Dolar watches him go, takes a healthy SWIG. Hears a WHIMPER. Looks over and sees... EMMETT, huddled in a corner. CRYING.</context>
      <utterance>I take care of my kin, Nat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Emmett looks up, SNIFFLES. Dolar tosses him the WHISKEY FLASK:</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He gets up, walks off. Leaving the kid with the flask. As Emmett looks at it confusedly, stuffs it in his POCKET --</context>
      <utterance>Take a drink and shut p.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We brought enough water.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc nods: ah. Turns to go... STOPS. Turns back. Intense eyes:</context>
      <utterance>Not for drinkin', it's for blessin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meacham removes his spectacles. Looks at Doc --</context>
      <utterance>Padre... Maria came to see you in confession every Sunday. It seemed... she had a lot to talk about.  Was she having an affair?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Doc DOES know. But there's a quiet DESPERATION here --</context>
      <utterance>You know I can't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meacham sees the PAIN in his friend's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>The last thing I said to her... I...  Please. If I'm wrong about my wife... I don't want to die angry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can ask Maria if she was cheatin' on you once we get her back. 'Til then?  Don't die.</utterance>
   <speaker>50.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And OFF DOC, thunder CRACKS --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You missed a spot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell,-re- you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mindin' my own business.  Then you decided to take a shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you say anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws her shirt on, but her skin's wet and the shirt glues to her, celebrating her shape in a way that can't be ignored. Jake tosses her his jacket. As she slips it on, she notices a bottle of WHISKEY on the table... and the PHOTOGRAPH OF ALICE.</context>
      <utterance>Givin' you privacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake's quiet. DARK. Intense emotion, intensely suppressed:</context>
      <utterance>. she's pretty.  Who was she?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>only thing I know's her name was Alice...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>THEN; DISTANT</mode>
      <context>Ella looks up at him. INTO him --</context>
      <utterance>And she's dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake shakes his head, sort of mumble/chuckles in RESISTANCE:</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you loved her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All you women are the same -- Always wanna make it about Goddamn "love."</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>A BEAT</mode>
      <context>There is a force -- a strength about this woman -- that he connects with. But remains, true to character, ALOOF:</context>
      <utterance>Trust me, Lonergan. I'm not the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a step closer. Soft. Intimate.</context>
      <utterance>Don't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake just looks at her. Then, lifts the cheroot to his lips, the FLARE of its tip casting him in a demonic light...</context>
      <utterance>So what dj= matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now, he leans forward with a focused LOOK... holds up his</context>
      <utterance>What matters is I find the thing that killed her.  And make it pay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A beat. Ella -- somehow CONTAINED -- opens her mouth to lie. But he cuts her off --</context>
      <utterance>Where'd you see this before?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ella tightens. PAIN in her eyes. And Jake REALIZES:</context>
      <utterance>-- and don't lie to me. You wouldn't've asked me if you didn't recognize it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She swallows: a mixture of SHAME that he's found her out... and ANGER at what was done to her.</context>
      <utterance>Those things... they the ones who put those marks on your back?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They took my people. Destroyed where I'm from.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake CONSIDERS all this. Softens a little:</context>
      <utterance>North of here. Been trackin' 'em ever since, town to town. Best I figure, they're hidin' in a mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe if you'd told me the truth instead of throwin' rocks at me --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- what, you would've stuck around? Bullshit. I couldn't've turned you away from what you had to do, any more than I could've stopped these people from going after their kin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Their look HOLDS... until Jake SMIRKS. Likes her style:</context>
      <utterance>Truth ain't worth a damn, Jake... and we're gonna need all the guns we can get.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a pause... then Ella SMIRKS back:</context>
      <utterance>So that's the only reason you wanted me to come with you? Cause of my gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not your gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Among the many things these two ate feeling -- both separately and together -- the one that pops right now is ATTRACTION. Confusing as it is for him. The pregnant moment LINGERS... Until Happy suddenly starts to GROWWWWL, sensing something outside. ANOTHER CRACK OF THUNDER as:</context>
      <utterance>What you do with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go after the boy... then you get our people back...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop talking. DQW! GET YOUR ASS-- But Meacham GRABS Jake, EYE TO EYE. GASPING:</utterance>
   <speaker>MEACHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. AFFECTED. With a last RASP, Meacham DIES just as DOC races through the growing FLAMES -- REACTS -- no time to mourn --</context>
      <utterance>Listen up... 'cause I'm not gonna be able to say it again --  God don't care who you were, Son... only who you Mg.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DOLARHYDE, RAIN pouring down his face... VULNERABLE and GUILTY:</context>
      <utterance>That thing... was dead... it was d-ead...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. Rage-filled against the flames... Meacham's CRUCIFIX in his hared, as his FIST closes around it. Looks up, HARDCORE:</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't stop it -- It just... grabbed the kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we'd better get him back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GREAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolarhyde BURNS -- knowing he's being ABANDONED --</context>
      <utterance>Boss, only took one of them things to kill four of us. We got no chance here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Greavey, finally FREE to speak his mind, says SPITEFULLY:</context>
      <utterance>You're a goddamn coward.  You work for me, dammit. You're my m e 1 1 Qyees.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men turn tail and RIDE AWAY. Dolarhyde SHOUTS after them --</context>
      <utterance>Fine line between a coward and a fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc takes the opportunity to TWIST the knife:</context>
      <utterance>You're all FIRED!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolarhyde feels his world CRUMBLING away man by man... Ella trots alongside Jake, who's staring at that DARK CLOUD MASS overhead with a bad feeling:</context>
      <utterance>Looks like they finally found something to be more scared of than you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON ELLA. We SENSE she knows something, something more she isn't saying. SNAPS her reins and they RIDE OFF:</context>
      <utterance>Clouds've been moving east since sun- up... 'cept that one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OUTLAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the words catch in his throat as his EYES WIDEN:</context>
      <utterance>I say we just shoot 'em and take their--</utterance>
   <speaker>OUTLAW</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sure enough, they're looking right at (BRONC -JAKE. Both outlaws and HUNT) lower their guns, hostility replaced by SURPRISE:</context>
      <utterance>. Boss?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh, Christ. This is JAKE'S gang. ON DOLARHYDE. ELLA. COLORADO. All registering it. And JAKE, of course, doesn't REMEMBER these men as Bronc dismounts, NERVOUS:</context>
      <utterance>What the hell you doin' back here, Lonergan?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRONC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. Now does he handle this? Ht:nt rides up next to him, SUSPICIOUS, and for reasons yet to be known, UNFRIENDLY --</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Boss... Creek's gonna shit when he sees you.  And who the hell're they?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SMACKI Jake moves LIGHTNING FAST, SLAPS Hunt across the face, stopping the question on his tongue -- CATCHES the gun as it drops and presses the barrel into Hunt's NECK:</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, Jake. Cat got your--?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ella and our people REACT as Jake plays it up, beat defense a good OFFENSE. The outlaws are SCARED: this is the Lonergan they know. Hunt holds his BLOODY MOUTH:</context>
      <utterance>Since when're Qy the one asking the goddamned questions!?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, Jake... You broke my tooth</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bronc and Hunt nod, mounting up, SHOUTING to the OUTLAWS above:</context>
      <utterance>Quit whining. Now bring me to the rest of the boys, if that meets with your goddamn approval.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice company you keep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell're you doing? If we don't catch up to that kid, we're never gonna--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Qh. That actually makes SENSE. But --</context>
      <utterance>They called me "Boss." You wanna go after these things with five or fifty?  Like you said: we can use every gun we can get.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What exactly're you gonna say to 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>A BEAT</mode>
      <context>And he SPURS onward, leaving her to follow uneasily --</context>
      <utterance>Tell you when I figure it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunt nods over his shoulder --</context>
      <utterance>'Bout time you got back.  What the hell happened to you?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The outlaws part to reveal JAKE, riding in with Ella and the rest of our people. Creek's eyes NARROW, NOT happy to see him:</context>
      <utterance>He did.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It gets very, VERY QUIET. Our people tread warily, knowing whatever reaction Jake's eliciting, it AIN'T GOOD. He runs the gaunt of ACCUSING GLARES. Smart enough to know that CREEK is the man in charge. Dismounts:</context>
      <utterance>well, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Creek eyes him. TOUGH. Clearly, HISTORY here:</context>
      <utterance>You don't look happy to see me, Creek.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're fixin' to rob us a train in about twenty minutes and you come ridin' in like nothin' ever happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode>FUCK YOU</mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. How to navigate bad blood that he doesn't REMEMBER?</context>
      <utterance>No. Lonergan. I ain't happy to see you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, pretty much DISMISSING Creek, Jake turns, addresses the rest of the men. If he's their boss? </context>
      <utterance>Well I'm sure you'll get over it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The men seem... . CONFUSED. Not sure what the hell is GOING ON.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to see you, Boys, but we're not going after a train -- We're going after something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRONC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And this is a REVELATION. Jake glances at ELLA -- has to keep IMPROVISING to hold his ground:</context>
      <utterance>But Jake... you-- you said you didn't wanna be in charge no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I-- changed my mind. So saddle the hell up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Creek's heard enough. Strides forward, a direct CHALLENGE:</context>
      <utterance>They're not going anywhere with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The IRONY of the question isn't lost on Jake, as Creek walks right up to Ella. CLOSE. Violates her space: studies her with a mixture of curiosity and CONTEMPT.</context>
      <utterance>You got some balls on you -- walkin' outta here a week ago sayin' what you said and doin' what you did and then ridin' back in here and givin orders. Just who the hell do you think you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. Are you her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I who?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OH. Another piece of the puzzle falls into place -- Jake's eyes SNAP to Ella as they both REALIZE... the men think she's " e." Jake does his best to stay cool, meets Creek's stare:</context>
      <utterance>The whore Jake quit this gang for.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch your mouth, Creek.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. OUR HEROES. Shit. Jake turns to the men --</context>
      <utterance>Or what? These boys are with = now. jID in charge. You may be fast, but you are goddamned outgunned.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Creek doesn't wait for them to respond:</context>
      <utterance>That a fact, Boys?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT ONCE, 10 GUNS ARE LEVELED AT ELLA'S HEAD. No doubt as to who the men are LOYAL to. But Jake locks into Creek, UNFLINCHING:</context>
      <utterance>Put your guns on the whore. He so much as twitches, blow her brains out her ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call her a whore again, that'll be the last word you ever say.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunt reluctantly scrambles over to Jake, oh-so-carefully pulls the PISTOL from Jake's holster:</context>
      <utterance>You ain't in no position to make threats, asshole. Hunt: take his gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Creek now turns to BULL MCCADE, roughly the size of a BARN.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Boss... nothin' personal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Jake barely has time to react as Bull lets fly with a JAWBREAKING HAYMAKER that about knocks Jake out of his BOOTSI Dolarhyde and Colorado WINCE as Jake hits the dirt with a THUD -- Creek striding over, cock of the walk, LEANS over him:</context>
      <utterance>Put him down, Bull.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>"Gold?" Jake SPITS BLOOD, defiant:</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell's our gold. Jake?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Creek NODS to Bull: SMASH! Another devastating BLOW. ON ELLA -- at GUNPOINT. Wishing she could intervene. DOC too.</context>
      <utterance>Don't remember.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- WHAM! Bull PUNCHES Jake so hard he FLIES OFF HIS FEET:</context>
      <utterance>Well I _dg remember you tellin' us you was leavin' us high and dry because you were in love... You just left out the part about taking half our goddamned haul from the Yuma Bank. So I'm gonna ask you one last time -- Where. Is. Our. Gold?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>WHAM! Bull PUNCHES Jake back into oblivion, and on the HIT we: MEMORY FLASECUTi PEACEFUL SILENCE -- two FACES staring at each other across a pillow -- Jake and ALICE, naked, in a WHOREHOUSE</context>
      <utterance>Man can't run away from who he ja, Lonergan... you really think you could go straight just cause you were fool enough to fall in love with some woman?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. Clearly TORN. But just as clearly, in LOVE.</context>
      <utterance>You sure you wanna give it all up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches his face so gently. And whispers:</context>
      <utterance>What about you? Once we're gone, you ain't ever comin' back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>]11n as Creek GRABS Jake's hair and YANKS BACK, rears up a fist:</context>
      <utterance>You're the first person ever believed I was better than this place... so I gotta believe in y=.  You're a good man, Jake Lonergan. PRESENT: as the words "Good Man" ECHO back to Jake. Stir=g_</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TORY FLASECUTI REPLAY -- Jake and Alice in the cabin -- he drops the SADDLEBAG -- it CLINKS to the floor. She's worried:</context>
      <utterance>You figgered you could steal from us? All that gold was yours to take co you could go off and start a new life? Creek's next PUNCH takes us to another:</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your boys'ii come after you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BACK TO PRESENT -- as now Jake UNDERSTANDS the context of this moment -- what they were saying to each other -- He looks up at Creek, BEATEN AND BUSTED UP:</context>
      <utterance>Let 'em come.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... okay, I remember now...  Demons stole your gold, Creek. But when you get to hell, you can ask for it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEK JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode>TSK'S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay then. That's the way you wanna do this...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. Pure KILLER. As he turns his weapon on the rest of the (awestruck) gang -- through BLOODY TEETH:</context>
      <utterance>Told you not to call her that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all riding with me. Any one of you decides otherwise? So help me God, I'll kill you where you stand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>AND THEN</mode>
      <context>The gang quickly flips: "Absolutely, Jake/ Whatever you say, Boss..." Jake turns to the speechless Bull McCade and KICKS HIM IN THE BALLS as hard as he can, doubling him over. Now he meets eyes with ELLA. She can't help SMIRKING, grateful. DOC. Is the only one NOT looking at Jake. His attention drawn toward a SOUND coming from the distant DUNES --</context>
      <utterance>I'm j2acj&amp; and I'M in goddamne.d</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dios mio.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her head just falls back. Yeah. Hard to swallow, but it's true. ELLA'S DEAD. And if this moment ECHOES Jake holding his dead wife, well that's just fine. He stares beseechingly as... HOOFBEATS. The rest of our people gallop in: Colorado, Dolarhyde, Doc and Emmett in the wagon:</context>
      <utterance>Ella...?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake looks up -- unhinged --</context>
      <utterance>Aw no... is she --?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to get out of here NOT.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- I'M NOT LEAVIN' HER! -- This is Apache territory! They catch us, they'll kill u-- THHHHHHHUNKI The air SCREAMS as an ARROW pierces the ground inches from Jake's hand! Suddenly THIRTY MORE -- ALL AROUND THEM -- forming an instant circle perimeter as -- APACHE WARRIORS FLASH DOWNHILL. Dolar dismounts, swings Emmett to the ground --</context>
      <utterance>Not gonna leave her here -- L4Re.Xam --</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jake and Emmett freeze. The Apaches are ALL AROUND THEM. Fierce. BOWS and TOMAHAWKS drawn -- OFF THIS:</context>
      <utterance>Nobody move.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>THEN; SOFTLY</mode>
      <context>And just saying it, saying those words, brings a swell of EMOTION to the surface... but he FIGHTS it. A losing battle, as his eyes WELL:</context>
      <utterance>I-- I did love her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>(finally, voice almost</context>
      <utterance>She was like you. Seemed to think I was a good man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRACKS)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat... his bound hands gently touch her face...</context>
      <utterance>But I couldn't save either of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT' D </mode>
      <context>His eyes CLOSE. Too much.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the good in that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And that sits... then suddenly -- JARRINGLY -- THREE MORE BRAVES roughly enter, pull Jake up, FORCE HIM out:</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Ella.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That breaks the spell. Jake looks over --</context>
      <utterance>Wasn't your fault, Mr. Lonergan. Those things... were lookin' for her. Had a picture and everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you mean... 'a picture'?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Jake can makes sense of this, a teepee smoke flap OPENS and out steps the tribe's SACHEM. This is GREY WOLF -- dark, wrinkled face enhanced by TATTOOS. He takes one look at his prisoners and SPEAKS A FEW WORDS OF APACHE.</context>
      <utterance>Floatin', like that arrow thing we found in its eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc is amply freaked. Turns to Jake as FIVE OF THE BRAVES move for them, MENACING --</context>
      <utterance>"Kill them. And make it quick."</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Jake is VACANT. BROKEN. All the fight seems GONE from him. His bracelet DOESN'T MOVE. Dolarhyde's grabbed first... PULLED FORWARD by one of the braves, raising his TOMAHAWK -- they're really gonna KILL HIM --</context>
      <utterance>Now'd be a good time to use your gun bracelet, my friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GREY WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is it that you speak our language?</utterance>
   <speaker>UOLARHYUE</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>Grey Wolf's fascinated this man has the audacity to be a WISEASS given his circumstances. Turns to the Brave with the tomahawk --</context>
      <utterance>Because I'm a damn genius.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GREY WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>The Brave NODS, RAISES the Tomahawk again, but Dolar interrupts:</context>
      <utterance>Forget about quick. Make him feel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>Grey Wolf holds up his hand, halting the Brave's death blow --</context>
      <utterance>Two hundred head of cattle!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GREY WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>Dolarhyde nods to Colorado --</context>
      <utterance>And how do I know you'll come back?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>Colorado REACTS. He's the only one here who knows what the hell these two are saying to each other as Grey Wolf approaches Dolar, looks right INTO HIM --</context>
      <utterance>You can keep my associate here. if I don ' t come back, you can kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>Dolarhyde's eyes flash EMOTION. Quickly bottled. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Why should I believe that you even care about this man?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>Wow. Didn't see that one coming. Grey Wolf levels Colorado with those unyielding eyes --</context>
      <utterance>Because he's my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>And Colorado answers in ENGLISH, for the benefit of the others:</context>
      <utterance>Is this true?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REACTIONS. JAKE. EMMETT. DOC. Stunned silence. And so:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... he's my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>Dolar looks to Colorado, who won't meet his eyes. His FATHER's eyes. Turns back to Grey Wolf, HARD --</context>
      <utterance>Three hundred head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>HOLD ON GREY WOLF for a beat. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Two fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>The Brave does exactly that. Dolar's FREE to go...</context>
      <utterance>Cut him loose.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON DOLAR. A FLASH of regret. But it's gone fast.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! What about =?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he just walks out of the camp, leaving his son behind... GONE. And now, it's back to business --</context>
      <utterance>What about you, kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>Our people are GRABBED. Jake's yanked forward, PINNED DOWN -- a Brave raises a HATCHET to kill Jake, who glares back with lunatic eyes. Ready to die. Almost wanting it:</context>
      <utterance>Kill all of them except the half-breed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you waiting for, asshole? DO IT. And as Jake's about to MEET HIS DEATH:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. Holy. SHIT. Everyone else equally STUNNED.</context>
      <utterance>. what... happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... died.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- but he takes a step BACK. If he's relieved she's alive, he isn't showing it:</context>
      <utterance>If I'd told you on the boat, you never would'a trusted me --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear what I said?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.. What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's angry. Yes, even embarrassed. And because of it, something has SHUT DOWN in him again. That killer look is back.</context>
      <utterance>When you were playin' possum. Did you hear what I mid?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I was mendin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>His eyes narrow, trying to understand:</context>
      <utterance>It's like sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it you look like one of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can look like whatever I want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you can't die?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I can. If my heart stops beating... just like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>.JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>we can see that hurt her. But she deserved it, too. So desperately wants to reach him...</context>
      <utterance>You're nothin' like me, Ella. You're one'a them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He isn't sure what that means. Can he even trust her? Either way, she has ANSWER;. Darkly:</context>
      <utterance>I'm not, Jake. I'm from a different place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one that took you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>That LANDS on her. Knowing and painful.</context>
      <utterance>It killed her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even with his guard up... Jake can't help but be STRUCK. As the sound of HOWLING WIND takes us to:</context>
      <utterance>They call him The Slaver. He's the one, gave me the scars. Broke me. And made me watch... while he killed my family too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She says this meeting the eyes of GREY WOLF. There's immediate SIMPATICO here: a story the Indians could be telling.</context>
      <utterance>Our race was first to map the stars... that's why they came for us. Took our planet, piece by piece. Slaughtered anyone who fought hack. Ones who survived were turned into slaves. Trackers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As the terrible gravity of all this HITS everyone, JAKE is first to understand...</context>
      <utterance>They brought me aboard one of their scout ships -- a ship with only one purpose: to find other planets like mine. Planets they can take... people they can enslave.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ella swallows. Wracked with GUILT.</context>
      <utterance>X lead 'em here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well damn, lady, thanks a 1.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes are HAUNTED with memory. The inference is some kind of TORTURE. She pushes it away -- staying strong:</context>
      <utterance>I never wanted this.  But they got... ways. Of making you do things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been tryin' to make it right... tried to blow the ship to hell by burnin' up all their fuel, then escaped down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cept it didn't work... damn thing survived.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake's determined -- he's got his OWN agenda. Ella looks up to that OMINOUS CLOUD. Those BLUE LIGHT FLASHES ripple within:</context>
      <utterance>Where is it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiding in that cloud. Way I figure, they'll find enough fuel to leave by tomorrow, midday. Then they'll bring back the others.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"others"?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tomorrow. Midday. Hi noon. This is bad, bad news.</context>
      <utterance>The whole fleet. They'll take what they need. Everyone on this planet. Anything too weak to survive... they'll toss. Like that cow.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And before Ella can answer, Jake already GETS IT:</context>
      <utterance>What'd you mean, they're looking for "fuel"...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gold. That's why they're in a mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>. wherever it is, that's where you escaped from -- and it's the only way back up to the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>STEPS CLOSER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even with your memory wiped, your instincts kicked in --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>HIS BRACELET:</mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. Deeply STIRRED. As he looks down at the BRACELET and: MEMORY FLASBCUTSI REPLAY POV as we're HELD DOWN in that CAVE the TERRIFYING OCULAR PROBE lowers right in front of our eyes One of the ALIENS starts to activate the probe -- it begins to FLASH STEADILY -- HYPNOTICALLY -- PUvTNG OUR MIND -- But our arm manages to BREAK FREE -- a BLADE hidden in our sleeve -- WE SLASH OFF THE. ALIEN'S HAND -- GRAB THE BRACELET off its severed limb -- it COILS around our wrist and ACTIVATES: BLAM SLAM! We BLAST the creature to oblivion -- we're FREE! JAKE IN PRESENT -- Eyes ALIVE with MEMORY:</context>
      <utterance>That's how it works, Jake, the bracelet reads your impulse -- you wanna fight, it reacts. Somehow you took it off one of 'em... don't you remember any of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MEMORY FLASHCUTI REPLAY POV as we RUN through the cavern -- ESCAPE -- a LIGHT at the end of the tunnel -- BLINDING SUN hits us as we emerge -- our eyes ADJUST to see:</context>
      <utterance>I-- I blasted my way out...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Upon hearing that, Grey Wolf suddenly speaks in animated gestures, pointing North. Colorado REACTS:</context>
      <utterance>I remember seeing a tower... made of stone... on the rim of a canyon...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colorado turns to Jake, a flicker of HOPE:</context>
      <utterance>What? What's he sayin'?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That rock you're talkin' about... he- knows where it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DRIFTING over to see MARIA. Gravity PULLING her hair downward. Groggy. Mostly SCARED:</context>
      <utterance>You... all right...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode>BRAVE FACE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>. Fantastic. You?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they near the bluff, Jake sees the STONE TOWER. Dismounts:</context>
      <utterance>This is Kiowa land, their sister tribe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they near the bluff, they hear the growing sound of that MACHINERY. Everyone dips low, peering over to see...</context>
      <utterance>That's it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grey Wolf looks to his men, GRAVE, CRESTFALLEN as he realizes:</context>
      <utterance>Holy Jesus. Like a damn fort.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the ROOF of the steel structure blossoms open like a CHROME LOTUS... and WHOOSH! The SHUTTLE TRANSPORT flies out of the canyon, RISING into the dawn sky...</context>
      <utterance>The Kiowa... they were taken too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Transports. Way they get people and gold back and forth to the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grey Wolf SPEAKS --</context>
      <utterance>Place is crawling with those things. We'll never even get close.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says there's a back way in... The Twin Rivers run underneath this whole canyon. Limestone tunnels up by the falls, couple miles East. Lead right down there. Jake looks to the SKY. DARK. DETERMINED.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ella nods, HARD. Off their SHARED DETERMINATION, our SCORE rises. A DRUM CADENCE that suggests a MISSION starting to form:</context>
      <utterance>The Slaver... he's up in that big cloud?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just so I got this straight... three of those things just kicked the shit out of your entire gang, took our whole town, and now you two're gonna ride right into that fort, try to hijack one'a those-- He pauses on the word --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Transports."</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- ride it up to that space boat --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spaceshp.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then bring it down here and get everybody off alive? That's your big plan? Jake and Ella share a LOOK. Simply:</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And just how do you figure on getting in there in the first place?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poke a hornet's nest... they swarm at'cha.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat of incredulous, do-you-believe-this-shit STARES:</context>
      <utterance>You gotta draw 'em out. Buy us a distraction.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's suicide.</context>
      <utterance>You want us to storm that fort? Against those things? With less than fifty men?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't, it's been done! I read at school how Ethan Allen and his Green Mountain Boys took Fort Ticonderoga, they weren't but a small garrison and they were outgunned --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Together. It's the only way.</context>
      <utterance>We need all of you to make a stand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake turns to the WAGON they rode from Jake's gang camp -- the WHISKEY CRATES. Sweeps up a bottle:</context>
      <utterance>Make a stand with what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An impossible mission. Sure death. Yet for the first time... they have an ADVANTAGE. Emmett cuts the moment with a BIG GRIN:</context>
      <utterance>This.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grey Wolf CHUCKLES, murmurs. Jake looks to Nat for translation:</context>
      <utterance>Hell, yeah. Let's squish some bugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somethin' funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... that you whites finally know what it feels like to face extinction. Now that we're on the same side, he says we can all die together.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>The LOOK holds between them --</context>
      <utterance>They're with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colorado's face CLOUDS. Years of ANGER and RESENTMENT:</context>
      <utterance>Guess that means you're not waitin' for your dad to come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as Colorado TURNS away, the PERCUSSION finds another GEAR --</context>
      <utterance>Been Woodrow Dolarhyde's son my whole life... first time he ever copped to it was to save his own ass.  He's not comin' back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not you, Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake draws his gun, SPINS it in his palm, aims at Emmett's FOOT:</context>
      <utterance>Aw, hell, we been through this. Ya can't stop me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can shoot you in the foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake SIGHS -- bluff called. Holsters the gun and takes a knee... but just when we think this is gonna be a tender moment, he GRABS Emmett by the collar, pulls him CLOSE:</context>
      <utterance>Bu111i11SHIT.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emmett's nailed. ANGRY, but knows he's gotta stay.</context>
      <utterance>You told me your daddy's all you got left. Want me to save his ass? Then park yours right there on the ground, you little shit. Got me?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake releases him. Happy moves to Ella but she TSKS:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I gotcha.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog WHINES but complies, moving next to Emmett. Jake climbs on his horse. Looks back to the boy -- now he Ia tender:</context>
      <utterance>Stay with the kid, Happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hint of a SMIRK... long enough for Emmett to SMIRK BACK. Ella, Doc, and Colorado mount p too, along with a 10-MAN APACHE WAR PARTY. Jake meets eyes with GREY WOLF:</context>
      <utterance>I'll get your father back. Bastard still owes me fifty dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Grey Wolf NODS. Some part of the PLAN we have yet to learn. And now Jake starts to trot off, Ella beside him. This plays just between the two of them:</context>
      <utterance>You'll be ready?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. But Jake turns to her -- deadly serious:</context>
      <utterance>That's a nice thing... what you said to the boy. I didn't know better, I'd say you got yourself a sweet side.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Ella reacts to the DARKNESS in his voice. Shakes her head:</context>
      <utterance>There's nothin' sweet about me. I told that kid what he needed to hear so he wouldn't get in my damn way. All I care about is killin' that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He CRACKS the reins, riding ahead. HOLD ON ELLA... who finally follows as they all ride out and MUSIC SOARS:</context>
      <utterance>Well believe it. I was playing a part.  Just like you were.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>Without response, he levels the axe and SLAMS it down on the FLOORBOARDS. Wood chips SPRAY until a GASH is opened. Dolar REACHES in... pulling out a CANVAS BAG. A few COINS spill out... COLD. He picks them up -- looks at the woman:</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need it to save Nat.</utterance>
   <speaker>86.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now her worry becomes FEAR; English now:</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A storm of mixed emotions in his eyes. That stoic Dolarhyde veneer starts to CRACK... just a hint... as the woman MOVES to him... and TOUCHES his face. And he lets her. WHOA. We realize: this woman is COLORADO'S MOTHER. Dolarhyde, for all his wicked bluster, LOVES AN APACHE.</context>
      <utterance>He's gonna be.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't let anything happen to him, Jenny.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>SOFTLY</mode>
      <context>With that, he's GONE with the gold. Leaving her full of DREAD.</context>
      <utterance>Come back to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and Percy're brothers, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... half.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... your momma and Dolarhyde---</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We friends now? Last I checked, you shot my ear off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want it back?</utterance>
   <speaker>87.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colorado GRUMBLES, pushes ahead of Jake...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolarhyde rides into camp, REARING in front of 30 guns</context>
      <utterance>One of them fellas Jake was ridin' with!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRONC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into his pocket and tosses Bronc a GOLD COIN:</context>
      <utterance>It's about what you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The men trade LOOKS. Bronc eyes the coin. Alight with greed:</context>
      <utterance>Lonergan stole your gold. That's a taste of what I got -- more'n you've ever seen. It's all yours if you help me get my boy back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRONC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's got your boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's the rub.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Off that --</context>
      <utterance>I got two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colorado readies his TOMAHAWK -- Jake meets his eyes:</context>
      <utterance>C g_that shuttle.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knew there was a good reason I didn't kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men trade FATEFUL LOOKS... then the Indians HURL MOLOTOVS at the charging horde: KAAA-BOOM! Aliens TWIST and SCREAM -- The Apaches STRIKE FEARLESSLY -- but the aliens quickly RECOVER and SHAKE THEM OFF, tearing most of them to SHREDS. The horses BREAK FREE and crash madly through the cavern -- And this is the DISTRACTION Jake and Ella need to make their run, for the transport -- up the loading ramp:</context>
      <utterance>Just thinkin' the same thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strap in. dammit!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ella JAMS a lever forward and the shuttle RISES. JAKE grabs WEBBING that must be some type of SEATBELT, feeling the sensation of ELLQU as:</context>
      <utterance>Into what?!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>90.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She cranks back and the ship PITCHES upward --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELLA JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Dammit --- -- what--?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Engines are warming up -- got eight minutes til the ship leaves, and about one til automated retrieval --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- autojamated what --?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake does that beside her as the next bolt PINGS out --</context>
      <utterance>Hug the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks at his bracelet, adrenaline SURGING -- it ACTIVATES:</context>
      <utterance>When they come at us, aim for their heads. Only way to kill 'em for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE LAST BOLT FIRES and the airlock door SHOOTS OFF:</context>
      <utterance>I'll aim just fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She turns -- hits buttons on a console -- a door SLIDES UP leading to a series of CORRIDORS. She starts to MOVE --</context>
      <utterance>We can't let that thing see us or they'll know we're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This'll take us to the bridge -- But Jake doesn't follow. STARES at her --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slaver's up there--?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sure as hell hope not.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now she HARDENS --</context>
      <utterance>Then I'm not goin' with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- SLAM!! Jake interrupts her by aiming at the LASER SCANNER and FIRING HIS BLASTER, blowing it apart. The scanner eye CRASHES to the floor, flaming. A KLAXON rings --</context>
      <utterance>You got any idea how big this ship is? No ray you'll ever find him alone. Be like findin' a needle in a--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and RUNS. Jake moves to that scanner eye on the floor, walks right up to it and STARES into the shattered IRIS:</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the head start.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, you sonofabitch... come and get me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need more bandages now!/ You: lint and splint that leg!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context>And then, out of nowhere... the BANG BANG BANG of 30 pistols fills the air as -- DOLARHYDE RIDES IN WITH JAKE'S GANG! A renewed SURGE of energy as cowboys join Indians to fortify their ranks:</context>
      <utterance>We're losing ranks ! ! !</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came back!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colorado knows that's as close to "I love you" as he'll ever get. But the UPSWING is short-lived as: A speeder WHIZZES past, dropping a METALLIC BUNDLE. It splits open right in front of the fort's STEEL GATES -- pieces hydraulically ASSEMBLING THEMSELVES in seconds, becoming: THE MOTHERFUCKING SUPERGUN_OF DEATH. TWO LETHAL BARRELS spin to life, firing STRANGE STEEL BALL BEARINGS in every direction. CLAW HOOKS snap out of the balls, EMBEDDING in soldiers! One LODGES in a GANG MEMBER beside DOC -- he FLAILS:</context>
      <utterance>Told you: I take care of my kin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But The Slaver only presses his blaster HARDER into Ella's neck. Almost GRINNING. And Jake MEETS the look --</context>
      <utterance>Drop the woman. We both know this ain't about her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jake curls back the fingers on both hands, CRACKING knuckles:</context>
      <utterance>She says you're as bad as they come.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A pipe SPEWS STEAM -- UNNERVINGLY LOUD. Then STOPS.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you ugly sonofabitch... they say the same about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could'a had your boys kill me five times over, instead you rolled out the red carpet... so let's get it over with.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>In PAIN, she snatches one of those SMART DISCS off a dead alien:</context>
      <utterance>-- you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slings an arm around her shoulder and LIFTS her, helping her to the elevator --</context>
      <utterance>Reactor's hit. if I don't get this ship on the ground soon, we're all dead...  Get me over to that turbolift.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He does. She sees his eyes go back to The Slaver's BLOOD TRAIL:</context>
      <utterance>Put me inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>(tough... but with</context>
      <utterance>I can manage the rest without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPASSION)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her. At the blood. At the unstable REACTOR. And Jake Lonergan makes a CHOICE:</context>
      <utterance>Go do what you came up here to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- he gets INTO THE ELEVATOR with her. She SLAMS the control pad, doors CLOSE -- they start rocketing upward. She half-grins as her eyes hold on him. And within them... trust. AND FAITH.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop smiling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOL.ARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Grey Wolf MOANS in pain. Doc SHOUTS to Dolar:</context>
      <utterance>The hell iz that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him to hold still! If I have this thing figured right, long as t keep my finger under the red pin we won't blow up!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he saying?:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>SUBTITLE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says we're all gonna die.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to pull it out of his shoulder!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not pullin' anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>RE: DOC</mode>
      <context>ZZZZZZAM! MORE people are CUT DOWN by the Alien GRENADE CANNON -- the BLOWBACK nearly KNOCKS the grenade out of Doe's hand --</context>
      <utterance>He's the damn doctor!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On three...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode>DOLAR NODS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One... t --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Wait. Everyone LURCHES from the tension interrupt:</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell your wife we're clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON DOC. Reeling, now REALLY confused --</context>
      <utterance>-- your wife. Maria. We had an arrangement. I left your saloon alone and she paid me off.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're broke. Paid you off with what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It LANDS on Doc: that's why he fond the watch under their bed.</context>
      <utterance>She stole from the people in your morgue. Gold teeth, trinkets, pocket watches --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought she was cheating!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just robbin' corpses.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With GENUINE REMORSE:</context>
      <utterance>Thank God!  Wait. You hate me. Why're you telling me this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May not get another chance --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>A MOMENT. Forgiveness and atonement.</context>
      <utterance>-- and I still hate ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She calls up telemetry on a HOLO-WINDOW: EARTH TERRAIN -- The BATTLEFIELD. Sets coordinates, vectoring the ship that way: A WHIR as a SECOND TURBOLIFT arrives... AND THE SLAVER STEPS QQT. Wounded, and very PISSED OFF. Jake says to Ella:</context>
      <utterance>We're going down fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake and The Slaver HURTLE into each other, TUMBLE off a catwalk, CRASHING into conduits and GUNKY WATER below. Jake staggers up but The Slaver is HUGE -- SLAMS Jake back into the water. PINS A FOOT on his blaster arm -- CRUSHING IT. Jake HOWLS as The Slaver presses a series of those HIEROGLYPH MARKINGS on Jake's BRACELET -- the symbols LIGHT UP in an UNLOCK CODE -- and KA-CHING! The bracelet POPS OF.E. The Slaver TOSSES IT into the gunky water. Draws his LASER WHIP -- WHUP-SNAP! The white-hot tip LASHES JAKE'S BACK, ripping his shirt and BURN-SCARRING HIS BACK! Jake SCREAMS in agony as The Slaver WHIPS HIM MERCILESSLY --</context>
      <utterance>No matter what.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lied.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I heard what you said when I was layin' there...</utterance>
   <speaker>103.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>JAKE. Taken aback. LAID BARE. As she says:</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The ground GROWS BIGGER out the window. Her HAND reaches over for his. JAKE'S HAND clasps hers and --</context>
      <utterance>You are a good man. At least... to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>A VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Colorado turns -- it's PERCY. Confused. Like waking from a dream. Sees his father on the ground...</context>
      <utterance>Nat?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And all Colorado can say is...</context>
      <utterance>What... happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAT COLORADO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That HANGS there. Percy blinks. And then --</context>
      <utterance>He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON COLORADO. At first, words that don't compute. Then PURE BLIND RAGE takes hold and his FISTS FLY, PUNCHING PERCY:</context>
      <utterance>Who's gettin' the ranch?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Stunned, Colorado GRINS. Percy spits blood, points accusingly --</context>
      <utterance>No one's gettin' my ranch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paw, he-- Dolarhyde SMACKS Percy across the face:</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OW!!! What'd you do that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>UOLARHYUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For being an ungrateful little bastard. Now shake your brother's hand and thank him for saving your ass, cause it's more than you ever would'a done bjM.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>. what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That LANDS on Jake, as he too looks toward the endless horizon. HOLD on them, together, a VICTORIOUS but UNRESOLVED note... We RISE UP over the sea of bodies and the CRASHED SHIP, until Jake and Ella are just two small figures in the crowd...</context>
      <utterance>We didn't get all of 'em. Some ran oft.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- what? What'd I dQ?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART EMMETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs off. Taggart SMIRKS:</context>
      <utterance>Get outta the road before you're run down! If your  momma saw y-- -- "saw me playin' in the street she'd roll over in her grave and shoot lightnin' bolts outta her eyes," I know, I know!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid's got a mouth on him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DEPUTY WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolar moves up to Taggart, tough as ever. The men HOLD looks:</context>
      <utterance>Well, Kyle, considering he saved your life, guess you'll just have to grin'n bear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woodrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Percy STEWS about something. Dolar WHACKS him upside the head:</context>
      <utterance>Kyle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Grudgingly, Percy hands Taggart a SHEAF OF PAPER --</context>
      <utterance>Go_ _on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claims to the land 50 miles west of here. I've signed it over to the township of Absolution.  Considering I'm a businessman, I figure expansion's in both our interests. Needs the Sheriff's signature to be official.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty miles west of here is where the goldmine is, Woodrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode>A BEAT</mode>
      <context>With surprise, Taggart studies the paper. SMILES:</context>
      <utterance>That so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolarhyde glances at Colorado. A moment. But the hardened rancher maintains his rock-solid facade:</context>
      <utterance>What's this about twenty percent going to the Apaches?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Figure the only way not to piss 'em off is to buy 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when'd you worry about pissin' anyone off?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a grin, Taggart gestures for Deputy Wade to turn around and flattens the paper on his BACK, using it as a surface to SIGN:</context>
      <utterance>Just sign it, Goddamnit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF TAGGART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd say you were being generous, Woodrow, but I know you'd just be insulted.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLARHYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolar gives his hat a TIP, then mounts up to go -- and we RISE UP to the UPPER FLOOR of the GOLD LEAF SALOON, in the process of being rebuilt in grand style -- and MOVE IN on a WINDOW where:</context>
      <utterance>Damn right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOC MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they TUMBLE back onto the bed, Doc LURCHES. Reaches under his back to find... a GOLD POCKETWATCH.</context>
      <utterance>SHH! The workers will hear us!!! Let them hear!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flips it open to find an ENGRAVING: "MI CORAZON... POR SIEMPRE." Doc looks up at her, MOVED. Then -- PLAYFULLY:</context>
      <utterance>Look at the inscription.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This looks like Aldo Mayberry's watch...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls him down, OUT OF FRAME --</context>
      <utterance>Shut up and kiss me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Second damn time that dog ran off on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Happy's tail wags. The look between Jake and Ella HOLDS. And it seems freighted with everything. Finally, he breaks it -- glancing at the Apaches finishing their work with the dynamite, and the remnants of the ALIEN SHIP and FORTRESS below.</context>
      <utterance>Second time he brought me to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ella eyes Jake's horse, loaded with GEAR. Looks up, clearly</context>
      <utterance>Looks like you got everything set.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you headed?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>A BEAT</mode>
      <context>But she looks at him. fEADI.NG liim. wryly:</context>
      <utterance>Got some messes to clean up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Messes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks right up to his horse. Right up to HIM:</context>
      <utterance>... Yep.  What.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An INFERENCE here. Ella's going BOLD. Jake swings off his horse, lands beside her. Now. Almost CURIOUS:</context>
      <utterance>I think you're ridin' off cause you're just scared of what'll happen if you stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what's gonna happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>109.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She steps CLOSER to him... INTIMATE:</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CHARGE between them. All they wanna do is KISS... But that'd be too easy. And those wounds of his, they haven't quite healed. He drops his eyes; SOFTLY NOW:</context>
      <utterance>You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. She looks off. Nods. They say nothing. And now he slowly climbs back on his horse. Ella TOUGHENS:</context>
      <utterance>If I stay... it's not gonna be good for anybody, Ella.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heard some rumors outta Abilene. Weird noises at night. Cattle mutilations. Weather phenomena. Figured I'd ride down there. Give it a look-see.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's 'phenomena'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON JAKE. Every fighting instinct in him suddenly IGNITED, though he plays it down:</context>
      <utterance>Big storms in places that don't get big storms.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You goin' down there yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You bet your ass he is. But, he shakes his head--</context>
      <utterance>Why? You worried about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am. You can take care of yourself just fine.  Be seein' you around.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets back on his horse. Starts to ride off. Happy BARKS and trots alongside him. BARK BARK BARK. In dog that means "Don't be an idiot." Jake glances over --</context>
      <utterance>goodbye, Jake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the hell away from me, you damn mutt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>BARK, BARK</mode>
      <context>He heels his horse, leaving Happy behind to WHINE. Jake rides off into the sunset. But his heart's KICKING in his chest. And this is pretty much where things usually end... But. Jake pulls the REINS as he SIGHS. Turns the horse around. TROTS back to Ella, whose smile WIDENS as he closes the gap between them. Finally STOPS right in front of her. And despite his best effort to stay TOUGH... he just plain likes her:</context>
      <utterance>Go on, GET.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He reaches out a hand... she takes it... as he PULLS HER UP INTO THE SADDLE. Ella grinning ear-to-ear as she folds her arms around his waist. Jake -- ever the outlaw -- grumbles:</context>
      <utterance>Abilene happens to be on my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He KICKS the horse and Happy follows. Ella shoots a goodbye look to Grey Wolf, who NODS. Signals his men and FUSES ARE LIT: The DYNAMITE FUSES ssssssnake down the mountain -- reaching the canyon floor -- INTO those limestone tunnels where CLUSTERS OF DYNAMITE have been placed... and as FUSE MEETS EXPLOSIVE: ANGLE - JAKE AND ELLA CRESTING A HILL -- B000000000000MI The THUNDER of EXPLOSIONS makes them rear. They turn back to see...</context>
      <utterance>Stop smiling, Goddammit.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
