<movie id="143" title="Crash">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dolly grip with very close-cropped hair looks up from a section of dolly track which he is adjusting with small wooden wedges.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for James. Has anybody seen James Ballard? You know who I mean? The producer of this epic.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I saw him in the camera department.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man, James, looks up from the woman's thighs.</context>
      <utterance>James? James, are you in there? Could we please get your stamp of approval on our little tracking shot?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera girl twists around on to her back and throws her legs over James's shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. Be there in a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERA GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll take more than a minute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the private aircraft hangar. Anybody could have walked in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you come?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. What about your camera girl? Did she come?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine turns toward James and pulls open her blouse, exposing her left breast. She pulls James's face down and presses her nipple against his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>We were interrupted. I had to go back to the set...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor darling.  What can I do about Karen? How can I arrange to have her seduce me? She desperately needs a conquest.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking about that, about you and Karen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There, that's better.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James examines himself in her hand-mirror, staring at his pale, mannequin-like face, trying to read its lines. Catherine looks around her as she puts her makeup away. There are twenty-three other beds in the briskly efficient-looking new ward, all of them empty.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a lot of action here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They consider this to be the airport hospital. This ward is reserved for air-crash victims. The beds are kept waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I groundloop during my flying lesson on Saturday you might wake up and find me next to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine crosses her legs and tries to light a cigarette with a heavy, mechanically complex lighter with which she is obviously unfamiliar.</context>
      <utterance>I'll listen for you buzzing over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a gift from Wendel? It has an aeronautical feel to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine finally succeeds in lighting the cigarette. She takes a deep drag. James props himself up on his elbow, breathing with transparent pain.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. From Wendel. To celebrate the licence approval for our air-charter firm. I forgot to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's going well, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're getting out of bed tomorrow. They want you to walk. James gestures for the cigarette. Catherine puts the warm tip, stained with pink lipstick, into his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Well, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other man, the dead man, his wife is a doctor -- Dr Helen Remington. She's here, somewhere. As a patient, of course. Maybe you'll find her in the hallways tomorrow on your walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And her husband? What was he?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dark-haired student female nurse comes into the ward. She wags a finger at James.</context>
      <utterance>He was a chemical engineer with a food company.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Catherine retrieves the cigarette from James and stubs it out in a glass, the nurse examines Catherine's glamorous figure, her expensive suit, her jewelry.</context>
      <utterance>No smoking, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you this gentleman's wife? Mrs Ballard?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nurse pulls the bedclothes back and digs the urine bottle from between James's legs. She checks the level and, satisfied, drops it back, flips over the sheets again. Both Catherine and James watch her closely, her sly thighs under her gingham, the movement of her breasts as she bends to check the chart at the foot of the bed, the pulse in her throat. The nurse catches them watching her, smiles enigmatically back at them, and leaves. Catherine pulls out a manila folder from her bag and slips a set of storyboards for a commercial out of it.</context>
      <utterance>You can stay for this, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James waves the folder away. Catherine examines his body, aloofly curious.</context>
      <utterance>Aida telephoned to say how sorry she was, but could you look at the storyboards again, she's made a number of changes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the car?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outside in the visitors' car-park.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!? They brought the car here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My car, not yours. Yours is a complete wreck. The police dragged it to the pound behind the station.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sergeant asked me to identify it. He didn't believe you'd gotten out alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After being bombarded endlessly by road-safety propaganda, it's almost a relief to have found myself in an actual accident.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>James Ballard?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crash victim?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughan shuffles his photos again. James manages to make out the shapes of a few crushed and distorted vehicles caught in lurid, flash-lit news style. Vaughan flips through them distractedly, then with an unexpected, almost flirtatious flourish slides them back into his briefcase and tucks it under his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flashes James an enigmatic smile, and walks off down the hallway. As James turns to continue, a young woman comes out of the same room that Vaughan appeared from and moves toward him, using a dark wooden walking stick. She presses her face into her raised shoulder, possibly to hide the bruise marking her right cheekbone. The woman is Dr. Helen Remington, whose husband died in her car crash with James. James stops as she approaches. He speaks without thinking.</context>
      <utterance>We'll deal with these later.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman looks up at James as she continues her approach. She does not falter, but changes her grip on the cane, as if preparing to thrash him across the face with it. She moves her head in a peculiar gesture of the neck, deliberately forcing her injury on him. She pauses when she reaches the doorway, waiting for him to step out of her way. James looks down at the scar tissue on her face, a seam left by an invisible zip three inches long, running from the corner of her right eye to the apex of her mouth. James is acutely aware of her strong body beneath her mauve bathrobe, her ribcage partly shielded by a sheath of white plaster that runs from one shoulder to the opposite armpit like a classic Hollywood ball-gown. James steps aside. Deciding to ignore him, Helen Remington walks stiffly along the communication corridor, parading her anger and her wound.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Remington...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine resoaps her right hand from the bar in the wet saucer on the bed tray, a cigarette in her left. James strokes her stockinged thigh as she continues her monologue.</context>
      <utterance>Both front wheels and the engine were driven back into the driver's section, bowing the floor. Blood still marked the hood, streamers of black lace running toward the windshield-wiper gutters.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Minute flecks were spattered across the seat and steering wheel. The instrument panel was buckled inwards, cracking the clock and the speedometer dials. The cabin was deformed, and there was dust and glass and plastic flakes everywhere inside. The carpeting was damp and stank of blood and other body and machine fluids.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should have gone to the funeral.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I had. They bury the dead so quickly -- they should leave them lying around for months.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about his wife? The woman doctor? Have you visited her yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I couldn't. I feel too close to her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Renata tells me you're going to rent a car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't sit on this balcony forever. I'm beginning to feel like a potted plant.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you drive? James... your legs. You can barely walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the traffic heavier now? There seem to be three times as many cars as there were before the accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never really noticed. Is Renata going with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought she might come along. Handling a car again might be more tiring than I imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm amazed that she'll let you drive her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not envious?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I am a little.  James, I've got to leave for the office. Are you going to be all right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we allowed to park here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James unbuttons Renata's raincoat and places his hand on her thigh. She lets him kiss her throat, holding his shoulder reassuringly, like an affectionate governess.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure the police would make an exception in your case.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's still a patch of blood there on the road. Did you see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw the blood. It looks like motor oil.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were the last one I saw just before the accident. Do you remember? We made love.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An airline coach passes, the passengers bound for Milan staring down at the couple in the car. Renata buttons her coat.</context>
      <utterance>Are you still involving me in your crash?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you drive?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James shifts the car into gear and cruises slowly toward the man with the camera. As they approach him, he gets out of his own car, ignoring them, and kneels down to study the hieroglyphics of the skid marks on the road surface. As James and Renata drive past the kneeling man, the sunlight highlights the ridges of scars on his forehead and around his mouth. The man looks up at James and he recognizes Vaughan, the young doctor he last saw in the hallway at the airport hospital.</context>
      <utterance>I can drive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you've done this.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the exact same car as your old one, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it is.  Are you planning to have another car crash?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James is telling the truth. What he is thinking about is the way that Karen's hip casually brushes against Catherine's hip, without either woman seeming to be conscious of it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not thinking about the crash at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After this sort of thing, how do people manage to look at a car, let alone drive one?  I'm trying to find Charles's car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not here. Maybe the police are still holding it. Their forensic people...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She peers critically at James's car, as if puzzled by its distorted geometry.</context>
      <utterance>They said it was here. They told me this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches out a gloved hand and touches the radiator grill, feeling a chrome pillar torn from the accordion, as if searching for some trace of her husband's presence among the blood-spattered paintwork.</context>
      <utterance>This is your car?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James gently takes her hand and moves it away from the grill.</context>
      <utterance>You'll tear your gloves.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think we should have come here. I'm surprised the police don't make it more difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you badly hurt? I think we saw each other at the hospital.  I don't want the car. In fact, I was appalled to find that I have to pay a small fee to have it scrapped.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I give you a lift?  I somehow find myself driving again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't told me where we're going.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At these words, James is stricken by an odd feeling of loss.</context>
      <utterance>Haven't I? To the airport, if you could.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The airport? Why? Are you leaving?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet -- though not soon enough for some people, I've already found. A death in the doctor's family makes the patients doubly uneasy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I take it you're not wearing white to reassure them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll wear a bloody kimono if I want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So -- why the airport?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James is very aware that, as they speak, Helen is intently watching his hands and feet operating the controls of the car, perceiving these motions in a way that she never would have before her crash with him. He, in turn, has trouble taking his eyes off her facial scars, which she now makes no attempt to hide. She pulls a cigarette packet from the pocket of her raincoat. She searches the instrument panel for the lighter, her right hand hovering above his knees like a nervous bird. Having found the lighter, her strong hands tear away the cellophane from the cigarette pack.</context>
      <utterance>I work in the immigration department there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want a cigarette? I started to smoke at the hospital. It's rather stupid of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at all this traffic. I'm not sure I can deal with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's much worse now. You noticed that, did you? The day I left the hospital I had the extraordinary feeling that all these cars were gathering for some special reason I didn't understand. There seemed to be ten times as much traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen waves her cigarette in a gesture that takes in the whole interior of the car.</context>
      <utterance>Are we imagining it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've bought yourself exactly the same car again. It's the same shape and colour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've found that I enjoy burying myself in heavy traffic. I like to look at it. Yesterday I hired a taxi-driver to drive me around for an hour. 'Anywhere,' I said. We sat in a massive traffic jam under an off- ramp. I don't think we moved more than fifty yards.  I'm thinking of taking up a new job with the Road Research Laboratory. They need a medical officer. The salary is larger -- something I've got to think about now. There's a certain moral virtue in being materialistic, I'm beginning to feel. Well, it's a new approach for me, in any case.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Road Research Laboratory? Where they simulate car crashes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that rather too close...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have now reached the top level of the multi-story car- park, and James pulls into a parking spot overlooking a major runway. An immense jumbo jet is maneuvering into its take- off position. James turns off the car and puts his arms around Helen. She offers no resistance, as though the whole scenario were well understood and agreed upon. James kisses her mouth, her eyelids, unzips her dress. With the jet engines screaming for accompaniment, Helen lifts her right breast from her brassire, pressing James's fingers against the hot nipple. Helen now straddles him and, awkwardly meshing with the technology around them, they make love in the driver's seat of the car.</context>
      <utterance>That's the point. Besides, I know I can give something now that I wasn't remotely aware of before. It's not a matter of duty so much as of commitment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renata hands James a brown manila envelope with no markings on it.</context>
      <utterance>I almost forgot to give you this. Probably because I know you're going to like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A complimentary ticket for a special stunt-driving exhibition. Definitely not part of the big auto show. There's a map in the packet and a note requesting you be discreet about the location.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? What kind of exhibition is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suspect it involves re-enactments of famous car crashes. You know, Jayne Mansfield, James Dean, Albert Camus...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Serious. But you'll have to take your new friend, the female crash- test dummy. She dropped it off for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renata kisses him hard, then bites his lip. James pulls away in surprise.</context>
      <utterance>You're not jealous, are you? You have to understand... Helen and I had this strange, intense... experience together.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renata turns on her heel and floats out the door, leaving James to contemplate the contents of the envelope.</context>
      <utterance>We've had a few of those ourselves, haven't we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen is consulting a yellow program sheet.</context>
      <utterance>It's strange -- I thought all this would be far more popular.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The real thing is available free of charge. Besides, it's not quite legal. They can't advertise.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first star of our show is 'Little Bastard', James Dean's racing Porsche. He named it after himself, and had his racing number, 130, painted on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that? The announcer. Do I know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Vaughan. He talked to you at the hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. I thought he was a medical photographer, doing some sort of accident research. He wanted every conceivable detail about our crash.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I first met Vaughan, he was a specialist in international computerized traffic systems. I don't know what he is now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The second star is stuntman and former race driver -- Colin Seagrave, who will drive our replica of James Dean's car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that part of the act or are they really hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stills cameraman runs out of nowhere and kneels beside the apparently stricken Vaughan in the weeds at the side of the road. It is not clear whether he is taking his picture or ministering to him. It soon becomes clear that he has handed him a radio microphone because Vaughan's low, melodramatic growl now ripples out of the woods from the tree speakers.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. You can never be sure with Vaughan. This is his show.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rolf Wtherich was thrown from the Porsche and spent a year in the hospital recovering from his injuries. Donald Turnupseed was found wandering around in a daze, basically unhurt. James Dean died of a broken neck and became immortal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold me. I'm dizzy. I can't stand up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen makes her way down the rickety grandstand steps toward the road, and James follows her.</context>
      <utterance>I know that man, Seagrave, the stunt driver. I think he's genuinely hurt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with Seagrave?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The police spread out through the crowd, collaring people at random before they are able to escape into the woods.</context>
      <utterance>Hit his head, I think. His balance is off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are the police taking this all so seriously?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the gathering darkness of the woods, it is apparent that James doesn't really know who they are either.</context>
      <utterance>It's not the police. It's the Department of Transport. Internal politics. It's a joke. They have no idea who we really are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VERA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vera and Helen lay the confused Seagrave down on the three- seat sofa, while Vaughan sits next to Gabrielle and helps her prepare another hash joint. James, awkwardly left standing, notices long scars on Vera's thighs and legs.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God. What happened? Here, lie down.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They did the James Dean crash. It seemed to go perfectly. But he started to feel nauseous on the way back. I'm sure it's concussion.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James watches Gabrielle and Vaughan. As she rolls a small piece of resin in a twist of silver foil, Vaughan brings a brass lighter out of his hip pocket. Gabrielle cooks the resin, and shakes the powder into the open cigarette waiting in the roller machine on her lap. On Gabrielle's legs are traces of what seem to be gas bacillus scars, faint circular depressions on the kneecaps. She notices James staring at her scars, but makes no effort to close her legs. On the sofa beside her is a chromium metal cane and, as she shifts her weight, James sees that the instep of each leg is held in the steel clamp of a surgical support. It now becomes obvious from the over-rigid posture of her waist that she is also wearing a back-brace of some kind. Gabrielle rolls another cigarette out of the machine, but does not offer it to James. Instead, Vaughan gets up and takes it over to Seagrave, who has managed to sit up.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, well... We're familiar enough with that, then, aren't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seagrave takes the lit joint and draws heavily on it. He holds the smoke in his lungs for a while, studies the grease on his hands before he answers.</context>
      <utterance>I'd really like to work out the details of the Jayne Mansfield crash with you. We could do the decapitation -- her head embedded in the windshield -- and the little dead dog thing as well. You know, the Chihuahuas in the back seat. I've got it figured out.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James turns to go, leaving Helen to her conversation with Vera, but Vaughan follows him through the door, holding his arm in a powerful grip.</context>
      <utterance>You know I'll be ready, Vaughan. But I'll want to wear really big tits -- out to here -- so the crowd can see them get cut up and crushed on the dashboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't leave yet, Ballard. I want you to help me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you live here? With Seagrave?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Vaughan hunts around the central table, turning the pages of a leather-bound album, James looks down at the discarded prints below his feet. Most of them are crude frontal pictures of motor-cars and heavy vehicles involved in highway collisions, surrounded by spectators and police, and close- ups of impacted radiator grills and windshields. Vaughan opens the album at random and hands it to James. He leans back against the door and watches as James adjusts the desk lamp. The first thirty pages record the crash, hospitalization, and post-recuperative romance of the young woman Gabrielle -- a social worker, the photos suggest -- who is currently getting very stoned in the next room. By coincidence, her small sports car had collided with an airline bus at the entry to the airport not far from the site of James's own accident. Vaughan had obviously been there, shooting film, moments after the crash. The incredibly detailed photos end with her affair with her physical therapy instructor. The remainder of the album describes the course of James's own accident and recovery, and includes his sexual encounters with Renata, Helen Remington, and his own wife, Catherine. Vaughan stands at James's shoulder, like an instructor ready to help a promising pupil. James closes the book.</context>
      <utterance>And this is the new project, Ballard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, there is a knock at the door, and then Gabrielle enters and takes a few stiff steps into the room on her shackled legs. She holds out a couple of joints to Vaughan.</context>
      <utterance>What kind of help can I possibly be to you? You seem to be everywhere at once as it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughan takes the joints and lights them both. He hands one to James, who takes it gratefully.</context>
      <utterance>Thought you might be missing these.  So here you are at the nerve centre. Vaughan makes everything look like a crime, doesn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What exactly is your project, Vaughan? A book of crashes? A medical study? A sensational documentary? Global traffic?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's something we're all intimately involved in: the reshaping of the human body by modern technology.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughan hooks his gear lever into reverse.</context>
      <utterance>Vaughan, what the hell are you doing? Are you trying to create your own Famous Crash?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughan reverses his car in a wide circle, almost running down a passing pump attendant, and sets off across the early afternoon traffic.</context>
      <utterance>It excited her, Ballard. Your wife, Catherine. She enjoyed it. Ask her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He must have fucked a lot of women in that huge car of his. It's like a bed on wheels. It must smell of semen...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It does.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you find him attractive?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's very pale. Covered with scars.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to fuck him, though? In that car?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But when he's in that car...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen his penis?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's badly scarred too. From a motorcycle accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both have huge orgasms within moments of each other.</context>
      <utterance>Is he circumcised? Can you imagine what his anus is like? Describe it to me. Would you like to sodomize him? Would you like to put your penis right into his anus, thrust it up his anus? Tell me, describe it to me. Tell me what you would do. How would you kiss him in that car? Describe how you'd reach over and unzip his greasy jeans, then take out his penis. Would you kiss it or suck it right away? Which hand would you hold it in? Have you ever sucked a penis? Do you know what semen tastes like? Have you ever tasted semen? Some semen is saltier than others. Vaughan's semen must be very salty...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please finish your story.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The junior pathologist at Ashford Hospital. Then the husband of a colleague of mine, then a trainee radiologist, then the service manager at my garage.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you had sex with all of these men in cars? Only in cars?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I didn't plan it that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And did you fantasize that Vaughan was photographing all these sex acts? As though they were traffic accidents?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.  They felt like traffic accidents.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>encouragingly, as if urging a child across some mental hurdle.</context>
      <utterance>Get all the paper you can, Ballard. Some of the stuff they're giving away is terrific: 'Mechanisms of Occupant Ejection', 'Tolerances of the Human Face in Crash Impacts'... Helen takes James's arm, smiling at him, nodding</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An audience of thirty or so gathers at the trestle tables to watch a slowmotion replay on a huge television monitor. As the hypnotic, grotesque ballet unfolds, the crowd's own ghostly images stand silently in the background, hands and faces unmoving while the collision is re-enacted. The dream- like reversal of roles makes them seem less real than the mannequins in the car. James looks down at the silk-suited wife of a Ministry official standing beside him. Her eyes watch the film with a rapt gaze, as if she were seeing herself and her daughters dismembered in the crash.</context>
      <utterance>We can have a look at it again on the monitors. They're showing it in slow motion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always wanted to drive a crashed car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could get your wish at any moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean a crash with a history. Camus's Facel Vega, or Nathaniel West's station wagon, Grace Kelly's Rover 3500. Fix it just enough to get it rolling. Don't clean it, don't touch anything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why you drive this car? I take it that you see Kennedy's assassination as a special kind of car crash?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They approach a major intersection. For almost the first time on this drive, Vaughan applies the brakes. The heavy car sways and goes into a long right-hand slide which carries it across the path of a taxi. Flooring the accelerator, Vaughan swerves in front of it, tires screaming over the blaring horn of the taxi. As they settle down, Vaughan reaches behind him and lifts a briefcase off the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>The case could be made.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James opens the briefcase and slides out a thick packet of glossy photographs, all of them marked up with coloured ink pens. The photos are culled from a variety of sources -- newspapers, magazines, video stills, film frames -- blown up to uniform 8' x 10' size. Each one depicts a famous crash victim in the prime of life, and each one has the wounds to come marked up very explicitly -- lines circling their necks and pubic areas, breasts and cheekbones shaded in, section lines across their mouths and abdomens. Handwritten notes complement the circles and arrows. A second packet of photographs shows the cars in which these famous people died. Each photo is marked to show which parts of the cars destroyed or fused with which famous body part: for example, a close-up of the dashboard and windshield from the Camus car -- Michel Gallimard's Facel Vega -- is marked 'nasal bridge', 'soft palate', 'left zygomatic arch'.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look at this and tell me what you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very... satisfying. I'm not sure I understand why.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the future, Ballard, and you're already part of it. For the first time, a benevolent psychopathology beckons towards us. For example, the car crash is a fertilizing rather than a destructive event -- a liberation of sexual energy that mediates the sexuality of those who have died with an intensity impossible in any other form. To fully understand that, and to live that... that is my project.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the reshaping of the human body by modern technology? I thought that was your project.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The traffic has jammed up to a walking pace. Using his horn, Vaughan forces the drivers in the slower lanes to back up and let him across on to the hard shoulder. Once free, he accelerates past the lines of traffic, occasionally scraping the right flank of the Lincoln against the cement divider. In the distance the airport car-park looms.</context>
      <utterance>A crude sci-fi concept that floats on the surface and doesn't threaten anybody. I use it to test the resilience of my potential partners in psychopathology.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The startled James numbly obeys, sliding over into the driver's seat as Vaughan approaches the whore and begins to negotiate with her. James gingerly maneuvers the boat-like car to one side to allow traffic to pass as Vaughan returns with the gum-chewing whore in tow. As the girl, with short black hair and a boy's narrow-hipped body, opens the passenger door, Vaughan hands her a joint and lights it for her. Then, lifting her chin, he puts his fingers in her mouth and plucks out the knot of gum, flicking it away into the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>You drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get rid of that. I don't want you blowing it up my urethra.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James leaves the table and looks out the window. Vaughan is sitting in his car in the center of the parking-lot. Most of the staff are leaving for home, taking their cars one by one from the slots around Vaughan's dusty limousine.</context>
      <utterance>Your friend's still out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he want from you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to leave now. Do you want a lift?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks. I'll go with Vaughan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're questioning Vaughan about an accident near the airport. Some pedestrian... they think he was run over intentionally.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if taking their cue from this, the policemen walk back to their car. Vaughan watches them go, head raised like a periscope.</context>
      <utterance>Vaughan isn't interested in pedestrians.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd better drive him. He's a bit shaky. I'll follow in my car. Where is yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At home. I couldn't face all this traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Catherine and James walk toward Vaughan, he reaches into the rear seat of his car and pulls out a white sweatshirt. As he takes off his denim jacket, the falling light picks out the scars on his naked abdomen and chest, a constellation of white chips that circle his body from the left armpit down to his crotch.</context>
      <utterance>I'd better come with you, then. Are you sure you can drive?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughan turns back to look at the wreck again, almost reverent. This is Seagrave's own solitary work of art.</context>
      <utterance>It's Seagrave. He was worried that we would never do Jayne Mansfield's crash, now that the police were cracking down. So he did it himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughan lopes off toward the Seagrave wreck. But James hangs back, watching, as the passengers from the taxi are carried on stretchers to an ambulance. The dead chauffeur of the limousine lies with a blanket over his face, while a doctor and two ambulance men climb into the rear compartment. Beyond them, Vaughan begins to snap away at every possible aspect of Seagrave's wreck, beginning with the dead Chihuahua.</context>
      <utterance>Come with me, James. I have to document it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughan kneels beside him and inspects the smears of blood.</context>
      <utterance>We must have driven through a pool of blood. If the police stop you again, they may impound the car while they have the blood analyzed.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughan rises and holds the door open for James, who sits behind the wheel, expecting Vaughan to walk around the car and sit beside him. Instead, Vaughan pulls open the rear door and climbs in beside Catherine. As they set off, Vaughan's camera lands on the front seat.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, Ballard. There's an all-night car-wash in the airport service area.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there something here that interests you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both James and Gabrielle enjoy the salesman's discomfort as he helps her into the Mercedes sports car. She does her best to make it difficult, deliberately snagging her leg brace clips on the soft leather of the driver's side armrest, forcing him to unhook her and to touch her deformed thighs and knees while manipulating her legs into the footwell.</context>
      <utterance>The white sports model. Could you help me into it, please? I'd like to see if I can fit into a car designed for a normal body.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She spreads her left leg and exposes a deep, trench-like wound-scar in her inner thigh. She directs his hand to this neo-sex organ.</context>
      <utterance>Don't. Not there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabrielle rotates over him so that he can see the wounds of her right hip. James turns her back, pulls her thigh in between his own thighs and enters her scar. With his mouth fastened on the scar beneath her left breast, his tongue exploring its sickle-shaped trough, he comes almost immediately.</context>
      <utterance>Do it there. And then after that, do it here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James nods. The AD presses the TALK button and hands the phone to James.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody named Vaughan. Do you want it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Ballard.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to see you, Ballard. I need to talk to you about the project.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're making it too clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>TATTOOIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Medical tattoos are supposed to be clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't a medical tattoo. This is a prophetic tattoo. Prophesy is dirty and ragged. Make it dirty and ragged.</utterance>
   <speaker>TATTOOIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prophetic? Is this personal prophesy or global prophesy?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughan spreads out a stained scrap of paper as though it were a sacred piece of parchment. On it is a fiercely sketched wound that looks as though it were made by the Lincoln's hood ornament.</context>
      <utterance>There's no difference. James -- I want you to let her give you this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughan spreads his legs in a mechanical, unsexual way and grabs the right inner thigh of his greasy jeans.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you think that one should go?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It should go here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought that was you, up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James can see now that Catherine is frightened. He takes her hand.</context>
      <utterance>My last lesson's next week.  James... my car...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Tell me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't driving. I'd left the car in the parking-lot at the airport. Could it have been deliberate?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of your suitors?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kneels down to examine the assault on her car. He feels the abrasions on the left-hand door and body panels, explores with his hand the deep trench that runs the full length of the car from the crushed tail-light to the front headlamp. The imprint of the other car's heavy front bumper is clearly marked on the rear wheel guard. James rises and takes Catherine's arm. He opens the passenger door for her.</context>
      <utterance>One of my suitors.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Vaughan. He's courting you. Let's go find him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The traffic... where is everyone? They've all gone away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to go back. James...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet. It's only beginning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At first she fails to recognize him. Her firm eyes cut across him to Catherine's elegant figure, as if suspicious of her cross-legged posture. James gets out of the car and approaches Vera. He points to the suitcases in the rear seat of Vera's car.</context>
      <utterance>Vera! Vera Seagrave!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vera finishes with the girl and, still staring at Catherine, steps into her car.</context>
      <utterance>Are you leaving, Vera? Listen, I'm trying to find Vaughan.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James puts his hand on the windshield, but she switches on the windshield wipers, almost cutting the knuckle of his wrist.</context>
      <utterance>The police are after him. An American serviceman was killed on the Northolt overpass.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before James can stop her, she accelerates toward the exit and turns into the fast evening traffic. James gets back into Catherine's car.</context>
      <utterance>I was with him in the car at the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he'll be waiting for us at the airport.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James turns the car into the traffic.</context>
      <utterance>James...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to register a claim for the black 1963 Lincoln, the one that came in a couple of days ago. Is there a form I can fill out?</utterance>
   <speaker>POUND OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There certainly is, but you'll have to come back between 7:30 and 4:30 to get one. What's your attachment to that thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A close friend owned it.</utterance>
   <speaker>POUND OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's got to be a total write- off. I don't see what you could possibly do with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine's eyes flutter open. Her mascara is smeared, as though she has been crying, and there is wetness at the corners of her eyes. Her upper lip is bruised and beginning to purple, and there is blood on her forehead and at the corner of her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Catherine. Are you all right? Are you hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James slips her panties down her legs, leaving them around her left ankle when they snag on the one high-heeled shoe she still has on. He gently rotates her on to her right hip, undoes his fly, then lies down on the concrete with her, ignoring the light, muddy stream which now begins to soak the thigh of his trousers. Kissing the back of her neck, he enters her from behind.</context>
      <utterance>James, I... I don't know... I think I'm all right...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We pull up and away from the couple on the ground until we lose them behind the overturned sports car, then rise and pivot until we are once again watching the frantic lanes of traffic hurtling by obliviously only a few meters away.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe the next one, darling... Maybe the next one...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
