<movie id="145" title="Crime Spree">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn on the flashlight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying. It doesn't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>It has to work. You just bought it this afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do they come with batteries?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't buy batteries?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought they came with batteries.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you didn't check.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bought everything you put on the list. Gloves. Pen knives. Flashlight. Batteries were not on the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I have to put it on the list? It's like saying to buy a car with tires.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julien starts to pick up the ZIPPO.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Too Late! Julien has already picked it up. It burns his hand ans he flicks it away. It flies through the air and lands in the corner of the room. The CURTAINS catch on fire.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julien panics! He grabs the canvas out of Daniel's hand and begins beating the flames with it. Daniel looks at him with disbelief. Julien flails his arms wildly as he beats back the flames. He turns to Daniel pleased that his efforts have extinguished the fire, but unaware that the canvas has now caught on fire. A beat. Julien sees the flames and puts them out. Daniel just stares at him. He opens the canvas. The painting is ruined.</context>
      <utterance>... hot!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julien remove a lighter and presses it. The entire room fills with light. Julien stares at the flame amazed.</context>
      <utterance>Light your lighter. I can't see anything... and try not to burn down the house!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn to see an old man standing at the top of the stairs in his bathrobe. He is frail, his face pasty white. He is holding a very long, double-barrel shotgun. Julien looks to Daniel with a 'what now' expression. The old man slowly moves down the stairs. He loses his balance and falls down the stairs, tumbling head over heals until he reaches the bottom. Daniel and Julien stare at the old man who is sprawled out on the floor, motionless.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. He looks dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DANIEL'S POV -- the old man runs out of his house with his shotgun and heads towards the car. Raymond is desperately trying to get the car free. They all slide down as the old man fires. The windows on the left side of the car shatter.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't think to move the car before we came out! Daniel looks out his window and sees...</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond pops up and returns to getting the car out as the old man opens the breach of the shotgun to reload.. Raymond floors the Peugeot keeping his foot on the brake. The engine revs. He turns the wheel to the left and releases the brake. The Peugeot juts forward smashing into the rear of the Mercedes and pushing in out into the street. Before the old man can take aim the Peugeot is speeding down the street.</context>
      <utterance>Raymond, get us out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're always pointing out my negative qualities. My analyst says positive reinforcement is a much more productive way of relating with people.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Raymond, we'd like to commend you on how well you fucked up tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel glances at Bastaldi to see if he appreciates his comments.</context>
      <utterance>I heard you almost got your ass blown off last night. Some thief. A regular black panther.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Black Panther was a member of an African American militant group in the sixties, Marcel. I think you're referring to The Pink Panther.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pink panther, black panther. Who gives a shit? And I don't remember asking you a God Damn thing, you little turd.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no reason to be abusive. You're projecting your anger on me as a defense mechanism.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is he talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talking about human beings communicating openly and honestly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about getting on your knees and communicating with my dick?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Raymond and Marcel stare at one another. We HEAR a muffled GROANING SOUND in the b.g.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Both of you! You're giving me a fuckin' headache.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel lays the cardboard tube containing the painting on the desk. Bastaldi removes the painting. To him it is not a work of art, just a commodity to be sold. He opens his desk drawer, removes several large stacks of money and hands them to Daniel.</context>
      <utterance>Vincent's in the States on business.  That it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We HEAR the groaning sound again. Bastaldi looks irritated. He gets up and walks over to a closet. He opens to the doors to reveal a man in his underwear, his wrists tied behind his back, his mouth taped shut. A wire noose is around his neck forcing him to stand on his tip toes to avoid hanging himself.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Now I've got something I want to --</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man looks at Bastaldi through pleading eyes and mumbles something.</context>
      <utterance>Do you mind? I'm trying to do some business here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bastaldi closes the door. Daniel looks at him inquisitively.</context>
      <utterance>One more sound out of you and I'm going to cut your fuckin' tongue out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take someone in. Give them a steady job and how do they repay you? By claiming to misplace a shipment of your merchandise.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he did misplace it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You misplace your car keys. You misplace your cell phone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bastaldi looks puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Laurant, how long has he been in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. What day is today?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bastaldi thinks about something for a moment, then...</context>
      <utterance>Is it Thursday already? This week has just shot by.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel is still staring at the closet.</context>
      <utterance>You and your crew speak English, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Daniel! Hello?  Do you guys speak English?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bastaldi tosses a photo of a middle-aged American couple. He points to a diamond necklace around the woman's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Good. I have a job for you in America.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Taylors from Chicago. Very rich. An acquaintance of mine recently quit working for Mrs. Taylor as an assistant. She tells me they keep all their jewelry in a safe in their bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems like a long way to go for a necklace.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, we don't know the city and--</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(More)</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bastaldi isn't asking you if you want to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you Marcel, for that... extremely redundant explanation.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Laurant, America?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The job is worth about two million euros. Pull this off and you and your crew could make some real money, Daniel. You leave tomorrow. They know they don't have a choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to need to find someone who knows the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know someone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long, awkward beat as Marcel just glares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Marcel! I thought you were somebody else. If I knew it was you I would have never run.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel opens the door to the bathroom and pushes Sami inside.</context>
      <utterance>You're probably here for the money I owe you.  I don't have it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel punches Sami in the stomach. He drops to his knees. A beat. The door to the bathroom opens and the LARGE MAN peers inside. He stares awkwardly at what he perceives as the beginning of a sexual act.</context>
      <utterance>You know this is how rumors get started.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel slams the door then grabs Sami by the ear and yanks him to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today's your lucky day, Sami.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I can see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're going with them.</context>
      <utterance>Normally I'd be breaking your fingers right now, but I'm going to give you a chance to make enough to pay me back and have some extra for yourself. We have a group going to Chicago to do a job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lived there. You know the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've still got a few legal problems back in the States. Marcel glares at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel stares at him with hard expression.</context>
      <utterance>But I'd be... I'd be happy to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Sami a piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>If you try to leave town I'll know. If you manage to leave town I'll find you... and the next time we meet in a bathroom I'll be cutting you up into little pieces.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be at this address at nine o'clock tomorrow morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami enters and walks over to Daniel and Julien.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mama. Yes, I have my vitamins. I have everything. Of course I'm coming back. I'm not leaving you. I'm only going to be gone a few days. I'll call you when I get there. Okay? I've got to go now.  Mama, I've got to go.  No, I'm not yelling.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Sami. Marcel sent me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it you do, Sami?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, a little of this, a little of that. I've boosted cars, stole radios, run a few scams. Right now I'm into pick-pocketing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. A master criminal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens. ZERO enters. No one knows his last name. He is 40's, blonde hair, leather jacket, black pants. Looks more like a rock-star than a criminal. His eyes are flat and there is an intensity about him that is unnerving. Zero casually nods to Daniel. Zero stares at Sami as Daniel leads him over.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I was told to come here by Marcel. You guys don't want me, I'll be more than happy to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Zero.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami laughs at his little joke. The others cringe. One look in Zero's eyes tells Sami what everyone else already knows: This is not someone to fuck with. Julien puts his arm around Sami and leads him away from the others.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm one and this is two, three, four and five.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me give you some advice. You don't want to piss him off because he'll kill you for the fun of it. What you want to do is keep your mouth shut and do what we tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, we are going to America?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In English. Sami doesn't speak French.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Algeria.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you don't speak French?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, not all Algerians speak French. It's a matter of what school you went too. Me I never really --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Zero isn't interested in your life story.  Who gets killed?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hopefully no one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami leans over to Raymond.</context>
      <utterance>No one? Then why is Zero here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He speaks about himself in the third person?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel free to correct him if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want you there in case there's trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if there is, then Zero can kill someone?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I would accompany you to the airport to say bon voyage... and tell you that Marcel will be going with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a considerable move up for you, Daniel. The temptation of having so much money might be too much for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't trust me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't trust anyone. You don't get to the top of this game by trusting people... and after all, you are a thief. It's in your nature to steal. I'm just protecting my investment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero doesn't like it. He pushes the button returning to the Renaud song and stares at Marcel. Marcel, not to be outdone returns the Hallyday song. Like two children they click the buttons of the radio, switching back and forth between Renaud and Hallyday. Bastaldi has had enough.</context>
      <utterance>That's better.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns off the radio. A long beat. Marcel, like a child who has to have the last word starts singing to himself quietly, but loud enough for Zero to hear.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it! Both of you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel sees Bastaldi glaring at him and stops.</context>
      <utterance>... que je t'aime... que je...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TAXI DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel looks at a piece of paper he is holding.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you guys have the right address? This ain't no tourist area.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The taxi speeds off, leaving them standing on the sidewalk, their bags in a pile. Suddenly, from out of nowhere three BLACK TOUGHS appear and walk over. Daniel looks behind him and sees another two approaching from the rear. Zero calmly sits down on one of the suitcases.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. We are sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LAMAR, 30's, the leader of the group steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Let me handle this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami raises his hand as if to greet Lamar.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, brother. What's happening, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami looks like an idiot with his hand up in the air. He casually lowers it. Lamar looks over the group and grins.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you brother me, motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in the bags?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lamar forces a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Dirty underwear.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond steps forward and places his hand on Lamar's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Dirty underwear. That's a good one. Let me explain something to you. This is my street and you're gonna give me want I what or I'm gonna bust your heads open.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lamar, violence is never an answer to settling disputes. I can see you have a lot of anger... but this is not the way to get it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lamar removes a knife. The others in his group bring out an assortment of clubs, chains and pipes.</context>
      <utterance>Get outta my face!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero is still sitting on one of the suitcases.</context>
      <utterance>Now, are you going to give me the suitcases? Or are we going to have to take them?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Va te faire foutre!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said to go fuck yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are tired and bored with your bullshit. So, put that stupid little knife away before Zero shoves it up your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is Zero?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julien shrugs his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>He speaks about himself in the third person?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Zero would like to get off his ass and take my knife from me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero stands up and raises his hand. He is holding a .9mm Glock. He aims it at Lamar's head. Lamar's brave exterior quickly fades now that he is looking down the barrel of the gun. The rest of his gang turns and runs away. Zero aims the gun at his groin.</context>
      <utterance>If you insist.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lamar runs away. Daniel and the others smile at Zero as they pick up their bags and walk towards a building.</context>
      <utterance>Leave now before Zero shoots off those little raisins you call balls.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You put a loaded gun in your bag and brought it through customs? How stupid is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero grins and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Zero did not put it in his bag. He put it in yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door is opened by SOPHIE (the girl in the photo on Bastaldi's computer). She is late 20's, beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>We are looking for Sophie. Laurant send us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouh La La.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't expecting this many of you. I've got a few sleeping bags you can use.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Of to the side, sitting on the couch is WAYNE, 20's, a burn-out with long hair and a scraggly goatee. His face is buried in a bong as he sucks in a lung full of marijuana. He watches a cartoon show on the television.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond walks over to him.</context>
      <utterance>This is Wayne. My roommate.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Raymond. Thank you for allowing us to stay here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem, man.  Hey, you wanna hit?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond looks at the television and sees a cartoon show.</context>
      <utterance>No thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Pepe Le Pew. He is very funny and quite well known in France.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I dig him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wayne stares at him with a dead pan expression as he tries to assemble a coherent thought.</context>
      <utterance>Although a cartoon I feel he shares a universal theme: We are all searching for love. No?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa... That's deep.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys hungry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julien looks up at her.</context>
      <utterance>Ready to order?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could we see a wine list please?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't have a wine list.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, then we will have the house wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure -- and would you like that before your escargot in white truffle sauce?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not order escargot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't serve wine here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of restaurant doesn't serve wine?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I will have a beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think he's grasping the concept. Iced tea, lemonade, coca cola, sprite or root beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'est quoi root beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll have a sprite. We'll all have sprite.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Now that we've gotten the beverage selection out of the way, dare we move on to the main course?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero grins as he puts a cigarette in his mouth. The waitress pulls it out of his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And no smoking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No smoking? No drinking? What kind of country is this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vinny gets off his knees and moves towards Zammito.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Frankie. Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vinny takes a step back.</context>
      <utterance>You bleed on me, I'll kill ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I tell you? Huh, Vinny? What'd I tell you when you came to me for money? Didn't I ask you not to do it? Did I not say that?  What'd I say to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said don't do it, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. I said don't do it. Did you listen to me? No. You wanted the money. So, I lent you twenty large. Now it's been three weeks and you ain't paid a dime. What do you think that makes me look like on the street? I don't do something to you and everyone will think they can skate.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankie, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vinny looks up at Zammito through pleading eyes.</context>
      <utterance>-- Shut up! Don't you try to make me feel bad about this. You knew what would happen to you if you didn't pay. This is on your head, not mine.  Break his arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Frankie, I'm your brother!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's an exterior alarm system. There's also another one in the hall that leads to the bedroom with a motion detector. The control panel is in the bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can handle the exterior alarm, but the one in the bedroom is a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After the outside alarm is off we go in through the bedroom window.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Zero and Julien will go in through the window and disable the motion detector. The rest of us will come in through the front door.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about transportation?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can use my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond, you'll steal one.</context>
      <utterance>Not a good idea. Someone gets a license number and it all leads back to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know they won't be home tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever hear of jet lag?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neighbors. They do this all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't even hear myself think.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are we supposed to sleep with this noise?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've asked them a hundred times to keep in down. They don't listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will talk to them. Sophie and Wayne both find his offer amusing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond leaves.</context>
      <utterance>It's just a matter of communication.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Biker takes a sip of his beer.</context>
      <utterance>Hello. My name is Raymond. I am visiting next door and I was wondering if you could make your music a little less loud.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Raymond can finish his sentence the Biker pours his beer over Raymond's head.</context>
      <utterance>But the music is very--</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams the door in Raymond's face.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck off!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you say to them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks up to Zammito and they kiss each other on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Bobby beans... How you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY BEANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I'm doing good. How you doin', Frankie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I'm good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY BEANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Maranzano sends his warmest regards.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you return please extend my regards to Mr. Maranzano and his family. Zammito motions for Bobby to sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coffee?</context>
      <utterance>Can I offer you something. A drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY BEANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can't find anything like it in the States.</context>
      <utterance>You sure? I just got a shipment of espresso from Sicily. Special blend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY BEANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm good. Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I understand you're interested in one of our properties?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY BEANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That warehouse over on Merchant Street. The volume on our import business has risen dramatically. The proceeds this quarter will be supernumerary due to the --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Super what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY BEANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Supernumerary. It means better than expected.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why not just fuckin' say better than expected? Everybody knows what better than expected means.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY BEANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking a vocabulary course to enhance my communication skills.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY BEANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not here to negotiate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY BEANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To tell you that we're interested in the property.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me that on the phone. What the hell are you doing here? Showing off your communication skills? Go back to your people and tell them when they're serious to put a number on the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY BEANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will relay the particulars of our conversation to Mr. Maranzano.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby Beans leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah -- you do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito looks over at Joey and Nicky.</context>
      <utterance>Jerk-wad!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's my brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY "THE RAKE"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's over at St. James. They had to put two pins in his arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said a clean break.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey boss, it's not a science.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky gets up to carry out his instructions.</context>
      <utterance>Send some flowers. Something nice. Roses or carnations. And one of those get well soon cards.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh and uh, send a case of steaks over to his house. I don't want the kids to go hungry while he's recuperating.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I like the bag. It would be good for the job tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami dumps the rest of the shoes out of the bag.</context>
      <utterance>It belongs to Vincent Bastaldi. He left it last time he was here. I'm sure he wouldn't mind if you used it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, how did you get hooked up with these guys?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just lucky I guess. How'd you start working for the Bastaldi's?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The art world doesn't fully appreciate my talent yet. I needed some way to pay the rent. Laurant and Vincent pay well for information.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you arranged to have the people you worked for robbed?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees a TATTOO on Sami's arm. It's a heart with someone's faded name.</context>
      <utterance>They're not nice people.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami is suddenly self-conscious of it. She traces along the letters with her finger.</context>
      <utterance>I like your tattoo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Casandra. Old girlfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she break your heart?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks old. Did you get it a long time ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ask a lot of questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's how you get to know someone. Did it hurt when you got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't remember. I was drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it in a bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I got it in prison. I went in for three years. When I came out she was married to my best friend. Happy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I didn't mean to pry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. It was a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking about getting tattoo. You know, a flower or something. On my ass. Sami looks at her quizzically.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's gonna see it there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles flirtatiously and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>The lucky ones.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man opens the cash register and hands him all the bills.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme the money!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open the safe!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raphael pistol whips him with his gun and drags him half way over the counter, then presses his gun to the old man's head.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have the combination.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raphael pushes him to the floor. He runs out of the store with the others.</context>
      <utterance>I swear! I don't have it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Vato, where's your car? Raphael stops as he sees the street is empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector has to grab Raphael who is too stunned to move and drag him down the street.</context>
      <utterance>My car!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They grab their gear and head for the door. Sophie leans over and kisses Sami on the cheek. He stares at her, half surprised, half embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>It's Raymond. He's outside with the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For luck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you didn't get something flashy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond pushes a button and the hydraulics make the car bounce up and down. Sami rolls his eyes as the others get into the car. ACROSS THE STREET -- Lamar is standing in the shadows with one of his friends, watching.</context>
      <utterance>Watch this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should call the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, idiot -- I've got stolen wheels and a stolen radio in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just thought that--</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other Gang Bangers laugh at Hector.</context>
      <utterance>-- Don't think. Okay? You're not good at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector slinks out of the room. Raphael's face hardens.</context>
      <utterance>Go do something -- get some beers for the guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I find out who did this I'm going to mount their head on my dashboard!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALF TOOTH TONY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. B. wants to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now? I've got a date with a drop dead major babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HALF TOOTH TONY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Zammito thinks it over.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell him that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks over to the MARIO, the OWNER of the restaurant.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'm coming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mario, I gotta go. When my date arrives tell her I had an emergency.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, Mr. Zammito.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we went the wrong way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The map said to go left.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankie, come in. Good to see you. You want something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bonanno motions to the couch. Zammito sits down.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm good, Angelo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand Bobby Beans came to see you today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Seems Maranzano wants to talk about buying the Merchant Street warehouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And nothing. He's just feeling us out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's trying to get a foot hold in our territory.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sticks his toes in the water again, we'll cut 'em off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Business must be good if he can afford to buy up useless property.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bonanno stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>I heard this quarter his profits are gonna be supernumerary.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna be what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Supernumerary. It means better than expected.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Half Tooth Tony, 30's, built like a tank step into the room. He has the face of a boxer, several of his teeth are chipped or broken.</context>
      <utterance>Good word.</utterance>
   <speaker>HALF TOOTH TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bonanno, I just wanted to remind you that you have an appointment in ten minutes. Half Tooth Tony leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone else coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You ever watch it?</context>
      <utterance>Nah, that's just Tony's way of telling me Judge Judy starts in ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, no --</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should. You can learn a lot about the criminal justice system on a program like that. Very informative. Stay and watch it with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I'm kind of tired. I'm just gonna go home if it's all the same to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bonanno takes a sip of his brandy, but his eyes stay on Zammito.</context>
      <utterance>Go. Rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Frankie, what's this I hear about your brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He missed three weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your own brother? You couldn't send someone else to do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. Joey "Two Tons" and Nicky "The Rake" did the deed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you were there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat. Bonanno thinks about what he said, not sure what to make of it, then...</context>
      <utterance>Angelo, we live and die by the rules we make. We are men of honor, but honor without respect is a... horse-less carriage.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck does that mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So much for no one being home. Julien goes to a bookcase and finds the safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes his tools and goes to work. Sami stares at Zammito with vague recognition, then turns to the others.</context>
      <utterance>At least they got this right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to be careful not to use our real names while we're in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be Elvis and you--</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I want to be Elvis.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, I look more like Elvis than you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel smiles happily.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. You can be Elvis.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel sees an autographed baseball on the book shelf.</context>
      <utterance>And the rest of us are... John, Paul, George and Ringo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel tosses the ball into the black canvas bag. Daniel stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Barry Bonds. The home run king.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's for my nephew.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like Zammito's being robbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I call C.P.D.?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel looks as surprised as they are.</context>
      <utterance>Where are the jewels? There aren't any jewels.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There has to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you I've pulled out everything in the safe. There aren't any jewels.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There must be half a million dollars here though.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami moves closer to Zammito, studying his face. He moves over to the dresser where there are several photographs of Zammito with various famous people. Next to the photographs is a plaque that reads: TO FRANCIS ZAMMITO... We can see the color drain from Sami's face. He glances over at Zammito whose eyes are locked on his. Sami grabs Daniel and Marcel and pulls them aside.</context>
      <utterance>Marcel, we came here for jewels, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a problem. Problem isn't the right word. Dilemma. No that really doesn't describe --  Do you know who that is?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Taylor?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's not Mr. Taylor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Frankie Zammito. The Under boss of the Chicago Mafia.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would they want us to rob the Mafia?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Zammito, there seems to have been a big mistake here. May I use your phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel free. Marcel picks up the cordless phone and dials.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Elvis...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcel?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're there now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're calling me on your cell phone, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're calling me on is phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My number's going to show up on his bill!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can hear Bastaldi sigh over the line.</context>
      <utterance>Should I call you back?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've already robbed the safe?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bastaldi hangs up. The line goes dead.</context>
      <utterance>Take what you've got and get out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walk out of here with nothing and I'll forget this ever happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Right. You're not a vendetta kind of guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll find you. No matter where you go I'll find you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't carry the same weight in France as you do here. Marcel whispers into Daniel's ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think it's smart to tell him we're French?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero who has been standing quietly by the window sees something across the street. A flash. Light reflecting off glass. He takes a pair of night vision binoculars out of one of the bags and looks out the window. ZERO'S POV -- of Agent Hadley and the other FBI Agent watching him.</context>
      <utterance>I think he's already figured that out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel grabs the binoculars and looks.</context>
      <utterance>We are being watched.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel closes the curtains. He tries to think. The crew huddles together in the corner, speaking softly so Zammito can't hear them.</context>
      <utterance>FBI. They've been there for months. Think I don't know. Morons.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was told to take what we have and go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel looks at the others.</context>
      <utterance>Go where? The police are outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel and Zero nod. Daniel looks to Julien who appears indecisive.</context>
      <utterance>If we do this we all have to agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Maybe if we did just leave --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julien nods. Sami walks over and grabs the black canvas bag.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, get real, will you. You think he's just going to forget about this? These guys are all about respect. All about honor. He's coming after us, so we might as well take the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all dead. Zero grins then tapes his mouth closed again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't expecting you guys back so fast. How'd it go? She quickly notices their angry expressions.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd it go? I don't know. Daniel, how would you say it went?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would have to say... pretty fuckin' bad. You gave us the wrong address Sophie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bastaldi got the address from you, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he gave it to us. 145 Ridgeway Road.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. 145 Ridgeroad Way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That moron.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ridgeroad... Ridgeway Road.</context>
      <utterance>It was an honest mistake. Ridgeway...</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone get some sleep. We're leaving in the morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are they doing in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Hadley thinks a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Chicago P.D. says they can't hold the units here any longer. They want to know if they should go in?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them no. We'll advise if anything changes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear Zammito's muffled cries for help. It almost sounds like someone moaning during a sexual act. Joey is surprised at first, then glances over at his wife to make sure she is asleep. He slides his hand under the covers and closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm.... Oh yeah... Uh huh</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is really deep into his fantasy world when...</context>
      <utterance>That's right baby, give it to papa Joey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS" WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey sits up quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Joey, who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again we hear the same muffled cries.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah boss?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boss?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone stole my car tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>FELIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Raphael, you don't think that I would steal your car?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raphael lifts up the hood and slams it down on Felix again.</context>
      <utterance>You run a chop shop for low riders. Yes, I think you'd steal my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear I didn't. I wouldn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I should just believe--</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- you stole my cousin Enrique's car.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hector, don't interrupt me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told Enrique he didn't know anything about his car.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hector is embarrassed as Raphael once again berates him in front of the others. Raphael picks up a pair of pliers of the workbench. He clamps them down on the tip of Felix's nose and squeezes. Felix's face fills with pain.</context>
      <utterance>I don't give a shit about your cousin's car. We're here about my car. So, shut your mouth! You think you can do that? You think you can keep your big mouth shut?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives the pliers one last squeeze, then releases Felix.</context>
      <utterance>If I find out you're lying. If I find out you know anything about this I'm going to come back and cut off your nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vamos.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FBI AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Hadley is about to answer when he sees something. HIS POV -- of a Lincoln Town Car pull up. Joey "Two Tons" gets out, goes to the front door and enters.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, do you think we could have a hostage situation in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on a second. Joey "Two Tons" just pulled up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were all French guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>French guys? You mean like from France?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, French guys from France.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd they take?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, you must be pissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, when five guys break into my house in the middle of the night, stick guns in my face, tie me up and steal from me... it does irritate me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I must say you're handling it very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know why I'm handling it very well? Because you're going to get these guys for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay boss. Where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I knew where they were you wouldn't have to find them, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't say find them. You said, "get them."</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just find them!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito stares at Joey for a long beat, then...</context>
      <utterance>Okay boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey looks away, embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Papa Joey?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry things went so wrong today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She notices the box of tapes.</context>
      <utterance>It's not your fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I'd listen to some of the tapes. See what's so important that a mob guy has to lock it away in his safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grins seductively, then leans in towards him.</context>
      <utterance>It's three in the morning. Not much else to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>I can think of something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not here, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes a moment for Sami to connect the thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>I think she went to do some laundry. Threw some stuff in a bag and left.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami runs to the table. The black canvas bag is gone. CLOSE ON DANIEL: Asleep. Sami shakes him. He opens his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Bag?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up. We've been ripped off!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A thought occurs to Sami.</context>
      <utterance>She took everything! Didn't even leave us cab fare.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes the tape he put in the cassette deck last night before Sophie entered.</context>
      <utterance>Not everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He realizes it may not be the time to tell them what happened.</context>
      <utterance>I was going to listen to it last night but I --</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wayne blurts out a sloppy laugh.</context>
      <utterance>-- feel asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you didn't, dude. You were bangin' Sophie. I saw you guys going at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You slept with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel stares at him angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Well, actually I would say she slept with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the big deal? It's not like I was on guard duty or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't think it was little suspicious that someone you only knew for a few hours wanted to sleep with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel grabs the cassette and puts it in the player. On the tape we hear a phone ringing.</context>
      <utterance>No. Chicks dig me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me. I need an answer from you if I'm going to move.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami is the first to realize what he is hearing.</context>
      <utterance>We're not just talkin' about a 'piece of work' here. We're talking about a boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami holds his hand signaling them to be quiet so he can hear the rest.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause on the line.</context>
      <utterance>Bonanno's a dinosaur. Guy thinks he's fuckin' Vito Corleone or something. The old ways are gone. If we don't change now we're going to get pushed out. I need to know if I can count on your support?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The line goes dead. Sami leans back.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No wonder Zammito didn't want us to walk out with this stuff. He's planning on killing Bonanno and taking over the family.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This wasn't the deal! The deal was to steal a necklace, not get in the middle of a Mafia war.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The deal is whatever Mr. Bastaldi says it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, if you could get your nose out of Bastaldi's ass for two seconds you might see what's going on around you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew this was a mistake! I knew it last night when you asked me to go along with this. I could hear that little voice in my head saying, "don't do it! Don't you do it!" Jesus, why don't I ever listen to myself?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but you did do it. So let's deal with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you guys so scared of? Zammito doesn't know who we are. We just get out of town and it's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you think it's that easy?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We just go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agree with Marcel. I say we go to the airport and get on a plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll be waiting for us at the airport.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You steal some money from a man he gets over it in time. But these tapes. He's never going to stop looking for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to find Sophie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are we going to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look over at him as he takes a huge hit off his joint.</context>
      <utterance>I know where she went.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard her talking on the phone. Bay View Motel. It's about five blocks from here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me the truth Hector... do you think we'll find my car?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard to say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we know what room she's in?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Did a woman just check in? She's about five six. Pretty. Dark hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTEL CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't give out information on our guests.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon man, I think she's having an affair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTEL CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami nods and walks outside. Through the window we see him talking with the others. A beat. Sami steps back inside with Zero.</context>
      <utterance>So are half the people in this place. I can't help you, pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTEL CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can finish the sentence Zero has his gun out and wedged under the clerks jaw.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I can't tell you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOTEL CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Room fourteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really thought we had something special going. I can't tell you what a disappointment you've turned out to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami feigns a smile. Zero checks the bathroom to make sure she is alone. He looks at Daniel and shake his head. Raymond finds the black canvas bag on the dresser and checks the contents.</context>
      <utterance>After last night I could say the same for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The money isn't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it, Sophie?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you think because you're a women this can't go hard on you, think again. She stares at them defiantly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you waiting for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stick around and find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero knowingly bends down and removes Hadley's backup gun which is strapped to his ankle. He gives the gun to Sami.</context>
      <utterance>He's FBI.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami looks at her -- at Hadley -- at the black canvas bag. Slowly it starts to come together in his mind.</context>
      <utterance>What is she doing with an agent du FBI?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at Sophie angrily.</context>
      <utterance>We've been set up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her expression gives away nothing.</context>
      <utterance>We didn't go to the wrong house. We went to right one, didn't we Sophie?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They send us to Zammito's house. The FBI is right across the street watching the whole thing, but they don't move. A crime is going down and they don't move. Why?  Because they were waiting for us to come out so they could arrest us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does arresting us get them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna tell him?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel motions to Zero.</context>
      <utterance>You're telling it fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero stares at Hadley, just waiting for Daniel to give him the go ahead.</context>
      <utterance>You see my friend over there? I nod to him and he's going to put a bullet in your knee.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They know he's right.</context>
      <utterance>That's going to make a lot of noise. Not much time for a conversation after you pull the trigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami lifts up a heavy brass lamp from the nightstand. He pulls the electrical cord out of the base, then touches two wires together. They spark. Before Hadley can say a word Sami touches them to his hand. Hadley's body jerks violent as he screams. Sami removes the wires. Hadley winces in pain from the burn mark on his hand.</context>
      <utterance>He's got a point.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay! Okay! We've been investigating Zammito for years, but we've never had enough evidence for a warrant to search his house. We got word through a snitch that Zammito was planning on taking Bonanno out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just don't take out a boss. You need permission from the other families to do something like that. Our informant told us that Zammito was talking with other bosses and recording their conversations in case they later claimed they weren't involved. Look at these tapes. The guy has recorded every conversation he's had for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Hadley nods.</context>
      <utterance>So we rob Zammito. You arrest us when we come out and the contents of the safe is now evidence which you can use against him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no point in hiding anything now.</context>
      <utterance>What are you getting out of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(More)</context>
      <utterance>Money. It was supposed to simple. In and out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mario, I gotta go. When my date arrives will you explain to her I had an emergency.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito leaves. Through the window we see Joey "Two Tons" open the door to the car. Zammito and Joey get in and drive away. A beat. A Taxi pulls up. The front door opens and Sophie enters, all dressed up and beautiful. She walks up to Mario.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, Mr. Zammito.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm meeting Frankie Zammito --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vincent Bastaldi is in jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laurant and Vincent were in business with Zammito.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of business?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Black market art. Zammito got to a few key security guards at the Metropolitan Museum. The Bastaldi's supplied the artists to make copies of famous works. They'd switch the paintings, send the originals to Paris and the Bastaldi's would sell them to private collectors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're talking Matisse, Renoir, Monet. We know for sure they replaced Van Gogh's "Vase with twelve sunflowers" last week with a copy. It was on loan from the London National Gallery and they're not going to be very happy when they find out about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Bastaldi makes a deal with the Feds to trade up for his brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. He delivers the goods on Zammito. If we got what we wanted we'd let his brother go providing he tells us where the Van Gogh and the other paintings are.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one has mentioned the part of the plan about us getting caught and going to prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're leaving. Raymond get the bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You walk out with that bag and you won't only have Zammito and his people after you. You'll have the entire United States justice department. How far do you think you'll get? I know who you are Mr. Foray? Mr. Zerhouni. Mr. Gayet.  Mr... Agent Hadley looks to Sophie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zero. That's all I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move to the door.</context>
      <utterance>You'll never get out of the city.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bastaldi's dead. He is fuckin' dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want Zero to kill him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to kill him myself!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the money?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has to be at Sophie's. She didn't have time to go anywhere else before she came here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't know that for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget the money! We've got bigger problems than the money right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She probably hid it at her place. The six of us could find it in --</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel dials a number on his cell phone.</context>
      <utterance>-- We don't have time to look for it. Hadley's first move is going to be to look for us there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're moving. Pack up and be on the street in five minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is turning to shit. If word gets out of my involvement in this I'll go to prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, we know their names. They don't know the city. You'll find them. You're the FBI.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't bring the Bureau into this. If I do the tapes become evidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're supposed to be evidence. That's why Bastaldi set this up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck Bastaldi and his brother. These tapes are gold. Do you have any idea what Zammito would pay to get them back?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you wanted Zammito?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She likes the idea. Already she's thinking how she can work her way into this.</context>
      <utterance>What for? The minute I get him some other Gavone will take his place. I've been doing this for twenty years. When I retire it's not going to be to some trailer park in the suburbs.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too many people know about my involvement in this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOPHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His jaw tightens.</context>
      <utterance>Then we just have to make sure everyone who knows can't say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley is standing behind her. He lifts up the brass lamp with his towel and swings down hard towards Sophie's head.</context>
      <utterance>You're right about that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would like to thank you for your hospitality.  If you are ever in Paris here is my number.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel grabs Raymond and leads him back to the car. Daniel sees Lamar standing across the street.</context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets out of the car and walks over to him.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want now?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guns. Can you get them?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, I can get anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bullshit me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't bullshittin'. I can get guns. I can get any kind of gun you want. But they ain't gonna help your sorry ass. You ain't been in town one day and already you got two of the toughest people in Chicago looking for you. How is that possible?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a way with people.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see that. The man's car you stole. Raphael Ruiz. He's head of the 19th Street gang and one crazy motherfucker. And Frankie Zammito's got the word out he's looking for some French dudes. You're French ain't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm from Belgium.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'd be from Belgium too if I was you. You know Zammito just put his own brother in the hospital? Broke his arm cause he was late on a debt. I mention this to illustrate the kind of people who are lookin' for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why haven't you turned us in?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel nods.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't no rat.  You got money, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, uh, I'm going to have to charge you a commission... kind of like a brokerage fee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A thousand dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel hands him his cell phone.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take this. I'll call you in a few hours. You tell me where we meet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley pushes past Wayne and enters.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey dude, what do you think you're doing? Hadley flashes his badge.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... excuse me, but don't you need a warrant or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not today. Where are your friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They left about a half hour ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did they go?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley punches Wayne in the face. Wayne falls to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey man, you can't do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Hadley kicks Wayne in the chest.</context>
      <utterance>What? This?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Hadley kicks Wayne in the ribs.</context>
      <utterance>Or this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. What kind of FBI agent are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm your worst fuckin' nightmare. Now, if you don't want me to keep on hurting you, it's important that I believe you and right now I don't. So tell me, where did they go?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley sees the phone number Raymond gave Wayne on the coffee table. He puts it in his pocket and stares at Wayne, then just for the hell of it gives him one last kick in the ribs.</context>
      <utterance>I swear man, I don't know. They packed up and left a half hour ago.  All I got is one of their phone numbers in Paris.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know Mama, but I couldn't call you yesterday we were very busy.  No, nothing's more important than you.  I don't know. I think I'm going to have to stay a few more days. Daniel, Sami and Julien sit at a table. Marcel stares out the window sadly. Zero is flipping through the television channels.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know about Bastaldi's deal with Zammito?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think if he told me he was going to steal Van Gogh's "Sunflowers in a vase" I would remember it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Vase with twelve Sunflowers."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond hangs up the phone and joins the others.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever! He never told me about the Van Gogh or any of the other paintings.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It makes sense. I mean, do you really think he would come along if he knew we were being set up?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he'd cut his dick off if Bastaldi told him to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you! You know I'd never go along with something like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This ain't about that and you know it. This is about you never forgiving me for leaving the crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys used to work together?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah and he can't stand it that I tried to do something to better myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call being Bastaldi's lap dog better?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better than spending my life crawling through windows in the middle of the night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, knock it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All you are is a professional ass-kisser.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a guy who is known for his patience and right now you're testing mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said knock it off! Now as far as I'm concerned you two girls can bitch slap yourselves silly when this is over, but right now we've got to figure out what's going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's simple. Bastaldi's moving up. He's closing down his operation and this is his way of saying thanks to all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero turns to another channel. A news broadcast. We see a mug shot photo of SAMI on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I say the whole deal is off. In fact, if you ask me, there never was a deal because we were screwed from the start.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero turns up the volume.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Sami, you're on TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Sami Zerhouni in connection with the murder of Sophie Nichols. Sami is stunned.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Police have confirmed that Zerhouni was seen entering the woman's room by the Motel Manager.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON TELEVISION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Reporter continues her story.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pull back. We are now in...</context>
      <utterance>Zerhouni is also wanted by police for questioning regarding a robbery last night at the home of alleged Mafia member Frankie Zammito.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON TELEVISION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Reporter continues.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other members of his gang are reported to be French nationals Daniel Foray, Marcel Burot, Julien Labesse... Pull back again...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON TELEVISION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The reporter finishes her story.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pull back again...</context>
      <utterance>... Raymond Gayet and an unidentified man only known as Zero.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hadley --</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is bad. This is really fuckin' bad. Am I the only one who sees how bad this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's not your picture on the TV, it's mine. So, try to be cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me to be cool! We were supposed to be in and out. In and out! In the last twenty four hours we've managed to get the Mafia... the FBI... the Chicago Police Department and a group of Latin gang members after us. I haven't left out anyone, have I?  I don't think so, because we've already pissed off everyone in the fuckin' city!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami gets into Julien's face.</context>
      <utterance>That's brilliant! Care to elaborate?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not helping.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julien, what you're doing right now is a very normal psychological reaction to stress. You're projecting your anger onto us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus. We're dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey you guys are becoming famous. I was just watching the news and--</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Did you set it up?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. All set. Tomorrow morning. Ten o'clock. Room 211. Barclay Hotel on River Street. Oh, and due to your recent notoriety and the heat that comes with it, I'm going to have to increase my brokerage fee to twenty five hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a deal before you and your friends became the new poster boys for crime.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The line goes dead. Lamar grins, happy with the money he's going to make.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Ten o'clock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sami, tomorrow you lift a wallet from someone who looks like one of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to rent a car and for that you need a credit card.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not just steal another one?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too risky. We don't need to get pulled over because of a stolen car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'm missing the obvious, but why aren't we leaving town? Any place has to be safer for us than Chicago.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter where we go. Between Zammito and the FBI they'll find us. We have to end this here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how do we do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an excellent plan. Very comforting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll think of something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bonanno places his hands on Zammito's cheeks and presses them together.</context>
      <utterance>You have enough to worry about, Angelo. You don't need my problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bonanno releases him.</context>
      <utterance>We're family. An insult to you is an insult to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They knew who you were when they broke in your house?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What did they take?</context>
      <utterance>What is happening with the world? There was a time no civilian would touch a made man. Now every babbo in the world thinks he can get away with something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some cash. Jewelry. The other stuff I can replace, but there's a cardboard box... photos of my mother. They're the only ones I have of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're doing everything we can to find these people. Right Tony?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALF TOOTH TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've reached out to everyone we know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they're still stupid enough to be in this city, Tony will find them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito walks over.</context>
      <utterance>Frankie, come here a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY "THE RAKE"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is closer to the wall, Joey or me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY "THE RAKE"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito grabs him by the neck and smashes his face into the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Just tell me who's closer to the wall?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both men walk to the car. Zammito starts after them, then stops. He turns back, picks up the coins and puts them in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>You are! Now get in the fuckin' car!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BLACK GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna have to search you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel pulls back his jacket to reveal the gun he took from Hadley in his waistband.</context>
      <utterance>We'll save you the trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel looks past him to Ellwood.</context>
      <utterance>You can't come in here with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel removes an envelope full of cash.</context>
      <utterance>He's my cousin. He's deaf.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellwood stomps his foot several times on the floor. The black guy feels the vibration and turns around.</context>
      <utterance>We're here to buy, not steal. If you guys are straight there's not going to be a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let them in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELLWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel looks over the merchandise.</context>
      <utterance>What can I do you for?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much for the nines?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A grand a piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel starts counting out the money. Ellwood points a .357 magnum he's been holding behind the open suitcase at them.</context>
      <utterance>I'll need extra clips and ammo.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell you doing, Ellwood? I gave them my word.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel slowly grabs his gun and places it on the floor, then kicks it under the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Zammito's offering twenty grand a head for these guys. You think I'm going to settle for four G's when I can make forty?  All right. Reach in easy and put the gun on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellwood speaks to his cousin, speaking slowly and enunciating each word so he can read his lips.</context>
      <utterance>I said put it on the floor, not kick it under the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The black guy get on his hands and knees and starts looking for the gun under the bed. As he does Daniel glances over at Zero with a look. Ellwood aims his gun at Zero.</context>
      <utterance>Get that and add it to my inventory.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero opens his coat and reveals his .9mm.</context>
      <utterance>I assume you're carrying too?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELLWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, put it on the floor... and do not kick it under the fuckin' bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at Ellwood calmly through dead, flat eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? Did you just say no? Listen cowboy, if you're thinking about makin' a move, don't. Nobody is that fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zero is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Zero?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellwood is confused. Daniel bolts to his left. Ellwood's eyes leave Lamar for a moment -- it's a moment too long. In a blur of movement Zero has his gun out and fires one shot into Ellwood's forehead. Ellwood slumps down on the bed, dead. The black guy who has heard nothing continues searching under the bed. Zero casually picks up the suitcase filled with guns and hands it to Daniel. They walk out of the room. Lamar stands there, stunned, then quickly runs after them. A beat. The black guy pops up with Daniel's gun oblivious to what has transpired in the room.</context>
      <utterance>He is.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Found it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's ten grand in here. It's yours. I'm going to call you again. There's one more thing I need you to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the background we hear the loud, agonizing scream from the black guy as he finds Ellwood's body.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you when it's time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not comfortable with this. I'm not a good liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They arrive at the counter. The RENTAL AGENT, a man in his 30's looks up at them with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Relax. It will be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAR RENTAL AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond smiles, a big, friendly, completely over exaggerated smile. Julien looks at him and rolls his eyes. The Rental Agent walks down to the end of the counter and dials a number on the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Hello. I am Robert M. Carney from Dayton, Ohio and I would like to rent a car with my visa gold card.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAR RENTAL AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a couple French guys here trying to rent a car.  Sure. I can stall them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him. Vinny stares blankly at his brother. Zammito takes a step back, looks her up and down. He lays on the charm.</context>
      <utterance>Angie, how you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you're looking good. There's something different about you. You get a boob job or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've gained weight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, it suits you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Richie. He's Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito pulls out a roll of bills that could choke a horse and peels one off.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie looks at the money.</context>
      <utterance>Angie, take the kids down to the gift shop and buy 'em something. I need a word with Vinny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the kids and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Gee, five bucks. What ever shall we buy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She seems pleasant enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She doesn't know. She thinks I fell down the stairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito sits on the edge of the bed.</context>
      <utterance>That's good. That's what a stand-up guy does.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, I just come by to see how you're doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You broke my arm. How the hell do you think I'm doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I mean besides that. They treating you all right? Food okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm going home today. What do you want, Frankie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(More)</context>
      <utterance>I don't want anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I mean, you are my brother and... well I should have found another way of expressing my disappointment. So, I've decided to make it up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna forget about the money I owe you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito's cell phone rings.</context>
      <utterance>What are you nuts? A debt is a debt. I was thinking I'd throw a little extra work your way. You know, you come down to the club, make espresso for the boys... wash their cars... run some errands... things like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?  I'm on my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito leaves. Vinny can only shake his head in bewilderment.</context>
      <utterance>I got something I gotta do. I'm glad we had this talk. Heal. Get better. Let me know when you're ready to start.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GANG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't seen it your car. Sorry man. Hey, you know who you should talk to is Freddy O.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought he was in prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(More)</context>
      <utterance>Got out last month. He's trying to go straight but he's still wired in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Hadley.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know who this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I figured I'd be hearing from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you ever want to get those tapes, meet me in one hour at Grant Park near the statue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAR RENTAL AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about the wait. There was a problem with the equipment.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Rental Agent's eyes drift to a black Lincoln Town Car parked across the street.</context>
      <utterance>Everything okay now?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAR RENTAL AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond nods and gets in the passenger seat.</context>
      <utterance>I've never driven a Cadillac before.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a car. I think this is the best American car I've ever driven.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the only American car you've ever driven.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley pushes him up against the statue and starts frisking him.</context>
      <utterance>You set me up, you piece of shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm going to talk to you until I know if you're wired.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wired? I ain't wired.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay. I believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You killed her!</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You killed her. Manager remembers you going into her room. Your fingerprints were found all over the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit! She was alive when we left her with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're fucked, Sami. You know it. That's why you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I just want out of this nightmare. I don't know these guys. A few days ago I'm in Paris picking pockets and now I'm America's most wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the tapes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can get them -- but what do I get if I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A witness can put me at the crime scene.</context>
      <utterance>A pass? How you gonna give me a pass?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Witness' can be convinced they made a mistake. Without the murder weapon the D.A. won't have enough to prosecute you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't have a murder weapon?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I have it. The lamp? The one with your fingerprints and her blood on it?  Remember?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami stares at him a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>Of course they could always get an anonymous tip. Find it in the dumpster behind the motel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want the tapes for yourself. You're going to sell them.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to retire with a shit-load of money. Find me a small country that doesn't have an extradition treaty with the States and live the good life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't have to kill Sophie.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I did. Lose ends are messy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me? Aren't I a loose end?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're just a two-bit crook.</context>
      <utterance>When this is over you can say whatever the hell you want. I'll be long gone. Besides, who's going to believe you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're a dirty cop. At least I don't pretend to be something different than what I am. Hadley hands him a card.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew I should have driven.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop talking. I'm trying to concentrate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we get to the next corner jump out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to leave you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond knows he's right. The car races into the next turn.</context>
      <utterance>We both know I'm already dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps out.</context>
      <utterance>Go! Raymond opens the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not your fault, Daniel.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at them sadly.</context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a chance to walk out of Zammito's house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all agreed to it. You had no way of knowing Bastaldi was setting us up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to live long enough to get back to Paris. Just long enough to kill Bastaldi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say we make him pay first. After that you can do whatever you want to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right. Do you have any idea what Van Gogh's "Vase with twelve Sunflowers" is worth?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It's gotta be millions.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We still have to get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe if we gave the tapes back --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks to Zero.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They killed our friend. It's personal now. Besides, if we do that, then Julien died for nothing. The tapes are the key.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right. The tapes give us leverage with Bastaldi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you guys find?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIFORMED COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead bodies. The ones in the Lincoln are your... associates.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the other car?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIFORMED COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some French guy. At least that's what his passport said. You know Joey, I shouldn't be talking to you about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you forgetting who supplements your income?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIFORMED COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's just that the French guy had a gunshot wound on his neck. So, this is a homicide. Are you guys involved in this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'll come down and make a full confession later. Right now, tell me what else you found?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIFORMED COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This sparks Joey's interest.</context>
      <utterance>A Wallet. A hotel room card. Some cash.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What hotel?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIFORMED COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Holiday Hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What room number?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIFORMED COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I didn't look.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Airports, train stations, bus station are out. We know they're connected to the car rental agencies because that's where they picked up Raymond.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if we get out of town and go to another airport I'm sure the FBI and Chicago P.D. has alerted customs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about Canada?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami opens a pack of cigarettes to find it's empty.</context>
      <utterance>What are we going to do, take a taxi?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to get some cigarettes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FREDDY O</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe someone would have the balls to rip off your ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I find them they won't have them for much longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY O</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll ask around. If they try to move it I can find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raphael and Hector exit. We move with them through the door into...</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks over to the HOTEL MANAGER and points to Agent Hadley. The Manager walks over.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to see the manager please.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOTEL MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Hadley shows him his badge.</context>
      <utterance>May I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for several French men who checked in within the last twenty four hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOTEL MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They checked in last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Hadley follows the manager as they walks towards the elevators and pass... Sami who pretends to read a magazine, covering his face so Hadley will not see him. Sami walks quickly across the lobby and passes... Joey "Two Tons", Nicky "The Rake" and three other WISEGUYS enter the hotel. Agent Hadley gets in an elevator with the Hotel Manager. The doors close as the wiseguys approach. The moment the doors close Sami bolts into the lobby and over to the house phones. All of them are being used except one. A MAN is just about to lift the receiver when Sami pushes him aside.</context>
      <utterance>I need you to take me to their room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami ignores him as he waits for the hotel operator to answer. The phone just rings and rings. Behind him another elevator has arrived and the wiseguys enter. Sami's frustration is growing as the phone continues to ring. The Man who Sami pushed away is still there.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. I was here first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey buddy, you just can't push in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami quickly smacks him on the head with the receiver. The man slinks away.</context>
      <utterance>I most certainly will not go--</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Operator.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get that, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I always have to answer the phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you're the closest.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not any closer than you are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is everything an argument with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel looks at Raymond and sighs, then gets up and lifts he receiver.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just setting my boundaries.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Daniel slams down the phone. The others can see the urgency on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of the room! You've got company coming up. I'll meet you at the Chevy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raymond, grab the tapes. We're leaving!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I have to pick up the tapes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel grabs the canvas bag.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raphael lowers his head sadly. Hector looks out the window. HIS POV -- of the Impala driving by -- rear window missing, bumper about to fall off. Hector watches it go by, then turns back. Raphael looks up.</context>
      <utterance>I can't eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, can I have your fries?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring me the scissors.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami removes the items from the bag. He opens the bottle and hands it to Zero who quickly gulps down a few mouthfuls.</context>
      <utterance>And the Vodka.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut his pants up the leg to the groin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He winks at Sami.</context>
      <utterance>And be careful when you get near the top. Zero has a very long one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he joking around for? He's been shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond cuts the pant leg away. Daniel walks over to Marcel who is standing over the gas range. Over the flame is a tire wrench, the metal tip glowing red hot. Sami opens the bag and removes some white bread.</context>
      <utterance>He's been shot a lot. He's used to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you get?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some bread and...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the French guys look at him as though he is from another planet.</context>
      <utterance>Cheese.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami stuffs his mouth with a big bite.</context>
      <utterance>Cheese? In a can?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, I want to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you know you can't this in France.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel uses a towel to pick up the tire wrench and walks over to the bed. Sami and Raymond grimace as they think about what's about to happen.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zero nods. Daniel takes the bottle of Vodka and pours some over the wound. Zero flinches. Daniel looks at Marcel, then releases the belt. Blood flows from the wound. Marcel presses the hot poker against the wound. Zero grunts, but does not scream. His face contorts violently from the pain.</context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY "THE RAKE"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They sort of got away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. Well, get back out on the street and find them before I "sort of" kill you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we ain't had nothing to eat all day boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito scoops up a handful of pasta out of his plate and throws it at him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey "Two Tons" looks down sheepishly, several pieces of pasta are stuck to his face. Zammito walks over to him.</context>
      <utterance>Had enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn around and leave. Zammito stares after them angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Try to get this through that fat, stupid fuckin' head of yours. If Half Tooth Tony finds these guys before we do and Bonanno knows what was in my safe we are all dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over at Eddie who is only half way to the table.</context>
      <utterance>Cafones!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna bring that over here today, or what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The new Beaujolais' come out in France next week. You like wine?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm more of a whiskey drinker myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glenmorangie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami realizes that Raymond wants to talk about something... anything... that will get his mind of the events that have lead them here.</context>
      <utterance>Glenmorangie is very good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond forces a weak smile. Daniel who has been watching them grabs a few things off the table.</context>
      <utterance>But I'll have a glass of Beaujolais with you when we get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel looks at Sami and motions for him to come outside.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be back in an hour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I trust you, Sami?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, who warned you that they were coming up to the room?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they had taken us by surprise they would have gotten the tapes back. That would have left us with nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that would have left me with nothing because all of you would be dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't answered my question.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it really matter what I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving you with my friends. I'm trusting you to do the right thing today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would like to see Mr. Bonanno please.</utterance>
   <speaker>HALF TOOTH TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him I'm the guy who robbed Frankie Zammito.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either you are incredibly brave, or incredibly stupid. Which one is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess we're going to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You rob an associate of mine... a friend and--</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bonanno looks to Half Tooth Tony.</context>
      <utterance>Not such a good friend. May I reach in my pocket?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALF TOOTH TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bonanno nods. Daniel removes the cassette player and turns it on.</context>
      <utterance>He's clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. I need an answer from you if I'm going to move.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not just talkin' about a 'piece of work' here Frankie. We're talking about a boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(More)</context>
      <utterance>Bonanno's a dinosaur.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to tell you, Mr. Bonanno, This guy's an idiot. How he's lived this long is a mystery.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think it will be a mystery much longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's recorded every conversation he's had with you for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I assume you want something?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got a lot of people looking for us. We'd just like to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel nods.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to help you get out of the country?</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And for my help I would get what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half the tapes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the other half?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll destroy them when we get back to Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only have your word for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to get my people home. I know who you are and what you could do to me if I don't honor my word.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you staying?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only ask so I can call you when the arrangements are made.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about if I call you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck was all that about at the hotel last night? I thought we had a deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami holds up the canvas bag.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you're not exactly the most trustworthy guy in the world. I took a shot. It didn't work. Did you bring the tapes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley opens the cardboard box to reveal the bloody lamp base. Sami hands him the canvas bag.</context>
      <utterance>The lamp?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley removes a small cassette player from his jacket. He picks a tape and inserts it into the player.</context>
      <utterance>Just a second. You must think I'm a real moron.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just came by to tell that "piece of work" you asked for on Johnny Wicks -- It's done.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. How'd he go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley stops the tape. He inserts another one.</context>
      <utterance>Like the crying rat bastard that he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angelo, we can't lean too hard on this guy. He's a congressman.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley grins. This is great stuff. He looks up at Sami.</context>
      <utterance>I made Peter Dimiano a congressman. We pay him each month to look after our interests.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami grabs the box and leaves. Hadley starts whistling a tune and walks off the other way. As he reaches the tree line Lamar pops out with two of his friends. All of them have guns.</context>
      <utterance>Here you go, sport.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take the bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of Lamar's guys searches through Hadley's pockets, finds his gun, then takes his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>You don't think I see through this? You tell Sami he's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley stares at Lamar defiantly. Lamar cocks the hammer back on his gun and presses the barrel to Hadley's forehead. Hadley drops the canvas bag. Lamar picks up the canvas bag and runs away. Hadley stands there fuming. Lamar runs towards the statue and disappears behind it.</context>
      <utterance>You're making a big mistake. I'm an FBI agent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I told you that you could trust me. Daniel grins and pats him on the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, we're square now, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lamar is about to protest when Daniel takes out a roll of bills.</context>
      <utterance>There's just one more thing I need you to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm listening.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the television screen we see Hadley and Sami in the park on their first meeting.</context>
      <utterance>Since we're such good pals I thought I'd sneak you an advanced copy of my latest work. I call it, "I am a scum-sucking FBI agent".</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want the tapes for yourself. You're going to sell them.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to retire with a shit-load of money. Find me a small country that doesn't have an extradition treaty with the States and live the good life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't have to kill Sophie.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The color drains from Hadley's face. Sami reappears, talking into the camera again.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I did. Lose ends are messy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tape turns to static. Hadley tries to think. He takes the VHS tape from the machine, then picks up his phone and starts to dial a number. A beat. He thinks better of it, hangs up and uses his cell phone.</context>
      <utterance>It's a little arty I know, but it has great content, don't you think? You were so busy looking for a wire you probably didn't even think about a video camera. It was on the statue. Anyway, I've sent a copy of the whole tape to the Chicago P.D. and the FBI. They'll get it tomorrow. If I were you I'd take the day off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Zammito?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I represent a person who wishes to remain anonymous, but is aware of your current financial problems with your brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. The person who sent me wishes to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vinny looks on the street and sees the Impala.</context>
      <utterance>You see that car?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's yours. A gift. A gift you could give to your brother... or anyone you owe money to as partial payment.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The papers for the car will arrive tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley starts to place the canvas bag on the hood of Zammito's car.</context>
      <utterance>Those the tapes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley opens the bag. It is filled with cassette tapes.</context>
      <utterance>Watch the paint.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito nods to Joey "Two Tons" who opens another briefcase filled with cash.</context>
      <utterance>The money?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you get these?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT HADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley starts to go. Zammito motions him to stop.</context>
      <utterance>I got 'em. That's all you need to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zammito picks a tape and tosses it to Joey "Two Tons." Who puts the cassette into the cars cassette player. Suddenly we hear Wayne Newton singing "Danke Schoen."</context>
      <utterance>Just a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE NEWTON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hadley's face turns white. He produces an audible gulp as he looks at Zammito weakly.</context>
      <utterance>Danke Schoen, darling Danke Schoen. Thank you for all the joy and pain...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you believe that guy? What a moron.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY "TWO TONS"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good song though.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great fuckin' song.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From there you can fly back to Paris.</context>
      <utterance>This plane will take you to Canada.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel hands him the cassette case with half the tapes. Bonanno hands it to Half Tooth Tony who takes them into the car and listens to a tape.</context>
      <utterance>You have something for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HALF TOOTH TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're good, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONANNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the other half of the tapes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have my word. I'll destroy them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A car.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really? Thanks. I thought it was a sewing machine. What the hell is it doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For me? What am I going to do with a piece of shit like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Sell it. It's gotta be worth something. Someone gave it to me. C'mon Frankie, I'm trying to make good here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vinny starts to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get you the papers tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, if you're well enough to be walking around you're well enough to start working here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lost?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm about to make you a very happy man.</context>
      <utterance>Don't come off like a hard-on with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody know about that car outside?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you that's my car! And someone's gonna pay for it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm tellin' you it ain't! Now, turn your taco-eating ass around and get the hell out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAPHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, grease-ball!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAMMITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are right on the edge of having a major disaster. The Dean Martin song ends. Dead quiet. Each group watches the other to see who's going to make the first move. The jukebox selects another record. The needle scratches against the vinyl intro. We hear the intro to JERRY VALE singing "Amore Scusami".</context>
      <utterance>Fuck me? Fuck you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JERRY VALE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raphael goes for his gun. All hell breaks loose! People dive for cover as shots rings out. In the close quarters it's like shooting fish in a barrel.</context>
      <utterance>My love, forgive me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY VALE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie lifts a shotgun from behind the bar and blows away a gang member. Another gang member kills him. It's a massacre! Bodies drop like flies. The room is so thick with smoke you can't see two feet in front of you. Finally it is quiet.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to have it end like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY VALE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We move through the room, past the carnage. Smoke swirls, blood covers the floor. Raphael is dead. Along with Joey "Two Tons" and Nicky "The Rake" On the floor, Zammito is against the bar. He sits up, amazed that he is untouched. He gets to his feet and makes his way to the front door.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to have you fall in love, in love with me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JERRY VALE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZAMMITO'S POV -- A Lincoln Town car speeding towards him. Through the windshield he can see the smiling face of Half Tooth Tony. The front of the car slams into Zammito, lifting him into the air. He flips head over heals then smashes into the windshield and over the car. He lays in the middle of the street, dead. The Lincoln speeds off down the street.</context>
      <utterance>My love, please kiss me... Zammito turns around to see</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY VALE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arrivederci amore kiss me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's looking around for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, Bastaldi turns around and goes back into his apartment.</context>
      <utterance>Zero can't stay like this much longer. His leg is hurting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Daniel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daniel. Listen I'm afraid there has been a big--</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I've got the tapes. If you ever want to see your brother out of jail do exactly what I say. Bring one million euros to your boat at six o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A million! I don't have that kind of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bullshit me, Laurant! I know about the Van Gogh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTALDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have it. That's why Vincent went to Chicago. They arrested him before he could bring it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The line goes dead.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you better get the money somehow. Six o'clock and come alone. If you don't we'll destroy the tapes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you have to use that much explosive?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond opens the suitcase and looks inside. As he peels through the stacks of money we see that only the top bill of each stack is real -- underneath them all is white paper, cut to the same size as the bills. Everyone turns to Marcel.</context>
      <utterance>I promised Bonanno I'd destroy the tapes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't check it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one answers him. Sami reaches inside the black canvas bag and removes the autographed baseball Marcel took from Zammito.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry! I was caught up in the excitement of the moment. I should have checked. I made a mistake. I suppose that none of you have ever made a mistake before?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is great. After everything we've been through we've got eight hundred euros and an autographed baseball.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The baseball is mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sami throws the baseball back in the canvas bag.</context>
      <utterance>No! You can't have the baseball! You're not entitled to the fuckin' baseball!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the one who took it. It's my baseball!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZERO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you say baseball one more time Zero will shoot you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raymond, don't you think they're over reacting a little?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I think they have a right to express their anger with you in light of the fact that you're...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. All of you want to be angry? Be angry... but I'm the one who took the ball and that makes it mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it to me, Sami.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel tries to take the ball out of the bag. Sami pulls it away. Marcel grabs the bag. Both of them tug on it. Marcel pulls hard and the bag rips down the seam. The baseball falls out and rolls off the bridge into the river.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel stands there holding the inside liner of the bag. Sami throws the canvas bag to the ground in frustration. Something catches Daniel's attention. DANIEL'S POV -- of the black canvas. The lining has been ripped away. A light breeze blows lifting the underside of the black canvas. There is a flash of color. Another gust of wind turns the black canvas over. On the other side is Van Gogh's "Vase with twelve sunflowers". Daniel's jaw drops. The others notice his stunned expression and follow his stare. THEIR POV -- of the priceless painting. They stand there, too shocked to move at first, then rush forward. They have almost reached the painting when a truck passes them. The wind kicks up the painting, blowing it over the railing. They reach out to grab it, but it is too far away. They stand there, watching as it slowly floats down to the river below.</context>
      <utterance>Perfect.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
