<movie id="149" title="Cruel Intentions">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. We've been at this for six months.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you haven't made an ounce of progress.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian takes out a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to say? That I'm supposed to feel remorse because I act the way I do? The truth is I don't. Dr. Greenbaum shakes her head and takes notes. SEBASTIAN  Look, I'm not like all the other kids in high school. I don't care about book reports and extra-credit. Teachers are idiots anyway. The only challenge out there for me is women. You see a girl you like. You pursue them. You conquer. You move on. It's exciting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you said you have the worst reputation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to change that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you something, doctor. Chicks love a guy with a bad rap. They say they don't, but they don't mean it. They all think that they're the ones that are going to "save me." The trick is to let them think it's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that's all the time we have for today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same time next week?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. This is going to be our last session.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Killer.</context>
      <utterance>Why? I like spending time with you. You know, you're quite attractive for a woman your age. You have killer legs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't a joke. Your parents spend a lot of money to send you here. I'm trying to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be insecure, Doc. You're a big help. Sebastian picks up a book of Freud. SEBASTIAN  He was a coke addict, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you can come in here with that cute little smirk on your face and try and flirt with me. It doesn't work, Sebastian.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It works a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No it doesn't. I see right through you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope for your sake you grow out of this immature phase. It's going to get you into trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian approaches a photo on her desk and picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you don't have to get nasty about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daughter, Rachel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yummy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't even think about it. Rachel is an exceptionally well rounded young woman, who happens to be attending Princeton this fall. She's way too smart to fall for your line of b.s.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Care to make a wager on that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Sebastian.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, nervous I'm going to win?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian puts on his glasses and leaves. DR. GREENBAUM (cont'd) Asshole. The doctor stews for a moment, then reaches into her desk, sifts through some papers where she finds a pack of Benson &amp; Hedges and lights one up. She looks at the photo of her daughter, then hits the speaker phone and dials. DR. GREENBAUM (cont'd) Rachel, it's mom.</context>
      <utterance>Would you please leave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel cries for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, is something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told me he loved me and I believed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues to cry.</context>
      <utterance>You don't know him. I'm so stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright honey, just calm down, take a deep breath, and step out of the circle.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you cut the psycho babble bullshit, mom. There's pictures of me on the internet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of pictures?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nudie pictures, what do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREENBAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, how can you be so stupid?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. He was just so charming. All he did was talk about how I had killer legs and how we wanted to photograph them. Things just got out of hand from there.  Mom? Are you there? Mom?  Mother!!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile is going to be attending Oakwood with you this fall. You've always been an inspiration to Beau and I on raising her. We just hope she can rise to the high standards which you've set for her.</context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you how happy we are that</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sook-Hee pours a dish of soy sauce in front of Kathryn. KATHRYN (cont'd) (to Sook-Hee, in Vietnamese) Thank you, Sook-Hee. That will be all. Sook-Hee leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do my best.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thanking her. Vietnamese is such a beautiful language. MRS. CALDWELL  Kathryn is a straight A student at Oakwood as well as being President of the French Club. Listen to whatever she has to say and you'll go far.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're too kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do it? I mean with all peer pressuring that goes on in high school. Where do you get your strength?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know this sounds corny, but whenever I feel temptations of peer pressure,</utterance>
   <speaker>I...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>turn to God and he helps me through the problem. Call me an anachronism, but it works.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are the boys like?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile, is that the best you can do?  You must forgive her, Kathryn. She's never been in a co-educational atmosphere before.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, it's totally understandable. Most of the boys that matriculate at Oakwood are very upstanding gentleman, however there are the occasional bad apples.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like your step-brother Sebastian. I can't believe they didn't expel him after what he did to the school nurse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mrs. Caldwell turns to see Sebastian standing in the doorway. He walks over and takes a seat. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Nice to see you again, Mrs. Caldwell.</context>
      <utterance>I hear she's recovering quite well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember my daughter, Cecile.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My, what an adorable shirt you're wearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father just took me on a trip to Australia.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are things down under? Blossoming I hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile's attending Oakwood in the fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What year are you in?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm what you would call a fifth year senior.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I thought high school is only four years.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is, unless you're a fuck up, like myself. He winks at Cecile.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn stands and approaches Cecile.</context>
      <utterance>I think we'll be going now.  Thanks for all your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call you later and we'll get together and plan your curriculum.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.  Nice meeting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ciao.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile follows Mrs. Caldwell out the door. Kathryn closes the door behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, Cecile. Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you care to tell me what Mrs. White-trash and her stupid daughter are doing in my house?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn sits on the sofa next to Sebastian. She unscrews her crucifix. The top part becomes a small spoon and the bottom part a small vial of coke. KATHRYN (cont'd) The parental units called while you were out.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just taking the poor girl under my wing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lovely. How is your gold digging whore of a mother enjoying Bali? Zipping through my inheritance per usual?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn uses her crucifix as a coke-spoon and snorts a bump. KATHRYN (cont'd) What's wrong with you today? Therapy not going well?</context>
      <utterance>Hopefully, though she suspects that your decrepit alcoholic father is diddling the maid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaps off the sofa and starts to pace. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) I'm sick of sleeping with these insipid Manhattan Debutantes. He walks over to the wall where nude Botticelli hangs. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Nothing shocks them anymore. He scratches the nude's pubic area. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) I'm beginning to feel like I'm losing my touch. He kisses it.</context>
      <utterance>It was fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, poor baby. Well you can relax. I have a mission for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Kathryn steps into frame and embraces him. She is wearing the same sweater. He kisses her forehead and messes up her hair.</context>
      <utterance>You know Court Reynolds, son of Garret Reynolds?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean the Nazi who dumped you over Fourth Of July Weekend?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KATMRYN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Kathryn rises up INTO FRAME, looks at Court and scowls.</context>
      <utterance>I went to great lengths to please Court. Huge sacrifices were made on my part to keep him happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She spits on him, then wipes her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Swallow?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Kathryn sprays her mouth with Binaca.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In any event, my feelings were hurt when I learned that he had fallen for someone else. Someone chaste... pure... innocent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She takes a lick of the ice cream, which falls off the cone. She mouths the word "shoot" and stomps her feet</context>
      <utterance>None other than Cecile Caldwell.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't find this very funny,</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's what this is all about.  We'll get together and plan your curriculum.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep your friends close and your enemies closer. When I get through with her, she'll be the premier Blow Job Queen of the Tri-State area and poor little Court's heart will be shattered.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why go through Cecile? Why not just attack Court?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because if there's an attack made on Court it could be traced back to me. I can't allow that to happen. Everybody loves me and I intend to keep it that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see your point... though why should I care?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to seduce our young Cecile. Introduce her to your world of decadence and debauchery.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds intriguing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>supple breasts, a tight firm ass and an uncharted pootie. Sebastian watches Kathryn rub herself. He licks his lips. KATHRYN (cont'd) Be her Captain Picard, Valmont. Boldly go where no man has gone before. Sebastian places his hand over Kathryn's as she continues to rub herself. He thinks for a moment, then:</context>
      <utterance>She's quite cute you know. Young</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn throws his hand off of hers.</context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come on, Kathryn. It's too easy. "But I thought high school was only four years." I mean, please. She knows nothing. She's seen nothing. I could have her under the table at Au Bar sucking me off before the appetizer arrived. Go get one of those moron friends of yours to do it. I have a reputation to uphold.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh but diddling the therapist's daughter is a challenge?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a magazine and throws it on the table. Kathryn picks it up. It's the latest issue of "Seventeen."</context>
      <utterance>That was just simple revenge. What I have planned requires sheer genius.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested in the latest dating tips from Jonathan Taylor Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to the page. INSERT MAGAZINE ARTICLE: The title reads: A VIRGIN'S MANIFESTO. "Why I Plan To Wait Until Marriage," by Annette Harrison. Age 17. Kansas City, Missouri.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up and turn to page 64.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, is she for real?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes. I've read it over and over again. This baby's the real deal. Daddy's little angel. A paradigm of chastity and virtue.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>B.F.D. What do you plan to do? Fly to Kansas and woo little Dorothy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just so happens we're not in Kansas anymore. Our little angel's father has accepted the new headmaster position at Oakwood. She's staying with my aunt up in Connecticut while Daddy sells his house. Can you imagine what this would do for my reputation? Screwing the new headmaster's virginal daughter before school starts? It will be my greatest victory.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't stand a chance. Even this is out of your league.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Care to make a wager on that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll think about it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh well, duty calls. Time to add another chapter to my work of art. He holds up a leather bound JOURNAL.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh gee, your journal. Could you be more queer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian stands to leave and heads to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Could you be more desperate to read it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Sebastian. About that little wager of yours. He stops. KATHRYN  Count me in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are the terms?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you lose, then that hot little Porsche of yours is mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She approaches him.</context>
      <utterance>And if I win?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you something you've been jerking off about ever since our parents got married.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be more specific.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In English.  I'll fuck your brains out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think I'd go for that bet? That's a seventy thousand dollar car.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm the only person you can't control and it kills you. Sebastian sneers at her. KATHRYN  Do we have a deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him and licks her tongue over his lips.</context>
      <utterance>No way, that car means everything to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can put it anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even there?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would feel so yummy. Sebastian hesitates, then shakes her hand. KATHRYN  Happy hunting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a beautiful home you have here Mrs. Rosemond.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Annette. Chance Hill has been with my family for over sixty years. Does your family do much riding?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother and I used to ride a lot, before she got sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Grandpa, used to breed horses on his farm so I would come over and ride all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm familiar with a lot of breeders in the mid-west. What's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben Schwarz.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Schwarz. Jewish?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>German.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't ring a bell. Annette throws her a concerned look. AUNT HELEN  In any event, I want you to consider this your home for the time being.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. It's so peaceful and quiet around here. BANG! A shotgun sounds in the distance. ANNETTE  What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aunt Helen gallops down the ridge followed by Annette.</context>
      <utterance>Sebastian must be here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TARGET soars into the air, SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Die motherfucker! He fires the gun, missing the target. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Shit, shit, shit. Franklin shakes his head. WE HEAR a cat MEOW. Sebastian perks up. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Kitty. Kitty. He quietly reloads his rifle. WE HEAR the cat MEOW again. Sebastian searches for the cat. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Puss Puss Puss Puss Puss. He raises his rifle and takes aim.</context>
      <utterance>Pull!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He lowers his rifle and turns to SEE Aunt Helen and Annette riding over to him. He waves. Aunt Helen dismounts from her horse and they hug. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) I've been looking all over for you. God, I've missed you.</context>
      <utterance>Sebastian!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've missed you too. How are your parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She strokes his cheek, lovingly.</context>
      <utterance>They're coming back next week. I write them everyday.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sebastian, this is Annette Harrison. She's going to be staying with me for a few weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess that makes two of us. Welcome. He extends his hand and they shake. SEBASTIAN   Why don't you head in and whip us up some of that ice tea of yours? We'll take care of the horses.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything for you, my dear. Sebastian climbs on Aunt Helen's horse. AUNT HELEN  Stay out of trouble you two.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN &amp; ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at Annette and beckons her to follow.</context>
      <utterance>We will.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what year are you going into?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a boyfriend back home?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Relationships seem too distracting. I'd rather concentrate on my studies.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a lesbo?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bends over to pick up the saddle.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sighs, disgusted, then turns toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you often this offensive on a first encounter?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head and continues with her chore.</context>
      <utterance>I was just being honest. You happen to have a nice ass. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read your teen beat manifesto.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must say I found it rather appalling.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a first. Most people praised me for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most people are morons. I mean who are you to knock what you've never experienced?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't knocking anything. It's just my belief that people shouldn't actually experience the act of love until they are in love and that people our age are too immature to be in touch with those emotions.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take yourself. You've slept with several women. Are you happier because of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know I've been with several women?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend wrote me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well maybe you should get to know the person before you judge them instead of listening to some bullshit gossip.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I didn't mean to upset you... but you still didn't answer the question. An uncomfortable silence falls between them,</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell is taking the time to write letters, spreading this shit about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not really important.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, forget it. It's obvious that we're not going to be friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you being so dramatic?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I've got a lot of problems and I'm trying to deal with them and the last thing I need is people spreading shit about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, I said I was sorry.  Can we start over again? I think we've gotten off on the wrong foot. She approaches him and they shake. ANNETTE  Annette Harrison.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, but before he releases her hand: SEBASTIAN (cont'd) So tell me, Annette. I'm curious, since you've never had sex do you touch yourself? She whisks her hand away and storms out of the stable. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) What did I say?</context>
      <utterance>Sebastian Valmont.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good, that's good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I suck. I suck.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her eyes and they repeat the scale. It sounds much better. Ronald takes the moment to study Cecile's face. It's obvious he's smitten with her. ON KATHRYN: who watches from the door. A grin crosses her face. Ronald replaces her other hand and plays a beautiful Bach Sonata, with he and Cecile sharing the bowing. He closes his eyes as the music takes over him. Now Cecile opens her eyes and gazes into his. The feeling is mutual. ON KATHRYN: She accidentally bangs her hand onto a table which causes a metal tray to fall to the ground. Ronald and Cecile look up as Kathryn replaces the tray</context>
      <utterance>Relax. It's okay. Take a deep breath. Cecile takes a deep breath RONALD  You're concentrating too much on your bowing. Let it flow. He stands and sits behind her. RONALD  Here, let me help you. He places his hand over hers. RONALD  Now close your eyes and let's try again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald quickly stands and moves away from Cecile</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I didn't mean to interrupt. Your playing was beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald approaches and shakes Kathryn's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Kathryn, this is Ronald Clifford. He's giving me music lessons over the summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleased to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Likewise I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronald is one of the few high school students attending Juliard. He's composing his first opera.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's based on the life of Doctor Martin Luther King.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald shakes his head, but laughs. Cecile looks at him and smiles. Kathryn rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor King is my favorite.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile nods.</context>
      <utterance>I guess our hour's up. Same time tomorrow?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unbelievable. Some fag, no offense -</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- none taken -</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- wrote a letter to this chick and saying shit about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any ideas who it could be?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blaine, if I knew who it was that person wouldn't be alive right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you say she's from?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kansas. Who the hell do I know in Kansas?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greg McConnell.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The football stud?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's from Kansas City. I wouldn't be surprised if he was your rat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would make sense. McConnell hates me. I fingered his girlfriend at the game last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think that bothered him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just say Greg likes tackling tight ends on and off the field.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you shitting me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shit you not. McConnell used to sneak in my dorm room drunk every month. We'd go at it for a while, then as soon as he'd cum, he starts freaking out. You know -  "What are you doing, man? I'm not a fag. I'll kick your ass if you say anything."  It's like, for Christsakes Greg, you're gay, deal with it. The only reason why I let him continue with his charade is because he's got a mouth like a Hoover.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad he's in Kansas this summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore. Football team started practice last week. He's already called me to hook up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. You think you could arrange a little get together with him tonight on my behalf?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. I do believe Bravo is showing Spartacus on television tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think it's not going to cost you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian hands Blaine two hundred dollar bills.</context>
      <utterance>No problem. Just make sure your front door is unlocked. Shall we say the "stroke of midnight" no pun intended?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, rumor has it that you went on a date with Court Reynolds. I hear he's very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's alright.  He kept talking about this bulimic headcase he dumped over Fourth Of July.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Bulimic headcase.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a loser she must be.  Anyhow, Court's invited me to the Hamptons for Labor Day Weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think so? I don't know. I guess I'm just scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you scared of?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah duh. Boys. I've never even gone to first base with a guy. What do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't you ever practiced with one of your girlfriends?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eww. No. That's gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile turns and faces Kathryn, who removes her glasses. KATHRYN (cont'd) Now close your eyes and wet your lips.</context>
      <utterance>It's not gross. How else do you think girls learn? Here turn around and face me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you for real?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to learn or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile does as instructed. Kathryn leans in and kisses her on the mouth.</context>
      <utterance>I guess. It still sounds gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See that wasn't so bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's try it again, only this time I'm going to stick my tongue in your mouth. When I do that I want you to massage my tongue with yours. That's what first base is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile closes her eyes. Kathryn leans in and kisses her again, only this time longer. She continues to kiss her then gently pushes her tongue into Cecile's. Cecile does as instructed and they start to make out. Kathryn eyes look towards the ground where Cecile's hands are now clutching the grass. Kathryn smiles and continues her seduction. She places her hand on Cecile's thigh and moves it under her dress. Cecile lets out a soft sigh. Kathryn breaks from the kiss. They look at each other and smile. KATHRYN (cont'd) Not bad.</context>
      <utterance>Eyes closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should try it on your friend Ronald sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come on Cecile. He's crazy about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it that obvious? Kathryn nods. CECILE  He sends me letters you know. Love letters.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's so romantic. Have you responded?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well do you like him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile, we just made out in the middle of Central Park. You can trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn grabs her and looks her straight in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>I do like him. I can't stop thinking about him. Cecile starts to cry. Kathryn hugs her. CECILE  What am I going to do? If my mother found out about Ronald she would kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me. Your mother must never know. Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hide the letters?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. They're in this antique doll house in my room.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to make me copies of his letters and bring them to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile if there's one thing I'm great at it's love letters. With my help, he'll be eating out of the palm of your hand. Perhaps we can arrange a little get together for the two of you at my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd do that for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I would. We're friends, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile kisses her on the cheek and hugs Kathryn.</context>
      <utterance>Best friends.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. Excuse me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talking to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I know this is your house and all, but do you think you couid keep it down? I'm trying to read.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'cha reading?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Fountainhead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great book.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've read The Fountainhead?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Several times. I'm not as dumb as I act, you know. When Howard Roark makes love to Dominique Francon... most romantic scene in all of literature.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Romantic? He rapes her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a matter of opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need help.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you come join me for a swim and we'll discuss it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At this hour? I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come on. Quit acting like a geriatric and get in the pool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, with an invitation like that how could a girl refuse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a minute. I'll be right down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She re-enters the guest room. Sebastian's cell phone RINGS. He answers it.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck her yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm working on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loser.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me later.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up and lights a cigarette. Sook-Hee accidently jabs her toe.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow. That hurt you stupid bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOOK-HEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn kicks some water in her face.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oops.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know it amazes me that someone as bright as you can be so horrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Another letter from your friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my favorite part.  Even more treacherous and dangerous than he is charming and fascinating. He has never taken a single step or spoken a single word without some dishonorable or criminal intention. Every young girl he has successfully pursued has regretted it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you could at least have the decency of telling me who's badmouthing me so I might have the opportunity to confront them face to face. How do you know it's not some girl who's pissed off at me for breaking up with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sincerely doubt it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me the fucking letter. Annette smiles and tears the letter up. SEBASTIAN  Why did you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The last thing I need is you going into my room searching for this while I'm away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the water?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Refreshing. She dives in the pool and surfaces. SEBASTIAN  You're right you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what you said today in the stable. I'm not a happy person.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You implied it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I didn't mean to give you a hard time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's okay. I mean I look at you with all your morals and values and well, YOU seem to be happy in your choices. I envy you. No bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seriously, you're amazing. You have everything going for you.  You're smart, you're beautiful, you're determined. You're everything I want in a girlfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't kidding. I'd like to take you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm flattered but, seriously it could never work.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swims towards her.</context>
      <utterance>Because you act like a pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you deny that there's an attraction between us?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't... I don't want to answer that... look we're friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flexes for her. She laughs.</context>
      <utterance>You don't find me cute? Come on, look at these muscles.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but you're not my type.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He extends his arms out for a hug. She moves in and hugs him. Her smile turns to a look of horror.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Friends it is. I can live with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're naked.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes him off her.</context>
      <utterance>It's my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's repulsive.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette climbs out of the pool.</context>
      <utterance>What's the big deal? We're friends. Haven't you ever seen your friends naked before?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Get some manners.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flips him the bird as she heads into the house. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Oooooo, naughty naughty. Ten Hail Mary's for you. (beat) Good night.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I didn't know you were peenaphobic.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh baby... oh baby...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby?  Right on time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door swings open and Sebastian enters.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God... Oh God, I'm gonna cum. I'm gonna cum... I'm gonna...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Blaine, did I leave my... holy shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Greg throws the covers over his face. Sebastian smiles and sits. He lights a cigarette. No movement from under the covers.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greg, is that you under the covers?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian stands YANKS the covers off the bed, revealing Greg and Blaine.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you to lock the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look Valmont. This was the first time I've ever done something like this. I was --</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- really drunk and blah blah blah blah blah.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't tell anyone. This could ruin my career.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your career? What about your family? Can you imagine the humiliation your father's going to feel when he finds out his pride and joy is a fudge- packer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey hey hey. Careful Valmont, he's not a fudge packer. Cum chugger yes but not a fudge packer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. I'm begging you. I'll do anything. Let's just forget the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmmmmmm... nah. I can't help you there. It's too good to pass up. Greg starts to cry. SEBASTIAN  After all, it is you who's bad- mouthing me to Annette Harrison.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annette Harrison? I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Greg. You're the only one who knows her. The truth will save you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear on my life, I never said a word to her about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he's telling the truth Valmont. Greg couldn't write a grocery list let alone a letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Greg, completely defeated, crawls off the bed and over to Sebastian. Blaine shakes his head and smiles. Greg places his hand on Sebastian's thigh when - SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Jesus Christ, I was only kidding. What do you think, I'm gay? My God, haven't you had enough for tonight.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, I believe you. Stop crying. Your secret's safe with me. Greg wipes his eyes. SEBASTIAN  However, this whole incident's kind of turned me on. Sebastian unzips his fly. SEBASTIAN  You get my point.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our boy just can't get enough dick.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blaine and Sebastian laugh.</context>
      <utterance>You sick son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll leave you guys alone.  Score one for the team, Greg. Sebastian leaves the room, then re-enters. SEBASTIAN  Come to think of it, there is something you can do for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need a lift?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you today?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh right, last night. I guess I owe you an apology.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to speak to you till you realize that you can't intimidate me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues her jog. Sebastian follows alongside. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Have a nice sleep last night?</context>
      <utterance>I said I was sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I could say the same for myself. I was up thinking about you all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we agreed that we were going to be friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette stops running and turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, well unfortunately I can't just switch the "on" button to "off." The sad fact of the matter is that you've unintentionally rubbed off on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's a bad thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to better myself, but the one person who can help me is the same one pushing me away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but I'm not here to be your savior.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well try this one on for size. I think I'm falling in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't even know me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you believe in love at first sight?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but only when it's mutual. And this is far from mutual.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch. Do you think we could spend some time together this morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. I'm seeing a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's none of your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doing what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's also none of your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me what to do, Annette. How can I win your heart. I'll do anything. I can't get you out of my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You truly want to do something to make me happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you promise to abide by it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without question.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright.  I want you to leave and go back to New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian thinks for a moment. He's pissed.</context>
      <utterance>If that's a problem, then I'll make arrangements to stay with some friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll leave this afternoon. Happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shifts the cart into reverse and backs away.</context>
      <utterance>It's not about being happy. You and I can't -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told you he's failing in love with you? I've never known him to say those words before.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? I thought he said it all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not his style. one thing I can say about Valmont. He always speaks the truth. Annette looks lost. GREG  What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a mutual feeling between you two?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I mean. I don't know.  What else do you know about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a whole lot. We take some classes together. He's got a bad rep, but it's mostly bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, a lot of people are jealous cause he's loaded.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I've been hearing some awful things about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Greg takes her hand.</context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you. I'm sworn to secrecy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annette, how long have we known each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Now it's my job to look out for you. You're like a kid sister to me. Do I look like some kind of gossip queen?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promise not to say anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On my mother's life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Positive.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you do everything I asked you to?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told her I never said I love you before?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told her that people are jealous cause I'm loaded?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you think she bought it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pretty sure she did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty sure or sure sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She bought it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Click. The line goes dead.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be in touch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws a magazine at the television. Sebastian bursts into the living room.</context>
      <utterance>Enough with the music. Fuck her already.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would not believe what--</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIDEO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIDEO</mode>
      <context>Cecile blushes. Ronald checks his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Almost as beautiful as you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIDEO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess it's getting late. Please thank Kathryn for the use of her Steinway.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIDEO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIDEO</mode>
      <context>He approaches her, awkwardly then shakes her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: LIVING ROOM - Kathryn FREEZE FRAMES the image.</context>
      <utterance>Idiot!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ready for this? I've recently discovered that our good friend Mrs. Caldwell is the one who sent the letter to Annette urging her to stay away from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I now plan to devote all my energies to destroying the douche bag. Any luck corrupting her daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks over to the "freeze frame" image of Ronald and Cecile on the television.</context>
      <utterance>Call Cecile up and get her to come over. I'll bust that cherry in a heartbeat.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plot thickens. It appears that Cecile has fallen for her music teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooo, I'm sure Mrs. Caldwell will love that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not to mention Court Reynolds. Unfortunately, Ronald's moving with the speed of a Special Olympic Bobsledder.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your plan of attack?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boo hoo.</context>
      <utterance>I rat Cecile out to mommy. Mommy goes ballistic and ends their relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn smiles and sits on Sebastian's lap.</context>
      <utterance>But who will they turn to for help?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile is planning to go away with Court next week. I'll need you to speed up her sexual awakenings. Sebastian rubs her shoulders.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm at your service.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Mmmm, that feels good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian moves his hand down her shirt and under her bra. He's met with no resistance.</context>
      <utterance>Oh sis. You're so tense.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate when things don't go my way. It makes me so horny.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his hand out from her shirt and slides it under her skirt. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) (baby talk) Oh baby, your soaking.</context>
      <utterance>I hate it too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her eyes and rubs his crotch. She unzips his fly. KATHRYN (cont'd) (seductively) Any luck with your girl?</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moving along quite well.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you succeeded in your task?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any day now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let me know when you do. Until then. She takes his hand out from under her pants. KATHRYN  No pootie. Kathryn smiles. KATHRYN  Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was just calling to see how you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm... I'm alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was your date?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a moment of uncomfortable silence.</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't a date. He's just a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was just calling to tell you I was thinking about you and I miss you. I'll let you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, don't hang up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses over to his circular bed where two scantily clad twins (GRETCHEN &amp; MORA) are licking popsicles.</context>
      <utterance>Reading.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you reading?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of Human Bondage.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somerset Maugham.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's pretty relevant considering my situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out a bottle of baby oil and pours it on the girls' butts.</context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna start that again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They rub the oil on each other then turn to him and smile. He clicks the phone back on. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Annette that's my mom calling. Can I call you tomorrow?</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm through with my childish games when it comes to you. Hold on, that's my other line.  Rub.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Have a good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GRETCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of Human Bondage. You're such a bullshit artist.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Gretchen. You don't even know what it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRETCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duh, it's a book.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what it's about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares. Books are for fags.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Books are for fags. I weep for the future.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>SALESWOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn examines the label.</context>
      <utterance>Here's something you might like.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you carry any real fur?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESWOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. All our fur is faux.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The saleswoman smiles, then walks away. Kathryn sneers then looks over at a small child, staring at her. KATHRYN (cont'd) (mouthing the words) Fuck off. She "shoos" the child away, when Mrs. Caldwell approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. The animals. How silly of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got your message and came as quick as I could.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope I didn't keep you from something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Cecile.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about her?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... you promise you won't say anything to her. We've developed a friendship and...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kathryn, you have my word. It isn't drugs is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's worse. I think there's something going on between Cecile and her music teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronald? That's crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. She's so young and he's so -</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn reacts to her remark.</context>
      <utterance>Black.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn picks out an expensive suit and approaches the sales counter. KATHRYN (cont'd) I hope I did the right thing in telling you. I'd hate to see Cecile ruin things with Court.</context>
      <utterance>He's been sending her love letters that she hides under her doll house. I questioned whether or not to tell you, but something like this could destroy her reputation at Oakwood and I don't want to see her get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't thank you enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will be discreet about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESWOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn looks through her purse.</context>
      <utterance>Will that be cash or charge?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Caldwell takes out her purse.</context>
      <utterance>Oh poo. I left my credit cards at home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me get that for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh please. I can't have you do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Caldwell hands the credit card to the saleswoman. Kathryn turns to Mrs. Caldwell.</context>
      <utterance>It's the least I can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell do you think you are?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not to pervert my child.</context>
      <utterance>I'm paying you to give cello lessons.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Caldwell I think you're misunderstanding something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald and Cecile exchange looks of worry.</context>
      <utterance>Is that so? Mrs. Caldwell holds up Ronald's letters. MRS. CALDWELL  You care to explain this then?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you find those?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margarita found them while cleaning your room.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are my letters!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald nods and Cecile runs out of the room. Mrs. Caldwell turns to Ronald. MRS. CALDWELL (cont'd) How dare you treat me with such disrespect. I got you off the streets and this is how you repay me?</context>
      <utterance>Don't you raise your voice at me. Go to your room, now. Cecile turns to Ronald. MRS. CALDWELL  Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got me off the streets? I live on 59th and Park.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald packs up his sheet music, while Mrs. Caldwell waits.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever. You are never to set foot in this house again and you are never and I mean never to see my daughter again. Is that understood?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First of all, maam, I never touched your daughter and second, I would like to think that in these times someone of your status could look beyond racial lines.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh don't give me any of that racist crap. My husband and I gave money to Colin Powell.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He storms off.</context>
      <utterance>I guess that puts me in my place. Thank you for the hospitality Mrs. Caldwell. It was a true awakening.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. I never knew she had these kind of feelings.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a lucky guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She really loves me. Sebastian and Kathryn roll their eyes. RONALD  What do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you do? Tell her you love her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I can't even see her. She doesn't have her own phone, I don't even know her e-mail address.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronald, e-mail's for geeks and pedophiles. Be romantic. Write her another letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How will I get to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN &amp; KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll make sure she gets it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you being so good to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald leaves the room. Sebastian closes the door while Kathryn picks up the phone and dials.</context>
      <utterance>Because we want to see Cecile happy and we know you make her happy. She hands Ronald a pen and paper. KATHRYN  Now you just march yourself into the study and start writing. We'll be there to check on you in a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you calling?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile. Sebastian hangs up the phone. KATHRYN  What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before we go through with this, I just want you to be aware of the damage we're going to cause.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up the phone and he hangs it up again.</context>
      <utterance>I'm aware.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you really? I mean, we've done some pretty fucked up shit in our time but this... I mean, we're destroying an innocent girl. You do realize that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches out toward his temple, plucks a handful of something, throws it to the ground and STOMPS on it. KATHRYN (cont'd) Court Renolds is going down and if you're not going to help me, someone else will.</context>
      <utterance>What is that? Oh my God, it's your conscience.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You amaze me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian says nothing. Kathryn picks up the phone and dials. KATHRYN (cont'd) Hello, Cecile. It's Kathryn. Alright, stop crying. I understand. Hold on for Sebastian. She hands the phone to Sebastian.</context>
      <utterance>Eat me, Sebastian. It's alright for you to fuck everyone, but because I'm a girl it's wrong. Well let me tell you something, I didn't ask to be a girl. Do you think I relish the fact that I have to act like Mary Sunshine twenty four seven, so I can be considered a "laaaady." Do you think I take great delight when I hear - "Kathryn is so wonderful." "Kathryn is a model child." "Kathryn is going to make an excellent wife one day."  I'm the Marsha fucking Brady of the upper East Side and sometimes I want to kill myself for it. No, I don't enjoy being a part of the weaker sex and for that reason everyone around me is going to suffer. So there's your psychoanalysis Doctor Freud. Now are you in or are you out?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile. Now I need you to listen to me very carefully. I have a letter from Ronald that he asked me to give to you. Now I can't exactly bring it to your house, since your mother despises me so here's what we're going to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands the letter to Sebastian, who looks it over.</context>
      <utterance>Finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think he'll like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points the camera at Cecile and snaps a photo.</context>
      <utterance>He'll love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just taking your photo.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile gasps.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm, you're right. Those clothes don't do you justice. Why don't you take them off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands to leave. Sebastian blocks her path.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry that was out of line.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves toward the phone</context>
      <utterance>I want to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay. I'll just call your mom and have her come pick you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mom? Don't call my mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile runs over to him, sobbing, and wraps her arms around his legs.</context>
      <utterance>Why not? ... Oh wow, she doesn't know you're here. In fact, you're grounded. Jesus, you could get in a shitload of trouble for this. I think I should call her anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please please please. I'll do anything. Just don't call my mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile, all I want to do is give you a kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then I can go home?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile breathes a sigh of relief. He pulls her up to her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. I'm not a monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a kiss, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her eyes, then puckers up. Sebastian takes the string holding up her sweats and pulls it open. Cecile bolts up.</context>
      <utterance>I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promised to let me kiss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile are you up yet? We're gonna to be late for the - She notices the bed is empty. MRS. CALDWELL  Cecile? She walks over the bathroom door and knocks. MRS. CALDWELL  Cecile?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in the bath, mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rosemond's before lunch.</context>
      <utterance>Well hurry up. I want to be at Mrs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was nice of you to invite us up for the weekend, Helen.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More the merrier.  Is everything alright my dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian enters carrying his tennis racket.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just not feeling well.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile is stunned that he's there. Sebastian takes a seat at the table.</context>
      <utterance>Afternoon ladies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know you'd be here, Sebastian.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>such a lovely day, why waste it in the city. Anyone for tennis? He looks at Cecile and strokes the shaft of his racket. Cecile stands and rushes into the house. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) What's wrong with her? No one knows. MRS. CALDWELL (cont'd) Would you excuse me for a minute? Mrs. Caldwell follows her into the house.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't planning on it, but being</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope she's alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aunt Helen stands and enters the house.</context>
      <utterance>I better go check on them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alone again.  What are you up to today?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm doing some volunteer work.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need any company?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You? Volunteer? I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know? Maybe I'd like it. I'm trying to change here. You could be supportive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette shakes her head and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Babe, you're looking at the next Mother Teresa.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. I need you. I don't know what to do. You're the only one I can talk to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>MRS. SUGERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I ever tell you the time when my late husband sent me -</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you already did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SUGERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did? Sebastian never takes his eyes off the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right after we played backgammon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SUGERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We played backgammon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh. You beat me three times.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SUGERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. Then I fucked your daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SUGERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to her and extinguishes his cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, do you want some water?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SUGERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a knock at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... no thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette and the nurse enter.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How we doing in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SUGERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won three games of backgammon. Sebastian smiles at Annette, who smiles back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's weird. I actually feel good about myself. Can we do this again next week?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I actually feel good about myself?"</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must take me for a real idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to tell me that you had a good time with the old lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. We played three games of backgammon and... She throws him a look. SEBASTIAN  Alright. I was bored out of my fucking mind. I hate doing charity.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. It doesn't make you a bad person.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it does.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it doesn't. I'm happy you're being honest with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't win with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not about winning. You know what your problem is? You take yourself way too seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lighten up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am lighten. Can we drop this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drive on in silence. A smile comes over Annette's face. She turns to him, crosses her eyes and makes a face. Sebastian looks over.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds the face. Sebastian starts to laugh. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Cut it out. He continues to laugh. She stops making the face.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? Stop it, it's distracting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh dear, are you actually laughing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She makes the face again. He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs with him.</context>
      <utterance>Stop that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches out and holds his hand. He squeezes it.</context>
      <utterance>There's hope for you, yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Cecile bolts up and unlocks the door. Kathryn stands there with a worried look on her face. KATHRYN (cont'd) Are you okay?</context>
      <utterance>It's Kathryn.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn enters and locks the door behind her. Cecile is crying.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down. Tell me what's wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something awful happened last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't think you want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile, you have to tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It involves your brother. He... took advantage of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does your mother know?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she knew, she'd kill me. It happened at your house last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you do something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, let me get this straight. You came over to our house late last night and he forced intercourse on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... not exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He made you give him a blow job.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile waits a moment, then whispers in her ear. KATHRYN (cont'd) He ate you out?</context>
      <utterance>Well what then?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's what you call it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile, I think you're going to have a hard time crying rape if that's all he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do then?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well did you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Well... I don't know - it was weird. At first it felt icky, then it felt kind of okay. Then, I started getting really hot and then I started shaking and then like, I don't t know... it felt like an explosion, but a good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile, you had an orgasm.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so proud of you. You're becoming a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn nods. Cecile embraces her, happy.</context>
      <utterance>I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now listen. Now that you're on your way, it would be stupid of you to stop. Think of Sebastian as a tutor. Let him instruct you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't love him. I love Ronald.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? Don't you want to make Ronald a happy pappy? Practice makes perfect, Cecile. My advice is to sleep with as many people as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that would make me a slut.  Wouldn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cecile takes the information in.</context>
      <utterance>Cecile, everybody does it. It's just that nobody talks about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like a secret society.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one way of looking at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just had a nice chat with Cecile. I don't think she'll be giving you anymore problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yippy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you spying on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the binoculars to Kathryn, who looks out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian grabs the binoculars from her.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, she reeks of Laura Ashley.  Oh, she's crying. Wittle baby's upset by the big bad book.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's really getting to you, isn't she?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you must know, yes. I don't know what to do. I can't stand that holier than thou bullshit and yet, I'm completely infatuated with her.  She made me laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's why you're losing your bet?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not losing the bet. It's just taking longer than I expected.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mind if I take my new Porsche for a ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He storms out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Kathryn, the only thing you're going to be riding is me. Now if you'll excuse me, I have some work to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I bothering you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits down next to her.</context>
      <utterance>Not at all. Have a seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me you finished The Fountainhead already? She nods. He points to her book. SEBASTIAN  Great book. What's the guy's name, Florentino...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian sticks his hand in his pocket and fiddles around.</context>
      <utterance>Florentino Ariza.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friend Monsieur Philipe is a friend of Florentino.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Monsieur Philipe?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know Monsieur Philipe? Sebastian takes out a SOCK PUPPET. SEBASTIAN   Bonjour mademoiselle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bonjour Monsieur Philipe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are very pretty. I would like to kiss you. The puppet kisses her on the cheek. SEBASTIAN   Oooo, that felt good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He paces for a moment and his mood turns to anger.</context>
      <utterance>I am too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what? I don't take it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you said we were going to be friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't handle it. I can't keep my feelings bottled up like you. Can you honestly tell me that you feel nothing for me? ... Tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have feelings for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what's wrong? I love you Annette. It's not like you have a husband, unless your married to Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette's eyes well up with tears.</context>
      <utterance>Why can't we be together?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really want to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hurries off.</context>
      <utterance>It's because I don't trust myself with you.  I took a vow and because of you I'm tempted to break it. Don't destroy that for me. Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I suppose to be this sore?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of silence.</context>
      <utterance>For the first time, yes. It'll pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it better when I'm on top.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecile. This is what I like to call quiet time. This is time when we reflect on what we've done.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at the troubled expression on Sebastian's face. CECILE (cont'd) Something's bothering you?</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think?</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SEBASTIAN'S P.O.V. - He looks out on the balcony, where Kathryn is eavesdropping. They make eye contact and she waves.</context>
      <utterance>No, you were fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands and walks over to the balcony, where he closes the blinds. CECILE (cont'd) You love her, don't you? It's okay. I don't love you either. I love Ronald.</context>
      <utterance>It's that girl, Annette.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian heads to the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking a shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need any company?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want a blow job?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night Cecile.</utterance>
   <speaker>CECILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prude.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian enters the room.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just came to say goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back to the city. I may take off to Europe for the rest of the summer. I just can't handle it around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that's for the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sebastian, please. I don't want us to end on bad terms.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette's eyes well up with tears.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm afraid you don't have a choice in the matter. You make me sick. You're a hypocrite and I don't associate with hypocrites.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How am I a hypocrite?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette races toward him and throws her arms around him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh please Annette. You spend all your time preaching about waiting for love. Well here it is. Right in front of you, but you're going to turn your back on it. I'm sorry that we're not at the age where we can get married. If we were, I'd propose, but that's not going to happen. So I guess we're just fucked. I'll move on, but you... you're going to have to live with yourself knowing you've turned your back on love. And that makes you a hypocrite. Sebastian heads to the door. SEBASTIAN  Have a nice life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him passionately.</context>
      <utterance>Get off me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian embraces her and draws her over to the bed. She lies down and starts to unbutton her dress. Sebastian stands over her watches her. Her crying does not let up as she continues to undress. Sebastian stands, stunned and watches her.</context>
      <utterance>I... I want you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pained look crosses her face. Sebastian leaves the room and closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wipes his eyes, which are starting to water. He goes over to a mirror at looks at himself. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Get it together you pussy. A stern look comes over his face. He smiles, then walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? How'd it go last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With who?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian sits up in bed.</context>
      <utterance>Well I know how it went with Cecile. She won't shut up about it. How'd it go with Mrs. Jesus?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If your asking if I nailed her the answer is no.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She shot you down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly the opposite.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what went wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. She was lying on the bed, ready to do it, but I-- I don't, I was... I just didn't feel right about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me you had the chance to fuck her and you didn't. God are you a chump.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs out of bed and puts on his robe. He starts out the door, when -</context>
      <utterance>A momentary lapse of judgment, soon to be rectified.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're heading towards her room, you won't find her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know?  She left thirty minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd she go?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian throws off the robe and starts to dress.</context>
      <utterance>She wouldn't say. She apologized to your aunt and told her she was going to stay with some friends.  You blew it, Sebastian. That girl has come to her senses and she will never go near you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see about that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sebastian, you faggot. Is she with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Why don't you leave her alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McConnell, I'm gonna out your ass in two seconds if you don't tell me where she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. She's staying with some friends of her parents. The O'Sheas. She caught the train twenty minutes ago into Grand Central.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bangs on his dashboard.</context>
      <utterance>Grand Central. You better not be fucking with me cause it's your ass on the line. Sebastian clicks off his cell phone. SEBASTIAN  Motherfucker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. She walks over to him and kisses him. SEBASTIAN  You alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine. I have to get going to my friends' house.  Was it --</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and holds her hand out. He takes her hand in his.</context>
      <utterance>It was perfect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sook-Hee smiles and moves on. Sebastian continues down the hall. He passes Kathryn's door and hear noises.</context>
      <utterance>You work way to hard. Here.  Take the day off. Merry Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sebastian leans against the door.</context>
      <utterance>Slower.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sebastian knocks on the door.</context>
      <utterance>A little to the left. Look, pretend like you're writing the alphabet. A... B... mmm, stay on B.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sebastian hears some fumbling then a door close from inside the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>One second.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad time?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kind of.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws open the closet door. Ronald stands there covering his genitals with his hands. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Well, well, well.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you obviously wanted me to witness your little adventure or else you wouldn't have invited me in. Sebastian walks toward the closet. SEBASTIAN  Who is our little friend so inexperienced that you have to resort to the alphabet game?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald picks up his clothes. As he leaves:</context>
      <utterance>It's not what it seems like.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald's head drops as he closes the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Say hi to Cecile.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me. Sebastian throws Kathryn a look. KATHRYN  You can't have all the fun. Sebastian sits on the bed. KATHRYN  You seem to be in a good mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A big grin appears on Sebastian's face</context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me all the details.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was... Fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come on. For her first time?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. That's the amazing part of it. I mean, it wasn't like Cirque du Soleil acrobatics, just standard missionary stuff, but it was... ah forget it. I'm going to sound like a Hallmark card.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was... it was like the emotional part outweighed the physical part.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. So you made love. Ooo, I hear the birds chirping.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She places her hand on his crotch.</context>
      <utterance>Mock, mock, mock.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian stands.</context>
      <utterance>So I assume you've come here to make some arrangements.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some other time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not in the mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's why you're leaving?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It clearly is why.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves and slams the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>And I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up the phone. Kathryn stands in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>I'll pick you up in an hour. I love you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. You're completely p-whipped.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>P-whipped, p-whipped.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you? Why are you acting this way?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. It's just upsetting. You're in love with her. You don't love me anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come on, Kathryn, it was just a contest.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At first it was, but now it's become something bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kathryn, you know I love you. I've always loved you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore you don't. It's obvious.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you're reacting this way. You're just saying this because you lost the bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. Kathryn sits down on his bed. She slips her underwear off from under her bathrobe and tosses it aside, spreading her legs. KATHRYN (cont'd) Alright, come on, let's get it over with. But mark my words, this is the only time it'll happen. She picks up the phone. KATHRYN (cont'd) Whenever you're ready. Just stick it in me. While you're doing that I'm gonna make some phone calls.</context>
      <utterance>Is that what you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not fair. You're taking all the fun out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then do me a favor and get rid of her. If not for me, then do it for you. Look at yourself. You're a joke. She's turned you into jelly. What do you want to be, one of those losers who walk down the halls holding hands and smiling. People used to respect you. They feared you and now you're going to throw that all away. Sebastian stares at her, lost in thought. KATHRYN  Poor Sebastian. He used to be cool, but now he's just another love-struck faggot. One of the many.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why so nervous?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never done this before.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How have you dumped girls in the past?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screening calls. Any suggestions?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew this guy last summer in the Hamptons. He and his girlfriend at the time were madly in love with each other. But she had this huge weight problem. His friends taunted him mercilessly about it. You know, "How do you breathe when she sits on your face?" "It's embarrassing for you to be seen with her." Finally he couldn't take it anymore and decided to dump her. She flipped and he went on the defensive. I distinctly remember him saying the same thing over and over again. "I'm completely fucked up." "I'm completely fucked up." "I'm completely fucked up."  Poor fatty never had a chance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Is Annette at home?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. O'SHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be Sebastian. I've heard such nice things about you. He smiles. MRS. O'SHEA   Annette.  Come on in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. O'SHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. O'Shea mouths "He's cute" to Annette. Annette smiles and nods. Mrs. O'Shea leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm going to head back to the kitchen. You two have fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like a tour?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his hand and leads him down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes the door behind them. She smiles and kisses him. ANNETTE (cont'd) You think we can be quiet? She embraces him. Sebastian remains lifeless.</context>
      <utterance>And this is my room.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't working out for me anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks him in the eye and can tell he's not joking. ANNETTE (cont'd) What's wrong?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, me neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not you, it's me. I'm completely fucked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why aren't you understanding?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette bursts into tears.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I wish I felt the same. Unfortunately, I feel nothing. I think it was just the conquest. Sorry, I'm completely fucked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you trying to hurt me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She attacks him but he grabs her hands and fends her off. He pushes her against the wall and covers her mouth with his hand. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Shh! Shh! I don't think Mrs. O'Shea would appreciate you acting like a total psychopath. She slinks to the ground and continues to sob.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just being honest. I just wanted to see what you were like in bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know how to love.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't even know me. The fact of the matter is there is some one I love. She's smarter, prettier... you don't even compare to her. The only reason I am here is because she wants us to be exclusive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you knew this was important to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette clutches her stomach and continues to sob. He moves towards her.</context>
      <utterance>What, your virginity? Well that's over now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Please go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves and closes the door behind him. Annette continues to sob.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I'm completely fucked up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian is sitting in a chair, wearing his shades, journal in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little melodramatic, don't you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a flair for drama.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind if I ask what you're doing in my room?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted an answer to your question.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off his glasses. We can tell he has been crying.</context>
      <utterance>Annette?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Devastated beyond repair. I doubt she'll ever trust a man again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up a bottle of champagne.</context>
      <utterance>Well done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we should celebrate.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd love to, but unfortunately I'm expecting some company.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronald?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian holds up a letter.</context>
      <utterance>Not that it's any of your business but yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Ronald. Kathryn takes the letter. SEBASTIAN  I haven't had a chance to read it, but I'm sure it goes something like "yahdah yahdah yahdah you mean a lot to me. Yahdah yahdah yahdah I hope we can be friends. Etcetera, etcetera, etcetera." You see, I expected your sort of bullshit so I took the liberty of phoning Ronald and Cecile. Right now they're having a little get together in my love shack at the Grand Central Hyatt. I'm so sorry he chose Cecile over you, but I promised him I would see you through your crisis.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches down and picks up two glasses. He fills them and hands one to Kathryn. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) What shall we toast to?</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Now, where were we? POP goes the champagne cork. SEBASTIAN  Oh yeah, the celebration.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To my triumph, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not my choice of toast, but it's your call. To your triumph over Annette. Kathryn giggles. SEBASTIAN  What's so funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silly rabbit. My triumph isn't over her. It's over you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come again?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She clicks his glass and drinks. Sebastian doesn't drink. He looks ill.</context>
      <utterance>You were very much in love with her and you're still in love with her. But it amused me to make you ashamed of it. You gave up on the first person you ever loved because I called you names. Don't get me wrong, I'm flattered that you chose me over her, but please understand, I never loved you, Sebastian. You're just a toy. A little toy I play with. And now you've completely blown it with her. I think that's the saddest thing I've ever heard.  Cheers.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In any event, you still owe me my reward.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs him and starts throwing wild punches. They fall to the ground. KATHRYN (cont'd) Nobody hits me.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but unfortunately I don't fuck losers. Sebastian slaps her across the face. KATHRYN  You motherfucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rolls on top of her and pins her to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get off me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you calm down?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands and gives her a hand up. They both catch their breaths.</context>
      <utterance>Fine! Get off me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm very sorry about that. I apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I accept. Now get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out? We had an arrangement.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you hear what I said?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care what you said, we had an agreement. You've slept with half of the borough so don't tell me you're being choosy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm giving you to the count of three to plop your ass down on the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I will consider it a declaration of war. One. Two... three.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you have your answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs his journal, leaves and SLAMS the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>War it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's desperate that I talk to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. O'SHEA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've already told you, she's not home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well please leave a message that I called.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. O'SHEA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He hangs up the phone and THROWS it into a mirror, which</context>
      <utterance>I'll do that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MRS. O'SHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to talk to Annette.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. O'SHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know where she is?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. O'SHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know when she'll be back?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. O'SHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Later. Listen, we're entertaining some guests so -</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annette! Annette!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. O'SHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Young man, I already told you she's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her the package.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Could you please see that she gets this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. O'SHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really important.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. O'SHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>I understand. Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronald?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald sits up, nervous.</context>
      <utterance>It's Kathryn.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Kathryn. Is everything okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cries.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Sebastian. He's out of his mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please come over.</context>
      <utterance>I think he's high on drugs. He hit me, then took off. I'm afraid to be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up the phone and grabs his pants</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Annette. Thank you for reading this letter. I don't know what I can possibly say to rectify the harm I have caused you. For once in my life I'm at a loss for words.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truth of the matter is that being with you was the only time I have ever been happy. My whole life has been a joke. I prided myself on taking joy in others' misery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it finally backfired. I succeeded in hurting the first person I loved. I wish more than anything I could take it back, but I guess that's not possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enclosed is my most prized possession... my journal. For a long time I considered it my trophy. A sordid collection of my conquests. If you really want to know the truth, then please read it. No more lies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when I confronted him about his affair with Cecile he told me it was none of my business. Then when I said "Well what about Ronald," he said you were nothing more than a stupid... the n word and that you deserved what you got...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this happened before you and I hooked up?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been going on for a while.  Then he called me a disgrace to our family and that's when he hit me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Racist piece of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be careful if I were you. God knows what he's up to.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't scare me. I'll kick his ass in.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you stay here for the night? You can leave in the morning. That's when my parents get back and --</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn hugs him.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. I'll stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks Ronald. You're a good friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHT DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight o'clock. You got to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she show up?</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHT DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mind if I check upstairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHT DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't have you do that, nor can I have you hanging around the lobby all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. Thanks for letting me crash here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHT DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian stands and staggers out of the building.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian walks toward Ronald, who blocks his path. RONALD (cont'd) Sebastian! Sebastian looks up at Ronald.</context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Ronald.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems that you and I have some talking to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we do it later. I've had a really bad night and - Ronald SHOVES Sebastian. SEBASTIAN  What's your problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell do you come off hitting women?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kathryn. Did you hit her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kathryn? Oh Christ, she got to you too?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hit her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronald, you don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know what I'm talking about? I know that you fucked Cecile. Sebastian says nothing. RONALD  It's true, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronald, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald TACKLES Sebastian to the ground. Ronald lands on top of him and hits in the mouth. RONALD (cont'd) I trusted you! Ronald hits him again. Blood pours out of Sebastian's mouth. Sebastian is dazed. Ronald grabs him by the collar. RONALD (cont'd) I trusted you! Sebastian takes a moment to catch his breath.</context>
      <utterance>You bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knees Ronald in the groin. Ronald screams in pain and falls over. Sebastian climbs to his feet. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Why don't you give me a chance to explain. Sebastian kicks him in the ass. Ronald falls over. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Don't you get it? We were all part of her game. Sebastian pins him to the ground. Ronald struggles. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) I'm gonna let you up, but you have to give me a chance to explain. Understood? Ronald nods. Sebastian releases him and Ronald catches his breath. Sebastian looks up and SEES - Annette, standing across the street, witnessing the event. SEBASTIAN (cont'd) Annette! Sebastian stands and races over to her, blindly crossing the street. Annette notices a speeding cab and -</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian looks up just as -- WHAM! The taxi HITS him dead on, sending him flying over the car and onto the street. Annette SCREAMS. The cab SKIDS to a stop. Annette runs into the street and over to Sebastian, who lies in shock, He sees her and grabs her hand. She starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Sebastian!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronald and the Cab driver run over to them.</context>
      <utterance>I'm okay. I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cab driver races back to his car. Sebastian looks up at Annette. ANNETTE (cont'd) We're getting you to a hospital. Sebastian nods.</context>
      <utterance>Get an ambulance!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sebastian nods.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit. ANNETTE  You're gonna be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. ANNETTE  It's alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEBASTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay. Everything's good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her arm around Cecile.</context>
      <utterance>Sad, sad, sad. To think of the opportunities that boy had. This should be a lesson to us all that our children need constant supervision.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all about quality time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Annette turns and sees Kathryn at the door. She enters the room.</context>
      <utterance>He loved that view.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn extends her hand.</context>
      <utterance>I can see why.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Kathryn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake.</context>
      <utterance>Annette Harrison.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have we met?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know Sebastian well?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I remember. Annette Harrison. Your father's the new headmaster at Oakwood.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette nods.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you're going to love it there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I know this sounds corny, but whenever I feel like I can't go on I...  turn to Jesus and he helps me through the problem. Call me an anachronism, but -</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh cut the shit, Kathryn.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell do you think you are coming into my house and saying those things to me. My brother is dead, have some respect.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kathryn, I know all about you and Sebastian.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sebastian was a pathological liar. I wouldn't believe a word he -</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have his journal.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His journal. He sent it to me the day before he died. Everything about you is in it. The blow jobs, the hand jobs, the menages, your bout with bulimia, the affair you had with your guidance counselor and how he gave you... eww. Let's see, then there's your coke problem... You still keep it in your crucifix, don't you? It's all in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't show it to anybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I was planning on running down to Kinkos. Do you think you could give me ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHRYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do this to me. It could ruin me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathryn starts to cry. ANNETTE (cont'd) Kathryn, please. Crying? Didn't you once say that crying is a sign of weakness? I'm very disappointed in you. Kathryn continues to sob. ANNETTE (cont'd) Alright, stop crying. There's a bright side to this you know. Annette puts a comforting arm around her. ANNETTE (cont'd) You're going to be my pet project next year. You're going to do what I tell you to do, wear what I tell you to wear. You're going to befriend the unpopular, sleep with the insecure. Think of the social ramifications it will cause. You and I are going to turn this school around. And do you know why you're going to do it? (beat) Cause your ass is mine. Annette grabs Kathryn by the face, KISSES her forcefully on the mouth, then shoves her back. Kathryn looks at her in horror. ANNETTE (cont'd) We'll be in touch. She winks at Kathryn then leaves. CLOSE ON: Kathryn. She sits down on Sebastian's bed, utterly defeated. ANNETTE (cont'd) Forgot something. Annette steps back into frame and takes the car keys out of Kathryn's hands.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
