<movie id="152" title="Dances with Wolves">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SURGEON 1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>One of the bearers stops and looks back. His face is numb. And he nods hollowly. We cannot see the patient stretched out on the table. But we do see that the first surgeon has succeeded in getting the man's boot off.</context>
      <utterance>Is this the last one?</utterance>
   <speaker>SURGEON 2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, what a mess... at least there's no gangrene.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURGEON 1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There will be if it doesn't come off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURGEON 2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>As the TWO SURGEONS duck through a tent flap in the background we see a mangled foot, torn by shrapnel, it oozes blood from a cut clear to the bone. LIEUTENANT JOHN J. DUNBAR'S eyes are now open. He's a young man, his features sharp and handsome. With effort, he lifts his head and searches the room. His eyes come to rest on the form of a legless man lying in bloodsoaked sheets. He's whimpering like a child. Dunbar comes to a sitting position on the operating table. As his eyes move around the room they come to rest on a crate filled with the boots of men who have lost their legs. A cane travels through space and deftly hooks one of the boots. Lieutenant Dunbar brings the boot onto the operating table. He tries to pull it on his mangled foot, but the pain makes him cry out. Deliberately he breaks the cane and sticks a piece of it between his teeth. Tears of pain are rolling down his face. A sweat has broken out on his forehead and with great determination he pulls the boot on.</context>
      <utterance>Well I can't saw if I can't keep my eyes open. Let's coffee up... he can wait a few more minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar says nothing. He just stands and stares. It unnerves the sergeant.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant... izat you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing here lieutenant?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant stares at Dunbar's foot.</context>
      <utterance>This is where I belong... this is my outfit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You went to hospital?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A ping of riflefire flies overhead and the sergeant dives for the wall. He calls over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>It was no good... what's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar settles next to the sergeant.</context>
      <utterance>Better come to cover lieutenant... those boys are shooters.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant nods at the distant hill and Dunbar looks too.</context>
      <utterance>What's goin' on here... seems to be the question alright... you could ask the major but he don't know. He's busy tryin' to figger out how come the officer's mess run outta peach ice cream...</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he nods toward the trees behind them and the lieutenant follows. Several union men are clustered around a huge hunk of material attached to a gondola.</context>
      <utterance>General's come up to see the show but all he knows is there ain't no show...</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More riflefire comes in and some of the union men answer with a few rounds of their own. The sergeant watches the confederate line across the field through a crack in the wall. Lieutenant Dunbar is not watching the enemy. He's looking at some horses picketed in the trees behind the union lines. There's a nice bay. There's a big roan.</context>
      <utterance>We started a balloon up but they shot her down fore she was ten feet off the ground... so nobody's made a run either way. It's been a stand- off all damn day... and now... the major, he's lookin' at the general and he's thinkin' I better do somethin', and you know what that means...</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar is still watching the horses. He's holding on a small, well-muscled buckskin standing a little apart from the others.</context>
      <utterance>They're 'sposed to be beat up just like us but everybody knows that Tucker's men are tough as cobs. I sure don't wanna die out there with them cows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tide lowers the telescope, glances at the aide and peers back down at the field.</context>
      <utterance>What is it sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like a suicide.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar gazes down along his leg. Blood is pumping from his wound.</context>
      <utterance>Alright by me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again he digs his heels into the buckskin's flanks and they fly down the line. The confederates are trying to reload. A few are able to get off a hasty shot, but they're all too late.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me Father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>General Tide stares down into Dunbar's blank face. He kneels next to the lieutenant and bends to whisper in his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Don't take off my foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL TIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The general looks up at one of his aides.</context>
      <utterance>You rest easy son... you'll keep you're foot. As God is my judge, you'll keep it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL TIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring up my ambulance...</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL TIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The aide dashes off to do what he's told, as General Tide gently removes Dunbar's foot from the stirrup and lays it carefully on the ground. The image fades out.</context>
      <utterance>Bring up my ambulance. And bring my surgeon with it. We've got an officer who's worth something lying here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where can I find Major... Fambrough?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Being roughly the same age and rank these two might idle awhile, but Dunbar is eager. He's already moving.</context>
      <utterance>Turn right... all the way to the end of the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lt. John J. Dunbar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar stops and turns, peering down the hallway. No one is there.</context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lt. Dunbar is standing in front of the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Lt. John J. Dunbar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indian fighter, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not ascend to this position by being stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fambrough returns to the order. Dunbar watches him in silence. The major's tunic is covered with food stains. Sweat has broken out all over his head. His grooming is awful. His hands are trembling slightly. Something is very wrong with him. Now the major sees something on the official paper. He looks quickly at the lieutenant, then back at the paper, moving his lips but making no sound.</context>
      <utterance>No sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says here you've been decorated.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they sent you out here to be posted?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually sir, I'm here at my own request... I want to see the frontier.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to see the frontier?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The major fixes Dunbar with a sly look.</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir... before it's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still sly, Fambrough digs into a side drawer. There is the distinct clink of glass on glass as he rummages. Now Fambrough has what he wants, a blank official form. He begins to fill it out, writing in a disturbingly childish way.</context>
      <utterance>Such a smart lad coming straight to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over his work with a schoolboy's excitement and affixes his signature with a wild flourish.</context>
      <utterance>Sir Knight, I am sending you on a knight's errand. You will report to Captain Cargill at the furthermost outpost of the realm... Fort Sedgewick.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He folds the order and hands it to Dunbar.</context>
      <utterance>My personal seal will assure you safe passage through many miles of wild hostile country.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm wondering sir, how will I be getting there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I don't know?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir, it's just that I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The major turns in his chair to stare through a single, dusty window. He can see a teamster outside, tying down canvas on a heavily-loaded wagon.</context>
      <utterance>Hold your tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar stands and salutes. Fambrough returns it snappily. The lieutenant starts for the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in a generous mood and will grant your boon. You see that peasant... he calls himself Timmons... he leaves this very afternoon for your Fort Sedgewick. Ride with him if you like... he knows the way. That is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Dunbar turns around. Fambrough is standing in front of his desk. There's a large, dark splotch on the major's trouser front. He jams both of his hands into the front of his pants and giggles.</context>
      <utterance>Sir Knight...</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just pissed in my pants... and nobody can do anything about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noooo, noooo...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Elgin sees a GRIZZLED SERGEANT approaching Fambrough from the opposite direction.</context>
      <utterance>It's alright Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fambrough turns on the voice behind him and waves his pistol at the sergeant.</context>
      <utterance>Leave him alone lieutenant... he's cracked.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Fambrough finds himself staring at the barrel of the sergeant's raised pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Nooo, nooo...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a panic Fambrough wheels back on Lieutenant Elgin.</context>
      <utterance>Don't sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly and kindly, Elgin is walking toward him. He holds out his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Are you deaf fool. I said I'll have my crown this instant... this instant!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's have the pistol.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the lieutenant keeps his hand held out. Fambrough eyes him silently. Then he screws up his face like a crybaby.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAMBROUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In one swift motion, Fambrough brings the revolver up, swallows the barrel and pulls the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>The king is dead... long live the king.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Dunbar stops his writing.</context>
      <utterance>We have been gone four days now and still we have seen no signs of life. Only earth and sky.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far do you make the fort?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Far.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty or fifty miles, maybe... what's the big hurry on Sedgewick?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going to be my post... my home.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Timmons slows the wagon and stops. He has seen something.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't hard to please, I'll say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look yonder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARGILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At last there's some real movement behind one of the holes and CORPORAL GUEST crawls through one of the curtains. He neither salutes nor speaks. He blinks down at Cargill, looking more like a hobo than a soldier.</context>
      <utterance>Corporal Guest... Corporal Guest... Corporal Guest. Corporal Guest, you don't have to talk to me... just please come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARGILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the end... assemble the men in front of my quarters.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response from the deep-sleeping driver. Dunbar starts to move closer to shake him awake but the odor under there makes him think twice. He snatches up the arrow and probes under the wagon.</context>
      <utterance>Timmons... Timmons.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The teamster comes awake with a squeal, he joins Dunbar staring up at the circling birds.</context>
      <utterance>Timmons.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something's out there...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somethin' dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might have a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Timmons' mood is different now. He begins to hitch the team with a new sense of urgency.</context>
      <utterance>Might stay clear of whatever did the killin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come we haven't seen any buffalo?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't figger the stinkin' buffalo. Sometimes you don't see 'em for days, sometimes they're thick as curls on a whore.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Indians?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Timmons, as usual, laughs at his own imagined wit. The wagon disappears over a ridge and again, Dunbar is alone. In gentle awe, he runs his palm over the top of the grass swirling about his waist. A meadow lark's mournful call startles him. Dunbar brings his head up at the sound and so does Cisco. Now there's a sudden lifting of the breeze. It sweeps through the valley, making the grass roll with a life of its own. The lark's sad call and the sudden violent movement of the wind sends a shudder through Lieutenant Dunbar. He scans the horizon in all directions, aware all at once of his aloneness. He flips the reins over Cisco's neck and sticks a foot in the stirrup. Dunbar heads for the ridge.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn Indians you'd jus' as soon not see, lessen the bastards're dead. Nothing but thieves and beggars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar appears from Cargill's former quarters.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't nothin' here lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The lieutenant looks briefly at Timmons, and marches over to the caved-in supply house. Again he ducks inside. Dunbar emerges from the supply house and stares up at the wagon driver.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody's run off... or got kilt.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright...lets unload the wagon.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, and leave it all here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm staying too... we don't know what's happened. Dunbar moves around to the back of the wagon.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There ain't nothin' here lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at the moment, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So things bein' the way they are we might as well turn around and get started back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my post...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lieutenant's eyes have gone absolutely black. The heel of his hand is dropping lightly on the butt of a long revolver at his hip.</context>
      <utterance>This is my... are you crazy boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Timmons leaps down.</context>
      <utterance>This is my post! And these are the post's provisions. Now get your ass off that wagon and help me unload.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I'll let 'em know where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Timmons clucks to his team and the wagon pulls out. The light on the prairie is fading fast.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE TOUGHEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only a white man would make a fire for everyone to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST PAWNEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Toughest turns back to face the others. Without another word, he jumps on his horse. Another silence as the three warriors consider what to do.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe there's more than one.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND PAWNEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have no rifles. White men are sure to have rifles.</utterance>
   <speaker>3RD PAWNEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Toughest has listened all the while, growing more and more disgusted. He pulls the blanket from his shoulders and flings it angrily at his companions.</context>
      <utterance>We should forget this and go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUGHEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts his pony walking down the rise toward the smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Then go. I for one, will not debate the merit of a single line of smoke in my own country.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST PAWNEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Third Pawnee starts after the Toughest. The other two follow.</context>
      <utterance>He will not quit until we are all dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He sticks a hand in his overcoat, pulls out a piece of dried meat and bites off a hunk. Dunbar starts down the hill toward the fort. He watches the horizon as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>No sign of Captain Cargill's command. I don't know what to do. Communication can only take place if I leave and I don't want to abandon my post.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Made a short patrol yesterday p.m... discovered nothing. Will go further tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A great bolt of lightning strikes outside, filling the room with violent white light. Dunbar walks to the door and tosses out a handful of bones. Two Socks scurries to collect the bones and retreats under the shelter of a nearby tree.</context>
      <utterance>Almost a month and no one has come. The longer this condition persists, the less inclined I am to believe that anyone will. Rain has forced me indoors for most of two days. I have begun an awning. The work has ruined my hands, but I am excited about the improvement it will bring to this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is the loneliest of times... but I cannot say that I am unhappy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Finished, he retreats to his bunk and sits staring across at his new window. He glances at the journal by his side and has a thought. He picks it up and starts to write.</context>
      <utterance>Have made all the preparations I can think of. I cannot mount an adequate defense but will try to make a big impression when they come. Waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man I encountered was a magnificent looking fellow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old woman looks up from her pounding but does not respond.</context>
      <utterance>Kicking Bird has been keeping to himself these last few days. I do not like to see our medicine man walking so alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does his wife say?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRETTY SHIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten Bears gives his wife a challenging look and she bristles.</context>
      <utterance>He is keeping to himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRETTY SHIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten Bears accepts this. Then he looks down at the bowl.</context>
      <utterance>That's what she says.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten Bears looks once more at the entrance of Kicking Bird's lodge.</context>
      <utterance>Make sure that meat is soft... my teeth hurt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little boy races over to the old chief, Kicking Bird makes a move to pull him back, but Ten Bears indicates the boy should stay.</context>
      <utterance>May I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is silence as the two men settle themselves by the fire, the little boy content in Ten Bears' lap.</context>
      <utterance>No, no let him sit with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our country seems good this summer, but I have not been out to see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... it is good. The grass is rich. The game is plenty and not running away.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A brief silence.</context>
      <utterance>I am glad to hear it. But the buffalo are late. I always worry about the bellies of our children.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking of a dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird seems suddenly uncomfortable. The little boy leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, a dance is always a good idea. It would be good to have a strong sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten Bears picks up the pipe and puffs away, seemingly without care.</context>
      <utterance>There's a funny thing about signs. They are always flying in our faces. We know when they are bad or good but sometimes they are strange and there is no way to understand them. Sometimes they make people crazy but a smart man will take such a sign into himself and let it run around for two or three days. If he is still confused he will tell somebody. He might come to you or to me and tell it. A smart man always does that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have seen such a sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten Bears' eyes get big for a moment. Then he thinks.</context>
      <utterance>I saw a man, a white man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just one?</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten Bears thinks some more.</context>
      <utterance>Just one. He was naked.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure it was a man?</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw his sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you speak to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten Bears rubs at his old eyes with both hands.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will council on this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a little murmuring around the fire, and it goes silent. Wind In His Hair rises to speak.</context>
      <utterance>He might be a god or he might be a special chief -- that's why we are thinking of having a talk with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not care for this talk about a white man. Whatever kind of white man he is, he is not Sioux and that makes him less. We've camped here for ten days now and each day our scouts find nothing. One old bull with wolves tearing him apart, nothing more. We need meat -- not talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird pauses here. Everyone is listening attentively.</context>
      <utterance>You are right, we need meat today and tomorrow. But we must also have meat in ten years.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the whites are coming. Our friends the Shoshone and the Kiowa, even our enemies, agree on this -- the whites are coming. More than can be counted.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a surge of enthusiasm in the lodge and Wind In His Hair is riding the crest of it.</context>
      <utterance>Kicking Bird is always looking ahead and that is good. But when I hear that more whites are coming -- more than can be counted I want to laugh. We took a hundred horses from these people, there was no honor in it. They don't ride well, they don't shoot well, they're dirty. They have no women, no children. They could not even make it through one winter in our country. And these people are said to flourish? I think they will all be dead in ten years.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This parting shot prompts a good-natured round of laughter.</context>
      <utterance>I think this white man is probably lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wind In His Hair has spoken straight, his words are strong and I have heard them. It's true the whites are a poor race and it's hard to understand them. But when I see one white man alone, without fear in our country, I do not think he is lost. I think he may have medicine. I see someone who might speak for all the white people who are coming. I think this is a person with which treaties might be struck.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is the best idea so far and there is much talk around the fire. They quiet down as Ten Bears prepares to speak.</context>
      <utterance>This white man cannot cover our lodges, or string our bows, or feed our children. I will take some good men... there are many here tonight. We will ride to the soldier fort, we will shoot some arrows into this white man. If he truly has medicine he will not be hurt. If he has no medicine he will be dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops his head, closes his eyes and starts to fall asleep. The meeting is over.</context>
      <utterance>It is easy to become confused by these questions. It is hard to know what to do. No man can tell another how he will be. But I know this... killing a white man is a delicate matter. If you kill one, more are sure to come. We should talk about this some more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter now?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiles a Lot trots his pony over to Otter.</context>
      <utterance>Otter doesn't want to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we take the horse of a white god they will make up songs about us.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will ask us to go on raids.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who gets the white god horse?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Otter and Worm have blank expressions.</context>
      <utterance>I do... but we share... you and Worm can ride him too. Who can say this is not a great plan?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me take him Otter.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To Smiles A Lot's amazement, Otter is suddenly gone. He's zooming backward in midair. Otter comes to ground a few yards back, throwing up a puff of dust. Cisco has screeched to a halt. Now he rears up, twisting until the rope is free of Otter. Then he sticks his tail in the air and makes tracks in the direction of the fort. Worm chases after Cisco as Smiles A Lot sees to Otter</context>
      <utterance>I have him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. My arm doesn't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't have fallen down... now we'll get in trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was your idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This squabble is interrupted by Worm's return. He gallops up and jumps off his pony.</context>
      <utterance>My idea was only to take the horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worm shakes his head in frustration. Otter grabs a handful of dirt and flings it at Smiles A Lot and Worm.</context>
      <utterance>Otter hurt himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not hurt... I'm hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will be when my father finds out, his bow will be across my back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COURIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wind In His Hair says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>The party that went against the Pawnee is coming in...</utterance>
   <speaker>COURIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are many hearts on the ground.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's still backing down the hill, her steps a little faster now. He's following her at a walk.</context>
      <utterance>Wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's reached the base of the knoll and has begun to run. Dunbar is trotting after her.</context>
      <utterance>Wait... you're hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's too weak to run and falls face first in the grass. She starts to crawl. Dunbar slips off Cisco and reaches down tentatively for her shoulder. She screams at his touch and he pulls away. But he follows on foot as she crawls.</context>
      <utterance>Let me help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her again, this time holding her firmly. She struggles mightily, twisting onto her back. She lashes out at his face but he grabs her hands, holding them tight. They're nose to nose.</context>
      <utterance>You're hurt... you need help.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't believe he heard it and she can't believe she said it. She spits out a Stream of Sioux curses, throws her head back and wails like a wolf. Then she passes out.</context>
      <utterance>Don't...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sioux buzz is stronger now. The mounted warriors are getting excited. Suddenly, Wind In His Hair breaks ranks and starts for Dunbar at a determined walk. A nasty war club is held tightly in hand. Dunbar stands his ground. Wind In His Hair halts only a few steps in front of Dunbar. He barks at the intruder as he takes another step or two.</context>
      <utterance>She's hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another step and he is close enough to touch the white man.</context>
      <utterance>You are not welcome here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar doesn't flinch. And Wind In His Hair's harangue is definitely part bluster. He's very curious about the woman in Dunbar's arms and now he peers down at her face. The lieutenant looks down too and in a flash she is torn out of his grasp. Holding her in one strong arm, Wind In His Hair backs a pace or two and shouts once more at the lieutenant.</context>
      <utterance>Go away from us...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his club and shakes it at Dunbar. Though he doesn't understand the words, Dunbar gets the message. As he goes for his horse, Wind In His Hair marches back to his people with Stands With A Fist. There is great commotion as the crowd surges in around Wind In His Hair. With a look of profound disappointment, Dunbar walks away on Cisco.</context>
      <utterance>Go away from us... go now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am in agreement with Kicking Bird. We will go down and talk to the white man and find out what kind of white man he is. Wind In His Hair jumps into the conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are many yeses in response to this. As is his custom, Ten Bears lets the outburst subside, seeming unruffled all the while. Casually, he pops a piece of meat into his mouth and begins to chew.</context>
      <utterance>If this council decides to talk with the man at the soldier fort then it will be so. But in my mind it is not right that a Sioux chief, a chief as great as Ten Bears, goes to ask the business of a puny, trespassing white man... a white soldier who has only a smart horse and a few white man clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not go... you will go... you and Kicking Bird. That is all I have to say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men slide off their ponies. Dunbar throws an unreturned wave to the escort warriors. There is a moment or two of silence.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome...  Come... please... sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no response.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like some coffee? Coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar disappears inside his quarters.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get some cups.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar reaches for a sack by the fire. Holding it in front of him, Dunbar suggests that Wind In His Hair put some of its contents into his mug. Wind In His Hair finally does, but his blank expression indicates that he doesn't know what difference this could make. Dunbar takes a lick at his fingers, suggesting that Wind In His Hair should do the same. A smile creeps over his face as the universal appeal of sugar is taking hold. Wind In His Hair has licked every bit off each finger.</context>
      <utterance>Is the coffee not good? Too strong maybe? Here...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wind In His Hair doesn't wait for Kicking Bird's answer. He reaches over and dumps a good amount in Kicking Bird's cup, adding some more to his own for good measure.</context>
      <utterance>Do you want some?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no response. Wind In His Hair's attention is now on Cisco.</context>
      <utterance>So what are you guys doing? Looking for buffalo?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wind In His Hair's interest borders on rude. Prompted by a light tap on his leg from Kicking Bird, Wind In His Hair turns his attention back to Dunbar.</context>
      <utterance>He's a good one... good horse. My horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No argument from Wind In His Hair.</context>
      <utterance>Good horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird and Wind In His Hair are baffled. The lieutenant is trying to jam a wadded blanket under the back of his tunic.</context>
      <utterance>My horse. You see any buffalo?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait just a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird doesn't respond. He's still intent on the lieutenant. In wedging the blanket under his tunic, Dunbar has become a hunchback. He bends over in a weird attitude, and with a finger peeking over each side of his head, he begins a bizarre display of dancing, punctuated with snorts and bellows.</context>
      <utterance>His mind is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffalo.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffalo?</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffalo.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird nods his assent and Dunbar flashes a pleased smile.</context>
      <utterance>Buffalo.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffalo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Dunbar is standing in the same spot, it is a new day Leaving their ever present escort behind, Kicking Bird and Wind In His Hair ride into the fort. Kicking Bird's pony is carrying something large and bulky on his withers. A buffalo robe. Dunbar walks up to greet them. Kicking Bird returns the welcome and signs to him as he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>They have come again, as always the same two with an escort of six.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar throws his customary wave but the escort remains noncommittal.</context>
      <utterance>Have you seen any buffalo? Dunbar can only shake his head no. Kicking Bird accepts this and dismounts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He rolls on his back, and lays aside the journal, practicing the hand signals.</context>
      <utterance>I believe I am dealing with Kiowa Indians as I have heard that word on several occasions.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am learning the Kiowa words for head, hand, horse, fire, coffee, buffalo, hello and goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar suggests they take some of his supplies but Kicking Bird will not stand for this. He waves Dunbar off. The three men say their goodbyes, and Dunbar as usual throws a wave to the six men on the hill. Unexpectedly, one of them returns it and the other five react with surprise.</context>
      <utterance>No, I haven't seen any buffalo. Are you hungry? I have food... are you hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESCORT 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He waved.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird and Wind In His Hair disappear over the hill, followed by their escort. Lightning bursts far out on the prairie.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing I have been told about these people is correct. They are not beggars and thieves. They are not the bogeymen they have been made out to be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She looks up to see the medicine man looming over her.</context>
      <utterance>Stands With A Fist.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will talk awhile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your wounds are healing well?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are happy here, with my family?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am glad to be here. I am missing my husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you will marry again when the time is right.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird is leading up to something and Stands With A Fist fears it. She keeps her head bowed.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird stops himself, he knows this must be hard. She brings her green eyes to bear on the medicine man, waiting to hear more.</context>
      <utterance>We have word from many places that the whites are...</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses letting this sink in.</context>
      <utterance>They are coming into everyone's country. They will soon be in ours I think. This white man who lives at the old soldier fort, the one who calls himself loo ten tant... I have visited him and I believe his heart is a good one. He knows things about the whites which we do not.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am afraid of the man at the fort.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is only one man.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am afraid that he will tell some whites that I am here. I am afraid that they will try to take me away.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is not much reassured by this. In the way of a defeatist she lowers her eyes once more.</context>
      <utterance>Every warrior in camp would fight them if they tried.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird waits. Still she does not raise her head.</context>
      <utterance>I cannot make the white man talk. Loo ten tant does not know Sioux.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a certain medicine which no other Sioux -- man or woman -- has.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has been a long time since I made the talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not ask this for myself... I ask this for all our people.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's dead in me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to try and remember the the word.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This outburst shocks Stands With A Fist, she runs out of the lodge.</context>
      <utterance>You don't want to know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will she make the white words?</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps I am asking too much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, the little girl gets up and looks over the edge of the roof to see her mother holding yet another child. She seems anxious.</context>
      <utterance>Christine... where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm right here mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get inside both of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FOUR PAWNEE are riding up in the background. TWO MEN are moving out to meet them.</context>
      <utterance>Just do what I... oh God! Stay where you are. Keep down do you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie is peeking over the edge of the roof. An old muzzle- loading rifle is by his side. He whispers to her.</context>
      <utterance>Who is it Willie?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down in the yard, out beyond a rough table set with the leavings of a Sunday dinner, two white men on foot are talking to the four mounted Pawnee warriors. It's an argument. As a baby cries somewhere inside the house the two white men sign the Indians to go away. The Pawnee make no move to go however, and with their patience at an end, the two white men turn back to the house. One of the warriors brings his hatchet down and nails a white man between the shoulder blades. The injured man grunts and hops sideways. The other runs for the house but is cut down by arrows. Women begin to scream. Willie is scooting down the roof, his face white with fear.</context>
      <utterance>They look like Pawnee... my father and your father are talking to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run Christine...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a hard shove which sends her rolling down the roof.</context>
      <utterance>Just run!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine runs past the point where the roof meets the natural hillside and down into the draw. She's running toward us. In the background we can see Willie on the edge of the roof, aiming his squirrel gun into the yard. He fires once, then grasping the gun like a club, he leaps off the roof and disappears. Christine never looks back. She runs up the draw as fast as her skinny young legs can carry her.</context>
      <utterance>Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird doesn't understand or can't hear. He brings his face close to Dunbar's.</context>
      <utterance>Buffalo...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffalo...  Buffalo.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffalo?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird raises up and yells it out to his people.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Buffalo.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a fleeting moment there is shocked silence. Then the Sioux explode with excitement. Still dazed, Dunbar is pulled to his feet. The people are surging in around him with yelps of joy.</context>
      <utterance>The buffalo have come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She listens. The hoofbeats are gone.</context>
      <utterance>Help...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment later, hands are clawing at the walls of the burrow and she is looking into three, surprised Sioux faces. The face in the center is recognizable. A YOUNGER KICKING BIRD.</context>
      <utterance>Help me...  Please... I need to get out. Someone is coming up the slope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Sioux voice, using english words, sails out of the circle of watchers.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I knew what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Startled the men turn to the sound. The other Sioux are stunned too.</context>
      <utterance>Say... thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His speed... his power... you have.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the warrior's hand in his own and shakes it crisply.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wind In His Hair doesn't seem to hear. He points at the epaulettes on Dunbar's tunic.</context>
      <utterance>Look I'm full... I can't tell the story again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wind In His Hair reaches out and fingers the gold lieutenant's bars. He fingers a couple of the brass buttons as well. The tunic is something he obviously puts much store in.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unbuttons the tunic.</context>
      <utterance>You want to try... put it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sloughs off the tunic and hands it over. Wind In His Hair slips out of the magnificent bone-pipe breastplate he's wearing and gives it to Dunbar as he wriggles into the tunic. The fit is too tight, the material too scratchy but those things are of little consequence to Wind In His Hair. He loves the tunic. With urging signs he asks the lieutenant to put on the breastplate. Dunbar slips it over his head and Wind In His Hair helps him with the ties. Now it's the lieutenant's turn to be amazed. The breastplate as craftsmanship at its finest. He runs his fingers over the ridges of bone now covering him from neck to waist. He looks up at Wind In His Hair. The warrior nods approvingly, as though a good deal has heen struck.</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But for Wind In His Hair it is already a trade. Wind In His Hair spots the next fireside and veers toward it. Dunbar holds him back.</context>
      <utterance>This is too much... I can't take this...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wind In His Hair grins. He holds up a single finger.</context>
      <utterance>I can't... No more...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more... eat...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still holding up the finger, he guides Dunbar into the firelight of the next party. Immediately, men jump up to greet the celebrities. Women begin to saw off more meat.</context>
      <utterance>I can't, I'm full... very full...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the sound of these words the cheerful talk around the fire begins to fade. Dunbar touches the top of his head and points to his hat.</context>
      <utterance>That's my hat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My hat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG WARRIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silence falls between the two men. wind In His Hair speaks.</context>
      <utterance>I found it on the prairie. It's mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That hat belongs to my friend here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG WARRIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He left it on the prairie. He didn't want it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Big Warrior shakes his head. He won't budge.</context>
      <utterance>You can see that he wants it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other men around the fire murmur their assent. The Big Warrior thinks for a moment then abruptly gets to his feet. He looks at his waist and unfastens a knife in a beautiful worked scabbard. He tosses it across to Dunbar. The lieutenant examines the trade item a moment. Now he looks back at the big warrior. A smile breaks slowly across his face and Dunbar nods. At last he smiles back. It's a trade. And at that, the cheerful voices around the fire are at it again. Dunbar takes his new knife out and as he watches the light flicker off the blade a voice comes into his ear.</context>
      <utterance>We all know that is a soldier hat. We all know who wears it. If you want to keep it that's alright. But give something for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar looks into his smiling face. He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Good trade.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He excuses himself and walks away from the light of the fire, finds himself alone in the shadows, still marveling at his breastplate.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's good. But, I have to sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is loo ten tant?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird reaches out and feels the strange material on either side of Wind In His Hair's chest.</context>
      <utterance>I ate him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I traded for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it scratch the skin?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little. But do you see how good it looks. Everyone says it looks good. Everyone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The medicine man says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>They asked me to dance...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lieutenant does a step or two, trying to explain. Finally, that strange half-smile appears on Kicking Bird's face.</context>
      <utterance>I was just dancing...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar watches a moment to see if he's done any good, then turns forward with a sour look.</context>
      <utterance>Go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar makes his way through a small, grassy valley borders by rolling slopes. He looks across the prairie. Two Socks is about fifty yards out, trotting parallel to Cisco and Dunbar. Exasperated Dunbar pulls Cisco up and slides off. Two Socks sits, waiting and watching.</context>
      <utterance>Damn him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar repeats his shooing motion and the wolf hops a few feet.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon Two Socks... you can't go... so go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar turns away and as he does a long, low and mournful howl swells behind him. He looks back. Two Socks muzzle is high in the air and one eye is trained on Dunbar hoping for a good reaction. Like an angry father who's had too much, Dunbar charges Two Sock with a roar.</context>
      <utterance>Alright then, don't go home. But stay... stay right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wolf races away this time and Dunbar immediately runs for Cisco, hoping to reach his horse and ditch Two Socks. But he's running long before the wolf comes bouncing alongside. Dunbar weaves out at him, startling Two Socks. He sidles away but as he does the lieutenant reaches out and gives the base of his tail a good hard squeeze. It might as well be a firecracker. Tow Socks gives a yelp and shoots off with his tail tucked. Dunbar laughs out loud. He watches until the wolf has gone a fair distance without sign of slowing down. Then still chuckling to himself, he turns once again and starts for Cisco at a trot. But moments later, something grabs at one of his ankles, the lieutenant's legs tangle and he goes down face first into the grass. Dunbar's lying on his belly. Not knowing what hit him, he rolls onto his side for a closer look. There's Two Socks, sitting in the grass a few feet back. Dunbar sits up cross- legged and smiles at his old friend. Two Socks catches something suddenly, perhaps from a shift in the wind, and starts to slink away. Dunbar peers over the grass up at the bluff. It's Stone Calf, Kicking Bird and Wind In His Hair.</context>
      <utterance>You go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STONE CALF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird watches Dunbar as he replies.</context>
      <utterance>You were right about loo ten tant -- he is a special white man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he is special... he should have a real name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not everyone thinks it is a good idea that he is here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wind In His Hair turns to the people that have gathered about.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kicking Bird has business with the white man. Let him do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist ducks through the arbor's entrance and seats herself between Dunbar and Kicking Bird. Stands With A Fist is wearing a band of bells around one ankle. She has a pair of simple but pretty moccasins on her feet. Her dress is old but well-cared for. Animal teeth are sewn along her bodice. On her wrist is a solid brass bracelet. Her hair is tied back loosely with a bret, accenting the feminine in her face. Her whiteness seems to show more than ever. But it is not dominant. The Sioux is dominant.</context>
      <utterance>We were waiting for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words are sweet music to the lieutenant. He replies with a feeling of great relief.</context>
      <utterance>Hullo. You here... good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you... I feel good.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He thanks you. It is good.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask him why he is at the soldier fort.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar jumps in. There are things he wants to know, has waited a long time to know.</context>
      <utterance>Uhh... you... come...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait... what is your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our... names?</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to know how we are called.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The medicine man nods agreeably. He smiles at Dunbar, quite right, introductions should come first.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh... He's right. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He... he... Kick...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kick?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kicks at the ground with the toe of her moccasin. Dunbar doesn't get it. She kicks a little harder.</context>
      <utterance>More.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kicking?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kicking... yes... Kicking... Bird.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist has the word but it takes a few seconds to make it come out of her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Kicking Bird...  What does he... is he a chief?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hul... hal... ho-lee... holy... holy man.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A brief silence. Kicking Bird seems ready to speak but Dunbar is too quick.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks. It's hard. She smiles thinly.</context>
      <utterance>Your name... you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An idea comes to her. She stands up quickly.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up? Get up?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She repeats the movement again.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her smile is a little wider this time.</context>
      <utterance>Stand.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar starts to speak but she cuts him off.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... Stands.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She draw something in the dirt. It's an "A".</context>
      <utterance>More...  Wiff...  With.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she makes a fist and holds it close to Dunbar's face.</context>
      <utterance>Stands With A...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods.</context>
      <utterance>Fist?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stands With A Fist. I'm John... John Dunbar.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John Dunbar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird and Stands With A Fist are walking away from Dunbar, who takes a few steps in the opposite direction before pausing. Toward the end of the following speech he glances back at them and Stands With A Fist glances back at him.</context>
      <utterance>I try to answer all of Kicking Bird's questions but I know he is frustrated with me. He always wants to know how many more white people are coming. I tell him that it is impossible for me to say. When he persists I tell him that the white people will most likely pass through this country and nothing more.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I am speaking to him in half- truths. One day there will be too many, but I cannot bring myself to tell him that. I am sure that Stands With A Fist knows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The lodge flap rustles and in comes Stands With A Fist and Kicking Bird. Dunbar stands to greet them.</context>
      <utterance>A war party is going against the Pawnee soon and I have asked to go. I sensed that I have made a mistake in doing so but I could not bring myself to take it back. They are my friends and from what little I gather the Pawnee have been very hard on these people. I hope I have not overstepped my bounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird speaks and Stands With A Fist translates.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad to see you... please sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kicking Bird wants to know why you want to make war on the Pawnee. They have done nothing to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are Sioux enemies.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only Sioux warriors will go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked that he would think about my going.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then tell him this. I have been a warrior for longer than many of the young men that will go on this war party. Tell him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says that the Sioux way of being a warrior is not the white way. You are not ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She translates this to Kicking Bird. The medicine man hesitates then speaks once more.</context>
      <utterance>I know, I understand. But I cannot learn these ways in camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dunbar looks to Kicking Bird then to Stands With A Fist unable to mask his disappointment.</context>
      <utterance>He asks that you watch over his family while he is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will be happy to watch over your family.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He thanks Dances With Wolves for coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is Dances With Wolves?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thinks and remembers the night with Two Socks.</context>
      <utterance>It is the name which everyone is calling you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves... that's right.  How do you say it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNBAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The medicine man smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep on with the white man talk if it pleases you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves is standing alone in front of his lodge. Wind In His Hair is riding past. He reaches down and shakes Dances With Wolves' hand. The big warrior smiles. Dances With Wolves watches the warriors go by, but his eyes begin to wander. He's looking for someone among the faces of the women. Who ever it is, he can't find her.</context>
      <utterance>I like to make the white man talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grass grows on the prairie.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist chuckles but politely checks herself.</context>
      <utterance>Fire lives on the prairie.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and tries again.</context>
      <utterance>Wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He really wants to get one right on the first try. His brows come together as he concentrates.</context>
      <utterance>That man is a fighter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He listens hard.</context>
      <utterance>Again.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves thinks some more. When he speaks it is with quiet confidence.</context>
      <utterance>That man is a fighter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright... I have it...  That man...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves' eyes get big. He leans forward for emphasis his whole face lit with the joy of having the right answer.</context>
      <utterance>Is...</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist doubles up and falls onto her side, laughing all the way.</context>
      <utterance>A... bone!</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist doesn't really hear. She's rocking back and forth on the floor of the arbor, laughing so hard that her eyes are tearing. Her laughter subsides to an occasional chuckle but Dances With Wolves is quiet. He gazes at her face.</context>
      <utterance>A bone... right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist hesitates in her answer, meeting his gaze. A little boy pokes his head in.</context>
      <utterance>What is the word for beautiful?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment is broken. Stands With A Fist brings herself to respond.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This makes so much sense to the little boy that he trots in and flings himself on Stands With a Fist's lap. Then a squirm or two.</context>
      <utterance>It is hot. We are sitting in the shade.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist leads the little boy off to a lodge. Dances With Wolves watches her walk away. From out of nowhere, Smiles A Lot appears. He's been milling about the arbor eavesdropping, and looks over to Dunbar with a teasing smile.</context>
      <utterance>Alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...a bone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist stares straight ahead as if she were wondering the same thing. Which she was.</context>
      <utterance>How is Dances With Wolves?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is he learning?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Case closed, she goes back to playing and Black Shawl continues putting the kids to bed. She looks again at Stands With A Fist wondering "what did you think I meant?"</context>
      <utterance>He learns well... he is fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His Sioux is perfect, and she smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You go for water?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let us take you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist smiles to herself as she fills up the last of the bags.</context>
      <utterance>How did you get your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lugs the filled bags onto shore and sits next to Dances With Wolves.</context>
      <utterance>I was not very old when I came to be with the people... I was made to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I worked every day... very hard... there was a woman who didn't like me. She called me bad names... sometimes she beat me. One day she was calling me these bad names, her face in my face, and I hit her. I was not very big, but she fell down. She fell hard and didn't move. I stood over her with my fist and asked if any other woman wanted to call me bad names...  No one bothered me after that day.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little silence.</context>
      <utterance>I would not think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He taps his jaw. She makes a fist and brushes very gently at the point of his jaw. Dances With Wolves' eyes flutter. They roll up in his head and he keels over backward... out cold. She goes with the joke. Bending over him she slaps lightly at each side of his cheeks, until Dances With Wolves revives. He sits up, rubbing his jaw. Neither one acknowledges the joke and, a sudden awkwardness falls between them. Stands With A Fist fiddles shyly with the ties on the water bags while Dances With Wolves draws lines in the earth with a stick. Finally he works up the courage to ask a delicate question.</context>
      <utterance>Show me where you hit her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The question comes as a jolt to Stands With A Fist. She stops her fiddling. A visible stiffness overtakes her. She quickly stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you not married?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves doesn't know what to do. He only knows that he should not have asked the question. She slings the heavy bags over her shoulders and starts back up the path. Dances With Wolves jumps to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>I must go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the words are delivered to her back. She is already hurrying up the path with her heavy load.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Let me help...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Five ponies have wondered into the middle of the path. She kicks violently at the nearest innocent bystander. The horses shy out of the way. He's left alone at the waters edge, frustrated and confused. He watches her go for a moment. Then he lets the stick drop from his hand. He stares at it for a second then gives it a vicious little kick.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not talking today?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Black Shawl gives her a deeper look, then lets it go.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>STONE CALF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves is a little taken aback. The elder has read his mind. He decides to speak it.</context>
      <utterance>Some of your words are wrong... but you are learning fast. That is good. What can I tell you today?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time, Stone Calf leaves his work. He gives his visitor a quick and penetrating look. Then he goes back to his shield.</context>
      <utterance>I want to know about Stands With A Fist.</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE CALF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your question?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stone Calf considers before he speaks. It is not something he wants to get into.</context>
      <utterance>There is no man with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE CALF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is in mourning.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not understand "mourning".</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE CALF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is crying for someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crying for who?</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE CALF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blood has gone out of Dances With Wolves' face. He tries to digest this.</context>
      <utterance>It is not polite to speak of the dead... But I will tell you... you are new. She cries for her husband. He was killed not long ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long will she cry?</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE CALF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is Kicking Bird's place to say when she is finished.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist stiffens a bit.</context>
      <utterance>People are talking about you...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist is quiet.</context>
      <utterance>They are proud of the medicine you are making with Dances With Wolves.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have hurt him and I must go talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist bolts up, racing to the lodge flap -- she pulls it aside and is stunned by the sight of Dances With Wolves' abandoned lodge -- Cisco is nowhere to be seen. She turns away, tears coming to her eyes. Black Shawl is beside her watching -- the girl's emotions have betrayed her. Black Shawl takes the crying girl into her arms. A child runs into the lodge but Black Shawl indicates "not now." The message is clearly understood, and the child digs in his heels and heads the other way.</context>
      <utterance>You can't, he is gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am in mourning.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She presses her body full against his, feeling all of him.</context>
      <utterance>I know... Stone Calf told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one can know... we must be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She climbs higher into his arms for a moment. Then, supporting each other, the lovers move into the cover of the willow breaks along the river.</context>
      <utterance>We must be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiles A Lot, Worm and Otter are sitting pathside. Worm is holding a sack.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiles A Lot looks to Stands With A Fist.</context>
      <utterance>Nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worm opens the sack. A large, wriggling snake lies in the bottom.</context>
      <utterance>Nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got a snake.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna see if it can swim the river. You wanna come?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two parties split up and everyone says goodbye to Stands With A Fist. She makes her way up to the village. Dances With Wolves watches her go. Turning back to head down to the river, he is greeted by the open hissing mouth of Worm's snake.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worm and Otter laugh and race off down the path. Smiles A Lot and Dances With Wolves follow, Dances With Wolves a little ahead. Something on his back, something curious, has captured Smiles A Lot's attention. There's a strange coating of fuzz on Dances With Wolves' back. Something occurs to Smiles A Lot. He stops and turns, his eyes going up the trail. Stands With A Fist is walking toward the village, it's there on her back too... cattail fuzz. Smiles A Lot laughs and runs to catch Dances With Wolves. The boy slaps Dunbar with a knowing pat and a big grin.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do that!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stone Calf is just passing by. Dances With Wolves stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Pawnee... a big party... thirty or forty men.  The Kiowa hunters found them not far to the north. The Pawnee are coming his way. Soon they will find our camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The older man doesn't mince words.</context>
      <utterance>Stone Calf... I follow you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE CALF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves nods.</context>
      <utterance>The Pawnee do not come for horses, they come for blood... and with many men gone, we are few.</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE CALF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your weapons and come to my lodge.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rushes off and Dances With Wolves falls into step behind Stone Calf. He hasn't gone two steps before a revelation hits him.</context>
      <utterance>I will go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The older warrior faces him.</context>
      <utterance>Stone Calf... wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have guns... many far-shooting guns.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, the ride is long... the weather is bad. We can spare no men.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The idea intrigues Ten Bears. As he thinks, he looks to Stone Calf. But the elder warrior says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Guns would make one warrior like two.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves turns away now, hoping to make a quick choice. But in their excitement all the warriors are busy running to and fro. Only one person is standing resolutely. He is staring straight at Dances With Wolves. It is Smiles A Lot, and from the look on his face it's easy to see that he wants to be chosen. Dances With Wolves returns the boy's stare, trying to make up his mind. He turns to Ten Bears.</context>
      <utterance>Take one man and go quickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten Bears looks briefly at Smiles A Lot. He too can see resolve in the boy's face. Now he looks once again at Dances With Wolves. He nods.</context>
      <utterance>I will take Smiles A Lot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone is waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Hear us now.  A white soldier with many far-shooting guns... how would he fight the Pawnee?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The warriors send up a chorus of derisive cries but Ten Bears angrily quiets them.</context>
      <utterance>I would hide in the village.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves has not finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten Bears smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I would let the enemy think we are asleep... let him come close. Then we would shoot together and run to fight them, drive them into the river and kill so many that they would never trouble us again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am of the same mind as Dances With Wolves... we should kill so many that they never trouble us again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SIOUX 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I killed this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIOUX 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sioux victors are in high spirits as they hop around finishing off the wounded and counting coup on the dead. Dances With Wolves looks down at himself. His body is streaked with blood, much of it his own. His arm is bleeding freely but he is too repulsed to move forward and too exhausted to retreat into the breaks. Dances With Wolves now looks up to see the lifeless body of Stone Calf. Ten Bears is hugging him. Pretty Shield starts to kneel beside her mourning husband.</context>
      <utterance>This one still breathes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIOUX 3</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Before he knows it, Sioux fighters are moving all around him, chanting his name. Like ants rolling a pebble up a hill, they push him into the middle of the battlefield. In a daze he allows himself to be carried along. When he looks up again he can see women and children emerging from the lodges.</context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves...</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves looks down and recognizes the face of a man he has just killed. Several warriors are crowding around him now. Dances With Wolves points at the body.</context>
      <utterance>It was hard to know how to feel. I had never been in a battle like this one. This had not been a fight for territory or riches or to make men free. This battle had no ego. It had been fought to preserve the food stores that would see us through winter, to protect the lives of women and children and loved ones only a few feet away. I felt a pride I had never felt before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shot this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST WARRIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I saw you shoot him.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND WARRIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the sun breaks fully through the clouds, the little knot of warriors, Dances With Wolves in their midst, continues its triumphant tour of the battleground. The men are hugging and slapping each other on the back.</context>
      <utterance>You killed that one too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had never really known who John Dunbar was. Perhaps because the name itself had no meaning. But as I heard my Sioux name being called over and over, I knew for the first time who I really was.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is gambling tonight... at Horse Back's lodge. Horse Back's games are always good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slips out. In a few seconds, the men have pick up another topic to jawbone. They pay no attention to Stands With A Fist's momentary exit, But Black Shawl does, it doesn't bother her, but she notices.</context>
      <utterance>I am tired... and Horse Back already has a good rifle of mine.  thank you...  goodnight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird gives his wife an odd look.</context>
      <utterance>How long will Stands With A Fist mourn?</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird rises on his elbows.</context>
      <utterance>I hope it will not be too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something has happened? Well what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has found love again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you certain of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you see them together you will know. Kicking Bird stares wearily across the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are people saying? They're not angry?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. They like the match. It makes sense. They are both white.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A brief silence.</context>
      <utterance>I suppose I will be the one to say something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird glances up frustrated with himself.</context>
      <utterance>She's your daughter now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK SHAWL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't see everything coming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stands With A Fist.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird turns abruptly and stalks off, leaving Stands With A Fist to ponder the meaning of his curt announcement. A smile gradually works onto her face.</context>
      <utterance>You are no longer a widow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's talk that you want to get married.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wind In His Hair and Smiles A Lot share a smile.</context>
      <utterance>To who?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To Stands With A Fist.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the one isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's in mourning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not today.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has been released. Kicking Bird did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wind In His Hair isn't really listening. He glances around the lodge curiously.</context>
      <utterance>He did?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kicking Bird told me to wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiles A Lot whispers in the warrior's ear.</context>
      <utterance>You might be waiting a long time. Smiles A Lot says he saw Kicking Bird riding on the prairie...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says he was talking to himself. When a medicine man is the last to know he can take it pretty hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wind In His Hair looks around at the sparse furnishing.</context>
      <utterance>What do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long silence. Dances With Wolves looks around his lodge. Wind In His Hair is right. He really has nothing.</context>
      <utterance>You are pretty poor my friend and a Sioux girl is not for free. I don't know if you can get married.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have the buckskin...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's too much medicine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiles A Lot is on the hot seat. He looks to Wind In His Hair, but no luck -- he's on his own.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think the buckskin is too much medicine?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wind In His Hair and Smiles A Lot leave.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we can help you... wait here for us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves does a three-sixty.</context>
      <utterance>Turn around...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A brief silence as Wind In His Hair contemplates something he wants to say.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty good...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, the man she mourned for was my best friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of music and people outside distracts both men.</context>
      <utterance>He was a good man. It's been hard for me. I am not the thinker Kicking Bird is. But I think he went away from her because you were coming. That is how I see it now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a good day for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shyly, she holds out a slender, graceful hand. Dances with Wolves meets it with one of his own. The medicine man looks Dances With Wolves in the eyes for several seconds. Dances With Wolves also begins to speak... internally. At first the volume of his voice and that of the medicine man are nearly equal, but Kicking Bird's voice quickly begins to fade.</context>
      <utterance>Stands With A Fist... if you want this man, take his hand in yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The medicine man's voice cuts back in. He's had to say it twice.</context>
      <utterance>I had never been married before. I don't know if all grooms have the same experience. But as Kicking Bird began to speak about what was expected of a Sioux husband, my mind began to swim in a way that shut out everything but her. The tiny details of her costume. The contours of her shape. The light in her eyes. The smallness of her feet. I knew that the love between us would be served.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you heard all that I have said?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, then take her inside... she is your wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The newlyweds disappear into their new home. The flap is dropped and there it stays. The light begins to change, growing darker, the wind comes up, blowing leaves against the door. In the distance there is thunder.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... good... thank you... goodbye...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves' door is closed alot these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two older boys look down at Otter.</context>
      <utterance>They're trying to make a baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would think they could have made a baby by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they're having a hard time. Some people have a hard time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMILES A LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think they're having a hard time.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silence as the boys watch smoke curl out of the lodge. Worm laughs to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Me neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys look at each other for the first time, their eyes brightening. What a great idea! The two boys are stalking toward Dances With Wolves' lodge when they see something that makes them peel off in another direction. It's Kicking Bird, coming to call.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should pull the smoke flap closed. Then they would come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a moment the lodge flap opens and Dances With Wolves steps outside. He's fully dressed but a little disheveled.</context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves, are you in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves ponders this.</context>
      <utterance>I am riding today to a far away place. It is a place I haven't seen for a long time. A sacred place. I would like you to come with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good to be out.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it must be.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are trying for a baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No waiting?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The medicine man keeps looking at his protege. There is virtually no semblance of Lieutenant Dunbar left.</context>
      <utterance>No waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves doesn't reply, but he is blushing a little.</context>
      <utterance>I was just thinking that of all the trails in this life, there is one that matters more than all the others. It is the trail of a true human being. I think you are on this trail and it is good to see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Kicking Bird does not acknowledge his companion's words. He seems to be concentrating on the quiet. The quiet is wrong and Kicking Bird knows it. He moves forward slowly. Following behind Kicking Bird, Dances With Wolves' attention is focused on the tree tops above him. A curious buzzing sound has started up and is growing louder by the moment. Perhaps there are bees swarming in the branches overhead. Now he is distracted by Cisco coming to a stop. Kicking Bird too has stopped. Just ahead the forest opens into an incredible cathedral-like expanse. Sunlight streams down onto the floor in beautiful pools. But still there is a deathly quiet and Dances With Wolves can see now that this remarkable place has been horribly desecrated. Trees have been felled everywhere, most of them left to rot for no explicable reason. At the same time he sees this destruction Dances With Wolves realizes that the strange buzzing sound is not coming from overhead but from the forest floor. The insects are not bees. They are flies and they are swarming over dozens of carcasses strewn over the ground. Badgers, skunks, squirrels and other small animals, nearly all of them killed merely for target practice. The men and their ponies move on. Deer carcasses are everywhere, many of them horribly mutilated. A choice flank portion is cut away here and there, while ninety-five percent of the bodies have been left to rot. Heads and legs have been chopped off. Dances With Wolves passes by a spot where several deer heads have been placed nose to nose as if the heads were having a conversation. Someone's perverted idea of humor. The men ride through the carnage in a sad daze. Now they reach the center of the cathedral and here they find a few crude leantos, hewn from freshly cut wood. The people who stayed here had bigger plans for all the felled wood, but lost ambition and settled for these ugly hovels. A great pile of wild turkeys, perhaps twenty birds in all, sit to one side. They haven't even been plucked. Just shot and left to rot. Dances With Wolves notices half a dozen liquor bottles in a heap of trash. He cannot bring himself to look at Kicking Bird. Any man would be repulsed at these sights, but in Dances With Wolves' case there is a feeling of shame as well.</context>
      <utterance>It's quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Bird says nothing for a long time.</context>
      <utterance>We must wait for these people...</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his pony away.</context>
      <utterance>No, they've been gone a week maybe more... we will water the horses and go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves looks at his friend and mentor.</context>
      <utterance>You have asked me many times about the white people... you always ask how many more are coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There will be a lot my friend... more than can be counted.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help me to know how many.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is what Kicking Bird wanted to know. And it hits him like a rock. Kicking Bird bows his head in thought while Dances With Wolves raises his. He never wanted to say this, he wishes it wasn't true.</context>
      <utterance>Like the stars.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It makes me afraid for all the Sioux.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man gets up, walks to his bedside, reaches up into the sacred rigging above an takes down a melon-sized rawhide bundle. He brings this back to the fire and unwraps it slowly. Inside is a rusted hunk of metal, the helmet of a Spanish conquistador.</context>
      <utterance>It's hard to know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up his pipe and puffs deeply.</context>
      <utterance>The men who wore this came in the time of my grandfather's grandfather. Eventually, we drove them out. Then the Mexicans came. In my own time the whites came... the Texans. They have been like all the others who find something they want in our country. They take it without asking. I have always been a peaceful man, happy to be in my own country and wanting nothing from the white people. Nothing at all. But I think you are right. I think they will keep coming. When I think of that, I look at this bundle. Our country is all that we want. We will fight to keep it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow morning we will strike the village and go to the winter camp.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have everything from the soldier fort?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands with A Fist laughs as she starts out of the lodge.</context>
      <utterance>No, there is nothing for me there.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But as he tightens the leather thongs on the shield case, Dances With Wolves' face begins to cloud.</context>
      <utterance>That's good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The words in the book are like a trail for people to follow. It tells everything about my life here. I must get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We cannot wait for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will catch up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something has happened... Dances With Wolves is not coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He must have trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pick two good men with fast ponies and send them back to the soldier fort.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>BAUER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pitiful looking man, SPIVEY, who is a soldier by name only, answers up.</context>
      <utterance>Spivey...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yessir sergeant...</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT BAUER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant's smallish eyes are fixed on Dances With Wolves. With some effort he manages to get himself into a sitting position against the back wall.</context>
      <utterance>Tell the major he's wakin' up... and move your worthless ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT BAUER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves only blinks at him. His cheek is crushed and so is his spirit. Someone calls attention and two officers walk into the roofless supply house. One is a MAJOR, one is a young lieutenant -- Lieutenant Elgin -- the officer Dances With Wolves bumped into at Fort Hays. Neither one recognizes the other.</context>
      <utterance>Got yourself a helluva shiner, didn't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does he speak english?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT BAUER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know sir... you speak english? Talk english?  Talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone is shocked at the clarity of the words.</context>
      <utterance>I speak english...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant John. J. Dunbar. This is my post.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you dressed like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The major and the lieutenant exchange whispers.</context>
      <utterance>I came out from Fort Hays last April. But there was no one here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have proof of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My journal is on the bunk in my quarters. My orders are in the journal. It will tell you everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spivey shifts uncomfortably.</context>
      <utterance>Spivey, you and Edwards were here first. Did you find anything... a journal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't see nothin' sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Edwards?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elgin indicates to the major that he will get to the bottom of this and walks out the door -- the major follows. Dances With Wolves lets his head slump forward. The men gathered around the supply house murmur among themselves, commenting on the prisoner. They can't take their eyes off him. Neither can Sergeant Bauer. He watches the prisoner from a distance. Then he walks across the floor, squats in front of him and whispers coarsely in his face.</context>
      <utterance>He's outside. But he didn't see nothin' either.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT BAUER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves lifts his head and stares at the sergeant.</context>
      <utterance>You turned Injun, din'cha?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT BAUER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The major and the lieutenant suddenly reappear.</context>
      <utterance>Din'cha?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunbar... D.U.N.B.A.R... John.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say you are an officer?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you read my orders?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was in my journal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a silence as Dances With Wolves takes this in. Elgin tries again.</context>
      <utterance>There are no orders and there is no journal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves takes a long time to answer.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you out of uniform?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to relieve myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you out of uniform?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sergeant Bauer shoves Dances With Wolves with his gun.</context>
      <utterance>What is the army doing out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAUER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elgin quickly steps in.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant's askin' the questions here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are charged with apprehending hostiles, recovering stolen property and retrieving white captives taken in hostile raidings.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no hostiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will ascertain that for ourselves. Now if you guide us to these camps and serve as an interpreter, your conduct will be reevaluated.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What conduct?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your status as a traitor might improve should you choose to cooperate with the United States Army.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you willing to cooperate or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, speak up...</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Dances With Wolves...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant... have a detail take him down to the river... let him clean up his face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CRAPPER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got paper over there Spivey?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spivey thinks.</context>
      <utterance>Well gimme some shitbird.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you read?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spivey looks down at the stolen journal, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, I can't read. What the hell do you care... you can't either.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright... hold your horses.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SERGEANT BAUER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves sticks a toe under the lip of the plate and flips it over. Most of it hits Spivey, a little splashes on Bauer. Spivey moves to kick the prisoner, but Bauer intercedes with his rifle.</context>
      <utterance>Lap it up Injun.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT BAUER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bauer and Spivey leave him and Dances With Wolves kicks out viciously at the spilled plate.</context>
      <utterance>Go on ahead Injun... You'll just get hungrier is all... but mebbe that don't matter. Word is they're gonna ship you back to Hays. And they'll hang you once you get there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SPIVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two shots ring out in rapid succession.</context>
      <utterance>Lookit the stupid bastard... he ain't even runnin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAUER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sergeant Bauer fires his own round. Everyone has missed. Bauer is jamming another cartridge into the chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot, I seen 'em first... it's my shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Spivey decides to get into the act. He rises up with his rifle aiming.</context>
      <utterance>It's my shot goddamit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can fire, there's a rattling of chains. And the next moment, Spivey's feet are being pulled out from under him by Dances With Wolves. His rifle fires harmlessly into space. Bauer turns from the wagon seat and slams the back of the prisoner's head with the gunstock. Dances With Wolves falls back, letting go of the shaken Spivey. Bauer smiles at Spivey contemptuously.</context>
      <utterance>You dumb sons a bitches.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAUER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the next instant, Spivey gives Dances With Wolves a resounding crack in the sternum with the butt of his rifle and he goes down on his back. More shots are fired. Dazedly, Dances With Wolves looks out and sees Two Socks still running parallel to the wagon. There's another shot and then shouting.</context>
      <utterance>He mighta killed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got him...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you did...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spivey is still poking Dances With Wolves.</context>
      <utterance>I got him... dead shot boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want more?... get up... get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elgin has ridden alongside the wagon.</context>
      <utterance>Spivey!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elgin's men are headed up towards Two Socks when shots ring out.</context>
      <utterance>I see you bash the prisoner once more and I'll put those shackles on you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELGIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera continues over the hill to Two Socks' body, but it is no where in sight. Instead the Indian war party of six is waiting silently in ambush. Frustrated, they will try again.</context>
      <utterance>You men! Get back to your places.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We go South?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This doesn't seem to bother Wind In His Hair. But it sets Dances With Wolves to thinking.</context>
      <utterance>We will ride South for two days... then turn East. No one must follow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have nothing to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What ever is on your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS WITH A FIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves lays his forehead on her back. He sighs. Then he pulls away, slips a robe around his shoulders and walks out of the lodge. Sadly, she watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>We have decided. You are my husband. I am your wife. That is all I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does not reply. He smokes a little more and passes the pipe.</context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves is quiet these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves glances at the men around the fire.</context>
      <utterance>Is his heart bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He searches for the right words.</context>
      <utterance>Killing the soldiers at the river was a good thing. It made me free and my heart was big to see my friends coming to help me. I did not mind killing those men. I was glad to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Objections break out all around the fire. Wind In His Hair jumps to his feet and even Kicking Bird is protesting.</context>
      <utterance>But the soldiers hate me now like they hate no other. I am more than an enemy to them, I am a traitor. They will hunt for me. They will not give up. And when they find me they find you and that cannot happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet!... sit down Wind In His Hair. You are hurting an old man's ears with your loud talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves gets up, opens the flap and admits the old chief. A few snowflakes cling to his wispy hair. He goes straight to the fire and sits.</context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stands With A Fist brings two small bowls of food, places them next to the men and busies herself with something else. Though neither one is much interested they begin to eat.</context>
      <utterance>Ahh... this is a nice fire... at my age a good fire is better than anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I wondered how your bad heart was doing and though I would come by and see for myself. This place doesn't look so bad-hearted.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we are happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you are leaving anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have talked with Stands With a Fist and we will go together.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's anguish for Dances with Wolves to think about his friends. He shakes his head "no". Ten Bears thinks again in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Have you told this to Kicking Bird or to Wind In His Hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are the only white man I have ever known. I have thought about you alot. More than you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That does not surprise me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten Bears words always have purpose and as always, he makes his point. He pauses for a moment and notices Dances with Wolves' nearly finished pipe.</context>
      <utterance>You have always spoken with your heart. And like all of us, you are a free man and can do anything you like. When I look across this fire, I do not see a white soldier. I see only a Sioux named Dances With Wolves. And there is nothing they hate so much as a Sioux.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are making a pipe?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten Bears holds out a hand and Dances with Wolves hands the pipe to him. Ten Bears inspects it briefly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This might be a pretty good pipe... how does it smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I haven't tried it yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN BEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's smoke it awhile... it is good to pass the time this way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've finished your pipe? How does it smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves moves to make the exchange. Kicking Bird does the same. From one hand to the other. Men couldn't be closer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm told it smokes well.</utterance>
   <speaker>KICKING BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't seem possible that we could come this far.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCES WITH WOLVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neither can speak. There is only goodbye.</context>
      <utterance>You were the first man I ever wanted to be like. I will not forget you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Wind In His Hair...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you not see that I am your friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves lets the unhappy echo of these words fade away before he starts his pony again. We follow for a few yards. Then the call comes a second time. If anything, more urgent than before.</context>
      <utterance>Can you not see that you will always be my friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIND IN HIS HAIR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Dances With Wolves stops. He drops his head painfully as the sound of his own name booms through his head.</context>
      <utterance>Dances With Wolves...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
