<movie id="153" title="Dark City">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOTEL MANAGER O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White stops, looks uncertainly towards a bead curtain.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you! You gotta message.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White sees several nooks for messages and keys in front of him. Reaching across the desk, he glances through the bead curtain into the manager's office. TELEVISION SOUNDS O.S.</context>
      <utterance>Message in d'box! You deaf?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MANAGER O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got my money?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I... How long have I been here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Totally confused, White turns to leave, sees something. Stops. HIS P.O.V. - A painting on a wall (cheap print variety) - waves on a beach. A breeze rustles the pages of a calender, pinned beside the picture.</context>
      <utterance>Jeez, too damn long if you ask me! What about the two weeks y'owe me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He backs away from the painting, looks about the lobby in panic - sees a sign: TOILETS. A painted hand points the way.</context>
      <utterance>What is your name... What is your name...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! WHITE  I'll be back later.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Well, y'better be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MYSTERY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White panics - he's cornered. He remembers the revolver. He pulls it from his coat and LEVELS it at the stranger, his hand shakes terribly. ON THE STRANGER continuing to advance. Something about his eyes makes White immobile, unable to think clearly.</context>
      <utterance>Co-operate. Do not make this difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE GUN FIRES again and again. Red splashes appear on the man. His shoulder. His leg. His neck. He walks forward, with spastic jerks as bullets RIP into him. A final shot POINT BLANK into the stranger's forehead. A stream of black liquid spouts from the hole. Blue smoke clears. The man stands motionless, his mouth hangs open. Then his eyes roll up, and he collapses to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>You will not shoot, yes. There is a place in your mind, a corner of darkness...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STROMBOLI leads the inspector into a tiled room containing several COVERED BODIES. The two men are greeted by a cheerful- looking MORTICIAN.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. This way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stromboli nods, then ignores the mortician and walks along the row of corpses. Bumstead follows.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome, gentlemen. Youre early. Here for the examination, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws back covers to reveal horrible mutilations.</context>
      <utterance>The handiwork of an extremely sick individual.</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STROMBOLI shakes his head, turns away from the final body, looks at the inspector.</context>
      <utterance>Youve read the reports. Not much to go on. We know nothing about him, except that he likes to cut them... Always the same type of blade. Forensics match in each case... Anyway, it's all in the reports, read them for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you wearing that thing on your face?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Germs, sir. These places are full of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Youll be a busy man from now on.</context>
      <utterance>I see.  One things for sure, hes ambitious.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stromboli looks annoyed at the smiling man. The Mortician becomes serious and goes back to his work.</context>
      <utterance>You can say that again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Thompson, sir? Wasnt this his case?</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thompson suffered a kind of severe delusion or some damn thing. Anyway he isnt with us any longer. The case is yours. Go through his files. Take what you need.  By the way, hows your mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chief-inspector turns, paces to the door briskly.</context>
      <utterance>Shes getting better, thanks. She... STROMBOLI  Very good...</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lets go, Bumstead. So much to do and so little time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FIGURE 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE HOTEL MANAGER looks up, moves forward into light: a squat, hunch-backed man with glasses. He steps through the beads, glares at the intruders.</context>
      <utterance>We are looking for Jonathan White.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE MEN - an uncanny resemblance to the one who tried to kill White. Black coats, glasses, pale skin. Creepy. A BLACK GLOVED HAND flashes forward, grips the managers face and doesnt let go. The manager struggles, gulps for air. Hes pushed back heavily against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The leather glove SQUEEZES, blood trickles from the managers ears, through the fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Which room is he in?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This Man turns to the others. They all smile, then turn back to White. MEN (in unison) Fifty-six. ANOTHER VOICE has been speaking softly - now it is louder. Repeating:</context>
      <utterance>Dont fall asleep.  Might never wake, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE - a chair falls to the floor. White leaps up from the table, terrified, disoriented. Just a DREAM - he had dozed. WIDEN ANGLE - The place is still empty. White glances to the serving window. A DISH waits for him, framed in the glowing fluoro square. He gets it. A bowl of soupy liquid with noodles. He sits down. He is about to start eating - realizes he has a fork instead of a spoon. Picking up the bowl again, he heads to the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty-six... Fifty-six...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fredrick looks nervously down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>What? Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little man grabs Whites sleeve, starts to pull him along.</context>
      <utterance>Cmon, lets go! We dont have any time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON - the top of a set of stairs in front of them. Two dark figures appear. Fredrick looks up at them in horror.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it a minute. Lets start at the beginning, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both men run like crazy, White awkwardly holding the bowl of soup. They come to a junction, each takes a separate corridor. Fredrick finds some stairs, climbs two at a time. White climbs INTO FRAME, looks around, finds another corridor. The little man is nowhere to be seen. White reaches another junction - several corridors branch off.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!  Quick! Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>HIS P.O.V. PANNING AROUND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Each passageway completely deserted.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps running.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Who are you?</context>
      <utterance>Dont ever sneak up on me like that!</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts out her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Patricia Crenshaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Im your new assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didnt requisition a secretary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her hand tentatively. They shake.</context>
      <utterance>The Chief-Inspector thought you might need a hand. BUMSTEAD  Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Poor man.</context>
      <utterance>Ive taken the liberty and had Inspector Thompsons office searched, as I believe you instructed. All clear now, sir. They found several more traps and things were filed under pretty strange categories...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wont regret this, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead moves off.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The librarian looks up from her book.</context>
      <utterance>Keep newspapers here, birth certificates, records of deaths, that kind of thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBRARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which would you like</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBRARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She replaces her glasses, watches White rush away.</context>
      <utterance>Are you alright? He looks around - restrained panic. WHITE  Sure. Im fine. LIBRARIAN  Mmm-hmm. Stairs at the end of the hall. Third floor. Turn left. Section C-7. Row 35, near the toilets.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBRARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She blows her nose into a handkerchief. The snort ECHOES</context>
      <utterance>Dont mention it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into his pocket, pulls out a coin, puts it into the slot. Hes sweating again. He wipes his brow with a trembling hand.</context>
      <utterance>Im trying to reach nine zero eight triple two. I cant get through...  What?!...  Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is?... Which area is that number listed in?... Is that near the ocean?... The</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CRENSHAW O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up. The secretary stands in the doorway with another big pile of paperwork.</context>
      <utterance>Coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crenshaw puts the paperwork down on Bumsteads already overcrowded desk.</context>
      <utterance>What? I dont drink coffee. A cup of tea would be good. Milk and no sugar.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her like she just slapped him.</context>
      <utterance>Making progress?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miss Crenshaw looks concerned.</context>
      <utterance>These are the investigations of a madman. He has fabricated an entire bizarre paranoid delusion with no internal logic whatever.  This is a mess. A horrible mess.  Its the second time now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up a sheet of white paper - a report. The woman steps over and looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You typed this report?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. Anything wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman bends down, adjusts her glasses, examines it.</context>
      <utterance>Wrong? Look at this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Im sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you wash your hands before you type things?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An embarrassed beat, then:</context>
      <utterance>Well be more careful, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cups the receiver with her hand, looks at Bumstead.</context>
      <utterance>Inspector Bumsteads office... Yes... Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. The Chief-Inspector said he would see you now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the waste-basket up and empties the contents onto his desk, sorts through it.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stromboli is looking through his desk drawers now.</context>
      <utterance>A formality. I need to speak with Thompson. Officially I need your written permission.</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you want to speak to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leave him alone - hes a sad case.</context>
      <utterance>A hunch. He might be able to... STROMBOLI  Bumstead, dont be so paranoid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Its extremely important to my investigation...</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ill be the judge of that. Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stromboli becomes distracted again - stands up, looks behind pictures hanging off the walls. A big sign suspended above his desk says, SO MUCH TO DO AND SO LITTLE TIME - his motto.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I was wondering, sir, if you could let me have a few uniforms, to follow up for me... STROMBOLI O.S.  Absolutely not. Up to my ears in cases right now - cant spare anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lost something?</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door clicks shut. Stromboli looks up - the inspector has gone.</context>
      <utterance>What makes you think that! If you would learn to concentrate on facts, not get so side-tracked - you might get things done faster, Bumstead...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need something to keep me awake.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you need a haircut to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Just some pills.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only two bucks. Shave as well... WHITE  Your sign says you sell drugs - well, Im here to buy some. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves dramatically to a shelf above his head, with several bottles of all sorts of different coloured capsules.</context>
      <utterance>Relax. Sure!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what - let me cut yer hair, give ya watcha need half price. Cant argue at that! WHITE  I dont</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sell maps?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What of?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The city. I need to get to the ocean.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White doesnt answer. The old guy with the violin moves back and forth behind White, smiling as he plays.</context>
      <utterance>Nope. No maps. Ocean, huh? On vacation?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grandpa thought customers might like some mood music. WHITE  Nice...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barber looks out the front window as his hands busily trim hair.</context>
      <utterance>You still look familiar. Its driving me nuts! Sure I dont know ya from somewhere? WHITE  Not me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mnunn. Cold lately.  That night, couple weeks ago. That was</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandpa laughs and plays louder.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Im like that. Senility says the wife. But she sure cant complain. Heh. The erector set still works good.  And this aint no fucking rug! Ghead. Feel it! All mine!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PUSH IN ON WHITE - he smiles weakly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! Feeeeel it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT ON the priests hand - It rises, points, moves over the heads of the congregation, accusingly. Suddenly the red finger jabs towards an OLD WOMAN in the front row.</context>
      <utterance>Beware! The night is deadly. There is a criminal among us. White looks forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the congregation turn and stare at the woman. Shes terrified. The hand moves slowly now, across to a BEAUTIFUL JAPANESE WOMAN several rows back.</context>
      <utterance>It could be she! The innocent across the street!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest pauses dramatically then:</context>
      <utterance>Or the temptress next door!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the finger is pointing at White. All the faces turn, stare suspiciously at White. ANGLE ON WHITE - frozen with fright. Fortunately his face is obscured by shadow and the priest lowers his hand, continues the sermon. The people look away.</context>
      <utterance>Or mister nervy stranger at the back!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White goes to leave. As he stands he notices the DOORS of the church open - two figures step in and move into the candle- light. MYSTERY MEN - Whites bizarre pursuers. They look around. White ducks down, crawls between pews, startling several of the congregation. He motions to them to keep quiet. He runs into the legs of the BEAUTIFUL WOMAN the priest pointed out. She is startled momentarily but looks down at him, smiles. PRIEST (continues sermon) Evil stalks our streets. It seeks to hide in our hearts. Have you not evil within you now? White sees a nearby CONFESSION BOX. Staying low, he runs, almost knocks over a large illuminated candle-holder, darts inside. The girl watches him. A GAUNT-FACED WOMAN stands. Hysterical. She looks at the priest.</context>
      <utterance>You are thinking it could be anyone? And youre right! Why, it could even be Mother!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAUNT WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HIS P.O.V. - carved on the dark stained wood in front of him is a crucified insect. A voice surprises him. Another PRIEST,</context>
      <utterance>He took my little boy! Ill rip out his eyes! INSIDE - White breaths relief.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>OLDER PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have sinned?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White watches the two Mystery Men walk past, through the ornate wooden grill in front of his face.</context>
      <utterance>NO. Ah...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am listening. WHITE  Theres a... woman. I don't know but I think I, ahh...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mystery Men look towards the box for a moment, towards White, but keep walking.</context>
      <utterance>You fornicated?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I, ah...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mystery Men seem to have gone. White takes out the gun, keeping it hidden from the priest. Opens the chamber. TIGHT ON THE GUN - Only ONE BULLET left.</context>
      <utterance>You seem restless.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someones after me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we must call the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The silhouette on the other side of the box leans forward.</context>
      <utterance>No. I mean... that isnt necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. Then who is after you? What sins have you committed?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest suddenly stares incredulously at White. His eyes widen in horror.</context>
      <utterance>Just let me sit here for a moment? Ill go soon, and stop bothering you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White lunges, grabs his collar with one hand, slaps the other over his mouth. The old man stares at him, trembling uncontrollably.</context>
      <utterance>Youre the murderer?  Yes! That must be it! Dont kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest nods stupidly. White pushes him out of the confession box, grabs his coat from behind, puts the gun to his back. Together they head for the doors. Still no sign of the Mystery Men.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Listen. Walk out quietly.  Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dont kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White loses his temper, grabs the priest, shakes him violently. WHITE (not so quietly) Im not going to kill you, okay! Faces turn. The priest kicks White in the leg, bites his hand. While White is wincing in pain, the priest breaks away. PRIEST (shouting/pointing)</context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you been here?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe ten minutes...  Thats strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop is shaking his watch, tapping it with his finger. He looks up. Bumstead indicates his own watch.</context>
      <utterance>Spinning backwards?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead nods. He removes a notebook from his pocket, walks about the room, glances at objects, makes notes. Bumstead steps over to a small RECTANGULAR HOLE in the wall. He examines it carefully, then bends down and puts his head through. On the other side is a corridor snaking off into darkness. Just beneath the hole, is a broken dish and a puddle. Lying half in the puddle is the business card of Doctor D.P. Schreber M.D. Without removing his head from the hole he shouts to the nearby cop.</context>
      <utterance>Yours too?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the door has caught Bumsteads head in it. He struggles. The cop and the photographer run over to help.</context>
      <utterance>I want prints over here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to see the doctor. It's important.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time was your appointment? WHITE  Look! Tell him I'm here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER MAN stands at the rear of the room.</context>
      <utterance>It has failed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YET ANOTHER MAN starts to tremble violently, seized with some kind of convulsion. He froths at the mouth and throws his head about. A TALLER MAN standing beside him opens a silver box, removes a small WRITHING WORM. He places this on the tip of the trembling Man's tongue, who swallows it and calms down.</context>
      <utterance>This is becoming dangerous, yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER MAN rises suddenly, pushes forcefully to the front of the group.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get this over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE MEN turn to face him. He is out of line. He becomes irritated, as if to say something further, then pulls himself short, sits down.</context>
      <utterance>What about the dance-steps! This is my responsibility, we must resolve this issue, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The situation has changed.  This one is in possession of knowledge... MAN 1  ...to avoid influence, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A freak!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RUMBLING NOISE O.S. attracts everyone's attention. They all look to a round portal high on a wall. The noise is louder. several figures on stilts run past outside the opening - then the noise subsides. The MYSTERY MEN go back to more important things.</context>
      <utterance>Impossible!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It gets interesting, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man 2 stares blankly into space, he makes a peculiar clicking noise with his mouth, his eyes roll upwards.</context>
      <utterance>Stop this! It has gone too far! Tell Mister Black!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What you've done?</context>
      <utterance>You remember nothing? Who you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know something about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, that would be cheating, wouldn't it?  Is there nothing</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Water?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor walks to a glass cabinet and removes a bottle, takes out two green capsules. Hands them to White. Sits behind the desk again.</context>
      <utterance>Waves... A beach. A woman whispering. That's all.  I need to stay awake. Do you have any pills?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does she say? The woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Asks my name. Over and over. Just like a broken record. Only thing is, I can't answer. I've no idea what my name</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Te doctor walks to a small sink in the corner, returns, hands White a glass of water. White swallows the pills. SCHREBER (indicates pills) And what's this about? Why? White stands up, starts to pace nervously.</context>
      <utterance>That's what people keep telling me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad dreams?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about them... WHITE  Yeah well, why don't I ask some questions for a change.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're supposed to be my doctor, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. I</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... WHITE  Am I a killer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cannot say... You don't know the answer to that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White reaches across abruptly, GRABS the doctor. WHITE (angry now - shouting) Look, you know something about me, out with it! Let's end this bullshit! I want answers! The doctor is obviously scared.</context>
      <utterance>I told you, I can't remember a thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won't get anywhere like this. Please. Let's take things in easy steps...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put simply... a penetration of the left parieto-occipital area of the cranium... complicated by inflammation that resulted in adhesions of the brain to the meninges. Without going into detail... the formation of scar tissue altered the configuration of the lateral ventricles, producing incipient atrophy of the medulla... WHITE  Look. It was a simple question. Can someone kill and not remember it? SCHREBER  I'm sorry. I get carried away sometimes. Possible? I'm... ah, afraid so.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she drown? The woman you told me about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White shakes his head, looking blankly at the doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Not exactly. She was found in a canal, disembowelled. Throat cut. Blood drained. The body wrapped in a bed-sheet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Horrible...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schreber turns, points to DOUBLE-DOORS. He walks towards these. White follows.</context>
      <utterance>You remember nothing, eh?  Let me show you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Formation of memories is the most important of brain functions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are little more than a sum of memories. From them we reference who we are, where we're going. Without a past we are nothing. This is why you are so interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm nothing then.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I get my life back?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schreber points dramatically at a wooden structure containing two rats.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rats perform various activities involving mazes and geometric symbols. Schreber turns to look at White, eyebrow raised.</context>
      <utterance>We know of two kinds of memory. Firstly, declarative memory.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT ON HIS SLENDER FINGER - pointing to a machine also run by rats. The object is to make it through a guillotine device. One rat is successful, the other is chopped neatly in two.</context>
      <utterance>And then there is procedural memory.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White nods.</context>
      <utterance>Follow?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schreber puts a hand on White's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Research on simple animals can be... useful. To show us where memory storing systems are located, for example. I am building an experiment with hamsters next.  Cute little things.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White nods again, extremely troubled.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me talk! You must be hungry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. About before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A set of swinging doors on the other side of the room open slightly and THE NURSE looks in. NURSE (to Schreber) I have to talk to you.</context>
      <utterance>I don't blame you for getting angry. You are in a frustrating situation. You must be patient though. Trust me completely. I'm here to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head, with a serious expression, then darts out again. SCHREBER (to White) Excuse me. Ah, make yourself at home. He leaves. Alone, White looks around the bleak room. He takes off his coat and sits down again. He removes the FISH. The eye opens. The creature looks up at him. It breaths painfully.</context>
      <utterance>It can't wait?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts it back in his pocket. The OTHER fish is spattering oil everywhere. Smoke starts to fill the room. White, steps over and looks at the frying pan. The fish is turning black. He turns the heat down. He notices a SMALL HOLE in the wall. At eye height. He steps across, looks through. TIGHT ON WHITE'S eye through the hole.</context>
      <utterance>Still kicking, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SCHREBER O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White spins, like he's caught doing something wrong. The Doctor walks across to the stove, prods the frying fish with a fork.</context>
      <utterance>How are things in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White is having a hard time focusing.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, nearly done. So tell me about your dreams. I'm very interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHITE'S P.O.V. - ANGLE ON Schreber with his back turned, at the stove. THE IMAGE is blurring.</context>
      <utterance>Just the typical fabrications of a distorted mind. You know, chased by mysterious men in black, that kind of thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smoke rises thickly around the doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, our friends in black... they are not just a figment of your imagination you know, in fact none of what you are experiencing is anything but real.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flames are shooting up around Schreber from the frying pan. His arms catch fire, and he suddenly spins around clutching flaming daggers in both hands, his whole body engulfed in fire, his face charred, black flesh hanging off his skull.</context>
      <utterance>I know everything about you. You have no choice but to trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schreber stands at the stove looking at White. Everything is normal.</context>
      <utterance>Scarey, isn't it? White startles awake.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White stands awkwardly, pulls his coat on.</context>
      <utterance>Are you feeling alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly White feels feint - leans against the wall to steady himself.</context>
      <utterance>You can't go yet. We've got so much to talk about...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON WHITE - swaying.</context>
      <utterance>You're tired. You need to lie down.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those pills...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FOETUS 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is madness. If we're caught...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOETUS 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut-up. Help me with these straps...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's tapping the side of the syringe, squirting out air bubbles. THE DOOR-BELL RINGS again - very insistent. Schreber looks at the nurse, annoyed.</context>
      <utterance>Leave it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads to the door - turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Damn! Whoever it is - get rid of them!</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schreber puts the syringe down, fumbles in his pocket, pulls out a huge collection of KEYS on a ring, walks to the nurse, hands them to her. White manages to wriggle a hand free from the leather strap holding him. The nurse leaves, the doctor shuts the door, locks it. He steps over to White.</context>
      <utterance>Keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White lashes out, PUNCHES the doctor in the face. His glasses go flying, and he falls to the floor, blinded, scrambling for the spectacles. A convenient scalpel cuts White from his remaining bonds. He undoes the last strap around his ankles as the doctor replaces his glasses and leaps at him trying to drive the syringe INTO</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I had to put you through this, Anton.  There will be some pain, but things will be easier this way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schreber and White FREEZE in mid-struggle, look at the inspector. Behind him, the nurse appears in the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Police. Nobody move.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He tried to kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead steps into the light, shoves his gun in White's face, handcuffs him. Bumstead searches White, finds the revolver, takes this. Also takes his wallet. He glances at the doctor, who hides the syringe behind his back. BUMSTEAD (to Doctor) You Schreber? Schreber nods blankly. Bumstead runs his hand over White's side pocket - feels something.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Everybody stay calm...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White says nothing. The inspector opens the pocket and looks in. BUMSTEAD (disgusted) A fish, huh?</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON WHITE - frightened now.</context>
      <utterance>Dammit!  I'm curious? How many so far? He shakes his watch, puts it to his ear. WHITE  What? I... BUMSTEAD  Let's see, there's the little guy with no arms or legs. And the young boy? WHITE  Young boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead pulls something from under the dashboard. A SANDWICH, carefully wrapped and prepared. After glancing at his watch again, he bites into it. BUMSTEAD (chewing) Y'know, the kid you left in the meat packing plant, cut into pieces. Packed into brown paper parcels, wrapped in twine, that kind of thing. No answer.</context>
      <utterance>The six year old. Sure, you remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure have demonstrated a great deal of... imagination. The baby was the best though. Several cops lost their lunch over that one. Head twisted off, spine pulled out, yeech... WHITE  Stop it. You're making me sick...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RADIO CRACKLE O.S. - A tinny voice cuts in.</context>
      <utterance>We count seven so far. Anyone we missed?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead picks up a microphone, speaks into it.</context>
      <utterance>Inspector Bumstead... Inspector...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Crenshaw?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just reminding you... your eight pee em...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dammit.  Very efficient, as usual, Crenshaw. Remind me to give you my watch. It needs fixing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead replaces the microphone under the dashboard, takes a SHARP CORNER as he finishes off the sandwich.</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burastead pulls out a small brush, cleans the fallen crumbs from his trousers, keeping a hand on the wheel. White is silent - his wounds continue to bother him. He leans down to scratch through his trousers. WHITE (quietly) Shit!</context>
      <utterance>Shut-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gesundheit! WHITE  I didn't sneeze.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead grabs a bunch of flowers off the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>What are we doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MECHANICAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A claw lowers from the ceiling, grips White's head, turns it abruptly - the camera fires.</context>
      <utterance>Left - profile.</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANICAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The claw turns his head the other way. The camera fires again.</context>
      <utterance>Right - profile.</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANICAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across the room A BUZZER SOUNDS, a red light flashes above a door. White is released by the mechanical hands, walks over, opens the door and steps into darkness. LIGHTS COME ON - extremely bright. A room for line-ups - markings on the white wall behind White indicate varying heights, a darkened window faces him. He is obviously to be identified by an unseen person. A buzzer sounds again, a light indicates another door.</context>
      <utterance>Move - forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White moves into another room. A chair faces a large wheel painted in a black and white spiral. He sits down - the wheel turns, faster and faster.</context>
      <utterance>Move - forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wheel stops after several seconds.</context>
      <utterance>Watch - the - wheel.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The next room is full of scientific equipment.</context>
      <utterance>Move - forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White sees a metal-frame X-ray machine - he steps across to it. The screen lights up, filling the room with a green glow. We can see the shape of his skeleton. Where his pocket would be, is the tiny skeleton of the fish.</context>
      <utterance>Stand - behind - the - screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The next room is empty.</context>
      <utterance>Move - forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White turns. As soon as he has done this hears a door open behind him. FOOTSTEPS approach. Blows rain down on him, fists, boots, clubs. He slides to the floor. The lights go out.</context>
      <utterance>Face - the - wall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name? WHITE  I don't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White shakes his head slowly and looks at the floor. The light is angled away, pointed down towards A TABLE. White can see now.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws the first shot down on the table in front of White. A black and white police photo of a murder victim.</context>
      <utterance>John...</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another photo goes down. Another victim. Another and another. Each more grisly than the last.</context>
      <utterance>...Murderer.</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White nods. He's looks utterly lost. Bumstead steps across to a small speaker box on the wall near the only door, presses a button. BUMSTEAD (into speaker) Okay. TWO GUARDS immediately step through the door, GRAB White by his arms. They carry him off.</context>
      <utterance>You'll sign a confession?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, stay calm. WHITE  This man wants to kill me. The guard remains indifferent. SCHREBER  Just one of his many delusions - it's nothing.  Shut up! Listen, damn you! This is a fortunate coincidence - we won't get another chance like this. Listen to me. WHITE  What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're innocent...  You didn't kill anyone. WHITE  What am I doing in</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Says he is the man's doctor...  You know...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White stands abruptly, pushes himself against the glass.</context>
      <utterance>The men in black - they're the killers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a liar!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're telling me the truth</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that again...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone get's one - very much like this...  But this one's special. It will help you understand, everything... WHITE  I'm not injecting anything into my brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schreber waves frantically at the air surrounding him.</context>
      <utterance>Anton - I mean, John, there has been an experiment, a dangerous experiment. I arranged it. It was a lie from the beginning. It almost worked, but things did not go as they should have. You have been left - blank.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can change this,</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look at this syringe.</context>
      <utterance>Please! Don't be foolish! Time is short. Let me show you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White reluctantly does this.</context>
      <utterance>Don't ask stupid questions. Look at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Concentrate. Imagine the syringe rising. Picture it floating above the table.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a trick.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No it isn't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor! What brings you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just visiting my patient.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? And how is his state of mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor is nervous, glancing about.</context>
      <utterance>He's seriously disturbed...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem a little edgy. Everything okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to push past. Bumstead grabs his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course. Everything's fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To tell you the truth, I'm glad we've run into each other like this. Maybe you can help me tidy some loose ends.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHREBER looks like a trapped animal, when:</context>
      <utterance>Loose ends?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumasead turns to look down the corridor. He sees STROMBOLI peaking out of his office door.</context>
      <utterance>Bumstead!</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door shuts again. Bumstead turns back. The doctor is GONE - the corridor empty.</context>
      <utterance>I need to speak to you. Immediately.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead suspiciously eyes the two men, beside STROMBOLI'S desk. BUMSTEAD (to men) Who are you? STROMBOLI (even more nervous) Please, Bumstead. Co-operate - it's easier.</context>
      <utterance>Bumstead, these... er, gentlemen are here to collect White.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is highly irregular. I have a right to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He notices that this man's moustache is LOP-SIDED. The other man wears spectacles WITH NO LENSES in the frames, clutches an un-lit pipe in his teeth.</context>
      <utterance>We are from a mental asylum.</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's right. He's ill - he needs expert help.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Inspector. Has he been displaying any strange... behaviour?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's been a little angel...</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLOW MOVE IN on Bumstead's face.</context>
      <utterance>If you could show them to the holding cell now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. I'm sorry... But I don't understand how it was possible. The only window was twenty feet up a vertical wall, he was cuffed...</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>shouts at cringing</utterance>
   <speaker>COP)</speaker>
      <mode> COP)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could you have been so stupid?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead gets up and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop hustles out, shuts the door.</context>
      <utterance>You stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bumstead, you're starting to annoy me. This case is very important to me. Just a little warning: I've got my eye on you inspector, remember that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NEWS READER O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White listens nervously.</context>
      <utterance>...earlier this evening it was reported a man fitting his description had been apprehended.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWS READER O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across the room he can see the woman's bedroom door ajar. He crosses to the doorway and looks in. The woman stands naked against a deep red wall, her back turned. She has an elaborate TATTOO on her back - looks like an INSECT. She puts on a dressing gown and TURNS SUDDENLY. White steps back before she notices him, he goes back to the couch. She steps from the doorway holding a BAR OF SOAP in her hand. She sits down beside White and takes his hands, gently lathering soap around the handcuffs, continuing to smile at him. White looks down. His hands seem to have SHRUNK - they poke out of his sleeves like tiny children's limbs. The cuffs effortlessly slip off. White looks at the woman, then back at his hands - NOTHING STRANGE, they are normal size, but somehow the cuffs have been removed. He looks at the woman again, grateful. He can't help smiling.</context>
      <utterance>...and now for a message from LUMP-O food products...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>That's me. I'm a shadow.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She just keeps smiling, not understanding. Kisses him. He notices an old phone on a corner table, removes the note again and rings the same number. This time, after several rings the call is answered.</context>
      <utterance>Do I look like a murderer to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White remains silent. Sachiko stands and leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?... Who is this?... Who's there?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please believe me. It's</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the truth... I need you. I know you're innocent.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know I'm innocent?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you are. You couldn't do those terrible things. Come home with me - maybe things will make sense then...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that. It's dangerous. What about my parents? Do you know where I can find them?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands and walks to the window - looks out at the city.</context>
      <utterance>They're dead, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fumbles in her handbag, pulls out a notebook, scribbles something on a piece of paper, hands it to White.</context>
      <utterance>You have an uncle. You were very close.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>silently stands and leaves the room. The wife puts her face in her hands, overcome with tears.</context>
      <utterance>This is where he lives. I'm sure he would like to see you. WHITE  Thanks. WIFE  Don't you want me? My body? Remember how my skin feels? Touch it. I... She notices Sachiko - becomes self-conscious. Sachiko</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIFE (looks up - still sobbing) Elizabeth. White removes the torn fragment of the photograph he has in his wallet, holds the black and white eye up to her face - it matches. WHITE (thoughtful) Yes... In the darkness of a doorway Sachiko watches the couple. She</context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to help...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the postcard from his wallet, holds it up so the woman can see it.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. Here...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White stands abruptly, startling the woman. He glares down at her intensely.</context>
      <utterance>Know this place? She looks at the card. ELIZABETH  Of course. Your home town - where you grew up...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I get there? Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She trails off into silence. Her hand, about to point in a certain direction, freezes in mid-air.</context>
      <utterance>That's easy. You...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White sits back down quietly.</context>
      <utterance>...strange, I forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>HIS P.O.V.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thompson backs away, points his gun at the figure through the door.</context>
      <utterance>Bumstead, back turned, glancing at his watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thompson puts his eye to the door again.</context>
      <utterance>Open up, Thompson. It's me...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THROUGH THE SPY-HOLE LENS the inspector turns, looks at us, his face DISTORTED, fish-like. Thompson undoes four locks, opens the door a crack, but leaves it chained.</context>
      <utterance>Bumstead?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't let you in... sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on the serial killer case, need to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thompson wipes at the sweat on his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Not that. Anything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thompson stares at Bumstead, then silently unchains the door and lets him through.</context>
      <utterance>You don't look so well... C'mon, let me in Thompson.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't talk about</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've taken my mind, my memories...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Who has?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your idea of a joke? I don't remember...  Take my advice, Bumstead. Get off this case. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strange business. I...</context>
      <utterance>What is going on? THOMPSON  Wish I could tell you, Bumstead.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thompson's face is heavily bruised, covered in sweat. His nose starts to bleed - he wipes it on his sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>It's - it's disgusting, I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus! We have to get you to a doctor...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead stands unsteadily.</context>
      <utterance>No... No doctor...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... How long has this been happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few days... a few weeks - dunno, I can't remember.  Worse thing is, I never know if it will change back again... Now, please leave me alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MYSTERY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A switch is thrown. Electricity sparks to life. A hum is in the air.</context>
      <utterance>We have located him. Now is the time, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The congregation of MEN place ELECTRODES to their foreheads in a trance-like manner. They chant, quietly at first, steadily building in volume. The MEN stand and MOVE RHYTHMICALLY to some inner beat. The CAMERA MOVES ACROSS to a diagram pinned on a board. A representation of a man's legs. Trousers rolled up above the knees, showing a number of bite-like wounds on the flesh. Labels point out various parts of the legs in medical fashion - the legends are an unknown language.</context>
      <utterance>Let the tuning commence!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the same entry wounds. It's definitely him.  She lives... lived here. A prostitute.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other one?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Small world.  Where's the photographer?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A third YOUNG COP steps up to the cop in charge, glancing at the bile on Bumstead's suit.</context>
      <utterance>No one available.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop leads Bumstead behind a WOODEN PARTITION. A small area neatly arranged - a double bed, various possessions. Someone obviously lives here. The room is empty however.</context>
      <utterance>We'll interrogate them anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the family of the victim - apparently they were in the apartment when he committed... BUMSTEAD  What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks to THE BED, bends over and lifts the bed-spread. In the shadows underneath, Bumstead can make out SEVERAL FACES. A man, an old woman, three or four children.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't speak English...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How will we interrogate them?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Under the bed, Bumstead can see a LITTLE GIRL. He walks over to her. She puts a hand over her mouth, edges away.</context>
      <utterance>Well, sir... I don't know exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without coming out from under the bed she hands the inspector a crumpled paper. He looks at it then glances over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>It's alright. I won't hurt you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have called this meeting for a purpose, yes?  It is clear to you we are - unhappy, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The tuning failed - when our agents arrived he was gone. He</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No excuses, dearest Doctor! Answers. Yes? MYSTERY MEN  Answers! Answers!</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said this would be containable! Nothing works this time. Why is this so?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERY MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why! Why!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I - ah - I... it's a little cold in here don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must find him. This is your responsibility. SCHREBER  Yes, of course...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't say. Says he must talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A light flashes. Bumstead picks up.</context>
      <utterance>Put it through...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He listens intently.</context>
      <utterance>This is Bumstead. Who is this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need everything on the Jonathan White case.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS CRENSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please - I'm in a hurry. MISS CRENSHAW  Certainly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why give yourself up?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I - ah - couldn't think of anything else to do. I thought maybe you know something...  I'm scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a pretty good escape act at the station. How did you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I woke up in a subway. I don't know how I got there. BUMSTEAD  Uh-huh.  What are you scared of?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People... after me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know who they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are they after you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know that either.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know much, do you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have duplicated the personality, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mister Black turns towards the OTHER MEN.</context>
      <utterance>It is ready. The Doctor was most helpful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear a clock in my head, and I like it! MEN  We hear clocks in our heads, and we like it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A world in our likeness!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Men close the hatch in the top of the puppet's head. SQUEAK... CLUNK! The puppet tests out its MANY WEAPONS, a series of nasty-looking blades snap out of its small body, then retract.</context>
      <utterance>A world in our likeness!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White stops. Bumstead indicates a CLEAR PLASTIC MAT running through the room.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Not that way. If you could just follow the covering - the carpet gets stained and it's impossible to clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White flips through it. Details of White's history.</context>
      <utterance>Everything the department knows about John White is in this. Here.  Excuse me for a moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That stuff helpful? WHITE  I suppose...  Why are you helping me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White looks up, pauses as if he didn't understand Bumstead, then:</context>
      <utterance>You're case has been driving me crazy. You see, I pride myself on being thorough. There's too many loose ends with your case.  Thought it was best you were hidden until we understand more about the facts. What do you know about these men in black?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The inspector is caught off-guard by the question. WHITE (continues) It's my legs. Been bitten. Giving me trouble. Bumstead walks silently to the bathroom, opens a medicine cabinet. BUMSTEAD (to himself) Insects? He returns clutching a small bottle and some cotton wool.</context>
      <utterance>If you shoot them here...  you can kill them. They're not people - like us - got insects in their heads... Got any disinfectant?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The inspector gives white back his revolver and his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>Here.  Careful with your trousers. That stuff stains.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead paces thoughtfully, careful to stay on the plastic protective covering. He turns, glares at White, who dabs his legs with the cotton wool.</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White shakes head.</context>
      <utterance>Any idea what part the Doctor plays in this business?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White looks down. Bumstead doesn't lie.</context>
      <utterance>Let's try and find out, shall we.  Lace is untied.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the dashboard, brushes away a small piece of lint.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't tell you the entire reason I helped you. It started with two little girls. Twins. Used to play with them when I was young. Couldn't remember for the life of me what they looked like, then I understood why...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They didn't have faces.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at White, then back to the road.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. Just seamless flesh across the front of their heads. No mistake. I just hadn't remembered it that way. Up until then they had been normal little girls in my memory.  That's not all. Once I started examining them, all sorts of things about my life, had... inconsistencies. It was like a game. I would think about a person or a place, or an event. Then I would turn the lights off. Sit down in a comfortable chair... And study each detail of this subject.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead and White are quiet momentarily, then:</context>
      <utterance>Everything was liquid beneath a thin surface that had always seemed solid to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Except...</context>
      <utterance>Is there anything you haven't told me about this business? Even the most insignificant thing? WHITE  No. Nothing I can think of.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. The only thing I've been certain of, all this time, is that I need to get to the ocean. The point is no one seems to know how to get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He trails off. Shakes his head slowly.</context>
      <utterance>Why, that's ridiculous. You just...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get to the bottom of this. I mean it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I met a friend of yours the other night, doctor. Tall fellow. No hair. Rather pale skin...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's surprising. He was leaving your office at the time...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are mistaken.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you hiding?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUMSTEAD removes his revolver, sticks it in the doctor's face.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I don't know anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, they'll kill me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's time you introduced us to your little friends.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The threesome step from the car, keep close to a wall. Schreber alone steps up to the door, leans down to a mat at the foot of the door, lifts it and takes a KEY from underneath. He unlocks the door, opens it, puts the key back, goes inside. He waves the other men forward. White and Bumstead step up to the door - Bumstead looks at the mat - it says: WELCOME on it.</context>
      <utterance>Just like that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When the doors open again the three men look out on a DARK</context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't believe me if I told you, Inspector. Have patience - you'll see for yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White points to a wall featuring a line of brass hooks. On these hooks hang MYSTERY MEN coats - that's not all. Each hook carries A FACE. Bumstead and White step closer, look at the faces. They seem to be elaborate, very life-like MASKS.</context>
      <utterance>Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White and the inspector look at each other, incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>Put them on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White, Bumstead and Schreber hop aboard. The cart takes them into a DARK TUNNEL, deeper into the secret underworld of the MYSTERY MEN. They MOVE THROUGH a subterranean landscape of unexplained contraptions and bones.</context>
      <utterance>Get in. Hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you think this goes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cart finally comes to a stop in a cave. Bumstead, White and Schreber leap out and hide in a dark doorway, as a LONG LINE OF MYSTERY MEN walk past them.</context>
      <utterance>It sure isn't the fun-fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They join the end of the line, falling into step.</context>
      <utterance>Follow me, and do exactly as I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MAN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Eye is too small for the head of the pin!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER MAN stands. Next to the first, who sits again.</context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Eye!</context>
      <utterance>What is it that floats on the water?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So it goes around the room, each Man takes his turn announcing part of the strange ritual. It will be White, Bumstead and Schreber's turn shortly. White is worried, looks at the others. WHITE (whisper) What do we do? SCHREBER (hisses back) Fake it!</context>
      <utterance>Indeed!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHREBER is next - he stands abruptly.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then it's Bumstead's turn.</context>
      <utterance>The eye. Master of time and space!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAN 1 at the front seems confused for a moment - SEVERAL of the others turn towards Bumstead. MAN 1 (uncertain) Good. The inspector sits back down - whispers to White without looking at him.</context>
      <utterance>The Eye - um - delicious with horseradish on rye!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White stands. Hesitates. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Nothing to it...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White sits down, shaking his head, embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Eye... eye, captain!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE MAN NEXT TO WHITE rises up - keeps rising, FLOATS IN THE AIR above the Men's heads.</context>
      <utterance>Um - yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns sideways, still floating.</context>
      <utterance>My spine will bend for the Eye!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that for real down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The inspector stops walking suddenly, grabs White, holds him back.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid so.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White thinks for a moment, pulls the paper his wife gave him from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>This ocean business... I know where I can find a map. I need to go back to the station. Where will you be?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead scribbles on the pad mounted to the dash, battles with the wheel, driving at breakneck speed.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go see an uncle of mine.  Five - one - eight - three - double six - three...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE PUPPET - sitting AT THE WHEEL of a stolen car, driving like crazy.</context>
      <utterance>Good.  Uh-oh... White turns and looks behind them. HIS P.O.V. - HEADLIGHTS gaining on them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TICKET SELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That's what I said!  What..?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man squints at the card White holds up, nods groggily.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for this address.</utterance>
   <speaker>TICKET SELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thumbs the blue curtain. Curls up, shuts his eyes again.</context>
      <utterance>Upstairs. Through there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White turns to see an OLD MAN in his pyjamas sitting in a WHEELCHAIR. The man pushes a lever on the side of the chair. A whir of electric motors. The chair carries him out of the shadows. White steps from behind the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>John?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you alright? What are you doing here? Is this one of your jokes, John? It's been so long, I thought you'd forgotten your uncle Karl?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uncle... Karl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PHONE RINGS. Uncle Karl wheels over, picks up the receiver. KARL (talks down the line) Hello... Yes, he's here... (holds out the phone to White) It's for you. White concerned - takes the phone.</context>
      <utterance>And this is me again about - um - I would guess about twelve feet further to the right of the last shot. Now just behind the wall is the hotel I stayed at - sweet little place...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?  Oh, it's you... Yes... My uncle apparently... Just looking at some memories... You have? That's good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look! This is a good one!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that door?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The uncle watches the slides.</context>
      <utterance>There. Behind the cabinet. Where does it go?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such a joker! Like your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads the old man over to the cabinet.</context>
      <utterance>No. Have a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where does it lead?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White pushes at the cabinet. The old man helps. They only manage to push several inches - it is very heavy. White decides to just climb over it. He squeezes through, opens the door and climbs a set of dark stairs. Uncle Karl watches.</context>
      <utterance>It must be a closet or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't trip over. It's dark up there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A NOISE O.S. White and Uncle Karl turn. A VENTILATION GRILL falls off a wall, revealing a hole. EYES shine from the darkness. THE PUPPET leaps from the hole. Its blades unfolding, spinning wildly before it hits the carpet. It faces the two men.</context>
      <utterance>John, I didn't see you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The puppet goes for Uncle Karl. A whirr of metal, BLOOD SPLASHES ACROSS WHITE and the walls. Uncle Karl SCREAMS horribly. White grabs a chair - holds it above him. The puppet turns from the dead man in the wheelchair. White lets it have it. The chair CRASHES DOWN, splintering into pieces. The puppet is dazed, but immediately recovers. White has a fire-poker now. As the puppet advances, he swings, connecting with the creature, hurtling it across the room, into a wall. White runs out the door.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is standing in front of the MALE NURSE in the glassed-in counter.</context>
      <utterance>I can't wait any longer...</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and storms off down the corridor. The NURSE stands, shouting after him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I told you, she is being examined...</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Bumstead!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead turns towards his mother.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, Inspector Bumstead! We are glad you are here - I'm afraid we have done all we can. Yes. Your Mother has passed. Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she was getting better...</utterance>
   <speaker>SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead turns to the men, confusion in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>We are sorry. The cancer - it was fatal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men glance at each other for a moment, then back at the inspector.</context>
      <utterance>She doesn't have cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bumstead leaps forward, RIPS OFF one of the surgeon's masks. ANGLE ON THE MAN - He turns to look at Bumstead, pale skin, staring eyes, a MYSTERY MAN. TWO OTHER MEN grab him from behind. BUMSTEAD (struggles) I'll kill you all! One of the Mystery Men steps up to the struggling inspector, places the palm of his hand across Bumstead's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>We knew that. Yes.  Anyway - she is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will obey us, yes. In your mind there is a dark space...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stromboli is upon him, grabs the empty gun, throws it away, picks up the inspector, leans him against the wall. Without Stromboli holding him up, Bumstead would not be able to stand.</context>
      <utterance>Dammit.</utterance>
   <speaker>STROMBOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you always have to find things out the hard way! Couldn't you just do your job, you idiot? I told you, didn't I? These people are not playing games, Bumstead. They can do anything they want, don't you understand? BUMSTEAD  You're one of them. You bastard... STROMBOLI  In a way, we</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR'S P.O.V.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>THE EDGE looms up - a long drop to the street.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mechanized figure trundles forward, pins him to a wall. A streetlight reveals... DOCTOR SCHREBER covered in blood, encased in a metal framework covered in silver blades.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh... it hurts!...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blades are connected to the wheels - they turn when he moves forward, metal cuts into his flesh, slowly SKINNING HIM ALIVE. A torture machine. Between screams of intense pain, the doctor speaks.</context>
      <utterance>I'm... being... punished.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to - ahhhh - find you... I..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schreber turns and rolls off into the night, screaming - BLADES SPIN furiously, peeling back flesh. He glances at White one last time.</context>
      <utterance>We are... living in their dreams...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHREBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Insect... dreams...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes roll up and he GOES LIMP. White stares at the body, then:</context>
      <utterance>Gesundheit!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't sneeze.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are looking for the White victims.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who the hell are</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FLASH OF STEEL. The mortician's throat SPOUTS blood. He grabs reflexively at the gash and falls back onto the floor, DEAD before he hits the tiles. The Mystery Men step to an adjoining chamber. Man 2 puts down a Box he is carrying, opens the lid. A green glow oozes out. The other Men manipulate levers on a control panel on a nearby wall. Stainless steel doors open. Body-length trays slide into the dim light. SHAPES covered in white sheets. Man 2 with the box removes a GLASS SYRINGE, filled with a glowing green liquid. He steps TO THE BODIES and injects each with the syringe, through the sheets. When he has finished he steps back, places the syringe back in the box. The MEN leave silently. All is silent and still. Then the shape beneath a sheet starts to SIT UP. Then another, and another.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White does not turn about, he takes a step forward, then another - and RUNS INTO THE SKY - A PAINTED WALL. He glances up at a small SPEAKER built into the wall - the SOURCE of the sea- side SOUND EFFECTS. He hears the click of the gun being cocked behind him. Hopes dashed, he turns. ANGLE ON A MYSTERY MAN - a gun pointed at White's stomach.</context>
      <utterance>John White...</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White is led into a pitch black room.</context>
      <utterance>There is nothing, Mister White. Beyond the city. Never has been. Unfortunate. Yes?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know where to find me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>eventually... Been waiting for you, yes. Hoped you wouldn't make a nuisance of yourself on the way... The Man motions with the gun for White to walk forward. As soon as White turns to do this, the Man slips from the room and shuts the door, cutting off any existing light. A NOISE O.S. - some kind of machine being turned on - lights start to come up all over the room. It's a normal, average-sized, living room. All the furniture has been removed and replaced with chairs, tables, podiums - an arrangement resembling an IMPROVISED COURT of law. In fact, White realizes he is standing behind some kind of witness box. The apartment is devoid of people, though almost immediately a door opens to the side (looks like it would lead to the kitchen) and a series of figures step through. MYSTERY MEN. All the MEN take up specific positions around the room, without uttering a word, but don't sit. One MYSTERY MAN opens a curtain beneath an arched entrance - beyond it, within a very small room, stand DOZENS OF PEOPLE, crammed shoulder to shoulder. The people stare at White silently - a bizarre gallery of spectators. An eerie silence falls on the room. The kitchen door opens again. White is shocked to see the VICTIMS WALK INTO the room and adopt positions in what is obviously the area for the jury. The DISEMBOWELED CORPSE OF A WOMAN steps out of the shadows, pushing a pram. Her throat is cut, she is shrouded in a white sheet. Within the pram is the BABY clutching its own head, with spine attached, under its arm. Then the mutilated FREDRICK hops out, followed by the three brown blood-stained paper parcels containing what is left of the YOUNG BOY. Finally, his WIFE and the JAPANESE WOMAN, still in passionate embrace, take their positions. Another door opens - a closet. Within stands the figure we have only seen as a shadow - the elderly MYSTERY MAN with the cane. MISTER BLACK slowly reaches above him and pulls at a chain hanging from the ceiling - the light snaps on inside the closet. Somewhere, a long way off in the same building, a toilet is heard flushing. He is much older than the rest, carries himself with authority as he hobbles across the room to a raised podium, supporting his withered body on his cane. Looks like he will play JUDGE. Everyone in the room now sits. Mister Black looks at White. ANGLE ON WHITE - He starts to tremble, not so much from fear, but cold.</context>
      <utterance>We knew you would turn up here</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White just looks at him, still clutching the small notebook called: ANSWERS.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White is silent. He leans over and scratches his legs through the fabric of his trousers. They itch like crazy. Mister Black turns to the assembled people.</context>
      <utterance>John White, you are to be tried for murder, yes. You wish to confess to these crimes now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO MYSTERY MEN stand and step across to a wooden easel. MAN 1 stands beside it, reveals a series of visuals, charts, etc. drawn on stiff cardboard. MAN 2 uses a pointer while he describes the evidence to support their case.</context>
      <utterance>Very well. The testimony of the prosecutors. Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERY MAN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAN 1 places a large black and white photo blow-up on the easel. It shows White at the door of the JAPANESE WOMAN'S apartment, clutching a kitchen knife, covered in blood.</context>
      <utterance>We will show that John White is abnormal, a menace to society, a dangerous sick individual, and that the court should have no mercy in finding him guilty and punishable to the extreme for his crimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERY MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A general murmur of agreement through the room as the point is made. Mister Black turns to the victims, nods his head slowly.</context>
      <utterance>Exhibit A shows the accused leaving the scene of his most recent crime, yes. A photo taken by a remote camera planted by one of our agents. White watches in stunned silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERY MAN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAN 1 removes a small tape recorder, hands it to MAN 2.</context>
      <utterance>Exhibit B...</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERY MAN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>committing aforementioned crime, yes. He turns a switch, the reels spin slowly. A hush fills the room. VOICE 1 (sounds like JAPANESE WOMAN) No... Please... A scream. VOICE 2 (sounds like White) Shut up! Another scream. A ripping sound. VOICE 3 (sounds like his WIFE) John! Don't... Another scream. White is standing up, involuntarily, he can't listen to this any longer. WHITE (a squeak, almost inaudible) Stop it! This is a lie... Mister Black turns to White. The Men testifying stop the tape and look at him also.</context>
      <utterance>Actual tape recording of accused</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Men in the audience turn and all stare at White, as do the victims and the spectators in the adjoining room. WHITE (back to a whisper) I didn't kill anyone.</context>
      <utterance>Something to say? Ready to confess?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SHRIEK from the pram containing the BABY - it rocks violently from side to side. The DISEMBOWELED WOMAN rises from her chair. She has difficulty standing, her limbs stiff. She looks at White, opens her mouth to say something, but no sound comes out. Instead a tiny RED CRAB scuttles out, across her face, and falls to the ground. She sits down. White is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Speak up. Yes. WHITE  It's lies. Everything. He grips the barrier before him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AN OLDER COUPLE are led out of the kitchen by a Mystery Man. Shown to seats behind a podium. The woman looks sadly at White.</context>
      <utterance>Bring the witnesses.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are the accused's parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER SLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had your turn! Let them speak. WHITE  My parents are supposed to be dead! You can't keep changing the damn rules like this! Why go through this ridiculous set-up! Why don't you just kill me and be done with it! MISTER BLACK  Please, continue...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over to the victims.</context>
      <utterance>This is insane!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone has a job - a function. Each one teaches you more about your invention. I'm what is called a</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is silence. Whispers. Faces staring.</context>
      <utterance>You're trying to get rid of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MISTER BLACK and the gathered MYSTERY MEN look speechless at White. Suddenly everyone bursts into spontaneous LAUGHTER, led by Mister Black. A terrible cackle fills the room - all the MYSTERY MEN laugh hysterically, so do the mutilated victims. The spectators in the adjoining room remain silent.</context>
      <utterance>Why do I threaten you? You're scared aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah - a</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mister Black seems startled by the book, then pretends it's nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! MISTER BLACK  You have proof? Evidence? Yes? WHITE  It's all here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A book of delusions. Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.  The verdict, yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DISEMBOWELED WOMAN stands again. This time she opens her mouth, there is a bubbling noise, water runs out, then: DISEMBOWELED WOMAN (whisper) Guil - ty... White is agitated, fear in his face. Mister Black stamps SOME PAPERS before him repeatedly. ON THE PAPERS - official-looking documents. The stamp says:</context>
      <utterance>Wait, this isn't fair...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUILTY.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CLOSE on White's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the papers on the bench in front of Mister Black BURST INTO FLAMES. Mister Black recoils, almost falling off his chair, taken by surprise. The Mystery Men all look at White, a murmur of concern. Mister Black looks up at White - angered.</context>
      <utterance>Before I pronounce sentence...</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White, genuinely surprised, looks around. Several Mystery Men BACK AWAY from him, scared.</context>
      <utterance>How dare you use your tricks on me!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't realise...</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glares across the room, angrily. An WOODEN CHAIR in a corner starts to vibrate. CLOSE on Mister Black's eyes. The chair rises into the air - HURLS across the room at White. Mister Black laughs as it crashes into the wall. White ducks just in time. The gathered Mystery Men erupt into enthusiastic applause. White regains his composure and tries some mind tricks of his own. He lifts a small table into the air, and makes it spin - a knife and fork dance back and forth on the surface, as several plates (from a stack in the kitchen) hurl, firstly at the spinning table, then go flying across the room, smashing near Mister Black, making him dance back and forth comically. This display is accompanied by a rousing rendition of a WALTZ playing on a floating gramophone White has also activated with his mind. SEVERAL Mystery Men are TERRIFIED. White is amazed at his own performance.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, freak! Monster! You are insignificant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mister Black is furious, spluttering, spit flying from his mouth. MISTER BLACK (shouts)</context>
      <utterance>You'll regret that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAN ON PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White doesn't understand what is going on. O.S. the SOUND of machinery WINDING DOWN. ANGLE ON a clock hanging on the wall. ON the SECOND HAND. It suddenly STOPS. All eyes are on Mister Black.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, we have a problem here. Shut it down immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISTER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mister Black starts to SHAKE. His eyes shut, clenches his teeth, grips the insect on his cane, plants his feet firmly to the floor. Around the room WALLS CRACK, plaster rains down from the ceiling...</context>
      <utterance>This has all gone too far. Yes, much too far.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His vision CLEARS, he can see. It's MISTER BLACK. Behind him a SMALL CROWD who turn out to be MYSTERY MEN. Mister Black suddenly pulls at his own face, removes the mask. Underneath is a mess of PULSATING ORGANS AND INSECT PARTS. This is what Mystery Men really look like. He laughs, starts to MOVE rhythmically - a strange dance-step. The others join in, as they too pull off masks. Each Man reaches up to his left ear in unison. They pull squirming INSECTS out, hold them up to the light. The insects scream triumphantly. White screams too. And he can't stop. Everything goes BLACK. Then the sound of a key rattling in a lock. A door slowly creaks open...</context>
      <utterance>Good as new. Yes. Everything is easier now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOHN WHITE enters. He is haggard, eyes rimmed with red. He still holds the small black NOTEBOOK, tight to his chest. He stands in the centre of the room, looks up. Strangely, though the room is very small, it extends upwards several stories - windows sit at various heights. White walks to the lace curtain, opens it with shaking hands.</context>
      <utterance>It's small but clean...  ...and the view's nice.  Isn't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her. Smiles. Then, slowly, brings his hands to her throat.</context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John... White.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
