<movie id="160" title="Death to Smoochy">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph slams the briefcase shut, startling the couple.</context>
      <utterance>So... uh... you'll make sure my boy dances up front, right? Where he'll get the most camera time?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want your kid on the show?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of... of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then don't tell me how to run my fucking business.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph rises. He takes a final gulp of his Scotch and picks up the briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, we were just --</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to walk off. Suddenly, the Husband and Wife jump up from the table holding guns.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call you if a spot opens up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freeze, you cocksucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Federal agents storm into the bar and surround Randolph.</context>
      <utterance>Drop the briefcase!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, let me be the first to say, in all sobriety, that I'm as shocked and outraged as all of -- The network CEO, a hog of a man, cuts him off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What are you doing about it?</context>
      <utterance>Save it for the papers, Stokes. We've got nervous sponsors and an angry public -- a combination uglier than two monkeys fucking.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sir, I'm currently in the process of compiling a list of viable replacements and it's my hope...</utterance>
   <speaker>CEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another EXECUTIVE chimes in.</context>
      <utterance>Clean replacements? With background checks? I assure you, Mr. Stokes, this network cannot survive another Rainbow Randolph. The goddamn P.R. department looks like the Jim Jones camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, Stokes, this was your dog that crapped on our rug.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We trusted you, Frank. And now we're in a tight spot. We have to post our quarterly earnings next month, for Christ's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>CEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever takes that slot has to be a straight arrow. Clean as a whistle.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Someone who'll take the heat off. One of those sweater types. Any chance of luring Fred Rogers away from P.B.S.?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, if we back up the Brinks truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. The idea now is to stop the hemorrhaging.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A giant hand slams on the table. All heads snap. The CEO drags his fingers along the shiny mahogany. Deafening sound.</context>
      <utterance>You better fix this, Stokes. Get us a white bread replacement, fast. Bland, milk toast. Not a speck of controversy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Squeaky fucking clean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bumble Bee Billy?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wife beater.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Square Dance Danny?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still appealing the mail fraud thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skippy Black and the Tippy Trolls?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora kicks the table in frustration.</context>
      <utterance>Black was deported, and the trolls... well, who gives a shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is impossible. If I ever see that Rainbow Randolph again I'll strangle him. Choke the life out of him. Squeeze his scrawny neck until his eyes pop out of his skull and bounce off the walls...</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before indulging such cheery fantasies, let's just concentrate on saving my job. Shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes flips through a thick stack of files. He suddenly stops at one.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora laughs.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on with Sheldon Mopes these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What a sap.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. Have we sunk to that level already? Smoochy the Rhino?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Always has been.</context>
      <utterance>Sap's just the pill we need right now. Mopes is a straight arrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes stands up and walks around the room.</context>
      <utterance>The guy can't get arrested, Frank. He can't even break into the birthday party circuit. Last I heard he was working hospitals and nursing homes. He's a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truth of the matter is, a successful children's show has always depended on two simple elements: a fuzzy costume and a lot of hype. Strip away the foam rubber and the network money and they're all jokes. Marginal talents.. cabaret acts... off- Broadway runoff...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I probably have ten acts in my development file -- acts I've been cultivating -- that are more deserving than Sheldon Mopes.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And each one a moral question mark. Something I can't risk at the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can do better than this guy, Frank. He brings nothing to the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes stops pacing.</context>
      <utterance>Except ethics. With Mopes, there's never been a whiff of controversy. The man's an ethical, harmless, cornball. In short, a glass of milk on two legs.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes gazes out the window at the city.</context>
      <utterance>Don't ask me to do it. You know I'll do anything for you, but please... not this...</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go find Smoochy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon stops.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Mopes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, uh, saw your performance tonight. Very...  ... spirited.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Thanks. I would've done a longer set if that guy hadn't pulled a knife on the security guard. Once the pepper spray starts flyin', that's it for the encores.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that did put a damper on the evening, didn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a new patient? On the juice, as we say?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him her card. He reads it.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, no. But it's sweet of you to assume so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Nora Bishop. V.P. of Development. Kidnet.'  Good gravy. You work for Kidnet?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon grabs her hand and shakes it.</context>
      <utterance>As stated.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's a pleasure to meet you, Nora. A real honor. Hey, you hungry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soy dogs... never thought I'd live to see the day. Organic, rich in natural protein, and nobody gets killed. Although I do feel bad for the beans. Just kidding. Sure you don't want one?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes another bite.</context>
      <utterance>Believe it or not, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So anyway, like I was saying, people always tell me, 'You gotta network, Sheldon... you gotta sell yourself... or you'll be playing the drug clinics and shopping centers the rest of your life.' And you know what I tell 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't the foggiest.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the stained, misshapen Smoochy head from the shopping bag.</context>
      <utterance>I tell 'em, it's not about the old handshake and back slap game. It's not about adding fuel to the shlock machine. It's about doing good work. Having integrity. Making people happy and delivering a positive message. Foundations are built with concrete, not plaster of Paris!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is concrete! This is integrity!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon realizes his voice was getting too loud.</context>
      <utterance>I can see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. As you can imagine, living by your convictions can be a little stressful at times.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all have our cross to bear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I was raised by my grandfather, and Grandpop paved driveways for a living...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we going into a story?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora looks glassy-eyed. She takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>Thing is, he didn't really pave them. Just covered them with black paint. Of course, once the first rain came along, people realized they'd been swindled. I vowed to myself back then that I'd never make a living through deception. Never. Whadda ya think of them apples?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She almost chokes on the word.</context>
      <utterance>The reason I'm here today, Mr. Mopes, as fate would have it, Kidnet is currently looking for a performer with... convictions. And integrity. Someone like...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon laughs.</context>
      <utterance>... yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right. Got any more jokes?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I could top that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold the phone. You're telling me that Kidnet is finally ready to do a show of Smoochy quality? Of Smoochy caliber?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... I believe we're ready to push ourselves to that level.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew this day would come! After all these years I finally meet someone in the business who gets what I do. Who gets what I'm all about. You get me, don't you, Nora?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>let's go make history!</context>
      <utterance>Well, Miss V.P. of Development...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angelo, you were always my favorite Krinkle Kid. The way you'd click your heels during the 'Jellybean Jam.' Real artistry. I'm honored to have you as a Rhinette.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A job's a job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The kids in the bleachers all scream in unison.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, kids! Who's your favorite rhino?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smoochy bounds out on stage followed by the Rhinettes who form a dancing circle around him.</context>
      <utterance>Smoochy!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, kids!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Smoochy!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids cheer as Smoochy and the Rhinettes featuring Angelo Pike, go into their "It's a Fantabulous Day in Smoochyland" number -- a catchy, bouncy song and dance routine that plays out in the sugar-coated jungle of Smoochyland.</context>
      <utterance>It's gonna be a fantabulous day in Smoochyland!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>END of prep MONTAGE.</context>
      <utterance>'Ohhhh... it's a fantabulous day in Smoochy-land/Let's have a great big cheer for the Smoochy-land band/We'll dance with our jungle pals, won't that be grand/Oh, it's a fantabulous day in Smoochy- land!' Smoochy dances right UP TO the CAMERA, FILLING the FRAME with his friendly, puffy face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was starting to think that maybe you weren't coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph takes a swig from a flask.</context>
      <utterance>I agreed to meet you, didn't I? I had a dinner engagement.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? You know, I used to have dinner engagements. Sometimes four, five a night. Dinner... drinks... I was the toast of the fucking town.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't start, Randolph. Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's why!</context>
      <utterance>Cars, boats, whores and horses, I had 'em all. When I walked into a restaurant, ten guys reached for my hat. When I stood up to take a piss, they cleared the rest room. I'd walk down the street and traffic stopped, mouths gaped. You know why? You know why, Frank?  I was Rainbow fucking Randolph!</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you through?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You're in a hurry? You don't have time for me? The guy who earned for you? The guy who put those fucking suits on your back and the pheasant au vin in your Brooklyn mouth?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph suddenly breaks down.</context>
      <utterance>I think it's fair to say we helped each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He now clings to Stokes' lapels.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta fix it, Frank. You gotta get me my slot back.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes pries Randolph's hands from his overcoat.</context>
      <utterance>How can I sit around while that rhinoceros... that horned carpetbagger gets a free ride on my dime? You and I have history, Frank! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing I can do for you. Nothing. You're a pariah. I can't even be seen with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do this to me, Frank. I'm in deep, deep shit. They kicked me out of the corporate penthouse... I got bookies breathing down my neck. I'm homeless! Don't you hear what I'm saying? I'm not gonna make it! The clock's ticking! Put yourself in my shoes, for Christ's sake!</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks Randolph squarely in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>The ugly truth is, your shoes have become my shoes. As long as the rhino's on the air, everything's by the book. No skim, no percentage. Nothing. The network wanted squeaky clean and they got it. And believe me, Mopes is sparkling.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're totally broke? You don't have a dime left to your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph looks at him hopefully as Stokes straightens his tie.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! Exactly! That's what I'm trying to tell you!</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes walks off. Randolph watches him disappear through the mist.</context>
      <utterance>Don't contact me again, Randy. Ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes is gone. Randolph takes a swig from his flask and wipes his chin with his sleeve. He stares out at the river.</context>
      <utterance>You'll get yours, Frank! The rhino too! Do you hear me?! The wheels are turning!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sooner or later, even a guy who's squeaky clean falls into mud.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon raises his hand. Nora ignores him and looks at her watch.</context>
      <utterance>Again, these are just prototypes. I've been assured by FunZone that all the bugs will be worked out before Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon suddenly stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, so let's recap before we break up...  Yes to the Smoochy ice pops. No to the Smoochy string cheese. And we're in a dick-measuring contest with Brown &amp; Brown over the shampoo split.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora throws him an icy look.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, time out, people! If I may interject, I think we're putting the cart before the horse here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora casually picks up a Smoochy Frisbee from her desk and sails it toward the open door. It lands in the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Smoochy's still earning the trust of the kids. We don't want to compromise that by asking them to buy shampoo and cheese. How 'bout we just concentrate on doing the best show possible. Huh? Without all the bells and whistles and rickata-rackita. What do you say, guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks out to the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>No problem, I'll get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John shuts the door.</context>
      <utterance>Shut the door please, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He locks it.</context>
      <utterance>Now lock it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good meeting today. I thought we tackled some hot issues. Although, I'll be honest, there were a few times that I felt my voice wasn't being heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that's a conservative estimate.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want the show to have some weight, you know? Some substance. Silly songs, sure -- but with a message. Pop quiz: How many original compositions are in the Smoochy songbook?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you sense my complete lack of interest?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora stops. She looks Sheldon in the eye for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Try two thousand. Covering every topic from how yummy vegetables are to the importance of donating plasma. Don't you get it, Nora? I'm a valuable resource. Use me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I make this real easy for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks off.</context>
      <utterance>The only reason you're on TV right now is because Rainbow Randolph is a degenerate scumbag. I didn't discover you, I delivered you. Like a bag of groceries. I have a bigger emotional investment in my nail polish. So don't peddle your sap to me, rhino. Your job is just to smile and nod your head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bartender nods and starts to pour Sheldon another drink.</context>
      <utterance>... No, no, you misunderstand me. It's not that I'm literally comparing Captain Kangaroo to Jesus Christ. I'm just saying that the Captain, like Christ, was someone you could believe in. Those guys didn't care about bells and whistles and rickita-rackata. It was all about the work. Especially Jesus. Forget about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay, my good man. Three's my limit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never saw anyone get loaded on orange juice before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sharply-dressed man, BURKE BENNETT, sits down next to Sheldon.</context>
      <utterance>Back in my college days I could put away a carton of the stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme a Five Crown. The Bartender nods. He looks over at Sheldon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smoochy the Rhino. Wow. I'm a big fan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke extends his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Gee, thanks. I usually don't get recognized without my horn.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burke Bennett. I represent kid show talent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Shel, Frank Strokes ain't in the business to make you rich. He's in it to make Frank Stokes rich. That's how these network goons operate.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's so sad. Is it just me, or is that sad?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, years ago, a client of mine, Dicky Gimble, was having a problem...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, you represented Dicky Gimble?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, before the asshole found religion. Anyway, Stokes was trying to screw my boy out of some merchandising points. Claimed he had a warehouse full of Dicky dolls that weren't moving. Now Frank and I are old friends, so I say to him, 'Okay, cock, show me the warehouse' -- see, I know the fucking warehouse is in the Bronx, and I know it's emptier than my wife's head.  To make a long story short, I walk out with a check for a hundred grand and Stokes is sitting there with his thumb up his ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pounds his fist on the table.</context>
      <utterance>That's very amusing, but I don't care about Smoochy dolls and Smoochy floor wax... I just want more creative input. This rhino came from my womb. I bore him, I nursed him, and dammit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should be the one who raises him!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shel, it's all about the dough. After you get the money, you get the power. And after you get the power, you can have Smoochy walk on stage with a hard-on if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke downs the rest of his drink and stands up.</context>
      <utterance>It's funny, that never crossed my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Sheldon his card.</context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately, until then... you're just another puppet in the prop room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a call when you're ready, kid. I'll cut the strings and open the magic door for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>at my table... talking to him.</context>
      <utterance>I saw you! I saw you in there...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, so what do you want? A parade?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're my agent! Or did you forget that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sets the tray aside.</context>
      <utterance>Ah! They're beautiful! A perfect batch of cock cookies for a very special rhino.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, you're going to learn about shame, my dear Smoochy. And I'm your professor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Nora. Why was the 'Please and Thank You Song' cut?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's sappy and it takes away from the 'Cookie Song.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Takes away? It enhances it! The cookie song is a meaningless piece of fluff without the 'Please and Thank You' coda! That's the moral anchor! That's where the lesson is! You can't sell the sizzle without the steak!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cut. And I want the 'Cookie Song' lyrics changed back to the way they were originally scripted.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that. I will not condone children consuming endless amounts of refined sugar. I have to look myself in the mirror every morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is network television, not a sprout farm. We're here to sell sugar and plastic. That's what keeps the lights on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're treating me like a puppet. You know that? Well, guess what? I am not your puppet.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An angry Sheldon storms off in frustration, but then stops. He looks back at her.</context>
      <utterance>Since when? Now get your spongy orange ass out there and dance for the cameras.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves on. Nora stares at him as he walks away. He obviously got to her. As Sheldon heads toward the studio, he doesn't notice the two beady eyes staring at him from under the stairwell. After a beat, Randolph emerges and slinks backstage. He's clutching a duffle bag.</context>
      <utterance>We have different eyes, Nora. When I go out there I see kids. You see wallets with pigtails.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cackles to himself. He then notices a box in the corner of the room. Scribbled in magic marker on the side are the words: "Rainbow Randolph crap." He walks over and pulls the box out. He slowly opens the flaps. Inside is his old costume. He pulls it out and clutches it lovingly. He smells it. The ECHOEY SOUND of his THEME SONG comes flooding back to him for a moment, along with the sound of CHILDREN LAUGHING.</context>
      <utterance>Bon soir, la Smoochy. Welcome to fatty Arbuckle-land.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up Smoochy's magic cookie bag. He then stuffs his old costume into his duffle bag.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, little ones. Rainbow Randolph will return...  After these messages!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids in the bleachers erupt in unison:</context>
      <utterance>Boy, all that jiggyin' and ziggyin' sure makes a fella hungry! Now if only I had my super duper, super secret, super special...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Magic Cookie Bag!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Magic Cookie Bag, I command thee! Come to your lord and master! The lights dim as the Smoochyland Band plays the "2001 theme." Smoochy's Magic Cookie Bag is lowered from the ceiling by a filament wire. The kids go crazy.</context>
      <utterance>Right-o-riffic!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Lookie, lookie, lookie, here comes the cookies! Fresh and organic, no need to panic! Right from the soil, no tropical oils! Sweetened with juice, for an energy boost! Fiber galore, you'll be askin' for more...'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids "ooh" and "ahh."</context>
      <utterance>Wow! Look at this cookie, kids! A rocket ship!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a special day with such special cookies!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon laughs. Stokes and Nora sit stone-faced.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you all for coming. I just wanted to iron out a few wrinkles I feel we're having in the communication department. No finger-pointing. Lord knows when you start pointing fingers, someone gets poked in the eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon applauds. Burke stands.</context>
      <utterance>Anyhoo, I'd like to turn the floor over to my new agent, Mr. Burke Bennett. So... heeeeeere's Burke!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pats Sheldon's head like a dog.</context>
      <utterance>As you can imagine, my client has many concerns, not the least of which is studio security, but we can address that later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See this guy, Frank? Take a good long look, 'cause this prick saved your life. Without him you'd be sitting in Kaplan's right now, sucking club soda through a paper straw.  And, you -- you'd be organizing puppet shows for the brats at P.S. 86. Excuse me, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no excuse for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon laughs, trying to lighten the mood. Burke gives him an affectionate slap.</context>
      <utterance>Man, I love club soda.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why the fireworks?</context>
      <utterance>We've always managed to come to some sort of arrangement, Burke.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke pours himself a drink from Stokes' private bar.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause I'm holding all the gunpowder. I represent the man who created, owns, and controls every square inch of Smoochy the Rhino.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God created Adam and what did he get? A fucking dud. My guy? He breathed life into a winner. And anyone who does a better job than God is gonna have a price.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burke, of course, is in no way comparing me to God.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem to forget that we went out and found 'your guy.' Dug up his corpse. Handed him his own show when he couldn't sell his face to a photo booth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To be fair, Nora, I was booked to open a car wash in Montauk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so you were doing him a favor?  Allow me to untangle this web of shit! I don't care what his resume was, I don't care where you found him, I don't care if his last job was juggling apples for a hut full of Pygmies on the outskirts of the Congo... the fact is, he fits a bill and you need him. Like a hungry baby needs a big tit. And that, my friends, is why you're in a box with no ventilation. And that is why the rhino is going to get what he deserves.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke walks over to Stokes' desk and leans across it. He's an inch from Stokes' face.</context>
      <utterance>What is that, exactly?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heaven, hell, and everything in between.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They clink glasses.</context>
      <utterance>To the star and new executive producer of the Smoochy show! May your reign be a long and healthy one!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still in shock. Complete creative control, part ownership of the show, discretion over merchandising and a dressing room with a toilet! Am I dreaming or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And don't forget the corporate penthouse. It took me six years to get that for Randolph.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, imagine... me, living in a penthouse. Who'd a thunk it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called the high life, kid. Get used to it. Pretty soon you'll be burnin' one hundred dollar bills just to see Franklin break a sweat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke pulls out a paper bag and hands it to Sheldon.</context>
      <utterance>Jeez, I hope not. I have a deep respect for money. Not to mention Ben Franklin who had some remarkable achievements in his lifetime.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon reaches in the bag and pulls out a revolver. He recoils in horror and immediately drops it back in the bag.</context>
      <utterance>That's your graduation present. Something you're gonna need now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think of it as a tool of the trade.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never owned a gun, I've never touched a gun, and I don't believe in guns. When I played cowboys and Indians as a kid, I was always the Chinese railroad worker.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke and Sheldon look up and notice the hulking, grinning figure of SPINNER DUNN standing over them. Spinner has the smile of a little boy despite his crooked nose and scarred face. He extends his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Trust me, Shel. It's a handy accessory in this business. Even if you don't load it, have it for show. Sometimes that's all you need. Especially with a creep like Randolph lurking around.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner!</context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Smoochy! I'm Spinner!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner's massive hand engulfs Sheldon's.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so excited to meet you! I'm Spinner!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... right. I saw you fight on TV once. I think it was your farewell bout.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RINGSIDE COMMENTATOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bloodied, defeated Spinner happily holds up the arm of his opponent after a match. He then hugs the referee. He jumps down from the ring and hugs the three judges.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight marks Spinner Dunn's final appearance in the ring. What a pleasure it's been to watch him proudly march into the record books for taking more blows to the head than any fighter in history.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGSIDE COMMENTATOR #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner wades into the stands and starts hugging the spectators.</context>
      <utterance>Scrambled a bit? Sure. You don't retire with a record of 81-59 and wind up the Governor. But on the upside, he's got the disposition of a collie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I love, Smoochy? I love when you do the Jiggy Ziggy dance! You know, the one you do during 'Silly Time?'</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet. That's a big one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna see me do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner starts Jiggying and Ziggying for Sheldon. He bangs into a table and knocks over someone's drink.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know why if there's enough room here to...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner stops, out of breath. He leans over and hugs Sheldon.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, champ, don't get overheated.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A powerful-looking woman, TOMMY COTTER, calls to Spinner from the bar.</context>
      <utterance>I... uh... love you, too, Spinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner dutifully hurries over to Tommy.</context>
      <utterance>Spinner, come over and meet the Senator!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He seems pretty popular. It must take real talent to run a place like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spinner? The guy couldn't run a water faucet. He's just a mascot. It's his cousins, a bunch of Irish mob boys, who really run the joint.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner releases the Senator's hand and rushes off.</context>
      <utterance>Don't go anywhere, Smoochy! I'll be right back after I take a dump!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you made a new friend, kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph suddenly kicks the door open and tackles Angelo. Randolph sits on top of the little man.</context>
      <utterance>Randy?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fucking traitor! My body's barely cold and already you work for the rhino?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't lie to me! I heard all about it! You strapped that horn on faster than a cheerleader gets the clap!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta eat, don't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a Krinkle Kid! Not a Smooch-bag! Say it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rhinette!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angelo punches Randolph in the mouth and flips him over. He now sits on Randolph, pointing the revolver to his face.</context>
      <utterance>Say it: I am a Krinkle Kid! Say it, before God! On the soul of Jesus Christ! Say what you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph starts crying like a child.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a Rhinette. Got that? The Krinkle Kids are ten feet under. With you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angelo sighs and puts the gun away.</context>
      <utterance>I missed you so much. Can I stay here? I got no place to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to a nasty bump near his eye.</context>
      <utterance>... They kicked me out of the corporate penthouse. Big surprise. Sons-a-bitches. That's how I got this beauty.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He yanks his lip back to reveal a missing tooth.</context>
      <utterance>And of course, there's this...</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slurps another spoonful of soup and spits a bay leaf on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>That happened after my little visit to the studio the other day. Network security. Fucking savages.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cackles insanely as he picks up a bottle of gin and takes a deep swig. He passes out and falls off the chair. Angelo leans down and lifts his head off the floor.</context>
      <utterance>I got liens, back taxes, lawyer's bills, threats against my life... I basically got the whole fucking world up my ass. It's okay, I got a loooong memory, son.  What dey sow, dey gonna reap.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph doesn't respond. Angelo slaps his face.</context>
      <utterance>Stop doing this to yourself!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wise up! You hear me? Don't piss your life away like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the rhino, Angie. He's been sent by the devil. Sent from hell to destroy me. Smoochy... is the face of evil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whenever you get a chance... I just need a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, can I call you back? Yeah, some asshole's screaming in my ear. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, you didn't have to hang up.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I didn't you'd still be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I am still here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hoping to correct that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nora, I want us to start off on the right foot. I want you to know that I value your input and I don't want you to feel intimidated just because the power structure has changed a bit. I consider you a partner.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. That'll come in handy if we're ever at a square dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was never much of the do- se-do type, but what I would love to do is take you out to lunch one day. You know, just two colleagues chewing the fat... forming a mutual respect... planting the seeds of cooperation...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fair enough. If you change your mind --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon just nods and starts to exit.</context>
      <utterance>I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He passes a plant by the door.</context>
      <utterance>Okay then, I'll be in my office if you need me. If you want to brainstorm about anything. Ideas and so forth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She ignores him. He exits.</context>
      <utterance>Ficus?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sheldon jumps. He's surprised to Tommy from Spinner Dunn's restaurant. Tommy's crew, ROY, DANNY, JIMMY and SAMMY occupy the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>My cousin Spinner's take quite a shine to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever since you came in the restaurant. He can't stop yakkin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he's a very nice man. Very sweet disposition for someone that size.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, I was wondering if maybe you could give him a little floor space.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, a little part on the show. You're the executive producer now. You call the shots, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon laughs again. Tommy gets quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, that's a very sweet offer, and I love Spinner, but TV is a complicated medium and... I mean, that would be like me getting into the ring with a prizefighter.  Can you imagine such a thing? Boom. K.O.! What's the alphabet, Mommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This makes me sad. Very, very, sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong, Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I'm just very sad right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who made you sad, Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guys look menacingly at Sheldon. They rise and walk around his desk until they're on either side of him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to mention names.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy now smiles and walks over to Sheldon. She musses Sheldon's hair.</context>
      <utterance>You know what? Maybe I can find Spinner a little something to do on the show. That's probably the best solution.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a good boy, Mopes. Don't think we don't remember favors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're looking to bring in that many pieces I gotta put a crew together. Plus, we're lookin' at transpo, a few leash handlers, a cleanup boy and a doper to keep the inventory quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, this all sounds awfully elaborate. I might have to forgo the union and just borrow a few animals from a pet shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't recommend it. Miss Carol from Romper Room tried that once and she's still limping.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... that's nice of you, Ben, but a card would have been fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FunZone Toys would very much like the Smoochy contract, Mr. Mopes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this... I mean... are you offering me a bribe or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon picks up the money and tosses it back to Ben. Sheldon rises from his desk.</context>
      <utterance>FunZone Toys would very much like the Smoochy contract, Mr. Mopes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon escorts Ben out the door and slams it shut. The PHONE RINGS. Sheldon walks over and picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Normally, sir, we take the trash out at the end of the day, but I think I'll make an exception in your case.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Mr. Feedlepepper on line two.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Sheldon punches line two.</context>
      <utterance>He says he's an old friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Sheldon hangs up stunned. Nora walks in holding the daily news.</context>
      <utterance>You better grow eyes on the back of your fucking head, you horned piece of shit! I won't sleep until the worms are crawlin' up your foam rubber ass! I'm going on safari, motherfucker... safari!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations on your little ice show.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tosses the paper on his desk.</context>
      <utterance>It didn't take you long to sell out, did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits. A confused Sheldon looks at the "Around Town" column.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to your precious integrity? Or was that just part of your dog and pony act.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burke, I never agreed to do an ice show.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shel, do you know what kind of cash we'll take in between the gate and concessions? A venture like this gets you money and muscle. Times twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ice shows represent everything I'm against. They're mindless spectacles whose main purpose is to sell overpriced sugar-water and cheap plastic toys that splinter in a kid's mouth on the ride home.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon tears the contract in half.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I know you got this fetish for ethics, but now's not the time to fly that kite. No one's ever refused a shot at an ice show.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until now. Smoochy doesn't sell out, Burke. You should be proud of that. Proud that you represent a client who paves driveways, not paints them over.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke just sits there, stunned. A waitress, SANDY, passes by the booth.</context>
      <utterance>I'm thrilled, Shel. Knocked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have a pineapple juice, Sandy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pineapple? What happened to orange juice?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm feeling feisty tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner stands up to take a bow and almost knocks the entire bandstand over. There is a smattering of confused applause from the kids in the bleachers. Spinner drops the cowbell and it clangs on the studio floor.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, wasn't that fun? In an awkward kind of way? Anyhoo, how 'bout a big round of applause for the newest member of the Smoochyland Band... former heavyweight contender, Spinner Dunn!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that was great, Spinner. Just watch your elbow next time. Pinky's probably gonna lose that tooth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner skips off humming "Pop Goes the Weasel" and banging his cowbell. Nora passes Sheldon backstage.</context>
      <utterance>Okey doke. I'm gonna go get drunk now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice job. Casting the show with mental patients, I like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is not a mental patient. He's an ex-boxer and nightclub owner who happens to have the sweet innocent brian of a five-year-old!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me for not making the distinction.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A limo pulls up in front of them. Merv opens the back door.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks anyway, but I'm going uptown.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merv Green, Sheldon. It's a pleasure to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon laughs nervously.</context>
      <utterance>If you're hoping for an autograph, the gun's a bit much. The whole 'catch more flies with honey' thing -- it really holds water.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheldon, I represent the Parade of Hope Foundation. Maybe you've heard of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You raise money to build children's hospitals, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merv and the thug laugh.</context>
      <utterance>We've been known to add a brick or two, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheldon, let me get right to the point -- there's talk on the street that you're pulling out of the ice show. Is that true?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I never agreed to an ice show, nor would I ever agree to do an ice show, and let me add that none of this is your concern, sir.  Sheesh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen carefully, son: Parade of Hope has sponsored every Kidnet ice show since 1964. We take a piece off the top and everybody walks away happy. So let's not buck history.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I appreciate the offer, but for the gazillionth time, I'm not doing an ice show, so we have nothing to discuss. Now, if you'll just pull over, I'll get out and we'll say our toodley-dos.  Far corner, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car pulls to the curb.</context>
      <utterance>Allow me to be less murky. Starting tomorrow, Smoochy the Rhino raises his baton for Parade of Hope. Benefits, banquets, fund-raisers, I want it all.  Pull over, Terry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And as far as the ice show goes... I recommend you start shopping for skates. The door pops open and Sheldon is tossed out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is unacceptable, Burke! I'm calling the authorities.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do it, Shel. You rat on Parade of Hope and you'll be lucky if they find your toenails. These guys are the roughest of all the charities.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was threatened by an organization that's supposed to help children! What kind of world is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Burke hangs up. After a beat, Sheldon's DOORBELL RINGS. He walks over to the door and opens it. To his surprise, Nora is standing there.</context>
      <utterance>The real one. My advice? Consider the ice show and stay healthy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora enters. She seems a little wobbly. Sheldon notices she's holding a pint of whiskey.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting drunk and I'm not used to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora looks at him for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well, not to make you feel worse, but with alcohol you're also consuming empty calories.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just that... I want to apologize, actually. And on those rare occasions when I feel the need to apologize for something, it helps if I'm, you know... shit- faced.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora trips slightly. Sheldon takes the whiskey from her.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. I'm honored.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads her out on the balcony. They look out at the city.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we get some air?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little out of line.</context>
      <utterance>I... I may have been a little harsh when we spoke the other day.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it wasn't as bad as the week before when you called me a pasty- faced, no-talent hack.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that was probably insensitive as well.  I heard you're not doing the ice show. I find that... incredibly admirable. Why didn't you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora looks down.</context>
      <utterance>I guess I didn't want to spoil your fun. You look so content when you're berating me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I have become a bit hardened over the years. Sincerity's an easy disguise in this business. It's hard to know who's on the level.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe me, I'm learning that more and more every day.  'Sometimes light is really dark, Sometimes crows can sing like larks Sometimes Winter feels like Spring, Don't think you know everything.'</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Rickets the Hippo'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember Rickets?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was my favorite show when I was a kid. Rickets was the one face I knew I could trust.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's how I felt! Rickets had real depth. He was my inspiration for Smoochy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? He was my inspiration to work in children's television.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe it. I never met anyone who even remembers Rickets. Do you remember the Klunky-Wunky dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon starts doing the rather insane-looking Klunky- Wunky dance. Nora does it with him. They both stop and look at each other. Sheldon impulsively leans in and kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>Remember it? I did it at my first communion.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora grabs his head and pulls it toward her. They begin kissing passionately.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. That was a mistake, right? I didn't mean for that to hap--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not full of shit like all the others, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're for real, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, I couldn't tell... First I thought it was an act... and then I just thought you were a simp or something...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue to kiss. Nora abruptly stops.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh... you don't have to explain...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora exits the balcony and collects her coat and purse.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong? Is it the whiskey? If you have to throw up, be my guest. Anywhere you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon follows her to the door. She stops and looks at him for a moment. The PHONE starts to RING. Neither of them says anything for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>It's just getting late.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits. Sheldon shuts the door and sighs. He goes to the bar to pour himself another orange juice before picking up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Better get that. Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Mopes? My name is Benjamin Kunklepeck and I'm calling on behalf of 'Parents for Decency in Children's Television,' perhaps you've heard of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I like where you're coming from. It's an issue very close to my heart. Why just yesterday I was commenting --</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we're having a banquet tomorrow and we'd be honored to have you perform for us. We would also like to present you with a plaque for your ongoing commitment to children's television. The presenter will be a young orphan with mild asthma. Can you attend?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be silly. The chance to have Smoochy the Rhino perform at our little soiree? I'd carry you piggy-back through a bed of hot rusty glass if I had to.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's always a pleasure to help out a worthy cause. And believe me, I've learned lately that it's not all sunshine and daffodils in the land of non- profit.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just looove your show, by the way. It's such a refreshing change of pace from that dreadful embezzler... what's his name again? Rainbow something or other?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Randolph.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Rainbow Randolph. What a scoundrel! He's probably gay too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know. I feel sorry for him, actually. He obviously has problems or issues that he needs to sort out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, yeah, but don't you take particular glee in that you basically stole his time slot? Helped shovel dirt onto his miserable corpse, as it were?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just try to imagine --</context>
      <utterance>No, I would never take pleasure in someone's downfall. You know the old expression about walking a mile in another man's shoes? Well, that really holds water.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You hate him! Admit it!</context>
      <utterance>Come on, he's a fucking asshole!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... can we listen to the radio?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, they're ready for you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta say, this is a first -- I never performed in a tractor parts warehouse before.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we like to do these things no-frills. It's all about the kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph opens the door a crack and listens. We hear an O.S. VOICE from inside.</context>
      <utterance>Amen to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We hear APPLAUSE. Randolph quickly opens the rusty door.</context>
      <utterance>It gives me great pleasure to introduce our very special guest... a supporter of the cause and a friend to the brotherhood. Please welcome, the one, the only... Smoochy the Rhino!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves Sheldon inside.</context>
      <utterance>Knock 'em dead, kid!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NAZIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A huge swastika banner unfurls behind Smoochy, framing him like Patton in front of the American flag. Flashbulbs go off. The "Heil Smoochys" continue. A GERMAN MARCH starts to BLARE from the SPEAKERS. Looking stunned, Sheldon slowly leans into the mic. He clears his throat. The MUSIC STOPS. Everyone quiets down. He searches for just the right words, and finally...</context>
      <utterance>Heil Smoochy! Heil Smoochy! Heil Smoochy!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a sea of policemen bursts into the warehouse.</context>
      <utterance>It's my sincere hope that I'm dreaming right now, but in the event that I'm not... what's the deal with the swastikas?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAD COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pandemonium ensues us all the Nazis run for cover. Sheldon stands in the middle of it all, unsure what to do.</context>
      <utterance>This is an unlawful assembly, you kraut sons-a-bitches! You're all under arrest!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you officially a member of the Aryan Brotherhood, Sheldon?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true you consider Adolph Hitler your personal hero?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think associating with neo- Nazis might adversely affect your career?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does it feel to be a hate- filled racist scumbag?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't hate anyone!</context>
      <utterance>This is a mix-up! I'm innocent!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that mean you don't hate Nazis?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon is shoved into the back seat of a squad car. It drives off, SIRENS BLARING.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! I didn't say that! I --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coos at a baby in a stroller...</context>
      <utterance>Hi there, poochy!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And grabs a rose from a flower vendor before handing it to an old lady...</context>
      <utterance>Well, aren't you the cutest little boo-boo in the world!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He continues to dance onward, waving back at everyone. Unfortunately, he doesn't realize he's heading straight for a light pole and slams into it with a sickening smack.</context>
      <utterance>For you, my dear! May you live to be a hundred!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have nothing to talk about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me you believe what they're saying!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to believe anyone. The picture in the paper said it all. No one forced you to perform at that rally.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perform? I barely sang one song.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well maybe next time you'll do a longer set.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nora, I had no idea that was a Nazi function. None whatsoever!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny, you'd think the fifty-foot swastika you were standing in front of might've given you a hint.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora stops and looks Sheldon in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>The papers are blowing that out of proportion. It was nowhere near that big.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon looks crushed.</context>
      <utterance>Look, the fact of the matter is, I don't know you, okay? Not really. So don't expect me to go out on an emotional limb here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about the balcony? What about the Klunky-Wunky dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him for a moment and then walks off.</context>
      <utterance>I was drunk. Don't read too much into it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLD VAGRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Vagrant shakes his head sadly.</context>
      <utterance>If you're lookin' to get a cup of juice, the well's dried up, son. City shut her down. Bastards'll put a new pair of tits on the Statue of Liberty, but they won't help a poor hophead.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD VAGRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks off.</context>
      <utterance>Just once I wish I had a little clout. You know? I'd set things straight in this town, believe me.  Hell of a world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell of a world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Stokes, let's cut the bullshit. We want Takashi in that Smoochy slot and we're willing to do whatever it takes to get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me for saying this, but for a non-resident of this country, you speak impeccable English.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm originally from Teaneck.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We own every hair on this bastard's head and we're willing to share a few strands... if you get my drift.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not that simple. I have an executive board to answer to. I wish I could just snap my fingers and make a deal but --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chick snaps his fingers and Tobi, the third Asian guy, walks over and drops a duffel bag on Stokes' desk.</context>
      <utterance>You mean like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my. And what is this on my desk?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes stares down at the bundle of opportunity on his desk.</context>
      <utterance>Two hundred grand in a Louis Vuitton duffle bag. Get our boy the slot and we'll round it off to a million. And you can keep the luggage.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes unzips the bag and gazes at the money. He looks up at Chick and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You're dealing with an honorable culture, Frank. We know how to play ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chick smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, I suddenly feel invigorated and full of hope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flops down on the couch.</context>
      <utterance>So here's the good news: Yes, I'll be happy to end my sabbatical and return to my old slot. I know you and Frank are in a bind, so I'll start Monday. Call wardrobe, call props, tell 'em the R man is back and he's ready to start whistlin' dem happy tunes for da little chillens.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh. Who do ya gotta blow to get a Scotch around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph jumps to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>You've got three seconds to pry your ass off my couch and get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dammit, Nora! The rhino's gone! You need that slot filled and I'm ready to reclaim what's rightfully mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just in case you forgot, you're a criminal and a scumbag.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, so maybe I commandeered a stray shekel or two. Big deal! Compared to what Smoochy did that's like jerking off in the supermarket.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph walks over and puts his hands on her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you shop?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Have you lost all affection for me? After what we once had?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a long time ago. I was young and stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why we broke up I'll never know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You turned into an asshole and I didn't love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans in to kiss her and she shoves him away so violently he almost falls over the coffee table.</context>
      <utterance>We could've worked through all that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it, Nora! The public is clamoring for me! I'm a fucking patriot! Mopes is a Nazi! He's evil! He's probably even gay! You should've seen the way he was checking me out in the car!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does what mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said he was checking you out in the car. What car?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora starts to walk closer to him. He backs up.</context>
      <utterance>No... it's just a vibe! A Nazi homosexual vibe! It emanates from the television! The whole Smoochy costume... with the erect horn... I mean, what's that all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're talking awfully fast, Randolph.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still love you! Let's go on a date!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She backs him against the wall and looks him in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Were you at that rally? Tell me! Did you have something to do with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph just looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Did you set Sheldon up?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora hauls off and punches him in the jaw.</context>
      <utterance>You know, now I remember why we broke up. Always with the accusations. Bitch, bitch, bitch...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They wanna meet ya.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong, kid? The mayor of Patterson's here with his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner starts violently pounding his head on the bar, causing GLASSES to RATTLE.</context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna meet no one. I miss Smoochy! He never woulda done the things they say he done. He ain't no Nazi. Someone's making stuff up. I just know it, Tommy. Someone's making stuff up!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora enters the restaurant. She looks around and approaches Tommy.</context>
      <utterance>I want Smoochy back! I want to be on TV again! I want to play my cowbell!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Tommy. Hi, Spinner. Has Burke been in tonight?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't seen him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something I can help you with?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner lifts his head from the bar.</context>
      <utterance>I have to talk to him. It's about Sheldon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheldon? What about Sheldon?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a beat, the door is kicked open and Tommy and his crew are standing there.</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to sleep, asshole! Read the fucking meter some other time!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna tell me about the rhino?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, this is private property, creep! And you're trespassing!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danny advances toward a shaking Randolph, fist clenched and rolling up his sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>Danny, go give Mr. Smiley a little back rub.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH'S POV - DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danny's fist FILLS the FRAME, TURNING IT BLACK as we hear the PUNCH.</context>
      <utterance>approaches. He cocks his arm and throws a punch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does it feel to be voted the most hated man in America, Randolph?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a country like this, where your average citizen is a fuckin' Neanderthal, I wear it as a badge of honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Ms. Bishop's charge that you have an unhealthy obsession with Sheldon Mopes?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone throws an egg and it hits Randolph in the face.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I barely know that broad. She's a wacko. An opportunist. I'm the most accused man since Jimmy Hoffa.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That was mean and uncalled for!</context>
      <utterance>That was unfair! Who threw that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't be back here if it wasn't for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just sorry I didn't believe you... that I got swept up in the frenzy of anti-Smoochyism.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a couple of pre-show deep breaths. A STAGEHAND approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Well, this town's a house of mirrors sometimes. It's hard to know what you're looking at.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGEHAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon exits backstage.</context>
      <utterance>They're ready for you, Sheldon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>An explosion of enthusiasm from the kids in the bleachers.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen... boys and girls...  Who's your favorite rhino?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gasps from the bleachers.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. It's good to be back. You know, kids, sometimes life in the jungle can be unfair. A place where nice guys don't just finish last... they get their heads cut off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That pretty world you think you know is just props and scenery. Lollipop trees with roots in venom!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>watches nervously from offstage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids in the bleachers howl along with Smoochy.</context>
      <utterance>So look around you, boys and girls. Every day. Be diligent! Stand strong! As the old proverb says: Beat a dog one time too many and you get a wolf! Let's start howling! Howl for me, boys and girls!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids cheer as the Smoochyland Band launches into the Hokey-Pokey song and Smoochy starts dancing. The kids pour out of the bleachers onto the jungle set. Everyone is dancing and having a ball. Nora is clapping to the music offstage. Sheldon and Nora exchange affectionate glances.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I just wanted to get that off my chest. Who wants to do the Hokey-Pokey?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TARA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Smoochy's back and boy did we miss him. Hundreds of well- wishers stood outside Kidnet Studios today hoping to catch a glimpse of their favorite rhino.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, Tara. Smoochy's popularity is stronger than ever thanks to his recent exoneration as a Nazi sympathizer. In fact, several movie studios are offering big bucks for a chance to bring the Smoochy story to the silver screen...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps up and kicks the TV over. He picks up a lamp and starts beating the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Bad... very bad... too much for brain... pressure building... ears ringing... eyes burning... contempt overflowing...</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angelo, who was cooking in the kitchen, runs out. He's wearing an apron.</context>
      <utterance>I hate you! I fucking hate you!!! You devil-horned mind fucker! Die, die, die!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the lamp from Randolph.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?! That's a Zenith!  Look at this place!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it! I want you out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I supposed to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care!  Out!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I missed you so much!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops Sheldon and pulls out his cowbell.</context>
      <utterance>I missed you too, champ.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts banging on it with a butter knife. Sheldon cringes.</context>
      <utterance>I've been practicing and practicing and I got real good, Sheldon. Real good!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna see me march?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner starts marching through the restaurant, clanging the cowbell. People who are trying to eat their dinner look annoyed. Sheldon sits back down at his table.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, why not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you were saying you had some good news?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke gleefully slaps Sheldon on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Some very good news. After giving it a lot of thought... I've decided to do the ice show.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally! I got me a bar mitzvah boy. Today you are a man!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I realize now it's a sin to waste your power.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like they say, rock bottom's a college education.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke's grin suddenly fades.</context>
      <utterance>But here's the really good news: I'm doing it myself. No sponsors, no vendors, no crooks. Not one dirty hand will touch this. Not one person will make a dollar off these kids. Smoochy on Ice will be a study in purity.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As far as food concessions go, I'll supply the refreshments. For free. Low sodium, whole wheat pretzels and apple slices. Healthy stuff. Now are you ready for the best part?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm holding my breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke looks pale.</context>
      <utterance>All profits from ticket sales will be used to built a state-of-the- art methadone clinic in Coney Island.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not just talking a run-of-the- mill clinic... I'm going to build a methadone palace. A place where men and women can withdraw in luxury.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheldon, you can't do an ice show and cut out the vendors. And more importantly, you can't cut out the Parade of Hope. It's suicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon rises and tosses his napkin down.</context>
      <utterance>You always told me, when you've got muscles you make the rules. Well, I'm feeling pretty strong right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon exits. Burke sits there, looking very concerned. On his way out the door, Tommy stops Sheldon. Spinner's COWBELL CLANGING continues.</context>
      <utterance>All this time I was letting the business use me. Well, I think it's time I start using the business. I've got my clout back and I'm not gonna waste it this time. Take care of it, Burke.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shel, you gotta help me out. He bangs that goddamn thing from morning till night. I got a headache that goes from my eyes to my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever I can do, Tommy, just say it. You know I love Spinner. And I owe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give the boy something else to do on the show. Anything. Just as long as it don't clang, chime or honk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like complications, Frank. You got one week to get Takashi that slot or you're gonna be shakin' hands with Buddha.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The show's more popular than ever.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you understand? My hands are tied. The rhino's been exonerated.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sambo and Tobi start to advance on Stokes.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, boys, chop him up, bag him and dump him in the woods.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chick leans into Stokes' face.</context>
      <utterance>All right! I'll take care of it! I just need time!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exit.</context>
      <utterance>One week, Jeeves. Got that? Or I get a blender and make an Orange Julius with your feet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph just looks at him for a moment. He looks at all the rhino-related imagery. He starts shaking and suddenly jumps over the table and attacks the Man.</context>
      <utterance>Save the rhino! Before it's too late! Make a donation! Save the rhino!  Hey, mister, ya wanna help save the rhino?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Save the Rainbow!</context>
      <utterance>I'm the one who needs to be saved! Me. I'm broke! I lost my lawyer! My only friend kicked me out! I'm a fucking peanut shell in the shape of a man! Save the Rainbow! Save the Rainbow!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph grabs the collection can and runs off.</context>
      <utterance>Help! Someone call a cop!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your client is suffocating me. To make matters worse, he's caused me to veer into a hazardous situation. A situation that otherwise could have a very happy ending.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me more about the Asians.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes stops walking and grabs Burke's arm.</context>
      <utterance>They're ruthless. Unwavering. Unprincipled. And best of all, they know how the game is played. They respect our delicate ecosystem of mutual benefit.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd bring you in on this, Burke. You'd be my partner on the Takashi deal. Split down the middle. We have an opportunity to get back on track here. Back to the way it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The good old days.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men look at each other as thoughts pass silently between them.</context>
      <utterance>Pre-rhinoceros.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is very sticky ground we're about to walk on.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you're used to a little glue on your shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me poke around. Sift through the possibilities.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is what happens to guys who keep secrets, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I promise!</context>
      <utterance>I'll give you the rest next week!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The thug punches him in the stomach again.</context>
      <utterance>It's not me you're fucking over, it's sick kids. You got something against sick kids, Johnny?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merv nods to one of the thugs who releases Peter Pan. He slumps to the ground. Merv kneels down and lifts his head from the pavement.</context>
      <utterance>No! I love sick kids!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of Merv's thugs leans in, whispers something to Merv, who looks up to see. Burke standing in the mouth of the alley.</context>
      <utterance>And you tell that fat producer of yours, if he ever gives me a low head count again, he'll lose the other thumb.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merv Green. How's tricks, kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whose bones are you pickin' today?</context>
      <utterance>Well, if it ain't smilin' Burke.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a minute, pally?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one freezes me out of an ice show. No one. I don't care how many fucking clinics he's trying to save.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm chokin' on the same bone as you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're trying to aggravate me, you're doing a hell of a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not here to aggravate, just educate. I think Mopes might be talking to people he shouldn't be talking to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an ugly string of words.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>He's got it in his head that he's gonna clean up the way we do business.  Truthfully? I wouldn't be surprised if he's wearing a wire.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps off the curb to hail a cab.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, I got a thing across town.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke hops into a cab. Merv watches the cab pull away.</context>
      <utterance>Let's keep talking, Merv. There's oughta be some kind of solution. Don't you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A crowd starts to form on the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>I urge you to listen! It has a surprise ending you won't want to miss!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches down and picks up a can of gasoline.</context>
      <utterance>It's the story of a venomous rhino and his aggressive campaign to slander, vilify, defame, denigrate and villainize my good name! But one thing he can't do, is take my life from me. No, friends, only I have the power to do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph raises the can over his head and pauses dramatically.</context>
      <utterance>This is what Smoochy has done to me! He's brought me to this! I can no longer live in a world where the innocent suffer and the wicked thrive!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is God??!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd starts to applaud. Randolph looks baffled.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to do this, people. Don't try to talk me out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it! Light it!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our guest of honor will be here any moment! This is for his eyes! For his conscience. He'll have to live with this imagine for the rest of his miserable life!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it from me, Lester. Use your power. Don't squander it -- build with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon glances up from his paper.</context>
      <utterance>Sound advice, Mr. Mopes. If I ever get any power I'll give that a whirl.  Hey, what's going on up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes back to his paper.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like a street performer of some sort.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph tries to light another match, but it's wet from the gasoline. The crowd laughs and starts taunting him.</context>
      <utterance>This is it, folks! It's showtime! I'm sorry to do this, but he's left me no choice!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph keeps trying to light the match. Finally, after several attempts, it lights. He holds it up. The crowd burst into applause.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, you hillbilly assholes! You're borough trash! Go back to your huts across the river!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you! Fuck all you people! I was the last of the Mohicans! You'll never see another Rainbow Randolph in this lifetime! You had me and you blew it! All of you! He turns and faces the approaching limousine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brings the match closer to his gasoline-soaked body. The limo continues to approach. The crowd taunts him to do it. He tries to bring the match closer, but his hand is shaking. Suddenly, a LITTLE GIRL pushes through the crowd. Everyone quiets down as she looks up at Randolph.</context>
      <utterance>This if for you, Smoochy! Remember this! As long as you live, remember this image! You did this to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph freezes as he looks down at the Little Girl. A slight look of hope comes over his face. She smiles sweetly at him, walks over, and blows out the match. Randolph is overcome with emotion. Just then, Sheldon's LIMO WHOOSHES past him. The crowd cheers.</context>
      <utterance>Whatcha doin', Rainbow Randolph?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smoochy!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're too talented for the cowbell, Spinner. Cowbells are for babies.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't no baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner's face starts to perk up.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. You're a fully grown man. With whiskers... and scars... the whole sha-bang. That's why you deserve a bigger role on the show. A more important role...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Stepdads are people too/ They have bad days, like we all do/ Be patient and help them through/ Stepdads are people too...' Smoochy continues the song.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smoochy addresses them.</context>
      <utterance>... 'So three cheers for the man that I proudly call Stan... He's not quite a dad or a brother... Yes, he gets cross, but still he's the boss... And besides he takes care of my mother!' The song ends. The kids in the bleachers applaud.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, kids. First impressions, good or bad, are not always what they seem. Just like a new puppy, new dads need to adjust to their surroundings. So give 'em time! But always remember... if he becomes abusive to you or Mommy... what are the magic numbers?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIDS IN BLEACHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine-One-One!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Smoochyland Band plays a little fanfare.</context>
      <utterance>Right-o-riffic!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moochy the Rhino!</context>
      <utterance>And now, boys and girls, I have a special surprise. I'd like to introduce the newest member of the Magic Jungle... my cousin...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner freezes. He stares at the camera.</context>
      <utterance>Howdy, Moochy! Welcome to the Jungle! You wanna say howdy to the kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moochy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Moochy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. We've established that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fine, Spinner. We'll edit it out. But tomorrow in rehearsal we're gonna work on a new thing called 'the importance of hitting your mark.'</utterance>
   <speaker>SPINNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spinner dances off. A beat later, Nora enters and shuts the door. There's an awkward beat of silence.</context>
      <utterance>Great! I get to hit something!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read about the ice show.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, the papers seem to be really covering it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's great. What you're doing for that clinic.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just need some clarification...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. Spinner just needs a little more rehearsal. I'll get him there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon looks uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>No I mean about us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever since you've been back I just feel like there's something that's not connecting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I'm still readjusting a little. Like a guy who's come back from the war. Not that I'd equate my misfortune with the brave men and women who protect us overseas.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon suddenly jumps up and grabs her. He kisses her passionately. Nora immediately starts ripping off his costume as they make out. They fall to the floor in a lustful embrace.</context>
      <utterance>I just thought we were on our way to something... granted, my mistaken belief that you had ties to Neo-Nazis might have put a damper on our relationship, but I'm sorry for --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knew Smoochy had a cousin Moochy? They look fucking identical.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smoochy is bright orange, Moochy is burnt rust! Read the papers! Do I gotta take you back to fucking kindergarten?</utterance>
   <speaker>MITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merv's anger builds. He turns to a picture of Smoochy which is tacked to a bulletin board along with other kid show personalities that the foundation extorts. Merv picks up a letter opener and violently thrusts it into the picture.</context>
      <utterance>All you said was 'hit the rhino.' You never specified the color. I'm not taking the blame for this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not through with you yet, rhino! Your time will fucking come!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my fault. He'd still be alive if it wasn't for me. He would have been so proud to be in the ice show.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was nothing you could have done. Don't torture yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy and the boys walk over. Tommy puts his arm around Sheldon as he gazes somberly at Spinner.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Spinner. I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He really loved you, Shel. And this I guarantee -- that fucking Randolph has seen his last rainbow. We're gonna find him, cut off his balls, and shove 'em up his ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you better leave it to the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's against procedure.</context>
      <utterance>They won't do the ball thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't forget -- that hit was meant for you, Shel. So from now on, everywhere you go, we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay, Tommy. I'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy's crew nods and agrees.</context>
      <utterance>Fine, nothin'. And as Christ is my witness, no one's touchin' a hair on your fuckin' head. Spinner would have wanted it that way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, boys, let's get shit- faced. For Spin. They head for the bar. Nora and Sheldon look down at Spinner in silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't Rickets the Hippo have a song about death?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'The Last Nappy Time.' It gave me a lot of comfort when my mother died.  'When doggies stop barking And fish cease to swim And Grandpa lays silent, from his head to his limbs Sadness will find you But soon you'll feel fine...' Sheldon joins in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON/NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon looks at her. They embrace as BAGPIPE MUSIC</context>
      <utterance>'In life we all have Our Last Nappy Time.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The papers say you were the mastermind.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mastermind? I can barely figure out how to unzip my pants these days. Just taking a piss is a logistical nightmare.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe you, Randy. But you can't come back to my place. They'll find you. You gotta go underground.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph sits up on the conveyor belt, blanket draped over his shoulders. He's a physical and emotional wreck.</context>
      <utterance>It's heatin' up out there. Every cop in New York is looking for you. And Tommy Cotter's boys are combin' the streets. You're gonna have to stay put for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was an altar boy once. Did you know that? I wanted to be a priest. Do you believe in angels, Angie?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angels?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angelo hops up on the conveyor belt to console Randolph. Randolph rests his head on Angelo's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>There was a little angel in pigtails. She was the only one who cared about me. She saved my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't want to kill yourself, Randy. You know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps it's time to heal. To accept the fact that Smoochy has won and gracefully march forward. True, I'm currently wanted for a murder I didn't commit. But I have faith. Faith that justice will prevail.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strokes Randolph's head.</context>
      <utterance>Now you're talkin', kid. This is a big step... I'm proud of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you bring lunch?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chicken and stars?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like you asked for.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I have some, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph sniffs and manages a small pitiful smile. Angelo musses his hair.</context>
      <utterance>For a smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Atta boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angelo hops off the conveyor belt and turns on the hot plate. He starts to open a can of soup. Randolph reaches into the bag and pulls out a copy of the New York Post. The lead article's headline reads, "WAKE FOR SPINNER." A large photograph shows mourners leaving the restaurant after the wake. Clearly visible are Sheldon and Nora. They have their arms around each other. Randolph's eyes widen. He starts to hyperventilate. Angelo looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Here, I got you some crossword puzzles and stuff to read.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, Randolph expels a blood-curdling scream that ECHOES through the factory.</context>
      <utterance>You okay? Randy?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angelo drops the soup. Birds in the factory flutter from the rafters.</context>
      <utterance>Motherfucker!!!!!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big news, Shel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't Smiley who killed Spinner. It was Parade of Hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merv Green?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure? The cops have tons of evidence on Randolph.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See the neck? Snapped like a twig. Animals... Parade of Hope's calling card. When they do a guy, they like to sign the tab.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Green?</context>
      <utterance>What's that guy's name over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Merv Green.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was one time they shoulda left the tab blank.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew Merv Green was a scumbag from the day he grabbed my ass at a 'Feed the Children' benefit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, God help those guys now. They're gonna get a first-class ride through the criminal justice system, and I'm buying the tickets.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all taken care of, Shel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a mistake! An honest mistake! All I'm trying to do is help children.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like kids, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Of course!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danny, holding a hatchet, advances toward Merv. Tommy casually walks away. We STAY WITH Tommy. Merv is NO</context>
      <utterance>So you must know a few fairy tales. Danny, tell him the one about the worthless prick who gets his head chopped off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We hear the sound of the HATCHET HITTING its target. Merv's pleading stops.</context>
      <utterance>No... no... no! He SCREAMS.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you know why charities go under sometimes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't want to hear this.</context>
      <utterance>Do we really need to hear this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A clean cut.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then we took his head and --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you! Specifics about his head are superfluous at this point.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She turns around. Chick, Tobi, and Sambo are standing there. Chick walks over to the cork board. He scans a row of cards that all read "Smoochy."</context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you with something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rips a Smoochy index card from the board, walks over to her and waves it in her face.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, honey, you can help us with something...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell that boss of yours he better take care of the rhino problem. In my culture we honor deals or invite consequences.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chick looks at his boys and chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about and your cologne's making me nauseous. Other than that, you're great company.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spicy little thing, isn't she?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes the knife from her throat and hurls it toward the bulletin board. It lands -- sticking right in the middle of a Smoochy card.</context>
      <utterance>Takashi gets that time slot. You hear me, girly? Tell that boss of yours we'll kill everyone at this fucking network if we have to. Starting with the pretty ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exit.</context>
      <utterance>Auf Wiedersehen, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Stokes. He's behind the whole thing! He cut some kind of deal for the Smoochy slot!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants you out so he can put Takashi in!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Takashi?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon's head is swimming. Suddenly the front door to to the penthouse bursts open. Randolph, dressed like he's about to do his old show, stumbles in waving a gun.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Sheldon! Don't you ever pick up a copy of International Performer? He's the hottest kid show host from Asia.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He almost trips as he stumbles over to Sheldon. He waves the gun in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Ah! How very cozy. Like two logs in a little bonfire. All we need is a few sticks and some wienies.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon looks stunned. Nora hangs her head.</context>
      <utterance>I had her before you! Pachyderm! I was in love with her! In love! And you snatched her away! Like a common thief! You're the bad guy! Not me! He's the bad guy, Nora. He's incapable of understanding the love we once had! Tender, yet passionate. Old-fashioned, yet experimental.  Tell him about a few of our experiments, Nora! Tell him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, but doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>Is this true? Please tell me it's just the confused ramblings of a diseased mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy mother of Toledo. When exactly were you planning to let me know about this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, there was a time -- and I'm not proud of this -- but there was a time when I was a bit of a... kiddie-host groupie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just another action figure for her collection!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not fair!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him about Jingle Jackson!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dated Jingle Jackson?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks down, somewhat ashamed. A look of utter shock comes over Sheldon.</context>
      <utterance>The bells turned her on. Hey, tell him about Jumbo Johnny! There's a tale for ya! A whale of a tale!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh good Lord in Heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, what I did before I met you is none of your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves the gun threateningly as he backs up to an armchair and sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Both of you! This is my show!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you fully understand the power of a condemned man? Do you? I'm already wanted for one murder, why should I give a flaming horse's twat if I commit two more?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... uh... read once that the best way to diffuse a tense situation is with a little humor. To that end, would you like to hear a funny joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please. Go blow yourself, Martha.  Fix me a beverage, woman. Make me one of those drinks that used to make us all warm and fuzzy before bouncy-bouncy time!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fix it yourself, asshole.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, I have Mr. Boomy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora rolls her eyes and goes to the bar.</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, you'd love this joke. It revolves around Santa Claus and the Easter Bunny getting into a fender bender.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No bush...</context>
      <utterance>You know, when I lived here I used to have a big painting above the fireplace. A naked chick holding a pumpkin. It was very tasteful.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Randolph. We know it wasn't you who killed Spinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll go to the police, first thing tomorrow... straighten everything out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the bottle out of her hand. He rises from the chair. He takes a CD, "PARTY TIME WITH RAINBOW RANDOLPH," from his pocket and puts it into an audio system on the fireplace wall.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! Goody-goody gumdrops!  Vodka straight up is fine, sugar babe!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The THEME SONG from his show starts to PLAY. He flicks a switch and a spotlight goes on. He sings and dances.</context>
      <utterance>Did you put on a little weight, honey? That's okay, you're still a hot little brood mare. I bet you miss the sweet sting of my riding crop. Giddy up, pony!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Rainbow Randolph is the man. Yes he, yes he, is. He's the Prez of Rainbowland. Yes he, yes he, is. With some fun, fun here, and a laugh, laugh there. Here a dance, there a song, Everything is fun, fun. Rainbow Randolph is the King, the King of Rainbowland!' Randolph takes another drink from the vodka bottle. Sheldon suddenly lunges at Randolph and tries to grab the gun. Randolph shrieks. The two men wrestle on the floor, but Randolph is not much of a fighter. He screams as Sheldon rolls him toward the fireplace.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this what you want? A Hansel and Gretel ending?! You want to be the big bad wolf?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph rolls Sheldon to the bottom. Nora reaches for a fireplace poker and whacks Randolph with it. Randolph cries out and drops the gun. Sheldon grabs it and points it at Randolph who lies on the floor, blubbering like a child. He's bleeding.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! It's too hot! The heat! It's driving me mad!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon slowly takes the gun away from Randolph's head.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, kill me! Finish me off. My life's over anyway. Everything I touch turns to shit. Put me out of my misery.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph sits up and looks at Sheldon through watery eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You're not nothing. You're bitter, misguided and I'm guessing a raging alcoholic, but you're still Rainbow Randolph. Despite everything that's happened, you once made children happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you be my friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You too?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph throws his arms around Sheldon and cries into his shoulder. Sheldon pats his back. He glances down at Randolph's gun and sees that it's a toy. Nora pours vodka onto a small pillow she's taken from one of the chairs. She kneels next to Randolph and blots the gash on his head with the vodka soaked pillow. Randolph lets out a blood curdling scream.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry about the brood mare stuff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks over to Sheldon.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon continues to load the gun.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just making the playing field even. I'm tired of running this race with one leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're letting them drag you down to their level.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He accidentally spills some hot tea on himself.</context>
      <utterance>She's right, Sheldon. Don't make the same mistakes I did. Keep your dignity intact.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son-of-a-bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora and Randolph look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>I appreciate everyone's concern, but I can take care of myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon stuffs some extra bullets in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>I tried.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph gets up and walks over to him.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, buddy, we have to get down to the Garden. You're welcome to stay here as long as you like. Just don't leave until I get things squared away.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph looks at him for a moment before turning to Nora.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful, Sheldon. Remember what I told you -- you've only scratched the surface of this scummy business. You have yet to strike oil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're lucky to have a guy like Smoochy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just rest, Randolph.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon slaps the cylinder into place and tucks the gun in his waistband.</context>
      <utterance>He's the real thing. Smoochy's the real thing. And I've been a fraud. A wicked man doing wicked acts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we all have our bad days.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We have to cover our tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Things are getting out of hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, everything's gonna work out.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Excuse my concern.</context>
      <utterance>Relax? They found Merv Green's head on the Grand Concourse!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, we can cover all the tracks we want, but in the end we still got the same problem. We gotta finish what we started.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes shakily takes a sip of his drink.</context>
      <utterance>God help us...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll all be over tonight. Buggy's gonna take care of everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buggy? Buggy Ding-Dong? The guy who hosted 'Buggy's Bumpy Railroad'?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes buries his head in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, until he discovered the joys of Turkish black mule heroin. For the right price he'll do anything. It's amazing the guy's still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shadow falls across their table. Burke looks up.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Burke... this whole thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buggy Ding-Dong's hand ENTERS the FRAME and snubs out his Camel. Stokes looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Speak of the devil. Have a seat, Bug.</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buggy. You're looking good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We GO TO a SPLIT-SCREEN with Angelo.</context>
      <utterance>Hellooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Randy, is that you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Angelo, my little Twinkie, shouldn't you be getting ready for the big show?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Buggy's been here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buggy Double D's? The Dong Man?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randolph thinks. He suddenly looks very worried.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he lifted my backstage pass and he's braggin' that he's doing some kind of job for Burke Bennett.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheldon's in trouble. I gotta get down to the Garden.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The place is crawling with cops. They'll jump on you like a trampoline.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rips the towel from his head.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to warn the rhino.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Smoochy skates out to thunderous applause. The entire arena is on its feet. The Rhinettes part as Smoochy skates through them and stops in the middle of the rink. The applause and cheering don't stop for several moments. One of the Rhinettes hands Smoochy a microphone.</context>
      <utterance>And now... it gives us great pleasure to introduce America's favorite rhino... ladies and gentlemen... boys and girls...  Heeeeere's Smoochy!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOOCHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On behalf of myself, the Rhinettes, and the soon to be restored Coney Island Methadone Center, I thank you all for coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>NETWORK BOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burke and Stokes roll their eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Sheldon can't hear over the orchestra. The soprano hits a high note.</context>
      <utterance>Sheldon!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATWALK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buggy aims the rifle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doing here?! He's going to screw everything up! Nora notices the distressed look on their faces and follows their gaze to the rafters. She now sees the rifle barrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>jumps to her feet. FAST PUSH IN TO Nora's mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to climb out of the box but Burke stops her.</context>
      <utterance>Sheldon!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nora...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes tries to put his arm around her.</context>
      <utterance>You're in on this, aren't you! You sold him out! You fucking snake!</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes him. He goes down hard. She starts to climb out of the box. Burke tries to grab her, but she spins around and punches him. She runs for the rink. Stokes stands in the box looking dumbstruck as pande- monium plays out around him. People are running in all directions, cops are everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>Nora, please. It's not what you think. I'm grooming you. You're going to run the division one day...</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now? What do we do now?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke runs off through the panicked crowd. Stokes looks around and heads off in the opposite direction.</context>
      <utterance>Survival of the fittest!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BUGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINK'S EDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nora screams.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheldon!!! Get down!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON BUGGY'S FINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's about to squeeze the trigger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOLPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pat the dazed Randolph on the back. He passes out.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I'm kind of fucked up in general, so it's hard to gauge.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhinettes litter the ice like broken dolls. Smoke fills the air. Sheldon is helping a random woman to her feet as Nora finally reaches him. She embraces him.</context>
      <utterance>People continue to run through the rink. Felled</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon looks toward the network box. Beyond it, through the smoke, he sees Burke shoving his way through people who jam the exit trying to escape. Sheldon reaches into his costume and pulls out his gun.</context>
      <utterance>Burke's with Stokes. He's been in it all along.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon runs off leaving Nora.</context>
      <utterance>No, Sheldon, don't!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as Sheldon begins to lose consciousness, we hear a GUNSHOT. Burke looks up. Nora stands there, pointing Sheldon's gun directly at him.</context>
      <utterance>You fucking point a gun at me? A gun I gave you as a gift?! Where's your fucking etiquette?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke just looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Let him go.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke smirks as he releases Sheldon. Sheldon jumps up and takes the gun from Nora. He shakily points it at Burke.</context>
      <utterance>Now. Before I pump one in that Grecian Formula scalp of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke slowly stands up, brushing off his suit.</context>
      <utterance>You know something, kid? You've turned out to be an incredible pain in the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were behind the Spinner hit, weren't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>That was a tragic mistake.  If only one could turn back time...  But what the hell, it's just one less mick in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon cocks the gun.</context>
      <utterance>You son-of-a-bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my. What are you gonna do? Kill me? That wouldn't be very Smoochy-like behavior.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon tears off the remains of his tattered costume and steps out of it.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. There's just one thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon is shaking as he extends the gun to Burke's head.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not Smoochy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke suddenly looks fearful, as does Nora.</context>
      <utterance>I finally realized we're living in a different jungle.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon closes his eyes as he tries to summon up the courage to pull the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>No, Sheldon.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, there's a voice from behind.</context>
      <utterance>Sheldon!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sheldon turns around. It's Tommy and her boys.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it, Shel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy walks closer to Sheldon.</context>
      <utterance>Stay out of it, Tommy. This is my business.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy extends her hand for the gun. Sheldon looks down at the gun. He can't believe he's even holding it. He hands it to Tommy.</context>
      <utterance>No more killin', Shel. Enough's enough. Don't destroy who you are for this piece of shit. You mean something to the kids. Don't take Smoochy away from the kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how I got pushed this far.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're only human, Shel. The important thing is... you never went over the cliff. You're a good boy. For some of us... it's too late. Tommy pats Sheldon's shoulder affectionately.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll take it from here, kid, you run along with your girl. Get on with your life. Sheldon looks over at Burke, who's petrified.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy, you're not going to --</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon and Nora take a final look at Burke before walking out of the alley. Burke is wide-eyed with fear as Tommy's boys advance on him. Just as they round the corner there is the sound of TWO GUNSHOTS. Sheldon looks at Nora.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. Sometimes even a rat deserves a little mercy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pats him on the back.</context>
      <utterance>Bus backfire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car doesn't move. Stokes pounds on the partition.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response. Stokes frantically pushes the button that lowers the partition. It slides down.</context>
      <utterance>Move this thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver turns around. Stokes recoils in horror. It's Takashi. He smiles as the back doors open and the Japanese thugs -- Chick, Sambo and Tobi -- pile in with Stokes. They slam the doors shut.</context>
      <utterance>Are you deaf?! I said --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stokes lets out a small whimper. Chick nods to Takashi who steps on the gas as he sings "Anything Goes" in Japanese.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I could tell you it'll be quick and painless, Frank, but you know how these things go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheldon gazes back at her.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go home, Smoochy. Show's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss passionately as MUSIC SWELLS and the CAMERA CRANES HIGH ABOVE the rink.</context>
      <utterance>No it's not. It's just beginning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>There's a dramatic pause; TYMPANY ROLL.</context>
      <utterance>And now... it gives us great pleasure to introduce America's favorite rhino... ladies and gentlemen... boys and girls...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Smoochy skates out to thunderous applause.</context>
      <utterance>Heeeeeere's Smoochy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Randolph skates out, somewhat shakily, to huge applause. Sheldon puts his arm around him. The audience is now on their feet. Randolph especially basks in the adulation.</context>
      <utterance>With his partner and comrade... the one, the only... Rainbow Randolph!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All proceeds from tonight's performance, will benefit the Rainbow Randolph Center for Alcoholism and Delusional Behavior.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
