<movie id="162" title="Deep Rising">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THROUGH THE WINDSHIELD we see LEILA, a muscular Filipina clambering over the foredeck. She's dripping wet. Tough as nails. She turns to Finnegan and "mouths" something into her headset. Finnegan flashes her his most charming smile.</context>
      <utterance>How we doing out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>His HEADSET comes alive withe the SOUND of LEILA bitching in an unintelligible foreign tongue.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm very warm and dry in here, thank you for your concern.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He watches as Leila fights the WIND and SEASPRAY and dogs tight a series of hatch-latches across the foredeck.</context>
      <utterance>A raise? I already pay you two bucks a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Leila turns and gives him a "jerking-off" sign with her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Missed one darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Radar Imager suddenly blinks, and goes to black. Dead. Finnegan taps on the screen. Nothing. Taps on the console. Still nothing. Simultaneously two more imagers shut down. His mouth screws tight.</context>
      <utterance>I love you too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>" -- if not for the courage of the fearless crew -- " He tugs at the wires.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan's voice explodes through his headset...</context>
      <utterance>" -- the Minnow would be lost, the Minowwww would be lost."</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we use our indoor voice please...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Pantucci pulls two wires from the tangle.</context>
      <utterance>I'm flying blind here God damn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to strip the wires with his teeth.</context>
      <utterance>You trying to make me feel guilty?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know...I know...if the cash is there we don't care...  Finnegan this is as mean a pile of shit as we ever carried... Pantucci notices Hanover impatiently looking at his watch again, and nods for a mass of Aussie mean and muscle named MASON to follow him up a ladder.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He quickly pulls out a wrench, slaps it over a bolt and tightens it down. The leak stops. He blows on the WRENCH like it's a six-shooter, then spins it at the speed of light and holsters it into his toolbelt.</context>
      <utterance>...and some of it's coming your way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember the first time we met Finnegan? I think you were just starting out...smuggling gold off Sumatra for those two Chinese...what did we use to call them?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fok Yu and Fok Yu Two...are we strolling down memory lane for any particular reason?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it just struck me as odd...I don't see you for all these years and you've still got the same tape stuck in the box.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover looks at the Topo Imager. Holding onto the rail to keep his balance as the boat slams over the choppy sea.</context>
      <utterance>You know what they say...the classics are eternal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan points to a spot in the middle of the map.</context>
      <utterance>So where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right here...middle of nowhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan points to another spot on the map.</context>
      <utterance>And where is our point of arrival?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right here...middle of nowhere...and the answer to your question is yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which question is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one you came up to ask...are we on schedule?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take note Mr. Mason...this is why you hire a professional...No whining. No excuses.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard a lot of stories about you mate...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of them flattering I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were...but they musta been talking about another Finnegan... because the one I heard about was as rough as they came...the one I'm looking at is, well, about as current as the music.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mind him Finnegan...you remember 25...balls of steel... splashing around in a sea of testosterone.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mind him...but I do think it's time for him to get back down below with the rest of the playgroup.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan looks at Mason...at the open hatchway just behind him...</context>
      <utterance>And who's gonna make me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...and jams the steering sticks full speed ahead. The force of acceleration tumbles Hanover into the console. Mason tumbles out the open hatchway, down the stairs behind him. As he rises, Hanover regards Finnegan for a moment. A smile flits across his face.</context>
      <utterance>The Finnegan you heard about.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan's hand finds the console. He hits a button. The first strains of Led Zepplin's WHOLE LOTTA LOVE comes roaring out of the speakers.</context>
      <utterance>That's why we're sill around Finnegan...you and me... Nothing gets the feathers up. Business is business. Eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan cranks the sound to the max, pulls back on both steer sticks, and holds on, as the force of acceleration hammers him into the pylon.</context>
      <utterance>And the classics are eternal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian looks down to a petite old woman, dressed impeccably, delicate, frail, her beauty long faded except from her eyes. Kindness becomes her, like moonlight does the night.</context>
      <utterance>He said an orchid and a beautiful woman belonged together... It was our first date.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said that it was the orchid I wore that made him fall in love with me...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sounds like a real gentleman.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best of the best he was... This cruise was supposed to be our 60th anniversary gift to each other. He died last Spring...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Woman looks at the orchid. And then at Trillian.</context>
      <utterance>I was going to wear one...special for him...like a memory...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Trillian takes the orchid from her hair, and places it in the lapel of the woman's jacket.</context>
      <utterance>But without him here I don't know why I should.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The smile Trillian bestows on the old woman is loving, sincere. The moment between them is broken by the keen clear sound of a silver spoon tapping a crystal champagne flute.</context>
      <utterance>Because an orchid and a beautiful woman belong together.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: The deck where the band stops playing. Voices hush. Everyone turns to NIGEL CANTON, 65, tall, elegant, every white hair perfectly in place, impeccably turned out, with the energy, and enthusiasm of a man half his age. Canton stands at the head of the pool, in front of a wall sized aquarium, flanked by his Captain.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The crowd roars with laughter.</context>
      <utterance>All my life I had the dream of building the greatest pleasure ship ever to sail the seven seas... tonight, seeing all of you here...so elegant...so beautiful...so rich...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Canton lifts his glass.</context>
      <utterance>I realize my dream has come true...I thank you all from the bottom of my heart for making it so...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the Fuji Maru! Good times forever!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd swells around Canton. ANGLE ON: The Captain chatting up some passengers when a woman's voice, seductive, beguiling, turns his head to...</context>
      <utterance>Forever!! Here! Here!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian takes one step closer, until her moist lips are pursed inches from the captain's.</context>
      <utterance>Is what true madame?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His breath catches.</context>
      <utterance>Madamoiselle...that the bigger the boat...the bigger the man...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian draws even closer. If looks could cause a man to climax.</context>
      <utterance>It is a theory I would be glad to put to the test.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In school, the Sisters said testing was my specialty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driven to distraction, The Captain turns his attention for a moment to a passenger introducing his wife.</context>
      <utterance>Captain...</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: Trillian, turning from the captain into the crowd. C.U. on her hand by the side of her dress. A man's wallet held surreptitiously. Her fingers open the wallet, extract a thin gold card with a black stripe. She discards the wallet, keeps the card, and disappears into the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Enchante...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain stands next to a bank of LASER IMAGING SYSTEMS. Canton steps up. Looks down at the THERMAL RADAR IMAGER. Multi-colored LASER IMAGES.</context>
      <utterance>You wanted to see me Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a storm rising behind us... we may have to close the canopy, I hope it doesn't ruin your party.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ruin my party? Captain, this ship was built to withstand a typhoon. I can't imagine there's anything on the sea today that could possibly ruin my party.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gum kwa she bam dok.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then over the headset, over the Hendrix...</context>
      <utterance>It's not noise...it's genius...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what my goal is? Before I die I want to make love to a woman from every country on earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean countries that are acknowledged by the UN...or like made up countries too?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like Mamooli's country...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you talkin'? Samoa's a county!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a dot on a map...</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Map...no map...I don't give a shit ...they got women on Samoa, it's on the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover watches calmly as BILLY, the Aborigine, cracks his fist against the side of Pantucci's head, knocking him out of Vivo's arms.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Billy you're in the batter's box.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY hoists Pantucci. He draws his knife under Pantucci's bloody nose.</context>
      <utterance>At home we denosy the nosy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chinese merc steps forward, and whaps Pantucci upside the head with a cruelly accurate crescent kick. Pantucci hits the wall hard, crumbling. Chin lifts him.</context>
      <utterance>We're not savage here Mr. Billy... we're professionals. Hold him...Mr. Chin...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Massive Mason steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone else?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take a go and the I vote we throw the little weasel overboard...</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mason raises his ham of a fist drawing his tree trunk arm back, taking dead aim at Pantucci's face. He never gets the punch off. His arm is caught from behind. He looks over his shoulder to Finnegan. Gripping his wrist. Right in his face.</context>
      <utterance>I vote we slit his throat THEN throw him overboard...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mason, enraged, swings with his free hand. Finnegan twists his arm sharply, sending Mason's head into the steel wall, knocking the big man senseless. The other mercenaries go to draw their weapons. Before the guns are out of holsters, Finnegan swings a spear gun into Hanover's face, an inch from his eye.</context>
      <utterance>...this is not a democracy. You don't get a vote.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan cocks the spear. CLICK! Hanover does not blink. Everyone freezes. With his free hand Finnegan lifts Pantucci to his unsteady feet, the spear stays poised. Finnegan backs out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>I'll say it again for the hearing impaired...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't right Finnegan. I've got a contract.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>RECITING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>20 hours on the clock. Out and back. Double for overtime.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And no questions asked.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who asked any?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did...with a crowbar...you know the rules on a broken contract.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that Finnegan leads Pantucci out of the hold, slamming the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>I know it...but you want to get where you want to get, and back? I need a chief engineer, and unless you got a replacement, I'd highly recommend overlooking the indiscretion.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan turns his gaze to Pantucci. It makes the smaller man quiver.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan stalks off. Pantucci swallows hard, knowing he means it.</context>
      <utterance>You put me in that position again I'll throw you overboard myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Trillian grits her teeth, and turns to...Canton, the Captain, and two burly Chinese security men.</context>
      <utterance>It is an amazing stone...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what were you planning on doing with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Retiring.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Canton exits. The Captain steps forward, and removes the diamond ring from Trillian's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Well you can still proceed with your plans then...in prison...Captain... escort the lady...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps her across the face. Trillian flushes, touches the drop of blood at her lip...and decks the Captain with a vicious right cross.</context>
      <utterance>Mademoiselle...you are not a lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you...Monsieur...you are not a gentleman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's what I think...I think these mokes below are a hit squad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He carefully threads the surgical needle.</context>
      <utterance>I saw these guy perform...at Altmont ...you know that? They opened for the Stones...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now...there's some bozo sitting on his yacht at those coordinates they gave us, sipping his scotch and soda...totally unawares that we are about to deliver 500 kgs of high power torpedo to light up his ass...that's what's down there in that hold and who knows what the hell else...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan centers the needle over Pantucci's wound.</context>
      <utterance>Hold still now...I was like three rows back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Jagger was here...I was here...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't give a shit about anything do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I do...I give a shit that at 0300 hour we reach our point of destination. I give a shit that those mojos got to do what they got to do, and 45 minutes later we are turn around and gone. I give a shit that by the time the sun comes up we are all safely tucked in bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it? That's all you give a shit about?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan sinks the needle into the wound. Pantucci's SCREAM rises above the music.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah...and that my stitch job doesn't make you uglier than you already are...this won't hurt a bit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The entire bridge electrical system is shutting down sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Switch over to auxiliary power, and run a circuit check.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COM. OFFICER is busy fiddling with the communications and imaging gear. DISTORTED LIGHTS from the scrambled systems plays off their faces.</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>COM. OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're losing radar and sonar!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST MATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain is confounded, on the edge of panic. Canton hurries onto the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>Communications systems are out sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Communication systems have failed! Radar...sonar...radios...I don't understand it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's the storm!</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense! We're impervious to weather!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIST MATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a main frame meltdown!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Canton storms out. Every piece of electrical equipment on the bridge starts to shut down.</context>
      <utterance>Well unmelt it!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The disquieted crowd turns to Canton.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen...your attention please... Ladies and gentlemen...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, and quite violently, a WOMAN is SUCKED UNDER THE WATER -- THWUP! Others swimmers notice and freeze. The Woman doesn't come back up. And then, THREE more SWIMMERS are violently JERKED UNDER. All the people in and around the pool see this and panic. SCREAMING. YELLING. SWIMMING. SWIMMING and RUNNING. A CRACK OF THUNDER! The Captain calls out --</context>
      <utterance>This is the most technologically advanced sailing vessel on the water today. Every problem has been anticipated...the Captain has assured me that we will be up and running in no time...so enjoy yourselves...there's nothing to worry about...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REMAIN CALM! The pool clears. Everybody backs the hell away from it. The WATER in the pool BUBBLES, and GURGLES, and then goes quiet. And then, from somewhere deep within the bowels of the ship, comes a loud, eerie, primordial YOWL. WE PUSH IN ON CANTON: His eyes slowly widen. Stunned. His calm replaced by pure terror.</context>
      <utterance>Remain calm! Stop! Do you hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leila exits. Finnegan's eyes go up from the action on deck to the radar screen, where a blip, fast moving, right toward the jet foil catches his attention.</context>
      <utterance>Leila see what they're up to...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do to my kids!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me??</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan notices something on the floor. He picks up a shard of the speedboat propeller. Strange. Hanover steps into the room.</context>
      <utterance>No! The man in the moon!! Who's driving this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan looks at the piece of speedboat in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shows the piece of speed boat to Hanover. Who stares at it. Finnegan sees the hint of recognition in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>We ran into a speedboat...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speedboat in the middle of the ocean...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How soon can we get up and running?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't...we got one engine dead, and the other limping badly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a schedule...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mason grabs Pantucci by the throat, lifting him off the ground.</context>
      <utterance>I spent two years building these things...screw your schedule!</utterance>
   <speaker>MASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan slams the piece of speed boat into the back of Mason's knees buckling him to the floor. In the blink of an eye there is the barrel of a .45 pressed hard against his head, Hanover at the trigger end.</context>
      <utterance>You little weasel!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were talking about my schedule...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to have to get a new one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not an option.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover cracks Finnegan across the face with the barrel of the gun. Finnegan's head spins. He touches the corner of his mouth, and comes away with blood, and a look of murder in his eyes. Hanover slams a round in the chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Then you better start swimming.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more joke and your comedy career is over. Now fix this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With what? Look at them...they need gears...cylinder heads...oil pans... we're in the middle of the goddamn ocean...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he knows that Joey.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mulligan comes running in.</context>
      <utterance>Good! So maybe he also know where the hell am I going to get the parts I need...</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Target in sight!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The merc's scatter below deck. Hanover hands the binoculars to Finnegan.</context>
      <utterance>Contact verified! You know the drill gentlemen!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan's POV through the binoculars. The Fuji Maru in the distance, lit up, beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>Care to see what dreams are made of Finnegan?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lines set. Mason swivels the big HARPOON GUN on the bow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tow lines!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He FIRES the HARPOON. It shoots and SLAMS into the rear deck of the Fuji Maru.</context>
      <utterance>Clear!</utterance>
   <speaker>MASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tow line secure.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swift, athletic, the mercs leap onto the lines and scramble hand over hand toward the Fuji Maru's deck.</context>
      <utterance>Secure the zone of operation!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The first mercs reach the Fuji Maru's deck, and toss life lines down to Hanover.</context>
      <utterance>When I was a little bit of a pissant we lived down the road from where all the big cruise ships used to come into Sydney harbor...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Hanover hands one line to Finnegan, one to Pantucci. The third he attaches around his waist.</context>
      <utterance>Mum and me we used to sit by our front door and watch them...she used to say "one day you're going to make your fortune in life on one of them..."</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great woman your mother. Real foresight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan and Pantucci comply.</context>
      <utterance>And she could do a hell of a barbie to boot! Belt up. You'll find all the parts you need up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I assume somebody up there has made sure no distress signal can be sent.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd say that's a pretty good assumption.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the crew could be armed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover hand signals to his men above. The lines go taut. Finnegan, Pantucci, and Hanover are hoisted to the deck of the Fuji Maru.</context>
      <utterance>With what? Martinis and tanning oil?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone hits a button on their watches.</context>
      <utterance>Synchronize watches...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>25 minutes...by the numbers. Engine room and machine shop are on the third sub deck...Vivo...Mulligan go with them...keep in touch...move out...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points the acetalyne tank she works with.</context>
      <utterance>Kwan bat! Kwam bat! Booom!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy heads for the deck. Leila looks after him in disgust.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...yeah...yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She ignites her torch, is about to flick her visor down again when a loud gurgling, a sucking sound, stops her. She cuts the torch. Looks around nervously...and then she spots the suction hose sucking away. She smiles to herself. Flips the visor, fires the torch, and goes back to work.</context>
      <utterance>Asshole...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH TO: The deck full of people partying, carousing. The railing is lined with 15 lifeboats suspended in their harnesses. FLASH BACK TO: Mulligan, Finnegan, Pantucci and Vivo staring at a completely deserted deck. The lifeboat harnesses swing in the breeze, eerily empty. Mulligan looks back to Vivo.</context>
      <utterance>You'd think they'd set a deck watch...</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought the plan was we'd evacuate them after we got through.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe plans changed...</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plans don't change...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's the wrong ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then a strange yowl echoes from somewhere deep in the bowels of the ship. Finnegan and Pantucci trade a look.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just keep going.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And again the yowl. Everyone freezes.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't giving the orders here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's keep going!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uneasy, Hanover and his men look around at the over turned chairs. The smashed aquarium. Chin bends down and picks up a small squid from the bottom of the smashed aquarium. The squid wraps its tentacles around Chin's hand almost immediately. Chin regards it with curiosity.</context>
      <utterance>What the...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...and then the yowl freezes them. C.U. on Hanover's face. His eyes flicker with uncertainty...and a tinge of fear.</context>
      <utterance>Focus on the task Mr. Chin...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan finally tilts the muzzle of Mulligan's gun to the ceiling. They stop firing. A little wigged-out. Their professional demeanor going by the boards. All goes quiet. They look at Finnegan, who is the picture of calm.</context>
      <utterance>Guys!! Whoa! WHOA! WHOA! WHOOOAAA!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Trolley car reverses. The ELECTRONIC VOICE is now CRACKED</context>
      <utterance>Guys...get a grip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELECTRONIC VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mulligan whirls, his gun poised. Just then his headset crackles.</context>
      <utterance>Next stop, Fisherman's Wharf.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Finnegan leans in towards Mulligan's mike.</context>
      <utterance>This is Red One...status report.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mulligan pulls the radio away.</context>
      <utterance>Your boys just killed a trolley car Red One.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Advise on how to proceed.</context>
      <utterance>We been down three decks, there's nobody home... Total spooky-town.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SOUND slowly MOVES across the wall. Then another WALL starts to GURGLE. Trillian spins around. She forces herself not to panic. Very cautiously, taking small measured steps she reaches the handle to the freezer, and tries to open it. No go. The gurgling ripples above her. Her mouth goes dry as her eyes follow the sound across the ceiling. Her hand goes to her hair. She pulls her lock pick out, and very slowly kneels down until she is eye level with the door lock. She begins to pick her way out, her ears and eyes following the gurgling above. Suddenly the sound stops. The silence makes Trillian's heart sound that much louder. She sidles close to the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Still silence. Cautious, she taps on the wall. For a moment nothing. And then...</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I'm gonna do after this...I'm gonna get a normal life...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan turns to Pantucci, his voice even, calm, almost kind.</context>
      <utterance>...Like a house in the suburbs... maybe a couple of kids...some sort of business...be in the bowling league...go to the ball games...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey...it's okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You don't think I can have a normal life?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He forces Pantucci to look him in the eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Joey...look at me...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Pantucci draws his strength from Finnegan. He forces himself to take a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>We're gonna get what we gotta get... do what we gotta do...and get the hell outta here...okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, overhead, something black and veiny skitters across the mass of pipes, so fast it shocks Pantucci back into the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Vivo spin their guns at the pipes. The red dots of their laser sights sweep the shadowy web of metal. Nothing.</context>
      <utterance>What the...???</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on...the sooner we get outta here the better I'll feel. Mulligan and Vivo move forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan turns to Pantucci, who has not moved from where he hit the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Finnegan...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay...come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pantucci tries to pull away from the wall. He is stuck.</context>
      <utterance>I'm stuck...</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! What are you trying to pull!</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan takes Pantucci by the front of his shirt, ignoring Mulligan.</context>
      <utterance>John...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Finnegan pulls, Pantucci does as he is told. He slips away from the wall. The jacket doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>Relax your arms...slowly...that's it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out to touch the wall. Finnegan grabs his wrist, grabs a flashlight from Vivo's utility belt and shines it on the wall. Their POV -- the entire wall is covered in a strange, yellow, secreted GELATIN. Laid on in some sort of weird, inhuman, geometric pattern. Like a spider web.</context>
      <utterance>What the...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KA-CHUNK-KA-CHUNK-KA-CHUNK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The water swirls around her waist.</utterance>
   <speaker>KA-CHUNK-KA-CHUNK-KA-CHUNK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's almost past the gaping hole now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hulls of these things are supposed to be impregnable...</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...If the hull's impregnable why are my feet wet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just stop figuring and keep working so we can get the hell out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you help us so we can get done faster so we can get the hell out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause grease monkey ain't in my job description dick head... Vivo pulls his feet further up on the barrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then out of the corner of his eye, Vivo sees SOMETHING MOVE. He spins around. Nothing but pipes and hoses.</context>
      <utterance>What I want to know is why the goddamn ocean is always cold...since I'm a kid I hate god damn cold water.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan and Pantucci stop working. All eyes are focused on the maze of pipes. THINGS are HISSING, HUMMING and RUMBLING. Nothing moves.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Come out here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check it out!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You hear me? Come out! Still no response.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disgusted, Vivo puts his feet in the water, gingerly.</context>
      <utterance>Will you check it the hell out!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks toward the mass of hissing pipes. His pulse rifle rising.</context>
      <utterance>Man this shit is cold!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Then he hears a strange SLURPING and SUCKING SOUND coming from behind some gears at the end of a little alleyway.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna kick your ass for putting me through this...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not screwing around with you man...I hate the cold water.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it man?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vivo slowly goes in for a closer look, gun out front, heading down the little alleyway. He looks behind some pipes. The SLURPING gets LOUDER. Then he sees it. His eyes widen --</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And that's the last thing he ever says. Because just then, from a dark area between the pipes, SOMETHING SHOOTS OUT! Mulligan, Finnegan, and Pantucci stare in horrified amazement as Vivo is viciously YANKED into the pipes. A moment later a WASH OF BLOOD is FLUNG across a wall. Mulligan freaks out, aims his rifle at the pipes.</context>
      <utterance>On shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mulligan's attention diverts, Finnegan instinctively heads for Vivo's rifle, lying on the floor. Mulligan swings around. KACHUNK!! His rifle is armed. The laser dot fixes on Finnegan's forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Vivo!! Vivo!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan freezes, looking up at a very freaked out Mulligan.</context>
      <utterance>Touch it and you're dead, asshole!</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot, man, don't shoot!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody's breathing hard. Freaked out. Major tension. Blood drips down the wall.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to Vivo?! What the hell happened to Vivo?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mason and Chin lift their pulse-rifles. KACHUNK!!</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... This area is for authorized personnel only. As the assistant to the Purser, I'm afraid I'll have to ask you to vacate...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or maybe not.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian is confused --</context>
      <utterance>Where is everybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover steps forward, right in her face.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean...where is everybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover grabs Trillian by the throat and slams her against the wall. He rams his gun against her forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Poolside?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell it straight or I pull the trigger. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover blinks.</context>
      <utterance>A passenger...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian shrugs. Mason grabs the card out of her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Where are the other passengers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mason runs the card through the slot. The ELECTRONICS KICK IN. LIGHTS FLASH. TUMBLERS ROLL. CLICK! It unlocks. Hanover's HEADSET comes alive with Mulligan SCREAMING.</context>
      <utterance>Forget her...let's get what we came for and get the hell out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Mason JERKS the vault door open. A FIRE-AXE SWING DOWN into his head, WHUMP! Kills him instantly. Eyes wide open. Everybody freaks out. Jumps back. Hanover lets go of Trillian, and stares into the vault directly at Nigel Canton. Holding the axe.</context>
      <utterance>Mulligan?? What?? I can't hear you?? Repeat I...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind Canton the Captain is on the floor, in severe pain, his clothes are ripped up, REVEALING nasty looking RED SCARS, blistered and puffy, all over his chest and arms.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. I didn't mean to...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chin jams his rifle to the middle of Canton's forehead, and cocks a round into the chamber.</context>
      <utterance>I thought it was one of them!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But this is one soldier who is slow to obey the order. Hanover grabs Chin by both shoulders and gives a colossal yank.</context>
      <utterance>Stand down soldier!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He slams Chin against the wall. In the process he loses his headset.</context>
      <utterance>I said...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chin and Hanover stare at each other, their chests heaving. Mason finally drops to the ground. All she wrote.</context>
      <utterance>Stand down!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to! I though it was one of them!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of who?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response. A sucking sound comes from the dark mass of pipes. Mulligan spins.</context>
      <utterance>Hanover!...Hanover! Come in! Come in you son-of-a-bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hanover!! Hanover!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget them... Mulligan spins back to Finnegan and Pantucci.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! You hear me!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...we gotta get outta here -- NOW.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, man, just shut the hell up! I gotta think! I gotta think!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's there to think about?? That THING back there...</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLIGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Mulligan's LEGS are suddenly JERKED OUT from under him. He hits the floor hard. Starts FIRING WILDLY. Finnegan and Pantucci hit the watery deck. BULLETS RICOCHET everywhere. Mulligan is WHIPPED across the floor. SCREAMING in fear. His pulse-rifle goes flying. He's SLAMMED into a metal pylon, then SUCKED into a dark void in the pipes. All in the blink of an eye. Finnegan grabs Mulligan's pulse-rifle. OPENS FIRE. BLASTING the shit out of anything and everything that moves.</context>
      <utterance>There ain't no thing here!! No thing!! There's you him and me!! Got it! You him and...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pantucci grabs the knapsack, cramming as many parts as he can into it as Finnegan keeps firing into the steaming, creaking, sparking machinery.</context>
      <utterance>Grab the parts!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Pantucci doesn't have to be told twice. He runs like hell, with Finnegan firing a final burst, and following.</context>
      <utterance>I'll cover! Move! Move!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gunfire stops, replaced by an ominous, horrifying, sucking sound.</context>
      <utterance>This is Red one! Come in Red two!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's find them!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the vault?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover rushes out with Chin right behind. Only Trillian remains, breathing deeply, scared...but not scared enough to forget the reason she came cruising in the first place. She goes right to the vault, opens one of the boxes, removes the giant diamond, drops it down her decolletage, pulls her high heels off, and runs out.</context>
      <utterance>It's not going anywhere...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finnegan, what the hell was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...you got what we need?</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both of them listen to the silence. And then, at the far end of the grating, one grate rises...and falls. Finnegan and Pantucci watch, transfixed. Then, like a locomotive gathering speed, the grates start rising and falling, faster and faster, clanking louder and louder, headed right for the two of them.</context>
      <utterance>If I don't, I ain't going back to get it...you think we're safe?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She panics. And starts pushing the up button frantically, her heart pounding in her chest. There is not a sound except for the hum of the elevator descending...until something drops on the roof with a THUMP! Trillian screams. The elevator comes to a bumps stop.</context>
      <utterance>Up!! I want to go up!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Trillian shrinks from the ceiling of the elevator...and then the car starts to move again.</context>
      <utterance>No...No...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Trillian pounds on ever button on the console, to no avail. The car continues its inexorable descent. Finally, in desperation, she hits the emergency stop button. The elevator stops. The emergency SIREN WHINES. A LONG BEAT. Nothing moves...and then... WHAM! Something beats on the roof, trying to break in. And again -- WHAM! The ELEVATOR SHUDDERS and continues its descent. Trillian backs up against the wall, staring at the ceiling, scared. The ELEVATOR DINGS! Startled, TRILLIAN SCREAMS. The DOORS start to OPEN. Panicked, Trillian raises the only weapon at her disposal...a high heel. The DOORS OPEN. -- SOMETHING LUNGES IN! Trillian swings her high heel...right into Pantucci's face! Finnegan plows in right behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Go up...please go up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not staying here!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian struggles. Finnegan does not let go of her.</context>
      <utterance>It ain't any better out there!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Trillian buries her high heel into the back of Finnegan's hand, breaking his grip.</context>
      <utterance>Lady, I'm telling you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now look what you did!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saved your life is what I did!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who asked you to!</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're with that other bunch, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What other bunch?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The thieves.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a thief.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian hears music to her ears.</context>
      <utterance>I'm their ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her demeanor changes, her voice goes to honey.</context>
      <utterance>You have a boat?</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian and Finnegan turn to Pantucci who is looking down at the floor where a mass of yellow slime has dripped from the ceiling. All look up to the yellow goo dripping from the ceiling...followed by a sucking sound.</context>
      <utterance>Finnegan!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan lifts his pulse rifle and blasts the ceiling. The sucking sound stops.</context>
      <utterance>It's up there!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator stops. DING! The door opens. Finnegan whirls his rifle, rising. Trillian lifts her high heel, ready to strike... Hanover, Chin, and Mamooli have their massive guns trained on the car. The Captain and Canton quiver behind them. There is a momentary stand off.</context>
      <utterance>Not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are my men?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan looks up into the barrel of Hanover's gun...and a pair of eyes that will use it. Finnegan does as he is told.</context>
      <utterance>Drop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Again, Finnegan does as he is told.</context>
      <utterance>Now, back up!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Captain and Canton are only to happy to comply. As they slip in, Trillian tries to slip out. Hanover swings his gun on her.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody in!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nowhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hanover, listen...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover hit the elevator button. The elevator starts to rise.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, where's Mulligan? Where's Vivo?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, there's something here! On the boat!</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see? You see?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Shut up all of you! Now here's what we're doing... Mamooli is going to take you back to fix your engines, Chin and I are staying here to finish the job...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you clear this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All of a sudden, the car is jerked to a halt, as if some giant hand was yanking on the cable.</context>
      <utterance>With who?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then, the elevator jerks down again. And up. Everyone is thrown about like straw. Everyone is shouting, panicked. And then the jerking stops...and the sound of sucking surrounds the car. The cable starts twisting, creaking sickeningly above their heads.</context>
      <utterance>With that...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian starts hitting the buttons frantically.</context>
      <utterance>It's gonna snap the cable!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan is at the doors, pulling them with all his might.</context>
      <utterance>Open! Open! God damn it!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pantucci, then Mamooli, then Hanover and Chin pull at the doors as Trillian keeps hitting the buttons. The doors part a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Help me!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The doors fly open to...a solid wall.</context>
      <utterance>They're coming! They're coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And silence...until the doors slam shut...the cable snaps...and the car plummets! Screaming and shouting mixes with the bloodcurdling shrieking of the metal elevator frame against the shaft. Finnegan's eyes go to the floor indicator.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan bends down to pick up one of the pulse rifles.</context>
      <utterance>The sublevel lobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan looks up to Hanover standing a bit shakily, his own rifle trained on Finnegan.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch it!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Finnegan picks up the gun. A test of wills. Finnegan wins, and then turns to the Captain.</context>
      <utterance>You shoot me and you got no ride home...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You the Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we get out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pantucci steps on something. CRUNCH! He looks down, his eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>We have to make it to the third deck...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts dancing around, trying not to step on whatever it is. Trillian looks down and SCREAMS. Everybody freaks -- Finnegan grabs a flashlight from Chin's utility belt, and sweeps the beam over the lobby. The entire floor of the lobby is littered with shattered HUMAN SKELETONS. Picked clean and spit out. Just like the earlier whale bones. Then suddenly, at the far end of the hallway, one of the metal WALLS suddenly EXPANDS and FLEXES. Everybody feezes. And then the FLEXING suddenly comes RACING down either side of the hallway, accompanied by the most god-awful PRIMORDIAL</context>
      <utterance>Oh no!! Oh no!! Finnegan!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no reply. The only sound is the sucking of the pump.</context>
      <utterance>Hey you! Muscles! Out here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He ENTERS the waist-high water.</context>
      <utterance>O.K. You want it that way...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Billy heads deeper into the hold.</context>
      <utterance>...when I find you, you pay...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've gotta call for help.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah man, no shit, call in the Marines.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't...all the communication systems went down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So get them back up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>where's the comm. center?</context>
      <utterance>Hey I can fix any damn thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should get off as soon as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if we can at least send a message...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say we evacuate as soon as...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the owner...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you want a message sent?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just think that...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment of silence.</context>
      <utterance>Because you know a message can't be sent...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Hanover sets Mason's pulse-rifle down and claps his hands.</context>
      <utterance>You're the inside guy aren't you? The guy who knocked out the communications.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Canton flashes Hanover a look. The Captain is confused. Trillian suddenly GRABS CANTON, spins him around and SLAMS him against the hull.</context>
      <utterance>Bravo.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tense moment as Canton debates his situation, then relents.</context>
      <utterance>How the hell do we fix it?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't... All the systems were melted at their core by nitric acid...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was your life's work...your dreams...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dreams cost more than they would make...I miscalculated the market... there was no way I could recoup...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless you collected on the insurance...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you people talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to the mercenaries.</context>
      <utterance>He's with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan fixes Hanover with a look of certainty.</context>
      <utterance>They rob the joint blind and torpedo it to the bottom. He collects the insurance, and sails off into the sunset clean as a whistle.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Captain blows. He leaps on Canton. His hands find the older man's throat.</context>
      <utterance>Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan pulls the Captain off.</context>
      <utterance>All these people dead!! Because you screwed up on the math??</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not going to help us!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan holds the Captain with both hands, calming him.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to die here! We're going to die!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was born in a City housing project in the Bronx OK? It's not in the cards that I die on a luxury cruise ship...now which way up?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unseen by anyone, there is MOVEMENT within the MACHINERY. The walls start to come alive with dark, SHADOWY IMPRESSIONS. HIDDEN within the maze of machinery, OBSCURED by the bad lighting, glistening abominations slither over pipes, squirm through gears, and undulate in and out of crevices and holes. The room is becoming a living, throbbing, pulsating horror.</context>
      <utterance>You hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are...they are everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody slowly and quietly moves for the far hatch. Then a loud GURGLING is HEARD. Everybody looks up at the ceiling. Hidden within the girders, and sticking to them, a large translucent INTESTINE-like thing CROSSES the ceiling. Inside it are strange, disgusting biological workings. The GURGLING suddenly gets dramatically LOUDER. And then we SEE BILLY and LEILA, being sucked down the entire length of the fatty intestine. Still alive. And squirming wildly. EVERYBODY freaks out and HAULS ASS for the hatch. Finnegan and Hanover OPEN FIRE. Covering their asses.</context>
      <utterance>All right, be cool, everybody, nice and slow, no sudden moves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ lady...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are those things?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan looks around to the engine room, a labyrinth of pipe lined alleyways, motorized chambers, swaying catwalks and pillars of steel. The LIGHTING is very poor, very dark. He takes off.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Hey! Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions into the deep shadows.</context>
      <utterance>...there's got to be a way to access out back there...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what makes you think there aren't more of hose...things...back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian weighs her options, and takes off after Finnegan.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing...you want to come, come... you don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to be so touchy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look lady, I know you people are used to getting your way...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to mean? You people.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You people...rich people...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not rich people.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you sure do a good imitation.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan comes to a ladderstair leading to a catwalk. He starts to climb. Trillian, hampered by her long slinky dress, rips at the bottom, making it maxi to mini in a flash, and scoots after Finnegan.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, I work at it...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reaching the top of the ladder, she clambers onto the catwalk next to Finnegan, who is deciding which way to go.</context>
      <utterance>I heard you say you grew up in the projects in the Bronx...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She holds out her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Trillian Daley...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan ignores her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Projects...South Chicago.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan starts to walk down the catwalk.</context>
      <utterance>Finnegan...John J...now that we've been properly introduced, can we get the hell out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this boat of yours...that's what you do? Give people...rides.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seen a lot of islands?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite a few.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since I'm a kid, I had this dream... I want to own my own tropical island... Beaches, warm ocean, lots of food, little clothes...population of one...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anti social?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Self sufficient...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the emphasis on SELF, and in selfish, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SNAP!! A TENTACLE SHOOTS OUT between Finnegan and Trillian. Just missing them as it SLAMS into a wall. Finnegan falls onto the catwalk, drops his rifle, unarmed. Trillian, freaked, stumbles back and lands on her butt. Finnegan sits up against the walls, turns and looks -- The TENTACLE slowly SQUIRMS across the wall like a big leach. Trying to find its prey. Finnegan is frozen in place. Watching. Trillian sits up, eyes widening in fear as she sees -- Hideous little worm-like FEELERS and SUCKERS protrude up and down the Tentacle. WRIGGLING and WRITHING and feeling their way across the wall. Getting closer and closer to Finnegan. Finnegan's eyes go to his pulse-rifle close to Trillian's feet. He motions for her to push it toward him. But, frozen in fear, she can only watch the slithering horror before her. Tongue-like, the Feelers lick their way across the oily wall. FINNEGAN DUCKS as they squirm over his head. Then he BRUSHES against some dirt, making a SCRAPING SOUND. A Feeler quickly drops down and touches Finnegan's arm. He leaps to his feet. So does Trillian. She grabs the rifle, turns and bolts off down the dark alley. Finnegan tries to run, but the Feelers hold him tight. Two more Feelers slap onto his arm. HE YELLS. The Creature starts reeling him in. ANGLE ON: Trillian, running. Finnegan's YELL reaches her. She stops cold. Looking back the way she came, torn. ANGLE ON: Finnegan, fighting for all he is worth, being reeled into the mass of machinery by the tentacle. When...out of the darkness, Trillian suddenly comes running back. Panting hard, she aims the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Takes one to know one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spurred to action, Trillian jams the rifle barrel against the tentacle and pulls the trigger. Nothing happens.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot it! Shoot it!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Trillian frantically fumbles around, looking for the right lever on the complicated, sophisticated weapon, trying to find it.</context>
      <utterance>The safety! The safety!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know where it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desperate, unable to find it, she does the next best thing...she swings her rifle like it's a baseball bat. SMACKS the TENTACLE. HARD. RIPPING into its flesh. It SQUIRTS ink blood, releases Finnegan and recoils. Finnegan drops to his knees. Grabbing his arm, in pain. The tentacle recovers and starts coming toward him again. Trillian grabs him, and with all her strength, jerks him to his feet, and starts to drag him backward. The tentacle coils, ready to strike. Just before it does so, Finnegan grabs the rifle with his one good arm, flips the safety, and fires, blasting the tentacle to pieces.</context>
      <utterance>On the side!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan staggers to his feet. He and Trillian run off.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get the hell out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The safety...the safety... He flicks the safety on and off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! I didn't have to come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah you did...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right... You have a boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boat or no boat... You woulda come back anyway. You're that kind of gal.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? What kind is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The "come back" kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan's small smile makes Trillian acutely uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>Takes one to know one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Canton does not move. All of a sudden Canton sees something deep in the web, behind the Captain, which makes his blood freeze.</context>
      <utterance>Help me!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Canton takes a few steps back.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Captain tries to look over his shoulder to see what it is. There is a DARK MOVEMENT deep within the spider web.</context>
      <utterance>What?!... WHAT?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Canton still pressed against the wall, staring at the spot the Captain disappeared, talking to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Where is the closest hatch?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover grabs Canton by the front of his tattered tuxedo jacket.</context>
      <utterance>I never meant for anyone to get hurt ...it was supposed to be clean...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Canton points down a darkened passageway.</context>
      <utterance>You hypocritical bastard...all you gave a shit about was the money... where's the hatch!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks at an uneasy Mamooli and Chin.</context>
      <utterance>Alright let's move out...you two on point...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey... Which way's aft?</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points in the opposite direction.</context>
      <utterance>That way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who gives a shit about aft?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's where my boat's moored.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You trying to take over my show Finnegan, that what you trying to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan takes off down a catwalk in the opposite direction that disappears in the dark. Pantucci is right with him. Trillian, a step behind.</context>
      <utterance>Just trying to get to my boat...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He disappears into the dark. Canton looks at Hanover for a long moment, and then takes off after Finnegan. The other two mercs look at Hanover, wavering.</context>
      <utterance>They respond to sound...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of his voice makes the two mercs look around nervously.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He made sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then conscious of his voice reverberating...</context>
      <utterance>He's a bloody...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's on the far side?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan touches Pantucci's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>It's your damn ship! What the hell do you mean you don't know?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan enters the water.</context>
      <utterance>Joey, what difference does it make...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Pantucci follows Finnegan to the water.</context>
      <utterance>If you hear one shot, you know I made it...start coming...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan stops.</context>
      <utterance>How do we know you're going to signal...how do we know you're not going to just take off?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover does not move.</context>
      <utterance>I'll wait here... You go check it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan wades into the water. Just before he sinks beneath the surface...</context>
      <utterance>I didn't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks back.</context>
      <utterance>Finnegan...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>With a smile, Finnegan dives under. Pantucci right behind him. The others stand looking around, nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You deaf?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you back off?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanover's jaw clenches. He releases the safety on his rifle, the click resounding ominously in the hollow room.</context>
      <utterance>You want some too?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian's eyes fix on Hanover's, unwavering. A Mexican standoff.</context>
      <utterance>How brave we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone turn to... A giant ball of black, wet, OOZING RUBBER UNDULATES down the gangway. Coming straight at them. A mass of glistening striated MUSCLE.</context>
      <utterance>Hanover!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three men open up with their pulse rifles. The CREATURE gets RIPPED TO SHREDS. Red and blue INK-BLOOD SPLATTERS everywhere. But onward it comes. Down the gangway. Trillian grabs the pistol off Chin's utility belt, and opens fire. Canton jumps into the water and disappears.</context>
      <utterance>Fire!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian can only nod, and gasp for breath. Canton and Hanover catch their breath, PANTING AWAY, waterlogged. Hanover reaches over to retrieve the rifle in Trillian's hand. Trillian points the barrel at him, and hits the safety.</context>
      <utterance>You O.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mamooli bursts out of the water, falling on the floor, close to panic mode.</context>
      <utterance>Finders keepers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Chin?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gone...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan TOPPLES a large, heavy metal BROILER onto the open floor gate, sealing the watery hole in the floor. There are two hatches in this room. The far hatch is closed. Mamooli stands next to an OPEN HATCH. Canton points to it.</context>
      <utterance>This is not real! This is not bloody real!</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Through there...another sixty, seventy yards...there are more elevators there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't goin' up no more elevators.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mamooli SLAMS the HATCH SHUT. Eyes bugging out of his head.</context>
      <utterance>There's stairways...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say we stay right here!</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's plenty of food here. We can hold out...someone'll rescue us...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone...maybe they sent an SOS!</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On what? This son of a bitch  zapped the communications.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mamooli stand down!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't even know if his boat is still there...you saw Billy!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan steps forward. Mamooli aims his rifle right at Finnegan's head.</context>
      <utterance>Boat or no boat...I'm going...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're wipin' us out one at a time. I say we make a stand. Right here! Right now! Maximum firepower!</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody shoot this jerk!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's shooting nobody...come on, just let us through the hatch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan freezes. CLOSE ON: The hatch. As a BLACK LIQUID starts to OOZE through a tiny latch-hole. No one sees it.</context>
      <utterance>I'll kill you!! I'll fucking kill you!! I'll do it! I'll do it! I'm not playin' around here!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I once saw a guy put a fish in a bottle, then he corked it, sealing it tight, and threw it to a baby octopus. The little sucker felt its way around that bottle, and in less than two minutes, got that cork off, slid inside, and ate that fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LIQUID SHADOW OOZES down and hits the floor, starts to EXPAND, filling like a water balloon. It's not a liquid. It's a Tentacle. VEINS, FEELERS and SUCKERS begin to form.</context>
      <utterance>Us...I'm talking about us... We're the fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what? These things are octopuses</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TENTACLE slowly RISES UP right behind Mamooli. Inches behind his head. Finnegan and Hanover see it. Eyes widening.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what these things are ...all I know is...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMOOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mamooli turns to the tentacle looming over him, about to strike.</context>
      <utterance>What...? What??</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan heads for another open HATCHWAY. It also SLAMS SHUT.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan and company keep going.</context>
      <utterance>They're herding us.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they round a corner, the CEILING IMPLODES right in front of them. PIPES and OTHER MATTER CRASH down. Cutting them off. Leaving only one route open...a slim passageway.</context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like cattle...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're saying they can think?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan heads toward the passageway.</context>
      <utterance>I'm saying they're calling the shots...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ceiling left above them begins to torque, and splits. The answer is plain. Everyone runs into the passage just as the ceiling comes down.</context>
      <utterance>Do we have to go there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The quiet...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we lost them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan moves on. The others follow. Guns out front. TENSE. They round a huge metal pillar and come face-to-face with a soul-wrenching nightmare. The CREATURES' NEST -- OR STOMACH. Across a small portion of the ship's midsection, is a huge GELATINOUS WOMB. Imagine a massive thick wall of clear-yellow JELL-O, with hundreds of BLUE VEINS running through it. If it weren't all so horrific, it would be considered beautiful. Inside the womb, A DOZEN HUMANS, passengers, float around in some kind of twisted embryonic state, the living dead. They all seem to be breathing the gelatin. Several TENTACLES WRIGGLE through the stuff; which divides and re forms in some sort of strange mitosis. Finnegan and the others look at the passengers, horrified. But even more horrifying is that the people can look back at them. Many start to reach out, seemingly in slow motion as their hands ooze through the thick gelatin. Trillian looks sick, trembles in fear.</context>
      <utterance>Or maybe we're exactly where they want us to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A meat locker.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Canton looks like he's about to throw up, he starts backing away, heading for a side hatch.</context>
      <utterance>We can't just leave them here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the womb, a Tentacle suddenly approaches a sexy young LADY. The Lady tries to back-pedal away, but because of the gelatin, it's like one of those nightmares where you can only move in slow motion. The FEELERS GRIP her naked thigh. She tries to scream, but her face is already starting to constrict, her whole body is being paralyzed. Pantucci is so horrified he's about to cry.</context>
      <utterance>I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TENTACLE-SAC gloms onto the Lady's forehead. THROUGH THE SAC we can SEE her SKIN MELTING. The only thing she can move are her EYES, which are bugging-out in absolute horror as she is imbibed alive. Our heroes are frozen in fear. Until the Lady's EYES LIQUEFY. Trillian burries her head in Finnegan's shoulder, trying to shut out the horror.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no...oh God please no.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to lead her toward the hatch...when her eyes recognized the old lady with the orchid in her hair. The old lady seems to see her too. Her hands read out, IMPLORING. Her mouth silently shapes the words: HELP ME! Just as a tentacle comes creeping toward her.</context>
      <utterance>We can't do anything for them... Let's go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Spitting FLAMES and SMOKE. The BULLETS IMPACT the gelatin. BLASTING IT AWAY. But the bullets only manage to go about twenty feet into the thick shit before gliding to a stop. GELATIN EXPLODES all over the place. TRACER HOLES STREAK through the stuff. But all the bullets are sliding short.</context>
      <utterance>You won't get her!! You won't!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan looks around and spots the place in the ceiling where most of the Tentacles are coming from. Their long TAILS WIGGLE down from a massive clutter of pipes. A bas-relief of horror. Finnegan reaches over and yanks two thermite grenades off Hanover's utility belt.</context>
      <utterance>Finnegan...do something!! Please!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...bites the pins and spits them out.</context>
      <utterance>Finnegan, No!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He chucks the grenades up into the strange WRITHING FRESCO, safely clear of the passengers.</context>
      <utterance>Eat this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking good...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the machinery shuts down. The engines go dead. ALL SOUND CUTS OUT. An expectant hush. Somewhere, WATER DRIPS... WE GO EXTREMELY CLOSE ON Trillian's EYES. Pantucci's EYES. Hanover's EYES. Finnegan's EYES. The air is riddled with ominous expectation. And that's when the HULL BEGINS TO TORQUE. RIVETS POP and SNAP. WATER SPRAYS. METAL BUCKLES.</context>
      <utterance>You should talk...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how do you get from the Bronx to the South China sea?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The knife blade slips into the crack.</context>
      <utterance>You quit high school, lie about your age, join the navy, and next thing you know, four years are up and you need a way to make a living...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He yanks the blade. Trillian pulls. The seal pops. The portal flies open. Waist-high in water, Trillian sticks her arm out, tries to get her shoulder out, but there's no chance in hell of that.</context>
      <utterance>I'll break the seal! Pull.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls her arm out. And a TENTACLE LUNGES IN. Just missing Trillian. It SPLASHES under the water. GRABS Finnegan's ankle. Pulls him under. FINNEGAN sticks the barrel of his gun underwater and OPENS FIRE. WATER EXPLODES. The Tentacle recoils. And rips itself back out the porthole. Trillian SLAMS the PORTHOLE SHUT and dogs it tight. The</context>
      <utterance>Too small!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knocks both of them out of Hanover's hands. They DISAPPEAR under the water.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme one! Gimme one!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They quickly fumble around in the water, trying to find them. A TENTACLE BLASTS around the corner. Partially obscured by the wave in front of it. Heading right for them. Hanover finds the two grenades. Gives one to Pantucci. They rip the pins out and toss the grenades behind them. Then HAUL ASS faster. The Tentacle right behind them. A BEAT. And then the GRENADES EXPLODE, BA-WOOM! BA-WOOM!</context>
      <utterance>You idiot!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then slowly, Canton gets a gleam in his eye, now thrilled.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, it's going to sink.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going to sink.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was so goddamn close, Finnegan! So goddamn close to my island... I could almost taste the sand...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan shoves the pulse rifle to the ceiling. And blasts away until part of the ceiling falls out and into the water. There's just enough room between two metal beams to get out. The rising WATER SHOVES them up through the hole.</context>
      <utterance>Keep tasting...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're catchin' up! They're catchin' up! We gotta slow 'em down!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A black STRIATED MUSCLE ROILS out of the foamy water, then quickly VANISHES under it, heading straight for them.</context>
      <utterance>Feed them. That'll slow them down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>'EM?! Hanover takes his pistol and SHOOTS Pantucci in the leg, BLAM! Pantucci SCREAMS. FALLS into the water. Hanover RUNS on. Pantucci doesn't even have time to deal with the pain. He starts SCRAMBLING through the water. UNDERWATER, the INKY FORMS RACE AFTER HIM. Only meters away. Pantucci throws himself into the opening of a dumbwaiter. SLAMS the DOOR SHUT. The TENTACLE ATTACKS the door. WORMING its way across the surface, trying to find a way inside. Pantucci is scared beyond his pain. Pushing back as far as he can against the rear wall, he sees the control button. He presses the up arrow. The dumbwaiter starts to move.</context>
      <utterance>Feed 'em?!! Okay! All right! Feed 'em what? WHAT ARE WE GONNA FEED</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tries to catch her breath.</context>
      <utterance>Ah...ah...ah...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then it dawns on Finnegan.</context>
      <utterance>It's OK...it's not one of them... it's from the aquarium...it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not them...it's it...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the squid.</context>
      <utterance>You know what kind of force it took to rip open the bow of this ship? A million little things like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>thing.</context>
      <utterance>...can't exert that kind of pressure... And the way it tracked us? A million little things don't carry portable phones to coordinate positions... What's chasing us... it's one...thing...one giant...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HANOVER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Pantucci limps around the bar, down a row of one armed bandits... rounds a corner, comes face-to-face with Hanover. Hanover's eyes are filled with terror and despair. His face is badly constricted. His body paralyzed. He clings to a black-jack table as a Tentacle-Sac drinks its way up his leg. It's already to his hip. He grasps desperately for his pistol, just beyond his reach on the floor. This guy ain't gonna survive. PANTUCCI YELPS and quickly back away, eyes wide, totally tense. He looks around, sees that there's only one Tentacle, and it's completely occupied with devouring Hanover. Pantucci is wigged, but manages to lock eyes with Hanover. Then he looks at the Sac, filled with regurgitated flesh.</context>
      <utterance>Help!! Help!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pantucci picks up Hanover's pistol. Then slowly, cautiously, he creeps forward, and sticks the gun into Hanover's</context>
      <utterance>...even you don't deserve this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boat touches down into the water.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He HITS the HOIST-RELEASE BUTTON. The speedboat breaks free. Canton HITS the IGNITION. The boat's ENGINE ROARS.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to but I have an appointment with my insurance broker!</utterance>
   <speaker>CANTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He red-lines the THROTTLE. The SPEEDBOAT HAULS ASS away from the cruiseliner. Canton steers for the island. Smiling. ANGLE ON: Trillian</context>
      <utterance>Life takes the damndest turns, doesn't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs Finnegan's pulse rifle, hefts it to her shoulder...</context>
      <utterance>You son of a bitch!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He forces her to look in the distance. Their POV. The island.</context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god! Oh my god! How do we do it? How do we get there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan points to the water...and an INKY PSEUDOPOD FORM racing after the speedboat underwater.</context>
      <utterance>Not like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Tentacle quickly picks up speed, going faster and faster, getting closer and closer, stretching further and further. Suddenly, behind them, a METALLIC THRASHING SOUND is HEARD. They turn around and look -- The hook, the tow-line, and the entire railing have dropped down onto the watersports platform and are tangled up around the two jet skis, trying to tear free -- The Saipan is still clinging by its fingernails to the Fuji Maru! Finnegan races over to a WINCH and grabs the winch- line.</context>
      <utterance>It's the engine...it can hear the engine...it goes for the loudest sound...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The HOOK and the TOW-LINE drop -- then SNAP TAUGHT as the winch-line holds them tight. Trillian throws the start lever on the winch. The WINCH KICKS ON and starts reeling in the Saipan. Finnegan tries to crawl up on the deck, exhausted. Trillian reaches down and pulls him the rest of the way up. He half collapses on top of her.</context>
      <utterance>Hit it! Hit it!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite the grimness of their position, the closeness of their bodies is...a turn on...to both of them...and then a SCREAM from the sea. They look in the direction of...</context>
      <utterance>You know, Finnegan, I'm starting to believe what you said about you not being born to die on a luxury liner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finnegan...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They step up to one of the big CRATES. Finnegan starts SMASHING it with the butt of his pulse-rifle. The CRATE BURST OPEN. REVEALING the WARHEAD of the torpedo. Trillian is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>...the minute you start your engines ...it's going to kill us, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan SMASHES more of the CRATE, it falls apart, REVEALING the entire torpedo. He hands her his pulse rifle.</context>
      <utterance>Not unless we kill it first.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan starts to yank open the top plates of the missile head. Trillian looks around nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Anything moves, you shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's not much horsepower left in the engines, but there's enough noise...once this baby's set...I'll rev it up...that slimy bastard will come for it like candy...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you blow up your boat, how are we going to get to the island?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The plate comes loose. Revealing a gaggle of wires, and parts.</context>
      <utterance>Jet ski...there's one left up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He starts to fiddle with the wires. -- Suddenly, there's a LOUD SLOSHING SOUND right behind them! CRATES TOPPLE! More pulse rifles spill out. Trillian spins, ready to blast away with the pulse rifle, to...</context>
      <utterance>...let's see, it was red wire cross compressor blue wire...or blue cross red?</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot!! Don't shoot!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He refers to the wires.</context>
      <utterance>Just the man I wanted to see. On this puppy here, you remember if it's red to blue or blue to red...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not even a Joey, I'm glad to see you? Joey, what happened to your leg?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey, you want to get sucked out by a giant fucking mutated squid?</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red cross over to blue double blue ...is that what it is? A squid?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Squid...squid like...squid type... it's got tentacles, a feed sac... probably one central nervous processor somewhere...what the hell do I know is going on deep down in the ocean...there's all sorts of shit we've never seen...eighty foot clams...60 foot sharks...I'm just guessing...can you get me more juice out of Hercules...fast?</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For juice, I gotta rebuild. That's not fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about noise? Can you get noise? We don't need speed, just noise, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can somebody tell me what the object of the exercise is here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seafood salad.  You ever operate a jet ski?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want ME to go up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not unless you can wire a missile or fix an engine.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan tosses her a pulse rifle from the overturned crate.</context>
      <utterance>And what if I run into one of those things?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hits the safety, slams a shell into chamber...</context>
      <utterance>Don't forget the safety.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Don't take too long...I'm not planning on being on the menu tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never seen you so congenial with a member of the opposite sex... The two of you got a nice patter going...got a nice rapport...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan attaches a wire to a sprocket. A red light starts to blink on the warhead.</context>
      <utterance>And you got 10 minutes before this thing livens up a boring evening.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I think? I think our luck has just about run shit out...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little to the left...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we gotta stop floating from one fucked up situation to the next...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The missile head is right in line with the hole in the bow.</context>
      <utterance>Line it up now, nice and easy...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, man, we got to give the future some serious thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have been.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what have you come up with?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pantucci looks at Finnegan quizically. This is news to him.</context>
      <utterance>How does an island sound to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian's scream tears through the night. Finnegan's eyes go to the Fuji Maru. He kicks open a box by the side of the console, and pulls out a sawed off shot gun with a pistol handle in a holster.</context>
      <utterance>I gerry-rigged the ignition...all you gotta do is start her up...it won't go fast but it'll go loud...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, don't go up there...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan slams shells into the shotgun.</context>
      <utterance>One whistle... Start the engine...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's gone...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Second whistle you make it to the deck and get ready to jump...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All you're gonna do is get yourself killed...and for what? Some chick?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan hefts a pulse rifle, and runs out of the pilothouse.</context>
      <utterance>You're beautiful what you're jealous, you know that, Joey?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian looks back. Sees the Tentacles coming out of the darkness of the web. Twenty feet back and closing.</context>
      <utterance>Finnegan!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan runs up and grabs her. Tries to pull her free. But she's stuck good. He looks behind her to the tentacles quickly closing in on her. Now fifteen feet away.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry!! Hurry!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As she struggles, Finnegan pulls out his knife, and starts to hack away at the sticky webbing. Trillian tries to look behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Get me out of here!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian struggles with every last ounce of her strength. Now ten feet away.</context>
      <utterance>Don't look!! Push!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan plunges his hands into the goo. Trillian latches onto Finnegan's wrists, he onto hers. Four feet.</context>
      <utterance>Grab my hands!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan strains, pulling, until every muscle in his body keens with the effort, every vein pops to the surface. Trillian pushes for all she is worth. Three feet...two feet...one foot...</context>
      <utterance>Push!! Push!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves her out the door, and is about to follow when the door is slammed shut in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Go! Go! Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finnegan!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get to the jet ski! Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean to drop in unannounced ...you ready...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finnegan whistles. Waits. No engine goes on. He whistles again. Still no response. Removes his watch, gives it to Trillian.</context>
      <utterance>Soon as I get over the heart attack...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three minutes...I'm not back...no matter what...you go...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't take orders very well, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't take orders at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs Trillian's pulse rifle, and leaps up on the side of the Saipan, and scales up to the deck. Trillian watches him, and then looks at the watch.</context>
      <utterance>This time, make an exception.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he spots something on the floor. He reaches down and picks it up. It's Pantucci's leather tool belt. It's been RIPPED TO SHREDS. Finnegan stares at it. His grip tightening. Tears rising in his eyes. His jaw clenching. Then he flings the belt aside. Filled with rage.</context>
      <utterance>Pantucci!... JOEY!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finnegan hits the ignition button. A desperate moment of dry cranking ...and then the one remaining engine catches, sputters, and fires to life.</context>
      <utterance>Time to die, motherfucker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's you friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Saipan strains on its leashes. ENGINES GUNNING. Finnegan swings his rifle around. OPENS UP on the tie-lines. All the TIE-LINES SHRED. The Saipan starts to break free.</context>
      <utterance>He's not coming...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He GUNS the ski...and it stalls. The jet ski stalls. Goes dead in the water.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nearby, the WATER SWIRLS violently. He hammers the starter button.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The ENGINE STUTTERS. He tries again.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Another STUTTER. More WATER SWIRLS, getting closer now. But the third time's a charm. The jet ski comes to life and shoots off along the side of the ship. Just as a tentacle comes shooting out of the water. Finnegan fires at it, blowing it to pieces. The last TIE-LINE SNAPS. The SAIPAN LURCHES AWAY from the Fuji Maru. The jammed steering-sticks force the rudder to turn it in a tight circle.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it the water in my eyes or were you guys about to...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's cool, you know, I can always take a walk or something down the beach...</utterance>
   <speaker>FINNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey...</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or I could go for a swim...although, I gotta tell you...if I never get in the water again...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PANTUCCI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then they head the most gut-wrenching, spine-tingling, teeth- shattering ROAR ever. Pure primeval. Like no sound or animal or thing we've ever hear beofre. Coming from DEEP</context>
      <utterance>OK...OK...you don't have to beg me ...I'll stick around...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
