<movie id="166" title="Detroit Rock City">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KISS - LOVE GUN, SIDE TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Bruce's blood boils.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>KISS! The devil's music!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOYS SINGING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stink, but they sure are trying hard. Meet the band "Mystery." Concert tee-shirts, holey jeans, total burn-outs. HAWK, a scraggily-haired, disenchanted youth, strains his vocal chords on the microphone as he SCRATCHES at his rhythm guitar. Hawk is sort of the brains of this operation, but knowing the others, that doesn't say much. LEX POUNDS a bass with earnest determination. Lanky with bad posture, Lex is already sporting worry lines. He takes everything way-too-seriously. TRIP STRUMS lead guitar like he's hammering nails. All id, Trip is slightly out of his mind. But, is it the chemicals or just his chemistry. He always wears a knit cap. JAM, a sensitive kid (but no wuss), BASHES on his drums like a madman making the bass drum pulsate like a spastic heart. The big drum bears the word "Mystery" painted on its skin with a lightning "S" just like the KISS logo. They bring the classic tune to a shrieking conclusion and thrust their hands over their heads in the KISS symbol. Hawk screams into the mike at their imaginary audience.</context>
      <utterance>"I wanna rock 'n' roll all night and party every day!"</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind him, Trip grabs Lex's bass and swings it by the neck at an amp pretending to bash it over and over again. Lex quickly yanks it away from him.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Cleveland! You're a great crowd. But after three and a half hours of kick-ass rock and seven encores on top of that, I'm sorry to say that this time we really gotta get back to our hotel rooms and fuck some groupies.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam emerges from behind the pile of drums smiling.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck, Trip? That's my bass!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was curly!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just one more day of school to get through, girls, before tomorrow night... Live!  COBO Hall! Detroit, Michigan!  You wanted the best!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL FOUR BOYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all make that BREATH SOUND that mimics a screaming crowd. Suddenly, headlights swing by in the window above them like a spotlight. Lex hops onto the unmade bed and looks out the cellar window.</context>
      <utterance>You got the best! The hottest band in the world... KISS!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam GULPS as if he's just shat out an whole can of Lincoln logs.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! It's Jam's mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex quickly throws a KISS towel over a TV tray hiding a bong, cigarettes, overloaded ashtray. Trip kicks half-empty beer bottles under the bed. Hawk sprays Lysol frantically around the room as Jam shovels gum into his mouth. KNOCK, KNOCK, KNOCK! Mrs. Bruce pounds on the cellar window crouching to see in. She looks like a crazed, underlit psycho.</context>
      <utterance>My mom? Oh, no! What's she doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys looks up like innocent, wide-eyed angels. Jam waves.</context>
      <utterance>Jeremiah! Jeremiah Bruce! You get out here this instant!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hi, mom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Bruce grabs her son by the ear and holds up the KISS LOVE GUN record waving it in his face.</context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hauls Jam across the lawn. Hawk, Lex, and Trip step onto the porch looking on in sympathetic embarrassment. Mrs. Bruce stuffs the record in the trash can then throws Jam in the front seat. SCREECH, the station wagon pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>The devil's body count, that's what's up! Don't you know what KISS stands for? "Knights in Satan's Service!"</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jam has yet to do an overnight with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a nightmare once that something like this might happen. I hope he doesn't get grounded again. If he misses Peter Criss's drum solo, I don't know if he'll be able to handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lex, quit trying to always jinx things. Don't worry, dudes. Nobody's missing that concert tomorrow night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jam, listen up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hawk?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just listen up, man, cause we are in a quandary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you on the crapper with one of those antenna phones? Sounds like you're taking a dump the size of Butte, Montana.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my Bullworker.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, listen up. They're gone!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The KISS tickets, you nimrod! They're just fuckin' gone! Please tell me you have'm!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gone!? Why would I have the KISS tick...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jam briefly scans his surroundings double-taking at the denim jacket lying on the floor. He checks the pockets and sees four tickets labelled KISS - JUNE 7, 1978 - COBO HALL,</context>
      <utterance>Just check whatever you were wearing last night. Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex and Trip collapse with relief.</context>
      <utterance>He's got'm!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip reaches in a breast pocket and pulls out Rosary beads. Spooked, he drops them like they were a bug.</context>
      <utterance>Trip, he took your jacket by mistake. You must be wearing Jam's.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry about that, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be a fembot. So, are you like grounded because of last night, or what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor, Jam, man. Imagine having to stash your KISS records inside Carly Simon album covers. No question, Mrs. Bruce is a psycho-bitch from hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip pockets his wallet which is affixed to a long chain attached to a side belt loop.</context>
      <utterance>You're one to talk, Lex. Your mom's a fuckin' dyke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trip, a female gynecologist does not a lesbian make. And even if it did, at least my mom didn't give birth to me while she was on LSD.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shrooms! And even if it was LSD, I can still give my mom a kiss without smelling the catch of the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex and Trip shaddap.</context>
      <utterance>Both you assholes, SHADDAP!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip and Lex cease and desist the mom-bashing and continue getting ready for school. Suddenly, Lex pushes Trip angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Enough of the mom-bashing, all right? Lex's mom is cool about us crashing over here while she's out of town. And if it weren't for Trip's mom, we wouldn'ta smoked that fine Panama Red last night. So leave the women who gave you life out of it. They're both cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trip, you fuckin' asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex points to a wet mess on the pillow.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You spilled my Sea Monkeys all over the bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeremiah, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to his closet, the door blocking her view of the KISS poster. Jam leaps to the window and yanks the "Destroyer" shade. It shoots up, FLAPPING around its rod. He's done this before. Mrs. Bruce peeks at Jam from around his closet door. He stretches in front of the window.</context>
      <utterance>Uhh... nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh, sunshine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to be late if you don't hurry up and change soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Change? What's wrong with what I got on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's dirty laundry for one thing and for another, you still haven't worn the clothes I bought you. You're skating on thin ice already, young man, so I wouldn't push my luck. Now get out of those rags.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam reluctantly takes off the denim jacket as Mrs. Bruce grabs the single drumstick from his hand and shakes it at him.</context>
      <utterance>Besides, those jeans are so tight I can see your penis.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and rummages through the closet.</context>
      <utterance>Someday you'll see the futility in forging a musical career with those idiots.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not idiots.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't forget you're on the honor system tonight. I'll be home a little after one and if you've been partying or playing that satanic KISS music... well, need I remind you of the consequences?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grounded for the rest of the year?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls two Sears department store boxes from the closet and lays them on the bed. Jam is visibly horrified.</context>
      <utterance>You're a smart boy, Jeremiah. And so handsome.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two GIRLS with tons of make-up, hair so feathered it could fly, and tight clothes, saunter by SNAPPING gum.</context>
      <utterance>School. What a fuckin' waste of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will somebody please tell those chicks disco is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stellas. I hate stellas almost as much as I hate dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their words say one thing, but their eyes say another. They can't stop gawking at the chicks' asses. Girl 1 sneers back.</context>
      <utterance>Same species when you think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys quickly cover.</context>
      <utterance>Don't stare too long, you'll go blind.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right. She wishes. Look at that big ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They chuckle. Just then, Jam steps off a school bus in an unbelievably geeky outfit, white corduroy slacks, plaid shirt buttoned to the top, argyle socks and brown deck shoes.</context>
      <utterance>You know what they say about a big ass... big shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk and Lex look and laugh when they see him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, that dork looks just like Jam.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, that dork is Jam.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Jam, who did your wardrobe, Tad the preppie sailboat captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, my mom had me over a barrel, all right. After last night, I had to let her dress me today. It's a give and take relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she gives you shit and you take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, enough. Enough. Gimme the tickets. I wanna hold onto them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're still at my house in Trip's jacket.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was standing right over me when I was changing for fuck's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's some sick shit right there. Did she comb your ass hair for you too?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If your mom so much as smells those tickets, they're history, and we get screwed outta seeing KISS for the third year in a row, the third year!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. They're perfectly safe. We can pick them up after school. My mom won't be home. It's no problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. After school we double- time it to your house for the tix before heading to the train station for the 2:45 to Detroit Rock City.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BELL RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Check.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLAM! They shut their lockers in unison.</context>
      <utterance>As they say in the Tampon biz, see you next period.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rubbing her head, she smiles and hands him the drumstick.</context>
      <utterance>Oof!  Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stuffs his drumsticks in his socks pulling his pantlegs down. Jam and Beth stare at each other. There's a mutual crush, but both are apprehensive about making the first move. Both want to speak, neither does. They awkwardly go back to their notebooks. Mustering the nerve, Jam breaks the ice and whispers...</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth spins too quickly. Her pen flies out of her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Beth?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOINK! The pen hits Jam in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Feeling awful, Beth moves in to help. The teacher looks up sternly.</context>
      <utterance>Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDY HALL TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bruce, Miss Bumsteen, is there a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam points to his eye.</context>
      <utterance>No. No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unamused, the teacher goes back to grading.</context>
      <utterance>Just a little pink eye. No reason to panic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth resumes doodling feeling like an idiot. Jam does too. Ah, teenage awkwardness. Finally, Beth musters up some courage.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeremiah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hems and haw, then...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to tell you something...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam throws a startled glance to the speaker as the class sings in unison.</context>
      <utterance>Jeremiah Bruce, come to the office immediately...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHOLE CLASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooo, you're in troubaaaallll.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More FEEDBACK as the mike on the other end changes hands.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother's here and would like to see you right away...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the kids except for Beth burst into hysterical laughter. Mrs. Bruce's tirade continues over QUICK SHOTS of...</context>
      <utterance>Give me that microphone... Jeremiah, you get your sorry self down to this office, mister!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And something much, much worse!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit, my jacket!</utterance>
   <speaker>4-WAY SPLIT SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We see Jam, Hawk, Lex, and Trip agog in dread.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you know what's good for you, you'll get down here... NOW!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made an appointment with Father Phillip McNulty at St. Bernard's. We're to see him directly where he will register you on the spot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean, you're sending me to... b- b-boarding school?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flicks the lighter, not yet lighting the cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>What else can I do? Oh, records and magazines and comic books are one thing, but tickets? TICKETS? Jeremiah, do you realize what this means? That you're no longer content merely hearing their awful songs or looking at photos of their horrific faces! Now you want to see the devil in the flesh. You want to reach out and touch pure evil... and in Detroit no less!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Bruce holds the tickets over the lighter's flame.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, three of those tickets don't even belong to me. They're for the guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Bruce lights her smoke with the flaming tickets, then drops them in the ashtray where they burn for a cruel eternity. Jam stares semi-catatonic through his mom's sour expression.</context>
      <utterance>And if the "guys" have parents who truly love them, they will elevate me to sainthood for getting rid of these blasted things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands and pulls him out the front entrance by his arm.</context>
      <utterance>It's been a long time coming, son, but you're finally going to get the kind of discipline you deserve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>AROUND THE CORNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They slump against the wall devastated.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it! I knew this was gonna happen! I had a bad feeling since last night. Remember? We are so totally fucked!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waitaminit, dudes! I got it! Maybe we can glue the tickets back together!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you, high?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a caustic voice BLURTS from down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>For once Lex is right. It's over. Things can't get any worse from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys whip their heads around to see a potbellied, yellow- toothed, security officer with long sideburns and slicked back hair at the far end of the hall, fists on his hips. Meet ELVIS.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you rodents have hall passes!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elvis laughs and breaks into a run barreling down on them like a maniac. Keys JANGLING furiously.</context>
      <utterance>Could that be three detentions I smell?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Second floor girls' john! Two minutes! He'll never look there!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They take off in three different directions. Still laughing, Elvis stops where the boys just were. Which one to follow? He bolts after Hawk who has taken the nearest staircase.</context>
      <utterance>Check!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elvis rises and shakes the CO2 off like a wet dog. Looking up, he sees the door gently swinging in and out. No sign of Hawk.</context>
      <utterance>You're way out of your league, Elvis.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex sits on the toilet in the stall.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck! Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, take it easy, man. This is the girls' crapper, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wake up, Lex! We just watched Jam's mom torch our fuckin' KISS tickets! Not REO Speedwagon! Not Journey! Not the Bay City Rollers! KISS! If you can think of a better reason to trash a bathroom, I'd sure like to hear it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip grabs Lex by the collar, yanks him off the toilet and shoves him against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Trip, it's not the end of the world, okay? Quit acting all squeezed out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, everything's hunky-dory now that the shit hit the fan just like you said it would, you snug sonofabitch! You fuckin' jinxed us!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk bursts into the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Smug, Trip! Not snug, smug.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They run to exit. Hawk first. Suddenly, Hawk backs up again into Trip and Lex as if a swarm of killer bees was out there.</context>
      <utterance>We're clear, dudes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk, Trip, and Lex run back and pile into the last stall. All three stand on the toilet bracing their arms against the walls for balance. A FOXY GIRL hurries into the stall next to theirs. We see the top halves of three heads peek over the stall's partition. The three boys don't make a sound as they watch her sit down. As she glances up, they recoil fast. They whisper super-quiet.</context>
      <utterance>A skirt just came around the corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Sherry VanHafton.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, a SOUND OF TINKLING. They all throw their hands over their mouths to stifle the giggles. Suddenly, POOT! She lets out an ECHOED FART. The boys are awestruck.</context>
      <utterance>I've been in love with her since the second grade.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa... she just farted.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have never heard a girl squeeze cheese in my entire life.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Weird...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, the SOUND OF CRACKING PORCELAIN, as the toilet they're standing on breaks into pieces with a SMASH. They topple over pulling the stall walls down with them exposing the foxy chick sitting on the can. Water GUSHES everywhere as she screams bloody murder, getting doused ruining her Farrah-do. They bolt out the door slipping and sliding across the torrent of toilet water. Lex turns and shrugs to the traumatized girl.</context>
      <utterance>Peeeyeewww! That stinks!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's gone.</context>
      <utterance>Heh-heh, sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someday you'll have a son just like you, Jeremiah. A boy who lies through his teeth, buys demonic records, and smokes the dope just like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm anything like you, I'll deserve him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, I'm sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you truly are sorry, son, then you better pray like you've never prayed before. God willed me to find those tickets because He wanted to hear from you. He knows you need help and He wants you to ask Him for it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonder if you could smoke shit out of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk turns the radio on and a HIGH FREQUENCY WHINE pours from its speaker. He adjusts the volume, then the tuner, until a DJ's VOICE comes through crisp and clear.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe some tunage'll chase those blues away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DJ'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Detroit? DETROIT? Hawk, Trip, and Lex react like they've just been hit by phasers on stun. God is intervening.</context>
      <utterance>...and this is Simple Simon on the rock of Detroit, W.A.R.P., home of the biggest KISS giveaway in the history of the universe!</utterance>
   <speaker>DJ'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HIGH FREQUENCY NOISES again, then the radio loses reception. Hawk exchanges an anxious glance with Trip and Lex.</context>
      <utterance>I got four, count 'em, four front row tickets along with four backstage passes to the concert tonight at Cobo Hall and I'm giving them to the 106th caller who can tell me the real names of each KISS band member!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad we're stuck in electronics or...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind with the too bad shit. I got a crazy plan, but only the craziest among us can pull it off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MR.J</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip puts one leg over the other always keeping a hand behind his back.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Verudi, get back to your bench.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I gotta take a piss like you would not believe, Mr. Johansen!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR.J</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put a clothespin on it till the end of class, Verudi. You know my rule.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a wet stain grows across the crotch of Trip's pants.</context>
      <utterance>But ever since my doctor put me on salt pills, it's been like Niagara Falls every half hour! Please, Mr. J! Have mercy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR.J</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. J. stops when he sees the stain starting to spread.</context>
      <utterance>Salt pills? Don't insult my intelligence, Verudi...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We now see Trip is squeezing the pump from before. He holds it behind him feeding water into the tube running down the back of his pants. The stain travels fast, hitting Trip's knee in a nanosecond. In a state of shock, Mr. J. slowly opens a long forgotten drawer on his desk, finding a cobweb and dust-covered pad of bathroom passes. He tears one off and dust flies everywhere. He holds the pass out to Trip like it was a cross he was holding before an advancing vampire.</context>
      <utterance>Jeezis, I'm taking a leak in my pants!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did it! I did it! We won!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three burnouts jump, scream, HOOT, and play air instruments like loons as if they're the only ones in the hall. They can't stop. The rest of the student body are not amused</context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' A! Woooooo!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the best thing that ever happened to me at school! Not only are we on again for KISS in Detroit, but we're actually sitting right at the fifty yard line! I dare you dudes to find a curlier scenario.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stan Lee couldn't think of a better one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Chinese have a proverb: "That which appears too good to be true, usually is." There's gotta be a catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? I have a saying too, Lex. It goes, "Catch my jizz in your mouth and stop jinxing us, asshole." We're going this time and that's all there is to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk's really got their attention now.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid our constipated little friend is right this time, Trip. There is a catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Namely?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our band "Mystery" is a quartet and we can't go on the road without our drummer. Jam's mom said something about sending him to St. Bernard's, right? We gotta bust him out before we go anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... but, St. Bernard's is way the hell over in the next county!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? Your mom's car has a CB, radar detector and cruise control, check?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are not stealing my mom's car.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn straight we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hawk, all I need is one ding on the Volvo and presto! There are my balls hanging from the rearview mirror after she gets back from Cincinnati.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when is she due back from that groinecologist's convention anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sunday, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then lighten up. She'll never know we touched it. Alright, here's the plan. We bus it to chez Lex, grab the Volvo, bail Jam the hell outta St. Bernard's and arrive at the train station precisely on time for the 2:45 to Detroit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simplicity, Hawk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simple-icity is more like it. And you guys thought Jam was in trouble before. Wait till Mrs. Bruce finds out he went to that concert with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's only so much trouble an individual can get into till it just doesn't matter anymore, Lex. You familiar with a condition known as Absolute Zero?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hypothetical temperature characterized by the absence of heat and even the slightest amount of molecular activity? Yeah, I'm vaguely familiar</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex nods.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Jam is in absolute trouble. He couldn't get any deeper into shit if he was a fly sitting in a horse's ass. You know as well as me he'd give his right arm just to see Peter Criss's drum solo, never mind a whole KISS concert, check?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the least we, his only buds in the world, can do is take him along with us tonight and give him one last curl before he starts serving his sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just for the record, I understood the last part of what you said, but for a while there you guys were making no fucking sense whatsoever.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just explaining to Lex here what you and I already know. Just had to make it a little more complicated so he'd understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very funny, Hawk. Okay, I'm in on this hare-brained scheme, but if anything happens to my mom's car, I'm blaming you. I'll say you drugged me or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk scopes out the cafeteria to make sure the coast is clear.</context>
      <utterance>Curly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ok, dudes, follow my lead.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. We ditching the rest of school?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About fuckin' time if you ask me. I'm just going through the motions till I drop out anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello summer detention.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk points across the cafeteria and sure enough Elvis has just entered. Luckily, he hasn't noticed the boys yet. Elvis swaggers to a table of CHEERLEADERS, puts his leg on a chair and starts a one-sided conversation with them. They promptly push their trays away, having lost their appetites. Meanwhile, back at the condiment tray, Hawk and Trip each grab a big handful of ketchup packets and head to a table. Lex reluctantly follows suit grabbing a big handful of ketchup packets too. All three of them put their trays down and sit.</context>
      <utterance>As I was saying, follow my lead. And maintain. Elvis just showed up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elvis takes his key ring off his belt and begins twirling it. The boys turn and face him. He savors the moment.</context>
      <utterance>KISS concert? Kiss my ass morelike. A nice, fat detention oughta put a crimp in this evening's plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking for something, rodents?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk's brow furrows as he pulls about fifty ketchup packets out of his pocket. Trip and Lex do the same.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Elvis...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elvis laughs and lurches forward -- the boys' cue to drop the ketchup packets at their feet and...</context>
      <utterance>..Your ass on a lunch tray.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip and Lex ready themselves, then...</context>
      <utterance>On your marks and...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start stomping on the packets, squirting Elvis's face and torso with tomato-based condiment causing him to let out a scream that lasts the rest of the scene. Ketchup spatters across his body in SUPER SLOW MOTION. A shot hits him in the mouth and he COUGHS it back out in mid-scream. The boys stomp relentlessly, mercilessly, blasting their nemesis with hideous cafeteria red as Elvis throws his arms back, body quaking at every splat. It's kind of like the scene in "The Godfather" where Sonny gets it. Beaten and spent, his scream now dried up to a hoarse GASPING, Elvis slips on some ketchup at his feet. He hits the floor with a THUD right in the goop. He lays there letting out DRY SOBS looking like a bunless wiener. Hawk jumps off the stoop. Taking Elvis's key chain away, he hops back up and unlocks the door letting Trip and Lex out. Hawk whips the keys back at Elvis, hitting him in the head, then flashes a pearly Error Flynn smile.</context>
      <utterance>Fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk bolts out the door. Elvis tries to get up only to slip in the muck again and fall back down twice as hard.</context>
      <utterance>Elvis, you ain't nothin' but a hot dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nooooo!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, here we are back at fucking school again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk and Trip roll their eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Huh. St. Bernard's. Figures it's named after a canine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father McNulty has a look of utter compassion on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Again, many thanks and praise to you for seeing Jeremiah on such short notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything for a potential tuition... to be given to charity of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God bless you, Father McNulty.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hug. She exits. And the look of utter compassion on Father McNulty's face disappears.</context>
      <utterance>He already has.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father McNulty sticks the pencil into an electric pencil sharpener and it makes the same NOISE a DENTIST'S DRILL does when burrowing into a molar. Jam shudders. The Father removes the pencil and blows the shavings away from the needle-sharp tip.</context>
      <utterance>Before enrolling you, Jeremiah, let me just say it would be greatly appreciated if your career at St. Bernard's was an uneventful one. Some students believe they can get expelled through disobedience and recklessness. What they don't understand is even after God's vengeance is meted out, He forgives. That His devastating anger is followed by His nurturing compassion. In a nutshell, St. Bernard's may punish you even for the slightest digression, but will never cast you out, even for the largest. So here you are, Jeremiah... here to stay!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's begin the enrollment, shall we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, how are we gonna do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hear an ENGINE and turn to see a delivery truck labelled PIZZA PIG parking behind them. A DELIVERY BOY holding a pizza box steps out. Trip's mouth waters.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme a second, dudes. Lemme think.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeing the boys, the delivery boy stops at the Volvo.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm, pizza...</utterance>
   <speaker>DELIVERY BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk, Trip, and Lex exchange an anxious glance, then Hawk smiles. He is officially inspired as he turns to the boy.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you guys know where...  Philip McNutly's office is?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm Philip McNutly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>Jeremiah, are you aware you need to answer these questions, not just listen to them? Jeremiah?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A NUN enters KNOCKING.</context>
      <utterance>Please don't become difficult this early in your stay. I hate disciplining boys before I get to know them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, Father. A young man here with a pizza for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nun exits and a second later Hawk enters wearing Lex's baseball cap pulled down over his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, yes! Send him in Sister Conimaria.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what's the damage, pizza fellow?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest swivels his chair around and unlocks a box labelled "Donations." While he looks for cash, Hawk gives Jam a discreet kick in the shin. Jam looks up and recognizes Hawk. He then looks out the window seeing Trip, Lex, and the Volvo below. For the first time we see what Jam looks like with a big, fat, shit-eating grin on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Ten even.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he offers you a slice, you're not the least bit hungry, check?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father McNulty swivels back around with a ten.</context>
      <utterance>Check.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's ten and I'm donating your tip to the church. The Lord thanks you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk takes the ten, tips the brim of the baseball cap and leaves, giving Jam a cautious wink as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>Tell the Big Guy not to mention it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And not a moment too soon. I'm famished. I hope you brought a lunch for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father McNulty raises his eyebrows, then opens the pizza box.</context>
      <utterance>No, but I'm not hungry anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father McNulty smiles, taking a big bite. Jam smiles for an entirely different reason. The priest mumbles with a mouthful.</context>
      <utterance>Well! It finally speaks. There's one barrier we've broken through.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam grins a bit feigning interest.</context>
      <utterance>You know, your coming here reminds me of a gospel called The Prodigal Son.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(suddenly alarmed)</context>
      <utterance>There was once a farmer who had two sons. Both grew up on the farm, helping their father until...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at their watches, then back at the window.</context>
      <utterance>Usually takes anywhere from ten minutes to half an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, INSANE LAUGHTER bellows from the window above.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! This is such a lousy view. How the hell are we gonna know when he's lit?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's lit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kids can't go in there!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, we're old buds of Father McNulty... How's it hangin', padre?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father McNulty laughs some more.</context>
      <utterance>A little to the right, pizza fellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was another dude. Anyway, we're here to take our bud Jam to the big satanic KISS concert tonight. Okay with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam gets up and all four boys exit.</context>
      <utterance>Rock on!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nun looks at the priest, deep concern in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Give my regards to the guy with the really big tongue!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets out a belly laugh as the shocked nun runs from the office. Father McNulty laughs even louder at her behavior, POUNDING his fists on the desk, tears rolling down his cheeks, until... He suddenly glimpses at the painting of the Virgin Mary and abruptly stops laughing. What appears to be extreme contrition washes over his face as he moves closer to the painting.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing, Sister Gonorrhea, waiting for a bus?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER MCNULTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus H. Christ, look at all the colors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex taps Jam on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, man, my mom is gonna send me to Alcatraz for this and I don't even care! I'm gonna see Peter Criss's drum solo!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex hands him a paper bag with jeans and a tee-shirt in it.</context>
      <utterance>Not looking like that, Mr. Rogers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got you a change of duds when we picked up the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys do their Three Stooges handshake and say "Curly!" Jam starts to change. Just then, the Volvo passes a two-tone Chevy Impala with luggage tied to the roof. The passenger in the back seat turns and spots Jam pulling off his pants. It's Beth. Her eyes bulge. Beth parents are in the front. Jam spots her and beams. Their eyes lock. She waves and starts to yell something, when... suddenly... BANG! The boys look out the driver's side of the car to see the rear hubcap rolling away. They've got a flat.</context>
      <utterance>Next stop: the 2:45 to Detroit Rock City!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car fishtails and weaves but Hawk manages to pull over. The Chevy continues on, Beth gazing out the rear window sadly.</context>
      <utterance>My mom's hubcap!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit!  Anybody know how long it takes to fix a flat?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeezis, Hawk, can you at least keep it within twenty miles of the speed limit?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip holds his stomach as we hear it GROWL.</context>
      <utterance>Lex, am I gonna have to lock you in the trunk till we reach Detroit? Don't worry, these babies are built for speed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm starvin' and it's way past lunchtime.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip spots a sign on the side of the road: Next Exit, Sandusky.</context>
      <utterance>Totally. All I've had for chow was a packet of Pop Rocks and a Yoo-hoo.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's stop in Sandusky, Hawk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in Sandusky?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pizza, and I been jones-in' for a pizza ever since we left St. Bernard's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eyowch! This is one hot pizza!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip grabs the wad of goop and throws it out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Trip, huck that out before it stains the upholstery!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns off the stereo and floors the accelerator, swerving into the left lane and passing the Volvo. Bobby is just now noticing the mess on the windshield. He starts to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Stop singing... NOW!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Kenny, look! There's a hunk of fawkin' cheese on your windsheel!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Trans Am runs alongside the Volvo and Hawk turns to see Kenny pointing to the breakdown lane.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit! We just pissed off the Incredible Hulk, his idiot half brother and two circus clowns.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk rolls up his window. Kenny yells, VOICE MUFFLED, and points to Hawk who pays absolutely no attention whatsoever.</context>
      <utterance>Stop the friggin' car NOW!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think we should at least pull over and offer to clean it off?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, SLAM, the Trans Am bangs up against the side of the Volvo pushing it onto the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>What?! Are you mentally deranged, Jam?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The paint!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you realize the sheer, goddamn, unadulterated, undiluted, no holds barred, one hundred percent pure as Ivory Snow, absolutely friggin' STUPIDITY of what you just did?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny hauls back and SLAPS the row of boys in the faces Three Stooges-style... WHACKWHACKWHACKWHACK!</context>
      <utterance>Hey, disco dude, it's cool...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk starts to say "yes."</context>
      <utterance>Lemme paint you a friggin' picture ahright? Imagine if you will a 1978 Pontiac Trans American in pristine condition.  An appealing portrait, nesspah?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk is unimpressed.</context>
      <utterance>BUT WAIT! What's that spec on the windshield? Could it be a wad of melted mozzarella, tangy tomato sauce, and various friggin' meat products?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if it ain't cleaned off?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kenny, come on with the macho crap already. Like this kid could take you in a fight anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer me, hippie girl. And if the mess ain't cleaned off my car?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny looks at Bobby and they exchange moronic grins.</context>
      <utterance>It could... bake on?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk figured out that any answer he gives will be incorrect and has decided to wait till Kenny's done.</context>
      <utterance>You're a smart little homo, aren't you, hippie girl? But, while astounded at your nimble, friggin' insight, I still detect an issue hanging fire, namely: where does a sharp-witted faggot like yourself get off doing such a dopey thing like that there?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No really, I'm perplexed. I mean, could you have done stupider if you were born without a FUCKIN' HEAD?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! With the language!</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine snarls at Kenny.</context>
      <utterance>Shut-up, Christine!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cold silence as Kenny replays Hawk's insult over in his head.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Kenny? I don't mean to drain your keg or anything, but could you speed up this process?  Don't get me wrong, we'd love to stand here and get shit on by the cast of Saturday Night Fever, but we're also on a schedule. So step on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you gettin' wise with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm dumber than a goddamn slug. Now can I please clean your windshield and leave without further ado?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny's temper's rising faster than the price of gasoline. Hawk on the other hand is cooler than an Otter Pop.</context>
      <utterance>Break his fawkin' legs, Kenny!</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Kenny grabs himself a fistful of Hawk's long hair and pulls him over to the Trans Am. He wipes the pizza off with Hawk's hair, tugging Hawk's head up and down, back and forth. Hawk GRUNTS with each wipe, but doesn't give Kenny the satisfaction of hearing him scream. Trip, Lex, and Jam watch helplessly, trapped under Bobby's dull-witted, but equally threatening gaze. Kenny gets the last of the big chunks off his windshield and looks at his handiwork.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're dumb all right, you hairy ass punk. But please, allow me to clean the friggin' windshield. I insist.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws Hawk to the ground and smiles at Bobby. Then, he suddenly hears the KISS tune coming from the Volvo. Uh-oh!</context>
      <utterance>There. Nice and clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny clenches his jaws and walks up to the Volvo, reaching in the driver's door. Suddenly Jam grabs his wrist.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, no, no! It's the fag band!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa! This is about pizza! Let's leave KISS out of it. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny pushes Jam away.</context>
      <utterance>A bunch of guys who make bad music, dress like freaks, and wear more make-up than all my sisters combined? These assholes must be stopped!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine gets out of the car and starts walking down the highway, exiting the scene.</context>
      <utterance>That's it, Kenny! I'm leaving!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Christine! You googatz in the head or something? We're on the side of the freakin' highway!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny meanwhile has his arm in the Volvo.</context>
      <utterance>Let her go, Barbara, she'll come back to Kenny. She always does...  Right, Kenny?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny takes the 8-track from the car...</context>
      <utterance>Kool and the Gang, now there's real music.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flings it into the highway, where it is summarily smashed to bits under the wheels of a passing semi. FOLLOW a chunk of cartridge and a strand of mangled tape streaming from it as it sails back toward the side of the road, landing at Jam's feet. TILT UP to Jam's face. He raises his eyes and turns to the CAMERA, a single tear rolling down his cheek, just like the Indian in that "Keep America Beautiful" litter ad. Hawk rises and Kenny comes face-to-face with him.</context>
      <utterance>But this... is crap!</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk pulls a cigarette from his pocket and lights it. He blows some smoke in Kenny's face.</context>
      <utterance>So. All that having been said and done, I believe we are ready for the final topic of discussion. Namely: Have you learned your lesson yet, puke?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's recap, shall we? You slapped all of us, yelled at me, used my head for a rag, threw me on the ground and tossed our LOVE GUN 8- track under the wheels of a passing semi.  So, if the lesson was that you're a dick with ears and a really bad haircut, then, yes... I'd say we learned it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, I'm a little deef-a- hearin'. Can you repeat yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Ahem! You. Are. A. Dick. With. Ears. And. A. Really. Bad. Haircut.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of original material, Kenny goes for an old stand by.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip, Lex, and Jam exchange "uh-oh" glances. Meanwhile, Hawk's eyes glaze over.</context>
      <utterance>That's not what your mother said last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk reaches into his coat pocket and pulls out his mostly empty can of Hawaiian Punch, holding it discreetly at his side.</context>
      <utterance>It's not, huh? Well, then, tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny draws a blank, not being prepared for this one.</context>
      <utterance>...what exactly did my mother say last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny chuckles and looks at Bobby. They have a good little laugh... the homo's got balls! Then Kenny turns back to Hawk.</context>
      <utterance>You heard me, prick. What did my mother say last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk is a little mad now. He tosses his cigarette to the ground and squashes it like a bug under his sneaker.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, fagmo... I'll tell you what your mother said last night.  She said that I was the fuck of her life.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would you like a nice Hawaiian Punch?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quick as a shot, Hawk SLAMS the bottom of the can into Kenny's nose, crushing it flat against his face. Hawaiian backwash spews from its tab hole like blood as Kenny falls backwards from the impact. He hits his head on the ground. Taking this as a cue... Trip whips out his wallet on a chain... Lex rips off his KISS belt... And Jam yanks out his drumsticks. As if choreographed, Trip swoops the wallet at Bobby's feet, snagging him around the ankles tightly with the chain. Lex THWAMS Bobby in the face with his big KISS belt buckle leaving a reversed, red, KISS logo branded in his forehead. Trip yanks the chain pulling Bobby off his feet. When he hits the ground, Jam's right there DRUMMING his balls. Bobby shrieks. Meanwhile, Hawk advances on Kenny who tries to get the can off his face, but it's stuck on looking like a pig's nose with fruit punch for snot. Hawk raises both his hands in Kenny's face, then executes the final insult... Hawk messes Kenny's hair. Kenny lets out a scream that comes from the bottom of his vanity. Hawk grabs Kenny by the ears and brings the guido's head swiftly against his kneecap. Kenny falls to the ground, unconscious on top of Bobby. Their heads collide knocking Bobby out cold. Terrified, Barbara leaps from the Trans Am and is cornered.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so fast, stella.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk grabs a cinderblock off the side of the road, walking up to the Trans Am.</context>
      <utterance>When they wake up, they're gonna come looking for you jerks. You best hope they don't find you, cause if they do, they're gonna kick your asses.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk puts the rock on the Trans Am's accelerator letting the engine WHINE in protest. (Again we are cautious not to show the guidos' faces.)</context>
      <utterance>Right, stella, and we'll deserve it. But let's really make it worth their while.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All who are conscience listen to the brief SCREECH, then watch the Trans Am as it barrels without a driver into the woods skirting the highway. It races into ditches, bounces off trees, and SPLASHES through ponds, all Smokey and the Bandit-like. The disco-mobile ramps off the edge of an embankment, tumbles down a steep, rocky incline breaking apart along the way, and finally, BOOM! It explodes on final impact. The boys all look at each other and shrug. Hawk walks back to the Volvo and gets in. Trip, Lex, and Jam follow suit and pile in as well. Lex shouts back to Barbara.</context>
      <utterance>By the way, when Kenny wakes up could you give him a message for me. Tell him, quote, Kool and the gang bite my bag, motherfucker, unquote. He throws the Trans Am into drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thanks for letting us draw from your ample make-up supply. You must have the entire Revlon factory in your purse!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam points out at the road ahead to Christine. She's a few hundred feet away walking sadly in the breakdown lane.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, look, it's that girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's no girl. That's a stella.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stella or no stella, we should pull over and help her out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, Jam. I'm not falling for that twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk slows down, turning into the breakdown lane, travelling about two miles per hour. Christine doesn't notice as they edge closer to her.</context>
      <utterance>Well, couldn't you slow down so I can at least state my case, Hawk? If you don't like it, you can speed up and I'll never mention it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it with you, Jam? You got a thing for that... thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a teenage girl walking on the side of the highway. They make very scary movies that start out like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Well, they may not make movies about four dudes going to a KISS concert. But if they ever did, the four dudes most certainly would not stop and pick up a stranded disco bunny.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless there was gonna be a scene where the disco bunny blows the four dudes on the way to the show.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, great. I just hitched a ride with a bunch of potheads... I'm hooking up with some people at this funky place in downtown Detroit called Disco Inferno. Mind droppin' me there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it worth to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that supposed to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't mean anything. Don't pay attention to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trying to be suave, Lex moves in close, putting the make on her.</context>
      <utterance>Disco Inferno? Disco's infernal morelike.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your clothes may say disco, but your eyes say rock 'n' roll, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes him away. Jam laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Well, your tee-shirt may say rock 'n' roll, but your breath says pepperoni, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, are you, like, gonna polish our nobs, or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? That's disgusting!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trip! That's so fuckin' rude, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, quit bein' the wussy, sensitive guy to impress her, Jam. She's obviously not gonna put out. She's a fuckin' tease.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tease? What the hell did I do to tease you mongoloids?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got in the car, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, how calculating of me to lead you all on like that after you offered me a ride in the middle of nowhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip lights the joint and takes a lungful of pot. He passes it to Lex and the joint begins to make its rounds with the exception of Christine. The car starts to fill with smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever... stella.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name's Christine, not stella. And there's no need to be such pigs just cause I prefer Donna Summer or KC and the Sunshine Boys or the Village People over KISS?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Village People? They're fags! You're a fag hag!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Hawk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can take care of myself, but thanks anyway, germ.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jam.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever.  Okay, Joe Burnout, let's get one thing straight here. As far as I'm concerned good tunes is good tunes, be it disco or rock or polka or whatever have you, regardless of the category. True, if I had to choose, I'd pick the category labelled disco because I happen to enjoy dancing. Disco is just easier to dance to.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call that John Travolta/Denny Terio shit dancing? I wouldn't dance like that in private if you paid me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine processes this remark.</context>
      <utterance>Disco blows dogs for quarters.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip looks confused, then smiles thinking she paid him a compliment.</context>
      <utterance>Now there's an intelligently biting remark wrought with wit and irony.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, if you don't like that one, maybe you'll think it's funny when we throw your ass out the goddamn car!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, why don't you put your money where your mouth is?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you kiss my hairy crack?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All, Christine included, pause to think about what that comment was supposed to mean. Lex takes a hit off the joint.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you bend over, you're looking right at it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex smiles despite himself and holds the weed out to her as we...</context>
      <utterance>Man, this is some kickass shit!  Gimme a hit off that jay will ya?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, that weed knocked Christine on her ass. She's sleeping like a baby stella.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's lift up her shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All look ahead. COBO Hall. A HALO GLOW forms around the building accompanied by a CHOIR OF ANGELS.</context>
      <utterance>There it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We made it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curly driving, Hawk. We still got two hours to spare.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One block on the left is the W.A.R.P. tower.</context>
      <utterance>Ample time to grab our tickets at the station. See, up ahead. W.A.R.P.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Look at the front entrance! A car's pulling out. The parking space from heaven. God is surely smiling down upon us tonight, dudes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The opening to the Carpenters' "TOP OF THE WORLD" begins.</context>
      <utterance>Kind of funny, I thought He'd be pissed as hell at me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that D.J.'s name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll remember it till the day I die. His name was... Simpleton the Simian? No, Samson Samoan... No, simply, similar...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SIMPLE SIMON strikes a pose before a full-length mirror in a glittery-back Gene Simmons tee-shirt, silver pants, and very high heel boots. He has a huge Afro and bushy moustache. He turns when he hears Hawk.</context>
      <utterance>Simple Simon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMPLE SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all enter and stand at Simple Simon's desk.</context>
      <utterance>The one and only. But can you kids hurry this up? I'm due at Coco Hall in half an hour for the warm-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys do a Three Stooges handshake and say "Curly!" Simple Simon on the other hand suddenly appears nonplussed</context>
      <utterance>We're right behind you, Simo. Just wanted to thank you in advance for handing over those burly-ass tix me and my buds won this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMPLE SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your name isn't Trip is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SIMPLE SIMON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simple Simon on the Rock, go caller.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Is this me? I'm Trip. Am I on the air?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMPLE SIMON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should hang up on you right now, but you're the right caller so answer quick or get your battleship sunk. What are the names of the four members of KISS?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Gene Klein, Stanley Eisen, Paul Frehley, and Peter...Criscula! Yeah, that's it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMPLE SIMON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your final answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMPLE SIMON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Trip? You just got yourself four tickets and four backstage passes to KISS live at Cobo Hall tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMPLE SIMON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you did!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeeeehaaawww!! This is totally fuckin' curly, man! Thank you God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIMPLE SIMON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simple Simon stops the tape and looks at the boys who look like they've just been served a life sentence behind bars.</context>
      <utterance>Trip? Trip? Oh, man, you didn't hang up on me did you? Trip?  What kind of total moron would hang...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMPLE SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk, Trip, Lex, and Jam stare at the floor in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there you have it. We had no choice but to give the tickets to the next caller. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMPLE SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got sodas in the fridge if that helps any.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip looks away from the rest, ashamed.</context>
      <utterance>Well, here we are, dudes. One hour and thirty minutes away from the concert of the century... ticketless. All thanks to Wile E. Coyote, Super- Fucking Genius over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, Trip, can we bore holes in your head and use it as a bong so it actually does us some good for a change?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, Lex! This whole thing wouldn't have happened if it wasn't for you jinxing us. I just made an honest mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry, Trip. What you made was a big, brainless, pile of horse shit. No offense.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys, GUYS! Come on, if this is anyone's fault, it's mine. I was the one who grabbed Trip's jacket by mistake. It's my fault and I apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam looks at his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Jam, we're trying to vent some hostility here. Sure the whole thing may be your fault, but who's gonna get pissed off at you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk, Trip, and Lex cringe.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I think I don't deserve friends as good as you guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have one question. How could a kid who wails on the drums like it's the only thing keeping him alive even think of such a femmy thing to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, Jam, you tryin' to make us barf?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doors to the elevator open and the boys step out.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's like you're possessed by The Flying Nun, or something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... dudes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now there's a woman who totally abuses the privilege of motherhood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk, Trip, and Jam look at their parking spot to see a beat- up Dodge Dart sitting there instead of the Volvo.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the Volvo?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see that, bright boy. What happened to it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was stolen!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christine stole it! Asleep, my ass! The stella booted with your mom's wheels.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we took the keys?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, she musta hot wired it. We picked up a professional car thief in the shape of Olivia Newton-John!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm just a little mad now! Jam, why'd you talk us into picking that bitch up in the first place!?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, guys. I thought it was a nice thing to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jam, not another word out of your femmy-ass mouth! Okay, we're here, we got nothing, and we got an hour and a half. We're totally committed. It's time to brainstorm.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's a suggestion. Let's stop worrying about the concert for the time being and get the cops in on this Volvo situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex is developing a look of resolve. This is Detroit!</context>
      <utterance>Wake up, Lex. This is Detroit. The cops aren't gonna waste city dollars looking for a Swedish car. Face it, the Volvo's on a cutting board as we speak getting sliced, diced, and julienned by Christine, the chop shop gourmet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now listen up. Here's the game plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I mean, my mom's got insurance. What's the worst thing she could do? Ground me for the entire year? I can handle that...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool, bro, now listen up...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Holy shit! I am in absolute trouble! I never should have let you drive, man! Absolute fuckin' trouble!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, shut the fuck up, Lex! Now, then, step number one, we find us a scalper. I got...  twenty-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-five more'n I got.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I got is five. The rest is in the Volvo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam holds up a ten keeping his mouth shut.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-uh. Don't tell us, Jam. Just show us.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So maybe we got enough for one ticket. Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waitaminit, dudes! I got it! We find four really small kids, beat the shit outta them and steal their tickets. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip smiles proudly.</context>
      <utterance>Brilliance, Trip. Sheer brilliance. Give Albert Einstein here the Nobel Prize.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should try sneaking in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four dudes sneaking in? We'd get busted fer sure. Bad plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, one of us sneaks in, gets four ticket stubs off some kids in the audience, comes back out, and we all "re-enter" the concerto. Voila!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk points to the intersection where the church, the male strip joint, the parking lot, and the Smiley Mart are located.</context>
      <utterance>Still too risky for my money.  We're running out of time here. This is KISS! A victory for one is a victory for the team. I'm sure I can barter with a scalper, but if you dudes think you got better plans, go for it. We'll reconvene at that intersection...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...at twenty-thirty hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more time in English.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the next hour and a half it's every dude for himself. Try to get at least one ticket and at 8:30 P.M. we'll meet over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! I know how we can get in!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jam, shut-up! You're not allowed to speak, remember? Go use whatever femmy idea you have to get yourself a ticket or four. I don't wanna hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... my plan involves all four of us acting together.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk, Trip, and Lex split up, leaving Jam alone. He starts walking in the opposite direction, passing MATMOKS. The leader is still on a roll, yelling through the megaphone.</context>
      <utterance>See you at 8:30, Jam. Later.  Dudes? Later.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The leader's gaze finally falls upon Jam. He lets out a GASP. Yes, the leader is Mrs. Bruce. So this was her church meeting. She freezes when she sees her son; her jaw slackens. Meanwhile Jam looks stunned beyond comprehension.</context>
      <utterance>Look around you tonight, mothers! Look at all the young faces! They smile and laugh but their eyes have lost all hope! Not one among them appears to possess the love and fear of God... This satanic group KISS has stolen their souls.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Bruce quickly hands the megaphone to another MATMOK member, who picks up where Mrs. Bruce left off. Jam looks around for someplace to run and hide, but it's too late. Mrs. Bruce slices through the crowd of KISS fans and grabs Jam by the ear. He yelps.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... dear... Lord!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how you got here tonight and I don't want to know either. All I know is you're going to pay dearly for this one, young man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, what're we...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They climb the steps to the cathedral passing a bulletin board reading: Thank God It's Friday Mass, 6PM-7PM. PARISHIONERS exit the beautiful church, shaking hands with a PRIEST as they leave.</context>
      <utterance>Just keep your lying, heathenous trap shut, Jeremiah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARISHIONERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a wonderful mass, Father/So inspirational, Father/Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Bruce pulls Jam up to the priest.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you/Come again next week.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next mass is tomorrow morning, sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we talk, Father? I'm desperate. My son was about to defy God by going to that blasphemous KISS concert.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, across the street...</context>
      <utterance>In that case, come right in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! That's Jeremiah!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeremiah Bruce from school. He and his mom just went into that church. He must be in Detroit for the concert. Can I go say good-bye to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beth, I am not letting you wander the streets of Detroit after dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth points to St. Sebastian's.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to wander. I'm just gonna go over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's with his mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth is already out the door and halfway across the street. Dad pats mom's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Fine, as long as we know where you are. But don't be long. We need to be getting back on the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's probably got a little crush on that boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk can't believe his ears. He looks up at a greasy-looking hybrid, part porn star, part used car salesman, the SCALPER.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, chief? Need a ticket?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCALPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trying to act confident, Hawk takes out his money clip showing the scalper twenty-five dollars.</context>
      <utterance>Second row center, seventy-five clams.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude, this is all I got.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCALPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, man, no can do. But I'll be here for a while if you scare up the extra gravy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell am I gonna scare up that kinda gravy in one hour?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCALPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scalper points over his shoulder and Hawk turns to see three GIGGLING WOMEN exiting the strip joint. None are under forty. A sign below the bar's logo reads: Amateur Night Giveaway! Guys Over 18 Only! Bare It All And Win 75 Bucks!</context>
      <utterance>The easy way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCALPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look a little scrawny, but it's worth a shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't just walk in and take my clothes off. It's embarrasskin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCALPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scalper turns and Hawk grabs his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Guess you don't want to see the greatest show on earth. And in Detroit no less. Well, take care, chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude, if it were dancing the way Fred Astaire did it, I'd give it my best shot. I'd learn the steps and practice in my spare time. But this... tribal, ritualistic bullshit, it's way-too-spontaneous for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCALPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're probably too young anyhow.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I invented fake I.D.s, alright. That's not the problem... They're playing disco music in there, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCALPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk gets a look of resolve on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Chief, here's a little secret. Drink heavily, your feet will know what to do. Now shit or get off the pot. Do you wanna dance or do you wanna see KISS only on their album covers?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCALPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you'll have a ticket for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCALPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk turns and walks up to the door, hesitating before opening it. Rummaging through his pockets, he pulls out a handful of expired driver's licenses. Choosing the one he thinks best suits himself, he walks in with trepidation. The scalper sees someone else coming up.</context>
      <utterance>You have my solemn oath as a public servant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCALPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's Trip.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, chief, you need a ticket? Second row center, seventy-five clams.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip exits FRAME.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks, dude. I'm beating my ticket out of some poor, defenseless chump.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCALPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening to kids today?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bartender gives Hawk the once over.</context>
      <utterance>Like to sign up for the contest.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a little scrawny, but thanks to the concert we're low on amateurs. Name?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hawk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pick a song, Hawk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got any KISS?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kidding? This is Detroit. Drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk squints at a name tag on the bartender's tie.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, a man's drink...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dickey goes to the bottle rack on the other side of the bar.</context>
      <utterance>...Dickey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk looks at the unfamiliar drink again trying to play it cool.</context>
      <utterance>You mean you never seen a Jack Daniels on the rocks before?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, I have. But not one with ice in it, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa... she is a killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dicky pats Hawk's shoulder and leaves. Hawk looks away from Amanda and scans the room. He glances back at Amanda. She's still gazing at him the way queens of yore must have eyed particularly cute knights. She winks and toasts Hawk. Hawk raises his glass smiling nervously. They both sip at their drinks. She licks her lips suggestively at him. And, Hawk proceeds to COUGH up his mouthful of Jack Daniels, SPRAYING it all over the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Amanda Finch. Her ex is one of the wealthiest businessmen in Detroit. Play your cards right and you could hit paydirt. She like 'em young.  And since you look a little new at this, let me give you three words of advice. Hard to get. Think it, act it, know it, be it. Nothing a woman loves more than when you beat her at her own head games.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you little twerps, gimme your KISS tickets or I'll pop your fuckin' faces in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIX YEAR OLD #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have any KISS tickets.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIX YEAR OLD #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, KISS sucks!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the Stretch Armstrong and stuffs it in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>I oughta kick your asses for sayin' that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids run away.</context>
      <utterance>But I'm in a hurry so I'll just take this instead. Now scram.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly distracted, the kid loses the ball.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, little kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip clamps a hand over the little kid's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! You just skunked my last ball, you...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little kid says something but Trip's hand muffles his words.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, booger, your KISS ticket or your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid says what he said before, but it is utterly incomprehensible, once again thanks to Trip's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Hunh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip pulls his hand away.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Okay... But scream and you'll never live to see puberty. I'll pop your fuckin' face in.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please sir, don't beat me up. I do have a KISS ticket, but not on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A likely story. Hand it over, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid turns and yells into the store before Trip can stop him.</context>
      <utterance>No really. My brother's hanging onto it for safe keeping. Please, let me get him for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A titanic guy at the comic book rack looks up from his issue of "Thing" when he hears his name. CHONGO has a very low forehead and the expression of an angry bull plastered onto his face.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Chongo!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, kid, that's okay. I don't wanna see KISS that ba...</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't try to run, maggot. Chongo's an all-state track star in every event.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A tag on your toe. Nobody threatens me and lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you can have my wallet...</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chongo is getting ever-closer with his tree trunk legs, his barrel chest and hydraulic biceps. He is joined by TWO BUDS.</context>
      <utterance>It's not nearly enough, punk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chongo arrives eyeing Trip with distaste. Trip goes white.</context>
      <utterance>Besides, I was gonna take your wallet anyway. After Chongo and his friends crush your ribcage like a pack of Luckys.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHONGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This fairy givin' you shit, bro?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was gonna mug me for my KISS ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chongo and his two buds laugh. Then, without a second of warning, Chongo belts Trip in the gut. Trip doubles over and falls breathlessly to his knees.</context>
      <utterance>Me? Mug? That's nuts. I said, do you know where I can take a piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHONGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip catches his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, pimple dick, you've got the option of walking outside with us or gettin' dragged out. Either way you're comin' with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, sir, don't kick my ass! I'll do anything to get out of a beating!</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chongo scratches his head.</context>
      <utterance>Say, Chongo, perhaps we could use some extra cash for tasty snacks at the KISS concert our weasly friend won't be attending.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHONGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much cash do you figure?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little kid taps his finger on his chin and the theme from "JEOPARDY" begins. While the kid thinks, Trip looks nervously up at Chongo and his buds. Chongo reaches into his denim vest pocket and we hear a CRINKLING NOISE. He comes back up with two walnuts, putting them between his bicep and forearm. Trip watches in horror as Chongo makes a muscle and the walnuts are shelled between two walls of iron-hard flesh. CREEEAAAACK! Chongo eats the walnuts, shells and all.</context>
      <utterance>Take five for a minute, Chongo. Let me do the math.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spooked, he lays down again intending to slide back through when a flashlight beam hits his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa. Danger Will Robinson.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex sees the guard standing about fifty feet away on the other side of the fence. Panicking, he bolts deeper into the field.</context>
      <utterance>Hey you! Get back in here!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex double-times it as we hear the guard yelling into his walkie-talkie.</context>
      <utterance>You're not getting far, kid!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The field gets darker as Lex closes in on Cobo Hall's well- lit loading dock, where ROADIES empty the remaining bits of KISS's monstrous set from an 18-wheeler. Other huge trucks are parked nearby. There's a bustle of last minute activity.</context>
      <utterance>We got one just ran into the field from the north lot!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex spins. The security guard, flanked by two others, barrel right for him.</context>
      <utterance>There he is!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dives rolls under the 18-wheeler. The three security guards leap for the pavement and crawl under the semi after him.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They suddenly realize they've got the wrong man. It's a roadie.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, wiseguy, you are so outta here!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The roadie holds up his all-access laminate angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what the fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The security guards look around frantically for Lex as other roadies join in to defend their comrade.</context>
      <utterance>Keep your paws to yourself, ya dumb fuckin' apes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one pays attention as a bass drum is carried past the guards and up the loading dock ramp. They don't notice Lex crammed inside contorted into a shape befitting a yoga master. Praying he won't be spotted, Lex holds his breath as he's carried into the building and disappears.</context>
      <utterance>Where'd he go? You see him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth smiles nervously and heads back toward the front door passing a confessional booth. She throws a glance back at the priest and Mrs. Bruce who have returned to conferring, their backs to her. She stealthily ducks into the booth.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, next mass isn't until tomorrow morning, young lady. Run along now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now it's been a while since my boy had holy confession. Could you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Bruce looks down at Jam and sees his drumsticks poking out of his socks. She immediately takes them out and stuffs them into her jacket. Jam doesn't even move.</context>
      <utterance>Consider it done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam is stung. Mrs. Bruce and the priest head back down the center aisle exiting through the gigantic front doors. She eyes Jam.</context>
      <utterance>It's about time you gave up on that stupid dream once and for all. No son of mine is going to be a career musician.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Father. I'll be back for him before you know it; after I take care of some unfinished business.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets her out and locks the door, leaving the keys in the lock, and walks over to Jam.</context>
      <utterance>Just knock loudly, sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He helps the despondent Jam up. They walk to the booth and Jam reluctantly gets inside.</context>
      <utterance>Come along, son. Get into the booth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, Father, for I have sinned. This is my first confession in... well... a really long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prepare to receive the Act of Penance. How many sins have you committed since your last confession?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth leans forward slightly and listens to Jam's confession.</context>
      <utterance>Just one, Father, but boy was it a doozy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EMCEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk wakes up fast. There's nothing more sobering than having to undress in public.</context>
      <utterance>You're up, Hawk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Dicky, I c-c-can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna chicken out on me now, are you? We've got your KISS song playing and everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-I c-can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, people undress in public because, A, they're exhibitionists, B, they're nutcases, or C, they need the money. I can tell you're not A, and I hope to hell you're not B. So my suggestion is, think about why you're a C and let your body party, shake your groove thing, boogie oogie oogie till you just can't boogie no more. Hawk thinks about it, then downs the rest of his drink. He grimaces at it's taste, then opens his eyes with new resolve.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk swivels his bar stool to the right and gets off, forgetting to stand when his feet hit the floor. He proceeds to fall flat on his face. Dicky looks down concerned, but Hawk stands with a little difficulty and heads for the stage. The crowd of women parts down the middle for him and checks him out as he walks by. They seem to like what they see. Hawk looks nervously at the carnivorous faces leering at his package first, his ass after. What the hell is he doing? Hawk reluctantly climbs onto the stage and the gals start CLAPPING to the song. He faces them and starts gyrating his drunken hips at them, feeling no confidence whatsoever, until... The CHEERS start to ECHO and the pulsing lights begin to hurt his eyes. Hawk watches the world proceed to spin faster than the disco ball above his head. He stops gyrating and clutches his stomach. BELCHING. Uh-oh. Hawk spots an almost-empty beer pitcher one of the CHEERING- IN-SLOW-MOTION women holds above her head. He runs up to the edge of the stage, grabs the pitcher, and PUKES. The cheering and music come to a grinding halt. You can hear a pin drop as Hawk yacks his guts out into the beer pitcher. It goes on for an excruciatingly long time, then finally stops. Hawk looks up at the hundreds of astonished eyes staring at him. He wipes his mouth, then a look of ease washes over his face.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, Dicky. I gotta do it for KISS. Gotta put a bag over its head and  Do it for KISS.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the vomit-filled pitcher back to the shocked woman.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. I feel a hundred times better!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over at the emcee, who gazes at Hawk from the DJ booth.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The emcee stands perfectly still, jaw agape.</context>
      <utterance>Maestro? As you were.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>entertainment! The show must go on! Hawk starts gyrating even though the music is still off. The emcee shrugs, re-cuing the song. It starts again as Hawk faces the crowd, dancing with new-found bravado. The women come out of their dumbstruck comas and reluctantly start CLAPPING again. Hawk pulls off his jacket and twirls it over his head Roger Daltry style. Then he pulls it back down and tosses it into the crowd. The women actually fight over it. Encouraged, Hawk then peels off his KISS Army tee-shirt and hurls it at the women, who SQUEAL with delight. Sure, he may be scrawny, but they don't mind. This lad's got personality. Adrenaline pumping, confidence building, Hawk starts playing the crowd of very responsive ladies. He unbuttons his jeans first. Then, leaving them on, he does an "air guitar" medley: Chuck Berry, ZZ Top, Angus Young from AC/DC, and Elvis Costello in six easy steps. Hawk finishes off with a Pete Townshend windmill, shaking his ass at his audience in mid-strum, then licks his finger and touches one of his cheeks: "hot stuff" (he does this in a manly way of course). Then Hawk pauses to adjust what looks to be his underwear bunching up in his crack. The women WHOO-HOO. He segues into a Mick Jagger rooster strut and the ladies go ga-ga. He makes the sign of the horns with each hand and wiggles a protruding tongue like Gene Simmons. The gals scream in orgastic joy. Then, Hawk goes for the gold. Yes, he does the Fonzie dance! The women are now overcome by sheer animal lust. Hawk's whipped his audience into a frenzied pack of bitches in heat. Amanda smirks and sucks from her little drink straw suggestively. At long last Hawk figures he has to give them what they want. He puts his fingers to his fly, pauses, then unzips. His Brittanias fall to his ankles, revealing a pair of bony legs sticking down from some KISS boxer shorts. The ladies go batty. Unfortunately Hawk has neglected a cardinal rule of disrobing. Never pull your pants down without taking your shoes off first. He tries to kick off his shoes. The left one goes flying across the bar and THWACK, beans a MIDDLE-AGED WOMAN in the face. She flies backwards over a chair. Trying to kick the other shoe off, Hawk loses his balance and falls backwards, hitting his head on the edge of the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, dude, we got a bunch of frisky felines waiting for some</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two hundred bucks?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me, nad breath. My time's precious and I think that's a reasonable price to pay for your sorry life.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little kid shakes his head in disgust.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I want to live, but I don't know where the fuck I'm gonna find two hundred bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chongo advances, muscles flexing.</context>
      <utterance>Chongo? Take him outside and tear his ass out through his mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on! I know how I can get the money! I just figured it out! Only you might wanna wait outside. The little kid and Chongo look at each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHONGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't trust him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look back at Trip.</context>
      <utterance>I think he's on the level. He's too stupid to try anything sneaky anyway. Look at him, he's a moron.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip nods sullenly as the kid, Chongo, and the two buds exit. Then he checks to make sure Stretch Armstrong is still with him.</context>
      <utterance>You got fifteen minutes and not a second longer. We have a concert to go to. See you outside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROADIE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Roadie 2 snags his foot on a mess of cable and loses his balance, dropping the oversized drum. In an instant the drum goes rolling down the ramp quickly gaining speed.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, this one's heavy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADIE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The roadies bolt after the runaway drum. Other workers scurry out of the way to avoid being hit by the speeding instrument.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you see if it wasn't for me, me and my friends would be at that KISS concert right now... together.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this is a unique confession to say the least, son. And not exactly the most interesting one I've ever heard either. You sure you don't want to talk about... oh, carnal knowledge with a neighborhood girl or impure thoughts about the new student teacher maybe... or how about finding a box of magazines under your dad's bed?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest SLIDES the door shut again. Jam is all but shrouded in darkness, but can make out the time on his watch. It's getting late. He resignedly sits on the bench behind him... right on Beth's lap. Jam yells, but Beth throws her hand over his mouth. His eyes bulge. He can't believe what he's seeing. He climbs off Beth and sits next to her.</context>
      <utterance>Well then, I suggest you have a seat on the bench behind you and think of something a little juicier to confess than losing KISS tickets. I realize this is Detroit, but I personally find, what that rock and roll band is all about, to be boring as Lucifer's kingdom. I'll return in a little while.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beth? I can't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam thinks for a beat. Something still isn't quite clicking.</context>
      <utterance>Believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETH can hardly speak. She gulps thinking of what to say.</context>
      <utterance>Are you waiting for confession? I thought you were Jewish?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth gives him the biggest, wettest, sloppiest kiss in recorded history. She pulls away finally wiping her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>I have a confession. Here it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean for that to be so... intense. Forgive me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lunges at him again, kissing him for dear life. Her lips leave his and begin to explore his chin, neck, ear.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care. I wanna hear more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've loved you ever since I first laid eyes on you, Jeremiah. I've just always been too scared to show it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beth, I can't believe you just said that because that's exactly how I've always felt about you... Call me Jam. It's my band name.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her neck. Unable to stop, they start undressing each other, both breathing heavy.</context>
      <utterance>You don't know how long I've been waiting to hear that... Jam!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to take this slow...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, slow...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tears his tee-shirt open with her teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, screw it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EMCEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FOLLOW the emcee's hand to Hawk who holds an ice pack on the side of his head.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, ladies, it's down to... Troy the Human Jackhammer... The women APPLAUD as we...</utterance>
   <speaker>EMCEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women APPLAUD but not quite as loud.</context>
      <utterance>...and Mr. Massive Head Wound Accompanied by an Upset Stomach-Hawk!</utterance>
   <speaker>EMCEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women cheer and a DISCO SONG starts as Troy does a reprise of his act. Hawk walks away from the stage with the rest of the rejected strippers, looking the way he feels: pretty damn stupid. He puts on his pants, trying to walk at the same time and falls to his knees. A helpful hand grabs him under the arm and helps him up. It's Amanda looking lustier than ever.</context>
      <utterance>No contest. The grand prize of seventy- five dollars goes to Troy the Human Jackhammer!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, miss.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're too kind. I'm Amanda.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, well, thanks for the drinks and stuff, Amanda, but there's no reason for me to stick around these parts anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be so glum, Hawk. The night's still young and filled with plenty of compensatory possibilities.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk GULPS.</context>
      <utterance>I'd be in a position to spend some money on you if you'd get in a position and spend some time on me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRIEST'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhh, tying my shoe.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. So, have you thought of a colorful confession yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, yes. Last year I walked out of a candy store with a Reggie Bar I hadn't paid for, but went back and apologized the next day.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the door SLIDE shut again as Beth and Jam pick up where they left off.</context>
      <utterance>Boooring. Think, boy, think!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LEX'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you're even thinking of committing a robbery, Trip. You don't pass go and collect 200 dollars for pulling stuff like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip sends brief, agitated glances around the store meeting the cashier's eyes again. She smiles at him coyly as she plays with her mood ring. He gives her the eye, then returns to his comic.</context>
      <utterance>No shit, dude, is this really worth it? Sure you get your ass kicked nine ways to Sunday by that fucking gorilla, but it's still a hundred times better than getting it porked for the next three to five.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what about that girl, Trip? She'll never forget this night. Even if you get away with it, she'll be scarred for life. When are you gonna realize sometimes being tough means being tender.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip snaps out of it. All the shoppers and cashier are starring at him. He COUGHS loudly, clearing his throat to cover his outburst. The shoppers go back to shopping. A MAN WITH A LONG COAT enters the store, looks around, then takes a spot alongside Trip and opens a Mad Magazine.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, everybody, SHUT UP!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH COAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His thunder now stolen, Trip drops to the floor along with everyone else. The air is very tense. The cashier starts SOBBING, keeping her hands in the air.</context>
      <utterance>Evening, honey. Y'know what I am, what this is, and what you have to do, so do it quick.  The rest of you kindly introduce yourselves to the floor and kiss it hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH COAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do or die, bitch! Next time I let the barrels do the talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man with the coat COCKS the chamber and the cashier immediately opens the register drawer and starts emptying it.</context>
      <utterance>P-p-please, mister, I'm just a high school kid...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH COAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man with the coat's laughter ECHOES in Trip's head till he just can't take it anymore.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck school, that's what I say! I just went through the motions till I was old enough to drop out and I'm leaving here with at least two fifty the easy way. Look where all that studying's gonna get you tonight. Robbed at gunpoint and possibly shot in the fucking head... for minimum wage!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Astounded by Trip's audacity, the man with the coat turns his shotgun point-blank at Trip.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, drop it or I'll kick your ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH COAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah! You and what army?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The KISS Army!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the opportunity to peer down some BIG BUSTED GIRL'S cleavage. Then his eye spots something else. He GASPS. A door. On it a star. Written on the star, the word, KISS.</context>
      <utterance>This is real. This is not a dream! This is real! I've pierced the inner circle!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A big-haired HIPSTER in mirrored sunglasses KNOCKS on the dressing room door. It opens, but Lex can't see inside. The hipster stands in the doorway talking to whoever is there. Lex cranes his neck to see around the door jamb. Desperate for a glimpse of his idols, he leans out too far. Suddenly, the entire duct collapses. Breaking loose of the ceiling, Lex hurls to the floor clutching the duct. Backstage goers leap for cover as SMASH... he hits the ground in a shower of plaster and dust. The hipster protectively pulls the dressing room door shut as two SECURITY MEN jump in front of it. Instantly, huge, burly hands come down on Lex's shoulders. Before he can react, a slew of OFFICERS have him off his feet and carry him away, a stunned expression frozen to his face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, they're in there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No luck. He stops, when several other DOGS emerge from the shadows and gather behind the first three. These new mutts immediately join in the GROWLING chorale. The Shepherd snaps at Lex.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up, Lex! Wake up, man! This part's gotta be a nightmare!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pack BARKS even louder.</context>
      <utterance>God, if you ever get me outta this, I swear I will never masturbate again!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. Is it true that Gene Simmons had a cow's tongue grafted onto his real one? Y'know, to make it so long?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. I think he had the piece of skin under his tongue removed so he could stick it out farther. I'm not too up on Gene trivia.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your man is the drummer, Peter Criss, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter Criss is my inspiration, man. If I paid a hundred bucks for a KISS show and all I saw was his solo, I'd consider it... money... Hey, how'd you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens her backpack and pulls out a package addressed to Jam. The return address reads: Beth Bumsteen, Somewhere in Ann Arbor.</context>
      <utterance>I have all your notebook doodles memorized, Jam... Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ann Arbor?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam opens the box and his jaw drops. It's a black tee-shirt with the "Mystery" logo printed in white on the chest. Jam holds it up. It's gigantic.</context>
      <utterance>My dad's company is relocating him. We're moving. That's why I was acting so freaky in school today. I thought it was the last time I'd ever see you. Anyway, open the box. I would have given it to you this morning, except... like I said, I was freaking out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Touched, Jam kisses her for a long time. He starts putting on the shirt when suddenly they hear the SHUFFLING of the priest entering his booth. Jam grabs his clothes and sits back on the bench. Beth starts getting dressed at his feet.</context>
      <utterance>I pass by this really cool tee-shirt shop on my way to school every day and I know you wear those black tee- shirts all the time. You look like a size thirty-five, but all the sizes were in Roman numerals. So I got you an XXXL. That's thirty-five, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, you better have something really sinful for me this time, son. My patience is worn to threads and your mom will be here any minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, Father, here it is. About two weeks ago I went to my cousin's wedding and one of the bridesmaids asked me if I wanted to take a bath.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth is tying her shoes. Jam slips on his socks.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was insulted, so I asked her if I was wreaking some wicked b.o., right? Then she said no, she wanted to take a bath with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is terrible... Please go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam pauses.</context>
      <utterance>Well, she was a very tempting siren, Father. Built like you wouldn't believe. So I gave into temptation about a block away from the wedding reception at this little motel that charges by the hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well? Continue! Continue!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... when she peeled off that gown, you'll never guess what she was wearing underneath.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fully dressed, Beth crawls out of the confessional.</context>
      <utterance>Was it a teddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Much bet... I mean, much more sinful than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bustier?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what. You keep guessing and I'll say something when you get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam quietly sneaks out.</context>
      <utterance>Splendid! I love a good game of Name That Nightie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex holds up a worn-out, old frisbee.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, you're pissed off. I can see this. So... Maybe what we need... ah-ha.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pack just glares and SNARLS. He tosses the frisbee over the packs' heads, but the dogs don't even acknowledge it. They just keep BARKING and GROWLING. Meanwhile, an unnoticed dog at the rear of the pack, a mangy Basset Hound, turns its flat head to see the frisbee land on the ground behind him. His tail starts to wag.</context>
      <utterance>Play some frisbee, poochies?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright! I give up! I hearby and forthwith defer my destiny to you mutts. I may be an intelligent, upright, walking, homo-fucking sapien, but you fleabags are a force of nature. So, I'm just gonna sit here and wait for you to decide. If you let me live, I thank you. If you bite my head off, I'll die knowing I did all I could. It's up to you. Lex waits before the GROWLING, SNAPPING canines. Suddenly, the Basset Hound runs up in front of the pack and drops the frisbee at Lex's feet. Lex looks down at the floppy, wrinkly dog, who wags its tail and PANTS furiously.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex starts to pet the hound, and one-by-one the rest of the dogs shut-up. Shocked, Lex picks the frisbee up again and throws it. This time the entire pack bolts after the Whammo product. Lex smiles, watching them fight for it in the air... in SLOW MOTION... as the theme from "CHARIOTS OF FIRE" begins. The black Shepherd finally grabs the frisbee in its mouth and runs back toward Lex. It's soon joined by the rest of the pack. That's right about when Lex realizes they aren't going to stop.</context>
      <utterance>Well, how do you like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dogs plow into Lex full-force knocking him into the garbage. They surround him licking his face. Lex bursts into unstoppable laughter. Pulling himself up, he pets the dogs as they jump around him wagging their tails and PANTING.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Whoa!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beefy jerk 2 laughs.</context>
      <utterance>So, I jump into the car, hot-wire it in thirty seconds and start driving. Then, suddenly I hear this scream. The disco queen was asleep in the back seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beefy jerk 2 laughs more. Beefy jerk 1 checks the time.</context>
      <utterance>You think it's funny? How would you like to have a stiletto heel smacking you in the temple when you're tryin' to work?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then a familiar voice is heard coming from the back of the shop.</context>
      <utterance>You about done splittin' a gut there? We gotta get these parts to Toledo by nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex follows the voice and sees Christine handcuffed to a radiator near the rear of the shop.</context>
      <utterance>Then maybe you guys'll let me go, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, whadaya say? You scratch my back, I scratch yours. You let me go, and in return, I keep my big mouth shut about your little operation here. Mum, know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're lucky you're still alive, wench. If you was a guy, we woulda thought nothin' of sawing your head off with a butter knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beefy jerk 2 bares what's left of his yellow, crusty teeth</context>
      <utterance>What are we gonna do with her anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno, but she sure looks fun. Beefy jerk 1 touches the bandage on his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine GAGS at the thought.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and payback's a bitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gulps some down and pulls the flask away COUGHING.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gin.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. Some of this hard liquor's a tad too manly for me. I'm a brewski man myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better ease up then, Hawk. Wouldn't want to give you whiskey dick would we?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amanda plants a stocking foot on Hawk's crotch and rubs.</context>
      <utterance>Who's Whiskey Dick?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. Obviously no one you have to worry about... Woody.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk's eyes cross as he lets out a DEEP, OBNOXIOUS GROAN.</context>
      <utterance>My name's not Woody, it's Haw-haw...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amanda looks down at his crotch.</context>
      <utterance>...holy shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk has never been more embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>But you do know Premature Peter, don't you? Shame, I just bought these stockings.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Amanda, this has been quite a night. So far you've seen me and my dick throw up.  What's next? Projectile diarrhea?  Man. What a stud, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a healthy swig of gin, relishing its bitterness.</context>
      <utterance>Believe it or not, you still have a way to go before you start competing with my soon-to-be-ex-husband... the champion of lousy lovemaking. The man who thinks he's the biggest and the best... The man who thinks every secretary, stewardess, and cocktail waitress he fucks should lick his feet for the honor. The man for whom faking it was invented. Christ, if I hadn't gotten pregnant with our son, I would have never known I even had sex with the prick.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You love him?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just told you, he's a big, hairy...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean... you love your son?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than anything in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he loves you back, doesn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a little spoiled, but I know he does.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pats his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Well, shame on him if he doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hawk stares out the windshield.</context>
      <utterance>You're sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>kisses it. He takes her arm and begins kissing his way up to her neck, her cheek, her mouth...</context>
      <utterance>My mom died of a heart attack while she was having me. Man, I wish I had known her for even one day. If they ever invent a time machine, that's what I'm doing. Going back in time to meet my mom. I'm gonna say, "Mrs. Pitchford?... or Miss Williams, depending on when I show up. You don't know me, but I'm your kid from the future. Just wanted to thank you for the blue eyes, pug nose and for tying the knot with a guy who didn't mind diaper detail... Oh, and, uh... cut down on the red meat, will ya?" Amanda caresses Hawk's cheek. He turns with her hand and</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAN WITH COAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme your gun, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you gimme your gun, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH COAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tempt me, I'll shoot!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if I shoot first!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH COAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even think you have a gun!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man with the coat puts his shotgun against Trip's head.</context>
      <utterance>Neither do I!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH COAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip GULPS. The jig's up. He slowly pulls out Stretch Armstrong, and the man with the coat glances down and starts to laugh very loud. So loud, he throws his head back. When he recovers, Trip's got Stretch aimed at his head and pulled back to maximum tension.</context>
      <utterance>Now, for the last time, take the piece out and lay back down or your mom's gonna need the White Tornado to get the brains outta your ski cap.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip lets go. WZZMACK! The man gets it right in the face and falls backward onto the Hostess display, toppling a whole bunch of Ho-Ho's, Ding-Dong's, Twinkies, and Suzy-O's to the ground. Trip runs up and grabs the shotgun away as the man with the coat lifts his head briefly, then passes out. Trip turns around and the cashier SLAMS into him, nearly knocking him over. She throws her arms around him letting out relieved SOBS. Behind her all the customers rise from the floor CLAPPING. Trip did it. He saved the fucking store! The cashier looks into Trip's masked eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Smile, you sonofa...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you! Thank you!... Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She plants a thousand mega-watt kiss on his lips and we ZOOM IN on her mood ring changing color from gray to fire engine red. Trip's eyes widen just before... KABOOM... The shotgun he's holding goes off, blowing a hole in the ceiling. The recoil from the blast jolts Trip and the cashier apart. We now see Trip's face is smeared with bright, red lipstick. A huge chunk of ceiling falls onto his head but he doesn't move. The kiss hit him harder.</context>
      <utterance>Call me... Dr. Love!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The beefy jerks laughs.</context>
      <utterance>You guys better kill me before you do what you're thinking of doing. Cause when I'm mad enough, I can bite down very hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweet Polly Purebred's got some spunk, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They put their blow torches down and turn to her.</context>
      <utterance>I'll give her some spunk alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They giggle maniacally and lumber toward Christine. Their shadows growing larger and larger across her.</context>
      <utterance>We stripped that Beemer in fifteen minutes. Bet we can strip her in fifteen seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now wait a minute, guys! Two against one ain't fair. Lemme go back and get my friend Barbara. You'd love her. Tits the size of your head. You'll feel like a little baby sucking on 'em. I swear, I'll bring her right back. It'll be a four-way... You guys like disco? I teach disco dancing at my church. You guys look like you got rhythm in your blood. Come on, free lessons if you let me go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both laugh. Just as they're about to grab her... Suddenly, the garage door behind them SLIDES UP revealing darkness. Christine and the beefy jerks look out anxiously.</context>
      <utterance>I know a dance we can do. The horizontal hustle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence except for CRICKETS. Then... from out of the darkness emerges a figure... Lex. Christine's eyes brighten like a bulb.</context>
      <utterance>Who's there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The beefy jerks laugh at this little punk. They start toward him, one with a tire iron, the other a big monkey wrench.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here for the girl and the car. You can try to stop me, but I must warn you, it may be hazardous to your health.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad. He was such a young idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex lets out a quick HIGH-PITCHED WHISTLE. The pack of BARKING dogs led by the Shepherd, the Pit Bull, the Doberman, and the Basset Hound, step from the darkness and flank Lex, GROWLING and SNARLING at the beefy jerks.</context>
      <utterance>Ehhh. He was a stupid boy. He deserved to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The beefy jerks drop their tools on their feet and yelp in pain. The pack takes this as a threat and charge the beefy jerks, who bolt for a glass-partitioned office. The dogs SCRATCH and BARK at the window ferociously. Lex smiles at Christine. She smiles back. He presses the "down" button on the lift and the Volvo descends. Lex yells to the beefy jerks through the glass.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to them. Children of the night. What music they make... Hounds of hell? Say hello to dinner!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex unlocks Christine. She leaps into his arms.</context>
      <utterance>One foot out of that office and your asses are Alpo!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a lingering kiss. Lex leans back, gives the double thumbs-up, and says...</context>
      <utterance>Wow! Thank you! You're cooler than the Fonz.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lex takes her hand and they walk over to the Volvo. Lex lets her in then rounds the car to the driver's side.</context>
      <utterance>Aaaayyyyy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY JERK #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what about the dogs?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They nod. Lex drips a dry smile onto them.</context>
      <utterance>You got a phone in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The beefy jerks watch in disbelief as the Volvo SCREECHES out of the chop shop.</context>
      <utterance>Call the cops.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ann Arbor isn't... that far from Cleveland, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah. Once I get my own wheels, I could come up all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam takes her hands.</context>
      <utterance>That'd be great. Hey, maybe someday your band'll play there. It's a college town, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel like such an idiot. Why didn't I just say something a year and a half ago? Man, think of how much time we wasted.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's not think about the past. Let's just think about from today on. I'll never forget you, Jam.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at each other for a really long time. Then, kiss. BEEP. BEEP. Dad looks back out the window and CLEARS HIS</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it. Church will never be the same again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming dad.  I'll call you. Soon as we get a phone. Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets in the car. They both wave as the Impala turns a corner out of sight. Jam is left alone still waving long after she's gone.</context>
      <utterance>Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amanda, as ironic as this is gonna sound, I can't take any money for... I'm no Midnight Cowboy, y'know. It would only cheapen the whole deal for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She forces the money into his palm.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not paying you for the lovemaking, Hawk. I just want you to have whatever you needed the money for when you took me up on my offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>...Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a good man, Hawk. Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't happen to know where we could find this... Dr. Love, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops shrug and get into the cruiser.</context>
      <utterance>It's company policy to hand over a cash reward of a hundred and fifty dollars to anyone who stops a robbery. I gave him the money and he took off.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cruiser takes off and the cashier stares at her mood ring. It throbs red like a beating heart.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, well, thanks anyway. And let us know if you happen to see him again. We'd like to ask him some questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I see Dr. Love any time soon, you're gonna have to wait till I'm done with him first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little kid puts the money in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>...hundred forty, hundred fifty. That's all I got.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chongo reels back and...</context>
      <utterance>Tsk. Tsk. Tsk. I really wanted things to work out for you, my weasly, dim- witted friend. You got spunk.  Chongo, give him a fifty dollar wallop.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THWAM! Right in Trip's face. Trip flies off his feet into the Smiley Mart brick wall with a THUD. A bag of weed drops from his jacket, then some uppers, a few sheets of acid, and finally a can of beer rolls out.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no... Please, look. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHONGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, the jerkoff's got drugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chongo laughs like an ejaculating gorilla as he and his two buds scoop it all up. The little kid, Chongo, and the buds leave Trip lying in a puddle of his own nose blood. He pulls out Stretch Armstrong and looks at him fondly.</context>
      <utterance>Consider it a bonus, Chongo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This oughta be enough to get you to Disco Inferno, Christine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come with. It's not too late for you to catch the fever.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine takes his hand and writes something on his palm in lipstick.</context>
      <utterance>No can do. But I made a promise to get you to that disco, and we KISS maniacs are men of our word. Besides... you're pretty cool... for a stella, I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives Lex a kiss then pushes him away.</context>
      <utterance>Here's my number. Tell me how cool I am over the phone sometime. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The taxi SCREECHES away as Lex smiles and gets back into the Volvo.</context>
      <utterance>Disco Inferno, on the double.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taken aback by his confidence, Mrs. Bruce grabs his ear and tries to pull him away. He won't budge.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna ask you nicely first. Mom, can I have my drumsticks back?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BUNCH OF IDIOTS walk by with big transistor radios. One of them holds a Mr. Microphone and heckles the MATMOKS.</context>
      <utterance>Again, can I have my drumsticks?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam yanks the Mr. Microphone from the lead idiot and screams at his mother, his voice amplified on the transistors. Everyone stares.</context>
      <utterance>Drumsticks are the least of your worries, young man. You are in a world of...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other MATMOKS turn to look as Jam climbs onto a trash receptacle and shouts down at his mother, his face slowly turning purple.</context>
      <utterance>I know, mom, I've been in trouble for about twelve hours now! Hellooooo!?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna be spending the next two years of my life at St. Bernard's Boarding School, remember?! I'm gonna be outta your hair till I'm a legal adult, remember?! That way, all you have to do is go to church, light a candle, pray to a little statue for me, and voila! All is forgiven and forgotten, right mom?!! Then, you can spend your days in guilt-free pursuit of more constructive activities like telling everybody else how screwed up their lives are! That way you no longer need the patience and understanding required to communicate on some normal level with your own child!!! And that way you don't even have to think about how tough it was for you when you were growing up, and it's a good thing too. Cause if you did, you'd realize what a LOUSY, GODDAMN, SHITTY-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MRS. BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeremiah... what's gotten into you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd cheers. Jam jumps down and hands the Mr. Microphone back to the lead idiot. He turns to his mom.</context>
      <utterance>I just lost my virginity in a confessional booth! Lord have mercy!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Bruce reaches into the trash, finds the drumsticks and hands them to him. He spins them like pistols, then stuffs them into his socks and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>For the last time, mom. Let me have my fucking drumsticks. Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scalper sees Hawk and bolts down the street disappearing around a corner. Hawk stops. He's lost him. Hawk sulks to the now-familiar intersection where all four landmarks meet. He takes one more look up the block at Cobo Hall. Nearly all the KISS fans are inside. The streets are almost deserted.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Whoa! WHOA! That better not be the last ticket! I hope you have another one for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees someone out of the corner of his eye across the street. It's Jam. Lex approaches the other corner. Trip comes up to the forth corner. They all stop when they see each other. Each standing on his own corner. They're all pissed. They meet in the middle of the street as last minute CONCERT GOERS hurry by.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any luck?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plenty, but it was all bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found the Volvo.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all shake no.</context>
      <utterance>Tickets?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a commotion up the street. A SURLY MOM yanks four 12 YEAR OLD BRATS dressed like KISS by the scruffs of their necks. She's furious, they're CRYING.</context>
      <utterance>Well, dudes, the only way we're gonna see KISS this tour is by some fuckin' miracle.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURLY MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws a wad of paper to the pavement as they pass our four heroes. The dudes watch her pull the brats away.</context>
      <utterance>How dare you sneak out of the house like that! You had me worried to death! Don't you know this is Detroit! And for a degenerate band like KISS! They're sick, sick, sick and oughta be in jail with their vile antics!</utterance>
   <speaker>SURLY MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jam, Hawk, Lex, and Trip turn and look at the crumpled wad at their feet. It's an envelope. An ANGELIC SPOTLIGHT FROM ABOVE highlights it.</context>
      <utterance>Just wait until your father gets ahold of you!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... You don't think...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all shake their heads in unison resolved that it isn't. Then, unable to control themselves, they dive for the envelope. Jam tears it open. His trembling hand reaches in. All their eyes focus like lasers on what's inside. Jam pulls out four KISS tickets. Their jaws drop. Their eyes bug.</context>
      <utterance>Nah. Couldn't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys are practically moved to tears. It's Divine Intervention at its finest. Suddenly, a greasy hand juts out of nowhere and grabs the tickets. The boys look up shocked. They can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>It's a miracle! A miracle!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose laughing now?! Whose laughing now, ya little shits?! I told ya... Over my dead body! Ha-HA-HAAA!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy, Elvis. Don't do anything crazy. Just give me the tickets before someone gets hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, wait a minute! This ain't school property! He's not the boss of us here!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. This ain't school. It's not about school anymore. Now it's personal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Elvis. We was only kiddin'. It's all in good fun. We run, you chase. Cat and mouse. You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elvis stuffs all four tickets in his mouth and chews crazily. In seconds, GULP. Elvis explodes into unhinged laughter as he runs away zigzagged down the street. Our boys are left dumbstruck and speechless. After a really long pause...</context>
      <utterance>Boys, this time... I win!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I still got my idea if anybody will let me speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, Jam.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand and think for a moment. Hawk's mouth curls into a devilish grin. Then, he lets out a gigantic "AIEEE!!! and slugs Jam. The four boys brutally pummel one another in the middle of the intersection. Punching. Kicking. Headbutting.</context>
      <utterance>We all beat each other up, then, once we're nice and bruised, we run over to the ticket takers and say we got mugged and our tickets were stolen. They gotta let us in then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude, you gotta let us in! Four muggers just stole our tickets!</utterance>
   <speaker>TICKET TAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You expect us to believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trip points into the crowd of fans inside the auditorium foyer.</context>
      <utterance>Look at us!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ticket takers turn to see the little kid, Chongo, and their two buds just going in. The ticket takers signal two security guards who proceed to stop the four stunned kids and confiscate their tickets. They find all the stolen dope and Trip's wallet.</context>
      <utterance>It was those assholes! They even stole my wallet!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The security guards see he's right and break out the cuffs.</context>
      <utterance>Inside that you'll find my KISS Army picture I.D. and a hundred fifty bucks cash.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tsk. Tsk. Tsk. I was really hoping things would work out for you, my weasly, midget friend. You got spunk. The little kid for once is speechless. Then the ticket taker extends his arm in SLOW MOTION into COBO Hall as if to say "Entrez Vous." The four friends pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They take a few slow steps almost as if they don't believe it, then run like the wind into the auditorium.</context>
      <utterance>This is it!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
