<movie id="177" title="Drag Me to Hell">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She catches herself on the last word, a hint of "Missouri twang" slipping through.</context>
      <utterance>There is no friction, with proper diction. Good sounds abound, when the mouth is round.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yawn. She slips off her nightgown and lumbers into the steaming shower.</context>
      <utterance>Round.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Van roars past. She pets the Kitten. It PURRS and licks Stephanie's face. She sets it down.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Slow down!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads for the Bank. The kitten follows. She turns back, frowning.</context>
      <utterance>Go on home. Shoo now!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoo!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MEXICAN MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We keep getting the same thing. Because I'm not employed by an American company, they won't take my application until they get my solvency statement. And the Mexican Treasury Department says that's going to take at least four more weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEXICAN WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the house will be gone by then.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says, here your employed by Pemex?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEXICAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't Pemex a subsidiary of Union Oil?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>3.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>a MEXICAN MAN Yes. So? 0</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The happy couple shake Stephanie's hand and exit. ELLEN, Stephanie's pretty, twenty two year old, roommate, flops down into the seat across from her.</context>
      <utterance>So technically, your employer is an American company. I think we can make this work. I'll call you this afternoon and let you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need clarification on the shoe issue.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First of all-- you know you've got the only perfect pair of black dress shoes in L.A. So was that a definite, irrevocable, "no way" or t just a rather not at this time, "no way"?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an absolutely, positively, forget about the shoes already, "no way". They're my only good pair and I need them in good shape for tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's Up?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen picks up a desktop photo: A shot of Stephanie and her handsome boyfriend, Ray, locked in an embrace, standing in the spray of a waterfall.</context>
      <utterance>Dinner with Ray's parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray's got a nice butt. Really tight</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1 --I know. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie looks longingly to...</context>
      <utterance>He's a keeper. But I told you about his mom, she's another story. I used to waitress at her country club, and with her, it's all about what private school you went to and who you know. You still up for that promotion? That would help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kitten peers out through Stephanie's partially opened desk drawer.</context>
      <utterance>Are you reading self help books again?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen reaches for the Kitty but Stephanie waves her off.</context>
      <utterance>Hello there!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie glances to her manager, MR. JACKS, a heavyset man sitting behind a large desk.</context>
      <utterance>--Shhhl I can't let my boss see him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you. No. Now beat it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh Oh. You better bring the kitty home for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. If I can take the shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jacks sneezes again, his eyes water. He turns to his</context>
      <utterance>I told you, no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jacks looks about the Bank, his twitching nose leading him toward Stephanie's desk.</context>
      <utterance>Has someone brought a damned animal into my bank?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, fine! Take the shoes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This catches Mr. Jack's Attention. He turns to the ladies, wondering what they're talking about. Stephanie takes Ellen's hand and vigorously shakes it goodbye.</context>
      <utterance>Just don't expect me to take care of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen plays along.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. I'll take care of everything. And thanks for choosing Bank of California.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ellen passes, Mr. Jacks sneezes again, harder.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He eyes Ellen suspiciously as she exits.</context>
      <utterance>Someone has definitely brought an animal in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see any cats. Or any animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hope to hell, not.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the way, I put the paperwork for the Mcpherson loan on your desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mcpherson?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That big corporate loan I've been trying to set up? It's just preliminary but--</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right. I'll look it over when I get the chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Jacks, I was wondering it you had made any decision regarding the Assistant Manager's position yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still deciding. Right now it's between Stu and yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie turns to see Stu, the balding loan officer who sits at his desk, watching, trying to figure out what Jacks is saying to her.</context>
      <utterance>Stu? The trainee?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know he's new but he's also quite aggressive and we like that. Don't get me wrong, you're well liked here, but we're also looking for someone who's not afraid to crunch the numbers and make the tough decisions.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Jacks, I feel that I'm perfectly capable of--</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--I'll let you know as soon as,I decide. In the meantime, take him through our loan qualifying procedures... just in case.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And would you mind taking your lunch now?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stu overhears them as he passes by.</context>
      <utterance>And on your way back, maybe you could bring me a turkey club?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then to Stephanie:</context>
      <utterance>Turkey club. Excellent choice, J.J.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind picking one up for me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jacks heads back toward his desk. Stephanie grabs her purse and keys and as she heads out, Stu calls after her:</context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie doesn't like fetching lunch for the trainee but hides her displeasure.</context>
      <utterance>On toasted rye! And spicy mustard!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The conscious mind abhors uncertainty. It seeks a pattern or reason for everything. When we can't find that pattern or reason, we sometimes ascribe it's cause to the world of the supernatural. The spiritual world is created by the human mind to conveniently explain everything we can't. So when does a belief in the supernatural cross into the field of abnormal behavior? Where do you, the Psychologist, come in? When these beliefs negatively affect our patients activities of daily living. Their jobs, their friends, their sense of well being-- The class bell RINGS.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow we'll be covering the clinical manifestations of psychosis. You'll find it all t referenced in the text.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How're things at the bank? How's that new position looking?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? You sounded so sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray sees how bummed out she is. He moves close, taking her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Well, now there's this new guy... they're considering him too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie nods.</context>
      <utterance>That job needs somebody with your experience. They know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rummages through her purse and hands Ray an envelope. He removes a coin. An old nickle.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I've got something for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where'd you get it?</context>
      <utterance>A 1925 Indian head! Hey, good find.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray puts the coin back into the envelope and tucks it into his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>One of the tellers found it for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She quickly gathers her things. Ray returns to grading his student's exams. The telephone RINGS. Ray hits the speakerphone.</context>
      <utterance>I'd better get back to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's the voice of an older woman, TRUDY.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Dalton.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY ON SPEAKERPHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns from the phone, whispering to Stephanie:</context>
      <utterance>Hi Mom, can you hold on a sec?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses Ray and exits.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call you tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>speakerphone. She moves closer to Ray's office to eavesdrop:</context>
      <utterance>Nothing much. Just had lunch with Stephanie. And trying to get these midterms graded-- She halts as she hears her name mentioned on Ray's</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Stephanie? The one from the farm?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know who she is. She's coming over for dinner tomorrow night to meet you and dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean she's just a teller at some bank right? Raymond there's a reason that your father and I raised you in a certain way. We have expectations.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, mom, not this again--</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard that Julie Kulick is looking for someone to play tennis with. You know she graduated Yale law with honors. I'm told she's quite a successful attorney now. I gave you her number but her mother says you never called.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm with Stephanie. I'm not looking for anybody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would it kill you to--</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A downhearted Stephanie quietly exits.</context>
      <utterance>--Mom. I have to go. See you tomorrow night. Okay? Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I didn't, Stu.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steph, I said "no mayo".</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie caught Stu's look, but what can she do? She exits.</context>
      <utterance>You never said that. Stu rolls his eyes to Mr. Jacks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you help me?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Ganush coughs up phlegm and spits it into a linen handkerchief, which she tucks back into her puree. She hands Stephanie a bunch of crumpled papers. Stephanie reviews them.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. What can I do for you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old woman nods.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. "Ganush"?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a delinquency notice... it says that the payment on your loan was due a number of months ago. And this other document... is a court order for repossession. The bank is informing you of their intent to repossess-your property at 325 Brandon street, tomorrow.,</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Ganush turns her head to reveal a milky white eye. Stephanie hides her revulsion.</context>
      <utterance>The trucks are there now. The men are packing all my things. Private things. Please, make them stop. This is my home for twenty years. And I make every payment until the sickness took my eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... do you have the payment with you now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope to get it soon. I just need a little more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think my manager is going to extend you anymore credit. I'd like to help but...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Won't you try?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie stands and moves off. The Old Woman picks through a bowl of hard candies on Stephanie's desk. Stephanie stands before Mr. Jacks. He acknowledges her without looking up from his work.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Wait here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie hands Mr. Jacks the loan file. He puts on his bifocals, studies it. Stephanie glances over her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I've got an elderly woman asking for an extension on her mortgage payment.. They're in the process of repossessing her home. She's on a fixed income and she's had some medical problems. I was wondering if we could give her a break.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her back the file.</context>
      <utterance>Apparently, we've already granted her two extensions. And you know on this type of foreclosure, the bank makes a sizable amount in fees.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would mean I'd have to throw her out of her house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans back in his overstuffed leather chair and studies her. Stephanie glances to the vacant office of the Assistant Manager. The large oak desk. The thick carpet. She sees a calculating Stu Rubin eyeing her from his workstation.</context>
      <utterance>Tough decision. Your call.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of it. Stephanie returns to her desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Ganush, another extension on the loan is out of the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Please, it's my home... I'm begging you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to talk my boss into it but he just wouldn't approve.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But where will I live?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Ganush, you've given your granddaughter as a reference... It says here, she lives nearby... Wouldn't you be better off living with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would not burden her.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay well, there's several fine "assisted living" facilities for the elderly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A nursing home? No. I will never live in one of those places1</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, of course, that's your choice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Ganush begins to sob.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry there's nothing I can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am proud woman, Miss Brown, and never have I begged for anything. But I will beg for you now. This one time. I humble myself before you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie takes the loan documents and places them neatly into a manila folder. she glances up but Mrs. Ganush is gone.. Stephanie turns in her chair and is startled to see the old woman, kneeling before her. She clutches Stephanie's leg with her gnarled hands.</context>
      <utterance>That isn't necessary, please. Let's not make this personal. It's just the bank's policy. I'm really sorry Mrs. Ganush.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie stands, tries to pull free, but the old woman will not release her leg.</context>
      <utterance>Have mercy on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Customers turn to look. Mr. Jacks glances up from his desk.</context>
      <utterance>Please, let go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, Sylvia Ganush, beg. On my mother's grave, I beg you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the old woman only clutches tighter.</context>
      <utterance>Please, take your hands off me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>t I'm calling security. She picks up the phone and presses a button.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Ganush finally releases her grip and bows her head in humiliation.</context>
      <utterance>Could you please come over?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She composes herself. Then, slowly stands, puffing up her chest. Mu3tering her damaged pride.</context>
      <utterance>You shame me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her one. good eye fixes it's hardened gaze upon Stephanie.</context>
      <utterance>I begged you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Ganush suddenly grasps Stephanie's arm. Stephanie tries to pull away but the old lady's grip is strong. Mrs. Ganush reaches out to pluck the charm bracelet from Stephanie's wrist-- but the Security Guard intervenes.</context>
      <utterance>.and you shame me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guard escorts Mrs. Ganush from the bank. Through the banks's window, Stephanie watches the Guard lead Mrs. Ganush to a old, Chevy Cavalier on the street. Stephanie composes herself and when she again looks up, the old woman's car is gone.</context>
      <utterance>I think your business here is finished, ma'am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie nods.</context>
      <utterance>That was one nutty old lady. You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You handled that just right. And by the way, as far as the Assistant Manager's position... You're at the top of the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jacks nods, heads for home. Stephanie loads a pile of contracts, a ruler and a desk stapler into a cardboard box and exits the bank. The Security guard locks up behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Woman reaches down. Stephanie flinches. Mrs.'Ganush's gnarled hand plucks a thin brass button from the sleeve of Stephanie's coat. She waves the button through the air, and breathes out a single word:</context>
      <utterance>You shamed me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clouds move past the setting Sun. A shadow falls over Stephanie. A cold wind makes her shiver.</context>
      <utterance>Lamia...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie sits up, reaching for her button. But the old woman 1 moves it out of reach.</context>
      <utterance>What--? What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie snatches the button back. Mrs. Ganush smiles cryptically as Stephanie stuffs the button into her coat pocket.</context>
      <utterance>You want it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon it will be you, who comes begging to me. It begins tonight when you hear the cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What cry?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A large black, BUZZING fly lands on Stephanie's face. She swats it away. Her vision blurs and she grows dizzy. She leans against the car for support. When she finally looks up, Mrs. Ganush is gone.</context>
      <utterance>The Lamia. It's coming for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about a restraining order?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER NAIMARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that's usually only something we do if there's a pattern of harassment. But like I said, we'll file a report and keep it on record in case you do have a continuing problem. But once we send an officer around to have a word with, her, I don't think she'll be bothering you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, you've been very helpful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just thank God you're okay. You are okay, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray waits, sensing that there's more to it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your fine, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-- It's just that I could have gotten her another extension. But I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loo]. You said the bank had already granted her two extensions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>23.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>RAY  When you don't pay your mortgage you lose your house, what did she t expect?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A breeze. She shivers. He wraps his arms around her protectively and after a moment, they walk on. Stephanie watches wistfully as a YOUNG COUPLE coo over their BABY. Behind the couple, Stephanie notices a neon sign in a storefront window. It reads: PSYCHIC.</context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get our fortune's read!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cajoles a protesting Ray through the front door of the establishment.</context>
      <utterance>You're kidding right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas, a small, dark skinned, fifty year old Indian man. He wears a plain black suit and a white turban. His inquisitive eyes evaluate the couple.</context>
      <utterance>I just hope to God none of my students see me here. Five bucks says he's wearing a turban. A beaded curtain parts, revealing...</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Rham Jas. Seer.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do? I'm Stephanie Brown and this is Ray...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas gives Ray a tight smile.</context>
      <utterance>But you probably already knew that. Just kidding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd like to have our fortunes read. Can you do that? Read the future?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have the ability to see certain energies... Sometimes these ' energies are a foretoken of things to come. Sometimes not. Sixty dollars, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty dollars? Isn't that a little steep for this kind of thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas turns to depart through the beaded curtain.</context>
      <utterance>Then go. There are many who would claim to be seers. But they are not. Although you would pay them little... you would receive nothing. If you.are not serious, go.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She removes some bills from her purse but Ray waves her off, handing Rham Jas a credit card.</context>
      <utterance>Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swipes Ray's card through the credit card machine. INT Rham Jas'S BACK ROOM - NIGHT A sparsely furnished, dimly lit room. The walls are lined with old books. Rham Jas stands before Stephanie and Ray, who sit at a card table. Stephanie giggles with excitement.</context>
      <utterance>Platinum card. Very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas smiles back.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas crosses to the window and closes the curtains.</context>
      <utterance>That's quite all right. So, you wish to know something of your destiny. Very good. We shall see what the fates have in store.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freud said destiny was not an act of fate but rather something created by our subconscious to control our conscious choices.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is true. But... "We should not pretend to understand the world only by intellect."</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carl Jung...</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. From his treatise "Psychological types".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jung-- the New Agers' favorite psychologist.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas takes a seat at the table, across from Stephanie.</context>
      <utterance>Because he wasn't afraid to bring God into the equation.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie extends her hand to Rham Jas. He closes his eyes and concentrates. Stephanie smiles excitedly to Ray, who raises a skeptical eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>Your hand, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You,work with money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right! 4</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... you've lost something.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, you're right. Something's been taken from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas grabs her arm and turns it, revealing the threads. that once held the button on her coat sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>No, I-</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A button.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes! Some Old Woman...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well anyone can see she lost a button. So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Ray, it was very strange. At the bank today. The old woman... the one I told you about... she plucked the button right from my sleeve.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would she do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jae concentrates, his eyelids flutter. Stephanie appears uneasy. The flame of the candle begins to flicker as a breeze sweeps through the room. The wind chimes TINKLE. Ray pulls his collar closed against the sudden chill in the air. Rham Jas's back stiffens.</context>
      <utterance>If you would please, both be quiet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that is enough for now.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. You saw something. What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I'm tired and I see it's become quite late. Of course I will refund your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas hesitates, then...</context>
      <utterance>Tell me. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bad spirit has come upon you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you blaspheme the dead while visiting a grave site?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you play with Ouija board or confer with those who practice the black arts?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then perhaps someone has cursed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who? 0</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did he know all that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what? That you lost,a button?1 He makes some good guesses, stirs you up, leaving you with a lot of questions. And conveniently, his business card. C'mon, he's a scam artist.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't want the money. He tried to give the money back.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the end, he took it, didn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this is him. Got a name?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... just "Kitty" so far.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you don't want me to spend the night?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tempt me. I've got to prep a presentation for the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray kisses her, opens the front door and exits. He calls back to her from his car:</context>
      <utterance>okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, dinner at my folk's house, tomorrow night. We're supposed to bring desert. I could pick something up?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm planning on baking my special cake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't he adorable?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sets down,the kitten and picks up her overnight bag. 0</context>
      <utterance>Let's hope the landlord thinks so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you? You going to be okay? You know, I don't have to go out tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm fine. Have a good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I look great? Be honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen smiles, grabs her car keys and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>You look great.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... Isn't that Marci's dress?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie places butter into a mixer for the cake frosting. Through the kitchen window we can see Ellen walking down the path, toward the street. She steps through the iron gate, latching it closed behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And if she calls, tell her not to go bi-polar on me, I'll'get it back to her by tomorrow. Or the next day. Bye! Ellen exits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to dial but Stephanie stops him.</context>
      <utterance>So she came to your house? This is crazy. I'm calling that police officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray, you're not listening. It wasn't her. It was something that she sicked on me...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't tell you the whole story. That old woman... after she knocked me down, and pulled the button from my coat, she told me that...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stares at her with concern.</context>
      <utterance>She said that something was coming for me... and it did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOCTOR RANGAVERTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray, you were right to call me. Never a good idea to be personally involved with your patient.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOCTOR RANGAVERTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doctor Rangavertz scribbles out a prescription and hands it to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>1b Medically, she's fine. She's just very distraught. She's displaying some paranoia and a sense of panic. Classic symptoms of a post traumatic stress disorder. Probably a result of being assaulted by that old woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How worried should I be?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR RANGAVERTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll have to wait and see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better now. At the time it just seemed so real. I'm so embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be, you had a terrible day and you.got a little wigged out. It happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>po, what now, Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was gonna surprise you, but what the hell. I've been planning a little trip for us this week end. Saturday morning we're taking a train to Santa Barbara.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My family owns a cabin up there. In, the hills. Overlooking this little river. We'll light a fire, drink some champagne and screw our brains out.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure know how to talk to a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a chance to just be together. Undisturbed. There's a lot of stuff I want to talk to you abqut but it never seems to be the right time.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She draws in a deep breath and for the first time that evening, she looks at peace. Ray watches, her as she closes her eyes and drifts off to sleep.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shamed mel MATCH CUT to: Ray SHAKING her!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steph! Wake Upl</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God: Oh Godl</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets control. Ray smooths out the tangled hair from her sweaty face. He looks deeply into her eyes, afraid of what's happening to her. The phone in the next room, RINGS.'Ray looks over, decides to ignore it. It keeps RINGING.</context>
      <utterance>It was just a dream. It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps into the next room and we hear him answer the phone. Stephanie sighs and lays back down... next to Mrs. Ganush! The Old Woman is covered in.a swarm of BLACK FLIES! Stephanie</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No-- Oh my God. I had some 4 dreams. Awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to tell me about them?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie shakes her head. She can't finish. Ray pulls back the drapes. Sunlight pours into the room. Stephanie tries to put the dream out of her mind. Ray sits next to her, strokes her hair.</context>
      <utterance>The old lady. She was here... I couldn't wake up.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie nods.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Rangervertz said you could stop by his office during your lunch hour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STU RUBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Steph. Just getting here?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you, the hall monitor?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU RUBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha ha! You're funny, Steph.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU RUBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to finish teaching me the loan procedures.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a lot on my mind. Let's do it tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU RUBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances up. Mr. Jacks'is still watching her.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. I'll just tell Mr. Jacks that you don't have the time right now. Maybe he can show me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, that's all right. I'll do it. Where were we?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU RUBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were going over the asset-based lending guidelines.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Okay. Let's say your client is a company that can't get traditional bank financing but 10 needs a secured loan. We offer--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.uh, we offer several types of asset-based lending which consist of revolving lines of credit and term loans secured by accounts receivables, their inventory, machinery-- ,</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRATCH... SCRATCH...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That Stu's hand has been replaced by MRS. GANUSH'S... it's yellowed fingernails SCRATCH across her desk. She looks again, and Stu's hand has returned to normal.</context>
      <utterance>Stephanie sees...</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>---and?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stu is taken aback by Stephanie's outburst. He retreats to his desk in confusion. Stephanie sits, rattled. A drop of blood falls onto a piece of paper on her desk. The blood is trickling from her nose. Stephanie grabs a tissue to halt the bleeding. She looks down to see a large black fly land upon the drop of blood. She gasps and stands, her mind racing. She knows what she must do. She finds Mrs. Ganush's loan documents. She stuffs them into a folder, grabs her purse and bolts for the exit. Mr. Jacks engaged with a customer, calls after her:</context>
      <utterance>--And get your filthy pig knuckle off my desk!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves quickly out the door, pretending not to hear him.</context>
      <utterance>Stephanie? Where are you going?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm here because I think I can help you. I can get your house back for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so empty now.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE .</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs Ganush does not look up from the photograph.</context>
      <utterance>I can arrange for all your furniture to be brought back. Would that be okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... on behalf of the bank I just want to resolve this to your satisfaction. This whole thing got personal and there was really no reason for that. The bank made a mistake and I can fix it for you and in return I'd like you to- cancel or call off, whatever you... you know-- that thing you did to me. Okay? No hard feelings. So...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie nods. Waits an appropriate moment, then: places the document gently down on the floor next to Mrs. Ganush.</context>
      <utterance>My mother was a proud woman. Dignity. That's what she had.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie offers her a pen.</context>
      <utterance>All you need to do is. sign here...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Ganush's hard eyes find Stephanie's. They bore in.</context>
      <utterance>.and I'll take care of the rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? But... I'm saying I'll make things right. Just sign this and you can keep the house. Isn't that what you wanted?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was what I wanted before you shamed me. Now I want to see you suffer.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please! I've suffered enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Ganush suddenly erupts in a broken toothed CACKLE.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're insane! Just... just a crazy old woman! I don't even know why I came here!</utterance>
   <speaker>1 MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terrified, Stephanie runs from the place.</context>
      <utterance>You know why.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men warmly escort into the First National Bank.</context>
      <utterance>Stu?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car behind her HONKS! She drives on.</context>
      <utterance>What's he doing at First National?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did it sound like.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. Closes the book.</context>
      <utterance>Like... shrieking. It was awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be the Lamia. The "Black Goat".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lamia. Right. That's the word the old woman used.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a nasty spirit. A taker of souls. A creature of misfortune for you and those around you. It is often summoned by the Gypsies for their dour deeds. On the third day the Lamia comes for the owner of the accursed object.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Accursed object? What object?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now it dawns on Stephanie. She looks to the threads on her coat.</context>
      <utterance>Something that the old woman took from you, cursed, then gave back.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The button...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds the button up for him to inspect. But it's presence makes him uneasy..He wags his finger back and forth. She lowers it.</context>
      <utterance>.this?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if I just burn the thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No matter what condition the button is in, you would still be the owner. The Lamia would still come to take you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take me where?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's got to be something I can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas produces a modern book on animal sacrifice which he sets before her.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. There are many ways to appease a spirit. The simplest is a blood offering. An animal sacrifice. A small creature would do. You could sacrifice a chicken. It's all in here...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't go around killing animals.</context>
      <utterance>No way. I'm a vegetarian. I'm a member of PETA, for Christ's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She considers his words, looks down to the book. CLOSE ON A DIAGRAM OF AN ANIMAL SACRIFICE - A creature's heart being cut from it's body. CAMERA pulls back to reveal that Stephanie now site at her kitchen table, reading the book. We see other diagrams: The heart being placed into a skillet over an open fire. The burial of the smoking heart. Stephanie's kitten PURRS, as it rubs against her leg. Stephanie closes the book, shutting out the disturbing images. She hears the SHRIEK of the rusty gate outside. She moves to the window and peers out. The rusting iron gate is open. Stephanie senses a change in the room... Shadows shift and grow deeper. The air is suddenly oppressive. Something is coming.</context>
      <utterance>You will be surprised what you will be willing to do when the Lamia comes for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie puts her,ear to the door. The sound of an animal's hooves on wood. Something is climbing the stairs. It stops outside her bedroom door. Stephanie holds her breath, listening. She sees a shadow beneath the crack in the door.</context>
      <utterance>Ellen? ! But it's not Ellen.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The window behind her explodes into the room with a deafening</context>
      <utterance>I know that you're there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE'S BACKYARD GARDEN AFTERNOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns on the garden hose, washing the cat's blood from the knife.</context>
      <utterance>She buries the heart in a corner of her garden.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie quickly tosses the knife into the bushes. Ellen appears.</context>
      <utterance>Steph?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>t Didn't you hear me calling? I was looking all over for you. Are you power eating Clark bars again? 'Cause there's about ten thousand wrappers all over the-- Oh my God, is that blood?1 Stephanie glances guiltily to the corner of the garden. But no blood shows.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Why would there be blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie glances at the red spot on her sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>Right there, on your sleeve.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen gives her roommate a worried look.</context>
      <utterance>That's just tomato juice. I was inside making a salad and... I cut a tomato and I must have gotten it on my sleeve.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Steph, we're friends so if something's wrong...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen isn't so sure.</context>
      <utterance>I had some problems. A situation. But I think everything is going to be good now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go with the short skirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hold up a longer, more formal dress.</context>
      <utterance>What about this one?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh uh. That one's saying "I'm trying to impress you with my conservative taste."</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen shakes her head, no. Stephanie takes a last look in the mirror, decides to go with the short skirt.</context>
      <utterance>But that's what I want it to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. This is it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me again... the exact words he used.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just that this little cabin would be a great place for us to really connect and that there was something he'd been meaning to talk about with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen's smile fades. She shakes her head despondently.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my god, you are so engaged!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong? I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>t I just know that Rob's never going to ask me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I thought you said that relationship was only physical.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'd never marry a guy like that... but I'd still like him to ask me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps from the car and models the dress. S</context>
      <utterance>Let's get a look at that dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just that I'm not, some ivy leaguer with an impressive resume. I have a feeling that's what your folks really want.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. But in the end, it's about what you and I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gives her a reassuring nod. The front door opens revealing Ray's parents, GEORGE AND TRUDY DALTON. Behind them we glimpse an exquisitely furnished foyer.</context>
      <utterance>Is that so?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RAYMONDL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She kisses her son.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trudy glances at Stephanie's revealing cocktail dress with thinly veiled disapproval. Stephanie self-consciously tugs it lower.</context>
      <utterance>Stephanie, this is my mother, Trudy, and my Father, George.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice tp meet you, Stephanie.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very nice to meet you, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a lovely home.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As George exits, Stephanie presents her home made cake to Trudy.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I'll get us something to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trudy hesitates, then takes the cake from Stephanie.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't mind. I baked something for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's lovely. Homemade.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a harvest cake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvest cake? Is'that some kind of cake you make on a... farm?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mother forces a smile.</context>
      <utterance>We used to, yeah, when you have a lot of extra duck eggs. Especially right before spring; that's when you get a real dense yolk. Makes for, rich cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must give me the recipe sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. It's easy. The real secret's in the milk. You want it unpasteurized.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unclean... Uh... I mean "unpasteurized"? Is that safe?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trudy has to stifle her gag reflex. George returns and hands Ray and Stephanie a cocktail.</context>
      <utterance>Uh huh. And you want that milk still warm. Straight from the cow.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Trudy takes away the cake, a cat rounds the corner. It HISSES at Stephanie. She takes a step back.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me while I go find someplace to put this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trudy returns from the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Never could understand that damned animal. Hate cats.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's strange. Hecuba's usually very sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. I had a cat. I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean "had a cat"? What happened to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray nods slowly. About to say something but let's it go.</context>
      <utterance>How would I know what happened? Probably nothing. You know how cats are. They come and they go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still keeping up with your coin collection, Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I try to. In fact Stephanie just found me a 1925 Indian Head nickel at her bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? So, how long have you been working there, Stephanie?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost two years now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The job of a bank teller must be so difficult. I'd think with all the counting and the repetition, it'd become so tedious.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you're right. But I'm not a teller.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stephanie's a loan officer in charge of small business and home loans. And she's on a fast track for a promotion. Right, Steph?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to think so... actually, It depends. If I could close this big account that I'm working on, it would really help.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be a very important loan.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would be the biggest that my branch has ever handled.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How''d it come to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure sound like you've got a lot going for you, Stephanie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mother must be very proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose. I don't see her much.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an awkward silence.</context>
      <utterance>Well, ever since my dad died she doesn't talk much. She mostly stays on the farm and... keeps to herself. Because...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does your mother have a drinking problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut her some slack, mom, she--</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I'm afraid she does.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. It's nothing to be ashamed of. And I find your honesty refreshing.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>stage whisper to</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE)</speaker>
      <mode> STEPHANIE)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He found her through the,internet.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mors, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie, happy to be taken into the family circle, winks at Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Stephanie, am I being too tough on Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not at all. That's what mom's are for.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trudy cuts herself a piece. Stephanie tastes the cake and emits a tiny cough.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Stephanie. Maybe I will try that Harvest cake of yours, after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She clears her throat. But the cough returns, grows larger.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands and takes a few steps away from the table. Ray looks on concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Just a little tickle in my--</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fly lazily BUZZES across the table, slowly circling Trudy's head. Trudy spits out a mouthful of harvest cake into her napkin. George lowers his fork and pushes away his plate of unclean farm cake. Ray is baffled, too stunned to speak. Stephanie's gaze shifts to the kitchen door. From The other side, she hears the sound of a hoofs. Ray tries to cover for Stephanie:</context>
      <utterance>Oh! OH MY GOD!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry, Stephanie. I don't know how that fly got. into your--</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Wait. What's that sound?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What sound-?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trudy listens along with the others. They can't hear anything. But Stephanie hears the FOOTSTEPS drawing closer.</context>
      <utterance>SHHH! Listen!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I can't hear anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Trudy heard that and takes offense. But before she can say anything, a SHADOW appears at the base of the door. Stephanie stands and shouts at it:</context>
      <utterance>Must be deafer than a post!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie grabs her dinner plate and hurls it just past Trudy's head. It shatters against the base of the door, spraying everyone with bits of broken china and fish. The shadow and FOOTSTEPS are gone. Ray rushes to her side.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone! Just leave me the fuck alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks about. George and Trudy regard Stephanie as if she were mad.</context>
      <utterance>Steph, it's okay! There's nothing there.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I think I'd better go.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads for the door. Ray starts to go after her but his</context>
      <utterance>I think that's best, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>mother stops him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let her go, Ray. She's a sick girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trudy grabs Ray's arm.</context>
      <utterance>She needs me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gently pulls free of his mother's grasp and chases after Stephanie.</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you not to go after her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray pulls her close.</context>
      <utterance>You don't want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What the old woman sent.</context>
      <utterance>The thing that's coming for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me. What you're going through right now-- It's like the doctor said, it's a stress reaction and --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray just stares at her. A long moment passes as he wonders if maybe she isn't right.</context>
      <utterance>No. I wanted to believe that-- but it's real, Ray. You just don't want to open your eyes to it because it threatens you. Because if I'm right and there is something out there, then you'd have to throw out everything you teach. And where'd that leave you? Like a plow without a mule.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps into the car and drives off. Ray watches her tail lights, as they vanish into the night.</context>
      <utterance>Unless you're willing to take a chance and believe in me, I can't be with you any more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VOICE OF THE EYE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens wider, revealing a sexy twenty-four year old Gypsy girl. ILENKA GANUSH. Bottle of beer in her hand, long black hair, earrings and a snake tatoo on'her neck. She wears a low cut shirt and tight shorts. EASTERN EUROPEAN HIP HOP and LAUGHTER are heard from within the house.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. Yes. I came to see Sylvia Ganush. Is she here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ILENKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Who are you?</context>
      <utterance>I'm Ilenka, Sylvia's granddaughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stephanie Brown. I'm... sort of... a friend of hers. Actually, I've been trying to help her with a loan</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ILENKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. I know who you are. Grandma told me you'd come. You're the woman from the bank. The one who took her house.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ilenka knows she's lying. Stephanie knows that she knows.</context>
      <utterance>It was really the bank that took the house. I just work there. In fact, I tried to help your grandma get-the house back, but my boss wouldn't let me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILENKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what happened, is it? Are you going to stand here on my porch and lie to my face?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>. no.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILENKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You used to be a real fat girl, to didn't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILENKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to close the door. Stephanie halts her. Desperate now, no where else to turn.</context>
      <utterance>I can tell. You know, you caused my grandma a lot of pain. That house was her pride. When you took that from her, she had nothing left. You're not welcome here.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay! I did it. It was me who denied her the loan. I was trying, to get ahead at work and I shouldn't have done it. It was wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILENKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn straight it was wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm ashamed about it. And I'm going to get down on my hands and knees and beg her to forgive me. She said-that I hadn't suffered enough. But now I think she'll see that I have and then maybe she'll let me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ILENKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.make everything all right for her, is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ilenka gives a bitter, cryptic smile. She motions for Stephanie to follow. They enter a room filled with young Gypsies drinking, smoking and talking loudly in a Slavic tongue. A WOMAN WITH A CANE shouts as she throws a pair of dice. A Hungarian man with a long, braided ponytail, curses his bad luck as he pays cash to the woman.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>' STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ILENKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mourners replace the corpse atop the coffee table. Ilenka addresses the crowd in Hungarian. She tells them that it was this white trash farm girl that threw her grandmother t from her home and that she now bears the curse of Lamia. A mother shields her daughter's eyes from the sight of Stephanie, the cursed one, then hurriedly kisses her .crucifix. A man spits at her feet then walks off.</context>
      <utterance>Still going to make everything all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, please-- I needed her to take this thing off me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILENKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will never come off.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know about it? Then, please help me. I'm begging you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILENKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blood drains from Stephanie's face.</context>
      <utterance>She said you'd come begging. I only wish she could have lived to see it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck that! I paid you a hundred and seventy nine dollars for that book!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a limited printing! Please control yourself!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lotta good that did me.</context>
      <utterance>I did what you said- that blood offering... I killed that little kitty deader than Hogan's goat.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wants to shout, but instead, closes her eyes and sits.</context>
      <utterance>We are dealing with elusive and powerful forces. There are no guarantees.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas considers. A dark look crosses his face. Stephanie tries to read his expression.</context>
      <utterance>Just tell me what to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must somehow dissuade the spirit from taking your soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1 A seance. And it should be soon. For tomorrow will be the third night...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you done this before?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But I know someone. I can arrange what is necessary, but you must understand that everyone involved in this would be taking a great risk with their lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas thinks for a moment, weighing the dangers. He pulls out a pipe and packs it with tobacco. He tamps it down and lights up.</context>
      <utterance>What would you need from me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty thousand dollars. Cash. By tomorrow. 5</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts stuffing the valuables into a large duffle bag.</context>
      <utterance>Ellen. I'm sorry. This a bad time right now. I got a little emergency and... say you got any cash I can borrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't. But Steph I--</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's your cash advance limit?</context>
      <utterance>--what about your credit cards?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>64.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>STEPHANIE  I'll pay you back. You know I'm good for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steph, we need to talk about the cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where has that little rascal been? He's always running off, have you noticed that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stephanie. I was in the back yard and I saw where the ground was dug up. I started digging and... You buried that little kitty in our backyard. What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to tell you. It fell out the window and died. It's sad,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found the bloody knife in the bushes.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you, a cat detective?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steph? I'm going to tell you this as your friend. There is something seriously wrong with you. Stephanie looks up from,her frantic panting.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... Duhi</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm moving out. I can't live like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen exits. Stephanie angrily calls after her:</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' don't let the barn door hit you on your ass on yer way out!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get the twenty thousand. You're gonna have to help me with what I've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She covers the mouthpiece, speaking to someone off camera.</context>
      <utterance>What do you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PULLS BACK to reveal that we are'in a PAWN SHOP. Men haggle loudly in Arabic over the price of a gold chain. The PAWN BROKER stands before-all of Stephanie's worldly belongings: A toaster oven, computer, racing bike, stereo, microwave oven, necklaces, jewelry...</context>
      <utterance>How much?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAWN BROKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-eight hundred for everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Including my jewlery?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAWN BROKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie curses under her breath, checks the balance on her checkbook, does the math, speaks into the phone;</context>
      <utterance>Including.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Not possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'll give you six now and--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up. The line goes dead. She tries to throw the phone but it's attached with a short metal cord. She turns to the Pawn Broker.</context>
      <utterance>No. There will be others involved and I cannot-ask them to accept such a risk for less. Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie thinks about how she'll get the extra cash. She hesitantly dials a number on the pay phone. It rings and rings as she glances to a picture buried deep in her wallet: A. photo of... The younger, obese Stephanie and her stern looking Mother. Both stand before a bleak snow covered, mid-western farm.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The line goes dead. She slumps down against the pay phone.</context>
      <utterance>Mom? Hi, it's me. Did you get,the Christmas card? Yeah, I guess it has been a while. Listen, I'm in kind of a fix, here. I've been pretty sick and I need to borrow some money for an operation. I need fourteen thousand dollars right away. Now I know you still have that pension fund at the credit Union so-- yeah, but... okay. Okay, it's just that--- I understand. Okay, mom. Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Jacks, this is kind of awkward for me... I know it's not official yet, but I was wondering if I could get a copy of the employment contract for the new position you offered me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The assistant manager's position?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. See, one of my family members is having a little emergency which requires me to get them an immediate loan--</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Stephanie... There's a problem. The McPherson deal was cancelled last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? 1</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JACKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie is devastated.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right after I informed the main branch that we had this big loan pending,,I find out that they just made their deal over at First National. I got a call in to see, what exactly happened but right now this doesn't look too good for you or me. So this assistant manager promotion has been delayed. In fact, I think that with everything that's been happening, I'm gonna have to give that job to Stu.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jacks sees tears begin to well up in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Stu. I see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAY.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I paid Rham Jas</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I thought you didn't believe...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>she embraces him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't. But you do. I know this is important for, you .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to but Rham Jas said non believers weren't welcome. I still don't like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. She kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>I know how crazy this must seem. But it will all be over after this I swear to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call you when it's done.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll laugh about it on the train, tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie steps from the car. Ray drives off. She turns to face the old house.</context>
      <utterance>t Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A woman rises from the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Brown. Allow me the pleasure of an introduction...</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The eighty year old woman smiles a toothless smile to Stephanie.</context>
      <utterance>.Shaun San Dena</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shaun San Dena is an experienced 41 medium. Furthermore, she has a personal knowledge of the Lamia.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I first encountered this spirit forty years ago in a small village outside of Bucharest.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHUAN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost a young boy's soul to the beast.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's reassuring.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was an. inexperienced seer then. I've learned much since that woeful day. I have waited these long years for a chance at redeeming myself. A chance to destroy the foul thing. Tonight my chance will come. But to summon it, I will need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do whatever it takes. And the sooner the better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our business must wait till darkness falls. Enough time for tea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>71.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SHAUN SAN DENA  He knew I would sense his spirit in this place as I have sensed others. It was to be our way of being together after he died. In earlier times it was a sacred place to the Tuanteteck indians. And their stories told that the place was a burial ground of the "old ones" that inhabited the earth before them. Here, there is a particular alignment of energies. A confluence, that allows doorways to be opened. Through which, we might pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS '</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milos removes the tea.</context>
      <utterance>And through which, others might pass into our world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shaun San Dena turns out the electric lights, leaving only the tables' candlelight for illumination. We hear the BLEATING of a goat. Stephanie startles. Milos reenters the room pulling a black goat along by a chain. The goat catches sight of Stephanie. It BLEATS in fear and attempts to run. But Milos holds it fast and tethers it to a post. He moves to the table and lifts a velvet cloth revealing a large cattle slaughtering blade.</context>
      <utterance>It is time for us to begin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She makes the sign of the cross. she pours a .vial of holy water over the blade. She turns to Stephanie.</context>
      <utterance>Lord Jesus bless this knife and allow it to do your holy work.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once the spirit has entered me, place my hand upon the animal. Do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie blanches but remains silent.</context>
      <utterance>I will force the spirit of the Lamia into the goat. Milos, that's when you strike.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shaun San Dena begins to intone a Romanian Gypsy chant. Stephanie leans close to speak quietly with Rham Jae.</context>
      <utterance>We must all.be receptive.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I have to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must allow the darkness in. You must invite the dead to co-mingle with your spirit..</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jae waits for Stephanie's response. She's shifts in her seat uncomfortably.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Now repeat these words... I welcome the dead into my soul...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I welcome the dead into my soul...</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie takes a deep breath and they begin the chant again. This time,, together.</context>
      <utterance>You must believe it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sense something here with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The parlor's crystal chandeleir tinkles. A tea cup and saucer tremble for a moment. Stephanie's eyes search the room.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMETHING UNSEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear FOOTSTEPS as something walks on the ceiling above them.</context>
      <utterance>emits a wheezing breath...</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN'S LOUD LAUGHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>echoes about the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is not the Lamia. It is the spirit of some unsettled soul from</utterance>
   <speaker>1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>years ago... The unsettled ones wait near the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a HOWLING OF WIND and the room is again quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Be gone, foolish spirit!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quiet. Stephanie looks about. Nothing seems to be happening.</context>
      <utterance>Show yourself Lamia. We invite you into our circle.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's coming...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who now inhabits the body of Shaun San Dena?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas nods discreetly to Milos who quietly uncovers the slaughtering blade.</context>
      <utterance>Lamia...</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shaun San Dena's chair abruptly spins about to face Stephanie. The mouth jerks opened and closed as if controlled by a bad puppeteer. Then, out of.sync, the demonic voice is</context>
      <utterance>Lamia, what is it that you desire?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was my manager, Jim Jacks. He was the one ! He--</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The possessed Shaun San Dena laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Silence! Lamia, please, surely we can dissuade you from taking this insignificant woman? Surely she's not worthy of your greatness.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! You--</utterance>
   <speaker>GOAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The possessed goat emits a terrible cry! The bone chilling SHRIEK of Lamia! It's oval eye reflects the blade as it descends toward it. The possessed Goat jerks aside and the blade misses, slicing into the chair. As Milos raises the blade for another blow, the goat bites his hand. In that moment, the spirit of the Lamia is transferred to him. A Possessed Milos SCREAMS and spins toward Stephanie, glaring at her with black goat eyes. He SHOUTS at her in a gibberish of tongues! His body jerks up into the air. He dances a jig atop the table, now laughing uncontrollably. t</context>
      <utterance>--tricked me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>76.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stephanie watches in horror.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A chair sails through the air and shatters across Rham Jas' back, knocking him to the ground. Milos' body is hurled up against the chandelier, shattering it. Glass rains down upon Stephanie. on the ceiling, Milos is spun.about like a pin wheel. Stephanie races for the door but a .huge bureau lurches in front of her, blocking her path. Rham Jas rouses a stunned Shaun San Dena.</context>
      <utterance>Lamial I command you to leave this--</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shaun San Dena places her hands on her ayes, then over her heart and chants an ancient Gypsy incantation up toward Milos. Milos SHRIEKS. A white vapor streams from his body as the Lamia is torn from him.</context>
      <utterance>You must banish the spirit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Shaun San Dena only chants louder. Milos SCREAMS grow more intense as-his body spasms in pain. Stephanie grasps at Shaun San Dena.</context>
      <utterance>Stop the chanting. I beg you!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas pushes her aside.</context>
      <utterance>For god's sake, stop the chanting, it's killing him!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A withered pair of hands reach down from above and clutch at Stephanie's face! It is Mrs. Ganush that now floats above her! Her long yellowed fingernails scratching at Stephanie's skin.</context>
      <utterance>You must not stop!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MILOS/MRS. GANUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make her stop, you dirty pork queen!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Ganush grabs at Stephanie's head. Stephanie pulls away but it costs her a clump of hair that Mrs. Ganush rips from her head. Mrs. Ganush opens her mouth... wide... wider still... she vomits out Stephanie's dead cat. It lands atop the table. Stephanie screams uncontrollably. Shaun San Dena, is trembling as her chanting comes to a climax. Mrs. Ganush changes back to the possessed Milo. The last of the white vapor is torn from Milos body as the spirit of the Lamia leaves him. Milos falls to the floor and all is quiet. An ashen faced Shaun San Dena halts her chant.</context>
      <utterance>No! Get her off!</utterance>
   <speaker>10 STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie notices that the cat has vanished. Was it ever there? Rham Jae kneels at Milos' side. He's starting to come around. Milos stands, shaken. The Lamia is gone. Shaun San Dena grabs at her chest, struggles for breath. Stephanie rushes over to steady her.</context>
      <utterance>Is it gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me help you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAUN SAN DENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shaun San Dena collapses into Stephanie's arms. Rham Jas moves to assist her. They lower Shaun San Dana to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>My heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Milos, call an ambulance!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas attempts to administer CPR to no avail.</context>
      <utterance>She's not breathing.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He checks her pulse one last time. The CPR is finally halted. Rham Jas closes her eyes, then touches her forehead, praying:</context>
      <utterance>My God. My God...</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gata, gata, para gata... bodhi suaha. Gone, gone, gone beyond. Gone beyond the beyond. Hail the goer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's sad:</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strange how things work out. She waited years for another chance to overcome the lamia ..and finally she did.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas looks at her with pity.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm afraid you misunderstand.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The,Lamia can not'be banished by a medium. This was our lesson tonight. I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>0</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I saw her get rid of the thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You saw her drive the Lamia from the seance. That is all. It will be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas shrugs. He fishes in his pocket for his car keys.</context>
      <utterance>But then, what am I supposed to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps on this final evening, you should finish up the business of this world. For before the night is through, the Lamia will come for the owner of the accursed object.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless, of course... you were no longer the owner.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rham Jas reaches into his coat pocket and removes a blank envelope. He places the button within and seals it.</context>
      <utterance>No longer the owner? I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To demonstrate, he hands the envelope to Stephanie.</context>
      <utterance>The Lamia comes for the owner of the accursed object. Just make a gift of it...</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.and you've given away the curse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me this before?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie looks from the envelope containing the button to Rham Jas. She places the envelope carefully into the side 'pocket of her purse. Rham Jas tries to conceal the sadness and fear he feels for her.</context>
      <utterance>Because we are speaking of murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods goodbye as Ray's car pulls up. Ray opens the door. for her and she gets in.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you decide, you have until sunrise.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie, stares at her envelope, thinks about telling him, then...</context>
      <utterance>Is it over?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray squeezes her hand. Appreciating the two of them now more than ever. Stephanie SCREAMS as... MRS. GANUSH.appears in the headlights, standing on the road before them! Ray hits the breaks. The car SCREECHES to a halt! Stephanie's purse with the envelope and.some of Ray's papers fall to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's all over.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie nods, catching her breath.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>R</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie looks to the figure in the road. Mrs. Ganush is gone. In her place is an old man who mutters angrily at them and moves on.</context>
      <utterance>That guy came out of nowhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you'still okay about the Santa Barbara trip?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, everything's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Our train leaves tomorrow morning. Seven A.M. When do you want me to pick you up?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie suddenly' clutches at her purse. The envelope is gone!</context>
      <utterance>It's better if we meet at the D station. There's something I've got to do on the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! Where's my envelope?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the car door and frantically rummages around the floor, through Ray's papers.</context>
      <utterance>What envelope?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, Stephanie comes upon something under the seat. She smiles and stands. A white envelope held tightly in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>It's got to be here!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got , it .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OLD MAN 0</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She extends the envelope to him. He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>I just need you to hang on to this envelope for me. Just until tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Man considers. He reaches for the envelope when an OLD WOMAN, his wife, hobbles toward the table. The Old Man helps her sit and puts away her cane. They turn to Stephanie who withdraws the envelope.</context>
      <utterance>Just take the envelope and I'll explain. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie returns to her seat, ashamed at what she almost did. She returns the envelope to the purse pocket, racking her brains, trying to think of some way out of this. Her gaze lands upon a stack of newspapers on the next table. She grabs the paper and finds the OBITUARIES.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>84.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He closes the book and gives it some thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are Gypsy blessings that are bestowed upon the dead... And the Gypsies give gifts to their departed to curry favor with the deceased soul. Yes. I do believe you could give the curse to someone who has passed on... for truly, the soul never dies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.but you must make a formal gift of the cursed object to the deceased.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Car headlights sweep over her grim face. She fingers the envelope, then glances to the seat next to her... a SHOVEL.</context>
      <utterance>Formal gift... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHAM JAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it to the corpse personally. Put it in their hand... their' pocket...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>CAMERA moves in tight.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll do better than that...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She zips up her raincoat. SOMETHING flits past the window. Too.quick to.see. Then it reappears. It's Mrs. Ganush's hankie. It.flies against Stephanie's windshield and gets caught on the wiper blade. Stephanie GASPS. It flaps in the wind, blocking her view. Stephanie hits the wiper button. The hankie is yanked-back and forth across the windshield.</context>
      <utterance>.I'll shove it down her goddamn throat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up the shovel and jams the blade into the old woman's mouth, wedging it between her teeth. She pries the jaw open. Mud and rivulets of water begin pouring down into the grave from all sides. The body of Mrs. Ganush is quickly being re-buried.</context>
      <utterance>You'll take it, all right...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She jams the white envelope down the old woman's throat.</context>
      <utterance>I, Stephanie Brown, do hereby make a formal gift of this button to you, Sylvia Ganush.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kicks the old woman's jaw.. It SNAPS shut, trapping the envelope between her broken teeth. Muddy water cascades down into the grave, flowing over Mrs.. Ganush's face. It covers everything, except the jutting envelope and a single, staring white eye. Stephanie tries to climb out but the walls are too slick. She grabs at a clump of sod at the top of the hole but it tears away, unleashing an avalanche of mud that buries her up to her armpits.</context>
      <utterance>Choke on it, bitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>89.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>t</context>
      <utterance>The Saleswoman opens the door a crack.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESWOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, we're not open yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Saleswoman considers.</context>
      <utterance>Please. I know what I want. That coat in the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie's smile is bright. Her joy is contagious. The Saleswoman relents and lets Stephanie in.</context>
      <utterance>My boyfriend and I are taking a very special trip this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray embraces her and grabs her luggage. A TRAIN WHISTLE sounds as the train approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Ray!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everything okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>0 She takes his hand. 0</context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad you're here. There's so much I've been meaning to tell you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share an intimate moment. A romantic kiss. He breaks off and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>But let me say this first while I have it straight in my head. You never stopped believing in me. I'll try and live up to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I tell you, you look great?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie models her new coat.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like it? It's brand new.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just the mention of it, makes her face darken.</context>
      <utterance>What'd you do with your old coat?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got rid of it. I never want to see it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray produces the envelope. And from it, withdraws... THE</context>
      <utterance>Too bad,'cause I just found this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She backs away in horror, but Ray follows her with the button still in his hand. The RUMBLING grows louder. She's backing up toward the edge of the platform.</context>
      <utterance>What? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray steps forward, still holding out the button. Stephanie SHRIEKS as she falls backwards, off the platform and onto the tracks. In her last moment of life, she turns her head to see...</context>
      <utterance>Stephanie. Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ONCOMING TRAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the swirling smoke, the engine's mechanical face, resembles the goat like face of the demon Lamia. It VOMITS STEAM as it angrily bares down upon her.</context>
      <utterance>Racing at her!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
