<movie id="178" title="Dragonslayer">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing happens.</context>
      <utterance>Omnia in duos: Duo in Unum: Unus in Nihil: Haec nec Quattuor nec Omnia nec Duo nec Unus nec Nihil Sunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the little flames stand at attention without so much as a tremble.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, candles, out!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's no use. There is a sigh and the figure moves forward into the light. Revealed in the glow is the discouraged face of Galen Bradwardyn, sorcerer's apprentice.</context>
      <utterance>In Volunta Divina et Verbum Magi: Lux! Exstinguat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ulrich, startled from his trance, slaps the water out of the basin and turns to confront his student. Galen is taken aback by the old man's grim countenance.</context>
      <utterance>Vide, Magister. There's something wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? What's happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've just seen something. Something of consequence to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a distracted gesture he causes the flames to extinguish themselves.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. My own death.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps we had better hasten your training.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This wood, these leaves, the birds, the very dome of heaven, once they all rang with one great chord: and philosophers like me kept it all in tune. Now, new voices are singing new songs.  Have you mastered the threefold transmutation?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, almost.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very difficult. Have you committed to memory undying the Codex de Profundis?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first two chapters.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's long. And what about the Ritual of Banishment as prescribed by my late master Balisarius?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To tell the truth, I haven't dared try it. What's the point, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The point? The point is you don't know it, and you're no magician without it. It was my hope to school you, to mold your faculties and wits... I still believe you have some talent. Somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate books. I hate drill. I want a real task.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no time now. When I'm gone, half the powers in the universe will vanish with me. And what's the use of a few lingering skills if they're left in the hands of a child?  Listen!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ulrich gauges the young man standing before him and makes a decision. Reaching under his cloak he lifts off a fine silver chain with an amulet dangling from it. He drapes it around Galen's neck.</context>
      <utterance>I don't hear anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen instinctively wraps his hand around the jewel. He cocks an ear.</context>
      <utterance>Here, wear this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hastens forward to a promontory, eager to have a look. Ulrich does not follow. Instead, doffing his cloak, he whirls it before him, where it magically floats a few feet off the ground. Awkwardly, the old man clambers aboard.</context>
      <utterance>Voices, singing on the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back, but the wizard is gone. A shadow falls over him. He looks up. There, two hundred feet above the tree tops his master is soaring on the wind.</context>
      <utterance>I don't see anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks forbidding enough, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here are your sticks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- they'll think me infirm. You know, Balisarius wore this whenever he changed lead into gold. He could really do that, you know. I never could. Too bad -- you'd stand to inherit some real wealth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in a morbid frame of mind. What's all this about dying? You don't even look sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He backs away from the mirror and fits a silver coronet onto his head.</context>
      <utterance>You still wearing that amulet?  Good. Don't lose it. It still belongs to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sorcerer starts down a circular stone staircase.</context>
      <utterance>Now, adeptus minor, get yourself a handful of that sulphurous ash over there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pffst! around the room candles flare in their niches.</context>
      <utterance>Nunc habeus lux!</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the fireplace, the birch logs are suddenly ablaze. Ulrich totters to the hearth and extends long bony fingers toward the warmth.</context>
      <utterance>Et calor!</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The travelers are suitably dazzled by the magician's performance. The young leader of the party screws up his courage and speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Cragganmore. I am Ulrich. Which one of you calls himself Valerian?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be me. We are here on behalf...</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The travelers exchange nervous glances. Valerian motions to one of his companions. The man steps forward and hands over a leather pouch. One by one, Valerian places the contents on the table for Ulrich's inspection.</context>
      <utterance>I know why you're here. You're a delegation from Urland, from beyond Dalvatia. Let's see the artifacts.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this, Ulrich advances and closely examines three shimmering irridescent disks as big as saucers.</context>
      <utterance>A bone. Scorched. A rock, fire- blackened.  Scales.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. How did you come by these?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found them. At the mouth of the lair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian reaches under his jerkin and withdraws what appears to be a curved sword. He jabs it into the table.</context>
      <utterance>What else?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A claw.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs a finger along a serrated edge and gazes bleakly at his visitors.</context>
      <utterance>That's no claw. It's a tooth. By the gods!</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian has lost all trace of timidity.</context>
      <utterance>And you want me to do battle with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else can we turn to? We all know what we're dealing with here. This is a basilicok.  A cockatrice.  A dragon.  This is no stag, no bear, no natural creature. This is one of your kind. And only a necromancer such as yourself can rid us of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you try the Meredydd sisters? What about Rinbod? I've heard it said he killed a dragon once.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a sigh, Ulrich lowers himself into a chair. He rubs his withered legs and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>They're all dead. You're the only one left.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a long way to Urland.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Greil, a grizzled peasant, speaks up.</context>
      <utterance>Every quarter, upon the solstices and the equinoxes there's a new victim.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daughter, for one.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER TRAVELERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My sister... cousins...</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All women?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen edges over to the table and inspects the scales and tooth.</context>
      <utterance>Girls. Virgins, to be exact, chosen by lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master, don't you think --</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He broods for a long time.</context>
      <utterance>Silence!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you afraid of dragons?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Sorcerers and dragons go back a long long time together. If it weren't for sorcerers, there wouldn't be any dragons.  All right. I'll go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hodge mutters something inaudible and grimly keeps packing.</context>
      <utterance>I know of this dragon. Vermithrax Pejorative: she's four hundred years old. As far as I can tell she's the last of her kind. Very appropriate that I'm the one to finish her off, don't you think?  There. Flatten the highest mountain. What say you, Galen?  Speak up.  You, Hodge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While I'm gone see you keep your nose in your books and your hands out of my reagents. Leave my instruments alone too. Galen crouches against the castle wall; he regards his master sullenly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at yourself. How far will you get like that? A league, two leagues?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not worried about the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you wave your hands around and summon up a coach-and-four?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mock me. Galen gets up and calls out to the Urlanders.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is too much for Hodge.</context>
      <utterance>You pilgrims: You're used to lotteries. Why not draw straws to see who'll be first to carry ironshanks here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen approaches the old sorcerer.</context>
      <utterance>Hold your tongue. If the master's got a mind to go, he'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send me. You're always saying I need seasoning. I need a test. Let me go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm ready for anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrian is a lean, heavily bearded nobleman. There is a coat of arms on the shield strapped to the pommel of his saddle.</context>
      <utterance>Tyrian!?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, all.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not afraid of you. Give us the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sensing trouble, Galen moves forward. Ulrich touches his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Why, the road is yours. All the way to Urland. It's a long journey, isn't it? But when you're in search of a sorcerer, I suppose no distance is too great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen hears the urgency in the old man's voice and obeys. Hodge takes it upon himself to deal with the strangers.</context>
      <utterance>Say nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, like my good friends here, I've come for a bit of black magic. No doubt you've heard of our troubles at home. This is Cragganmore, is it not?</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrian dismounts and saunters up to the old magician.</context>
      <utterance>Aye, this be the place of Ulrich.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And here we have the mystical presence himself, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd best keep your distance -- and your manners.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he's ready to lay a dragon in its grave, he's got nothing to fear from me.  I've no more love for that creature than you lot. Nor has the King. But, before you stir things up, don't you think it a good idea to see you've got the right man for the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aha -- it's a test you're looking for. We don't do tests.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you don't. They never do tests -- and not many real deeds either. Oh, conversation with your grandmother's shade in a darkened room, the odd love potion or two... but comes a doubter, well then, it's the wrong day, the planets are not aligned, the entrails aren't favorable, we don't do tests.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got no doubts. We require no test.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Ulrich finally speaks, his voice is low and authoritative.</context>
      <utterance>And you're not going to get one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen's eyes widen with alarm.</context>
      <utterance>Go to the conjuring room. The iron box. Fetch me the dagger within.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen dashes into the castle. Ulrich gazes almost shyly at Tyrian.</context>
      <utterance>The dagger. Be quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shall have your test.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not this one, was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen hesitates, then tosses it. Tumbling end over end, it arcs downward. The old conjurer calmly stretches out a hand and plucks it neatly out of the air. Galen watches as Ulrich passes the weapon to Tyrian and strips back his robe exposing a bony chest. Galen knows what's coming. He rushes for the door. He's only a step away when it bangs shut of its own accord. He sprints for a second exit. Whack! This door slams shut too. Locked in. Quick, back to the window and climb down the vine... Smack! the heavy shutters seal him in.</context>
      <utterance>The very one. Let it fall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone is filled with dread. Hodge is shaking. From the castle come the rattling of shutters and Galen's muffled cries. A sick sarcastic smile has crept over Tyrian's lips. He tenses himself to thrust.</context>
      <utterance>Vita regula, vita hieratica!</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on. Don't worry, you can't hurt me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hodge quickly conceals the pouch.</context>
      <utterance>Hodge -- what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He quickly climbs down, picks up his pack and follows Galen out through the gate. As the door is pushed shut a huge oaken timber falls into place, barring the castle against the uninvited.</context>
      <utterance>Just making my farewell, thank you very much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful with that! You don't know what you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his hands toward the castle and calls out:</context>
      <utterance>Stand back!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cragganmore! Domus non i am! Silva celet!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's a vale of tears in which we dwell. It doesn't matter who you are, a king in his robes, a peasant in his rags, when your time comes, no magic can save you...</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The apprentice's mind is elsewhere: he's got a coin hovering in mid-air above his palm, bobbing gently as he walks.</context>
      <utterance>I guess...</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the kindest lord a man could ask for... now he's gone. Ye gods he was fussy about his bath. And you'd think he could boil his own eggs with the snap of a finger, but no, he had old Hodge do it, of course.  Up before five I was, mucking out the cages, slopping the pigs, and never once got so much as a thankyou or a pat on the back...  I'm going to miss him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plucks a low-hanging leaf, waves a hand over it, and watches it turn into a spray of daffodils.</context>
      <utterance>Me too...</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you don't. All you care about is the tricks and knavery. Well, you don't pull any wool over these old eyes. It'll be a mighty long walk before you fill his shoes, you mark my word.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives the pack a slap. It flies out of its harness and floats alongside them. Hodge snatches it back and clutches it tightly.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, Hodge, pack too heavy? Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Careful with that!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A great coat drapes itself over Hodge's shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Too cold, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The greatcoat disappears, as do the rest of his garments, leaving him in his smalls.</context>
      <utterance>Too warm?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got as much respect for the master as anyone, old man. But -- then again, I'm master now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks up and down behind Valerian.</context>
      <utterance>I left my farm with seeds unplanted, calves unborn, nothing but a wife to chase down the strays, and for what? A funeral, that's what.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malkin, an older man, speaks up.</context>
      <utterance>Because some people said, find a magician. Not just a local fellow, an import, a good forty leagues from home. An all-powerful necromancer. Ha -- some necromancer!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold your tongue, Greil. Sit. Eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll not sit. I'll not eat. See you the Great Bear. His tail points east. It's the equinox. Have you forgotten? Or rather not think about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morrow, good morrow. Peace be with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy now. We mean no harm. We've been looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you've found us.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More the other way around, I'd say.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few words, that's all. You were looking for a conjurer.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Requiscat in pace.  Ecce: magister novus!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen surveys the puzzled faces. He draws himself up and plunges in:</context>
      <utterance>How say you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment of depressed silence. Hodge rolls his eyes. Greil starts to chuckle, then to laugh. Soon the others are laughing too.</context>
      <utterance>My lord Ulrich is no longer. All that you asked of him, you may now expect of me. The dangers he would face, I will now conquer. The task he would undertake I will now fulfill. I am Galen Bradwardyn, inheritor of Ulrich's craft and knowledge, and I am the Sorcerer you seek.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's a handsome thought, O wizard of wizards. But if there's one thing our friend Tyrian has shown us, it's to beware the pig in the poke. Who's got a dagger?</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No tests!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone brings out a dagger and hands it to Greil. Valerian pushes it away.</context>
      <utterance>Call it proof, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Greil persists, waving the knife at the group.</context>
      <utterance>We've seen enough tests.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lashes out with the knife. Galen jumps back, but Valerian steps in, delivering a quick kick to Greil's gut, followed by a right to the jaw that sends the bigger man sprawling. He takes the knife.</context>
      <utterance>Well I haven't. All I've seen is death. Death in our families, death on the road, and tonight, death at home.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He propels Galen out of harm's way and sits him down on the other side of the fire. Greil nurses his jaw.</context>
      <utterance>What's come over you, anyway? Have you lost your wits?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian hands Galen a plate of food.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like it. Young snot-nose comes in here for sport at our expense. We're on a fool's errand, but we don't have to listen to this. I don't want to hear any more about sorcery. I don't want to hear any more about spells.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both look up at the moon.</context>
      <utterance>It's not just him. It's all of us. It's the equinox.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HORSRIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A young woman, no more than seventeen, is brought forth from the cart. Long black hair falls down over a white tunic. Her dark eyes dart fearfully around in her pale face. She is half-carried, half dragged to the edge of a steaming crack in the ground where she is manacled to a wooden post. By lantern-light, Horsrik reads from a parchment scroll.</context>
      <utterance>Close enough! Bring her out!</utterance>
   <speaker>HORSRIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a low rumble; the earth shakes. Horsrik glances nervously around. He carries on by rote.</context>
      <utterance>Now be it known throughout the kingdom, that this maiden, having lawfully been chosen by a deed of fortune and destiny, shall hereby give up her life for the greater good of Urland.</utterance>
   <speaker>HORSRIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He prods the girl, but she is too terrified to speak. Beneath them, the earth seems to groan. Smoke issues from the mouth of the pit. One of the nervous witnesses leans forward.</context>
      <utterance>By this act shall be satisfied the powers that dwell underground and the spirits that attend thereto. In gratitude for this sacrifice His Majesty has declared the family -- what's the name? --</utterance>
   <speaker>RETAINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plowman! The family Plowman!</utterance>
   <speaker>HORSRIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Horsrik joins the flight, chasing his men back over the murky horizon.</context>
      <utterance>-- ordained and signed this day, etc., Casiodorus, in his glory the reigning king of this our realm... his seal, his mark, duly read by Chancellor Horsrik in his holy name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrian wipes his mouth unhurriedly and strolls over to look. Far below, half hidden by trees, the little company of Urlanders winds its way through the forest. A frown creeps over Tyrian's face.</context>
      <utterance>There. I see them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that old man?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where? Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That one. That's the man from Cragganmore. Now what's he doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Filling in for the chief, I reckon.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a pity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you got there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little gold, eh? What do you say I change it into lead?</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass Valerian, who has dropped out of line.</context>
      <utterance>Save your jokes for someone else. Me, I don't care for braggarts.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I don't care for frauds.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm no fraud.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call it fool then. Upstart. Whatever pleases you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hodge, nobody forced you to come along.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm here of my own free will, all right. We each do the master's bidding in our own way.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hodge snorts and fusses with his pack.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if he told you I needed wetnursing, why don't you just turn yourself around and go back home.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances over and discovers Galen missing.</context>
      <utterance>Home, is it? You've seen to that, haven't you? Gone to seed, I'd say...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're too far behind us. Come on out.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go ahead, I'll catch up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a good idea to get separated. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen leans over and splashes some water on his face. Feels good. He shucks his pack and starts to throw off his clothes. Valerian doesn't like it.</context>
      <utterance>Right. I'll be along.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Galen is now naked and walking into the water. He swims out toward Valerian.</context>
      <utterance>That's all right. Don't come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen keeps swimming.</context>
      <utterance>You better get back to the group, they're probably worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Galen has slipped beneath the surface; he doesn't hear.</context>
      <utterance>I prefer to swim alone, if you don't mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian is pale and frightened.</context>
      <utterance>By the gods!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She propels herself backward, then turns and swims for shore.</context>
      <utterance>Stay away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose you'll tell everyone. Go ahead, I don't care. It's a relief.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't blame you. I was stupid. Careless. A silly woman!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy. I knew the moment I saw you. I've known the whole time.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never knew a thing. No one knew. Not since I was born. Go on, run off and tell them. It'll make a great story.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. No one's going to find out. Just tell me: why?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They finish dressing in silence. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Ask my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The lottery! Daughters are chosen, but sons are not!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. Unless you have plenty of gold or property.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He studies her. She jams a hat down over her head and, once more the young man, stalks off.</context>
      <utterance>If you're rich enough, your name never goes in.  My father is poor. So are a lot of fathers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances back at him and grimly keeps on walking. Galen shoots past her and on into the forest.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hodge!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Galen? Can you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, somebody shot me, but I can still talk. There's something that has to be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hodge's hand comes out from under his coat gripping the leather pouch. Galen tugs at it, but Hodge can't let go.</context>
      <utterance>Not that cockatrice. Ulrich's ashes. Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen pries the sack out of Hodge's clenched fingers. Suddenly the hand comes up, grabs Galen by the hair, and pulls him near.</context>
      <utterance>Take it. Sorry, you'll have to peel it loose.</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...burning water... find the lake, throw it in...</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing with this, Hodge?</utterance>
   <speaker>HODGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dies. Galen frees himself from his grasp.</context>
      <utterance>...burning water...</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen is frantic. He pulls out the amulet and wraps his hand around it.</context>
      <utterance>Hodge, don't die. Listen to me. You're not going to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Hodge has passed on, and Galen's magic has no way to reach him. Suddenly the youth cries out in pain. He drops the amulet and looks at his palm. The device has burned his flesh. Now he becomes aware of troubled Urlanders looking over his shoulder, witness to his failure.</context>
      <utterance>Excede, mortem! Revoca, vitam!  Excede, mortem! Revoca, vitam!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen falls into step with her.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Don't dawdle here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whole kingdom like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen looks around with new interest.</context>
      <utterance>No. We're near the lair. Keep moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen stops. High on the slope beside them is a gaping fissure.</context>
      <utterance>Over there. Doesn't matter. We're in no danger if we just pass through quickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see it. Let's have a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Galen is already toiling up the incline.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The travelers turn to see what's the matter.</context>
      <utterance>Greil! Malkin! Help!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you don't have to do this. We know you're a fine young magician. None better. There's no need to prove it to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are there other entrances?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. One's enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. The road's this way. We'll tell everybody how close you got.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No smoke. How do you know it's in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instead, Galen starts into the crack. Greil and Malkin hasten away, but Valerian lingers, watching in mounting frustration as Galen probes further and further into the lair. She picks up a fistful of stones and throws them at him.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be a fool. Come away now and live to tell about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Galen is lost in the gloom. She flees.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead! You're going to die! What a fine trick that will be!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BROTHER JACOPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The travelers enter and mingle with the congregation. Valerian scans the crowd until she locates her father, Simon, a balding sturdy journeyman. He's overjoyed at her return and gives her a hearty embrace.</context>
      <utterance>Now are you cleansed of your sins! Now are you born again, purified in spirit, into the fellowship of Jesus Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome back, my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, what are you doing? Have you all lost your minds?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the monk, who is dunking a screaming infant and carrying on about the Bishop of Rome.</context>
      <utterance>Some have.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's this monk. He can read and write, and talk too, I'm afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they listen?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shh! They think this a holy place, a tabernacle.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the granary. What kind of welcome is this? I've got news of the sorcerer and news of the dragon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were brave to go, you and your friends. But nobody cares. Listen -- he knows what they want to hear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BROTHER JACOPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man who walks with Christ is not a man to fear a dragon: Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death I will fear no evil! You say you are preyed upon by a foul beast. Yes, but what is the nature of this beast? It comes to you on bat's wings and clawed feet, does it not? It breathes fire, does it not? And it lives under ground. This is no dragon. This is Lucifer!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is Galen, who has just stepped into the hall, tattered, bedraggled and triumphant.</context>
      <utterance>Whoever it is, he's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER JACOPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nay, brother! It is not as easy as that. Allegiance to Christ, to be sure, but also prayer and confession. These are the arms by which Satan may be put down.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He marches to the center of the gathering.</context>
      <utterance>You're talking about superstition, friend. None of that has anything to do with what I, Galen, have already achieved.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You brought this stranger?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ulrich's apprentice. He's a braggart, but it doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People of Urland! Send a messenger to the king. Vermithrax is dead. Crushed by the power of the moon and the stars! Laid low by ancient wisdom. Dropped into the Abyss by mystical practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER JACOPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spoken like a pagan. Every word as reprobate as it is false!  Solum in hoc signo vinces!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures boldly and a fireball crackles at the monk's feet. The holy man scurries back. A hush falls upon the congregation.</context>
      <utterance>Nihil plus mysterium!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BROTHER JACOPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praise God! Blessed is he that is humble before the Lord!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indeed, Galen's act is already the stuff of legend:</context>
      <utterance>Your god had nothing to do with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the younger villagers scamper forward to the spot where the cave had its opening. With yells and whoops they beat the ground with clubs. In the crowd Simon begins to smile, then to laugh. Soon he leads the villagers in a tumultuous cheer. Brother Jacopus and some of his converts drop to their knees and pray.</context>
      <utterance>We saw it with our own eyes. He flew to the mountain top. He was a bird. He brought forth lightning. I saw it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put that away. What if you were seen?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to be seen. I want to be seen. Tonight the world finds out that you never had a son.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you mustn't do that. It's too soon. We've got to think about this, we've got to make a plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits on the bed and puts his head in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Father: the danger is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. What am I going to say to my friends who still mourn for their lost girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at her, trying to imagine what it's going to be like having a daughter.</context>
      <utterance>You'll say you did what you had to. This is a time for celebration -- and forgiveness.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian doesn't know what to say.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like you've been up to a little sorcery yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She still doesn't reply. It's all she can do to keep on dancing.</context>
      <utterance>Or is it witchcraft?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? A real woman never stops talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it was much easier being a boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The damnedest thing is, she was twice the man of anyone else in the village. Now she's twice the woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would that I had been as clever as her father.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come now, Greil. Don't begrudge a life spared.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I begrudge nothing. But I wonder at what we have seen and how it was done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw what I saw. But this jack-anapes was barely ready to carry his master's chamberpot. Isn't it strange that at the very moment the beast is put down we should have a holy man here in the village?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't believe that superstitious Christian rot, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is said God works his wonders in mysterious ways.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The musicians leave their instruments in their laps. Tyrian draws himself a measure of ale and raises it above his head.</context>
      <utterance>A celebration! Don't stop on my account. You -- musicians, more music!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A toast! To the deed of the day! You see, good news travels fast. The King himself has already heard it. And like yourselves, tonight he's overcome with joy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would you have of us then?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a thing. It's this one.  The King would meet our new benefactor and offer his gratitude to the man who succeeded where so many have failed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My young friend, I'd as soon dispatch you as I did the others, and for the same reason. But his Majesty would like a cozy chat, and commands otherwise.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrian regards her coolly, taking in her change of costume and its meaning.</context>
      <utterance>Don't go, Galen. Cast a spell and turn them into toads. It should be easy; that's what they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Having buried the dragon under a mountain, Galen decides he's not worried about an appearance at court. He smiles at Valerian.</context>
      <utterance>Well, well: still plenty of cheek under those skirts, it seems.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'll be back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Water continues to pour into the goblet without overflowing. Galen takes a sip.</context>
      <utterance>One of the best things about the water here in Urland is that there's so much of it -- look at that!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King makes no sign. Galen approaches stiffly, takes a scarf and retreats.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm. Good. But not cold enough. Perhaps I could borrow a scarf from his Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he's done it: he turns the goblet over and a small chunk of ice hits the floor. The royal reaction is equally frosty. Galen is bombing, and he knows it.</context>
      <utterance>I cover the goblet, so... remove, so... and behold: winter in a mug!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He mutters an incantation. In the audience, Tyrian notes that Galen has his hand wrapped around the amulet. There is a loud clatter as the heavy oak table before the throne begins to jitter and buck. As the wine spills and plates go flying, the King wearily raises a hand.</context>
      <utterance>All right. How many of you have ever seen a table fly?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough! That's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, it'll rise now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The table cracks in half and dumps a mess of fruit and crockery at the onlookers' feet.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bother. Not necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me: the landslide -- it was accomplished this same way?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. And having rendered such unique service to our kingdom, what would you claim as a reward?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This handsome sentiment doesn't go over any better than his tricks.</context>
      <utterance>Please -- no payment. I have always found magical practice to be its own reward. I seek only some yet greater challenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King grimaces as the memories come flooding back.</context>
      <utterance>Did you ever hear of King Gaiseric? Of course not, you weren't even born. He was my brother, a great King and a valiant man-at-arms. When he ascended to the throne, the dragon was unbridled. No one knew where it might strike next. So he brought forth his broadsword and his spear, assembled a company of his best fighters and went out to do battle.  He was never seen again. But his attack provoked the most terrible reprisals: whole villages incinerated, entire crops burned. Death, famine, horrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you arrogate to yourself the role of savior?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was invited.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not by me. Did you ever consider the consequences of failure?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What failure? What's the matter with you people? You want the dragon back?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then the beast is dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course. Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We shall see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a long moment when nothing happens. A very long moment. Finally, a thoroughly frustrated Galen leaps to the window and rattles the bars.</context>
      <utterance>Cubiculum gravis aperat!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open up, dammit! Fenestra gravis aperat! Asser gravis aperat! Divinitus!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Startled, Galen whirls around to find Elspeth standing outside his cell. She hands some food and blankets through the bars.</context>
      <utterance>Salve, magistrum iuvenilum.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen looks her over. He's never seen anyone so angelic.</context>
      <utterance>I've studied Latin. Greek, too. Me appelo Elspeth, filia regis.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't think ill of us. My father is a wonderful man, a wise man. The lottery was his idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't understand. From the moment it began, the dragon was tame. The kingdom prospered.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And only a few had to be sacrificed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's true. Isn't it better that a few should die that many might live?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends on who does the dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, but we all take our chances. My father is a just man. My name is entered on the lists, along with every other young --</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Virgin?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maiden.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you say so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've participated in every drawing since I came of age.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's true. You don't believe me. You think I'm lying. Well I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I heard a rumor. Families with money, that sort of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't listen to rumors. They're lies. I have to go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait -- how long do I have to stay in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slips away down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Until we know. Not long. Goodbye. Vale. Dormi bene.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King picks up Galen's amulet, and holds it over the bars in his clenched fist.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough. Let's not be greedy here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a rustle of skirts and Elspeth appears behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Now then: I, Casiodorus Rex do hereby command thou base metal to change thy essence and become gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now. Tyrian, remove all but one bar. We'll try it one at a time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King and Tyrian glance up at her.</context>
      <utterance>Father: did you know that some families have paid bribes to stay out of the lottery?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lead remains unchanged, but the King gives out a cry and drops the amulet.</context>
      <utterance>Nonsense. By the power of this amulet, justly wielded by my hand in accordance with the laws of Urland, now lead be thou gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm burned! What devilish thing is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever kept my name off the lottery list?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrian bows and exits. The King uses his sceptre to pick up the amulet and chain. He conceals it in a hollowed-out book and places the volume on a shelf among many others.</context>
      <utterance>That'll be all, Tyrian. You may withdraw.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, my dear, what's troubling you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King paces over to the window and stares out. The rain has stopped.</context>
      <utterance>Answer my question: am I not exposed to the same risk as every other man's daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth sways in dismay.</context>
      <utterance>Your father loves you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's true! What have you done to me!?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment a tremor passes through the room. King and daughter look at each other in alarm.</context>
      <utterance>Who fills your head with such ideas?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men below scramble for the gates. Galen bursts out of hiding, sees the untended horses, and swings aboard as one goes past. A cry goes up from the guards.</context>
      <utterance>Close the main gate! Quick!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen rides like mad for the exit, but he's a half-second late: the doors boom shut in his face. He wheels the horse around. The King's men are coming toward him with pikes. Digging his heels into the horse's sides, he urges the animal back across the courtyard, up the steps and right into the building!</context>
      <utterance>There! Stop him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrian sweeps in with his men. The doors slam shut.</context>
      <utterance>Tyrian! Tyrian!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen is trapped. Just as Tyrian reaches for the horse's reins, the animal rears up, rolling its eyes. At that moment the floor heaves and cracks in a new series of shocks. The men at arms go down like ten pins. Tyrian reels back, dodging stone blocks loosened from the ceiling. As the shaking continues, a weakened section of wall gives way. Galen sees daylight! Without even waiting for the quake to cease, he prods the horse across the room and through the wall to freedom.</context>
      <utterance>So much for your magic! So much for your sorcery!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BROTHER JACOPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holding a cross before him, he starts up the slope. No one follows. They haven't been Christians all that long. One or two near Valerian get down on their knees and pray silently. Greil looks things over.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, my brethren. The moment of our fear is the moment of our triumph. This is a sign from God. Follow me, and our faith will send this creature straight to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strides after the monk. But he's the only one.</context>
      <utterance>You call yourselves Christians?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BROTHER JACOPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...for Thine is the kingdom and the power and the glory forever -- amen. At the base of the slope the villagers scatter. Greil wavers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER JACOPUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dragon's head sways back and forth, then belches out a waterfall of flame. It engulfs Jacopus and sends him to a better world, if there is one.</context>
      <utterance>Unclean beast, get thee down! Be thou consumed by the fires that made you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen staggers back, reaching for his horse. The animal shies and trots off. A middle-aged woman appears in front of him, her face contorted with rage. She swings a flaming broom and catches him on the back of the head. Galen reels away.</context>
      <utterance>Get away, you little bastard. We've had enough help from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen looks up and sees a couple of burlies moving his way with boards in their hands.</context>
      <utterance>This is your doing!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURLIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before they can get too close, Galen runs down an alley and bumps smack into a glassy-eyed, haunted man. It is Greil.</context>
      <utterance>Get him! He's back!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greil -- help!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes past. Galen ducks behind a smoldering building.</context>
      <utterance>May the Lord forgive you for what you have done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me. Are you hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have you been? Doesn't matter -- listen: Quick! Make it rain. That'll put the fire out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then get the animals back. They're all running loose. There's people been hurt. Stop their pain. You can cure them. And we'll need food...</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen's hand moves up to where the amulet used to hang.</context>
      <utterance>What? Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're a sorcerer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm no sorcerer. Whatever power I might have had, it's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can't be!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment, Valerian is too stunned to speak. Then her face colors.</context>
      <utterance>I know: I'm an imposter. A fraud. A fake. I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen sinks to the floor and sits in the ashes.</context>
      <utterance>You're sorry?! Listen to that! The damn thing is loose, we're all on fire and you're sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She snatches up a pitchfork and glowers at him.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't have the faintest idea what you were doing, did you? You're a fool -- and I'm a bigger one for bringing you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Galen still sits there like a puppet with its strings cut, every dream of glory utterly crushed. This piteous sight touches Valerian's heart. Her gaze softens. She slowly lowers the pitchfork.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want you in this house. Get out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cry goes up from the villagers. They know damn well he's in there.</context>
      <utterance>Not here. I can't help you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You too?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finding nothing, the group pushes into the metal shop, where Simon is hammering an iron wheel rim back into shape on an enormous anvil. He lays down his tools and grimly watches the men go through, overturning benches and tables. Tyrian props a leg up on the anvil and addresses himself to Simon.</context>
      <utterance>Damn right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As the proud new father of an eligible daughter who was some-how overlooked all these years, it may interest you to know that the King has called for a new lottery.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's months til the solstice.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In view of what's happened, we all know what's required.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never taken part in your cursed lottery, and I'll have nothing to do with it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The search party has exhausted the room's hiding places.</context>
      <utterance>You were very clever. But she'll take part, like all the rest. No exceptions.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENCHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrian nods and leads the way out. Simon catches up and pulls Tyrian aside at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. If he was here, he's gone now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. I know what you want. How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you offering me a bribe?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spins on his heel and joins his men as they ride out of town. Valerian and Simon watch them go. When the riders are out of sight, they return to the shop. With a couple of stout poles, they strain to lift the anvil off its base. Finally it topples over. Valerian slides the base aside, revealing a trap door. She raises it and a cramped Galen unfolds himself from the space below. On his face is a curious look of determination.</context>
      <utterance>Don't waste your time.  You could never afford it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smith -- have you ever forged a weapon?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon plucks up one of the swords, carries it to the center of the room. He lays a horseshoe on the anvil. He brings the sword down -- whack! -- and cuts the horseshoe in half.</context>
      <utterance>These are your sharpest?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen hefts it dubiously.</context>
      <utterance>Even Tyrian carries one of these.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian has been watching all this with growing concern.</context>
      <utterance>It's sharp -- but it's not sharp enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not sharp enough for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what I'm going to do with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon gnaws his lip. Reluctantly, he brings a long box from the bottom of the cabinet. He opens it. Lying on a bed of silk is an exquisite two-handed broadsword. The flat blade gleams like a mirror. Galen reaches in and lifts it out.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing's that sharp.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian is as awed as Galen.</context>
      <utterance>The best I ever made.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen brings up a finger to test the edge. Simon grabs his hand away.</context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him with affection. Leaning forward, she plants a kiss on his bald pate.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do that!  Girl-child, when you were born I knew I had to do something, so I set about the task of fashioning an extraordinary weapon: I had the skill to make it --  -- but not the nerve to use it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thankful for that.  No man should choose a senseless death.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen walks out into the shallows and pushes the sword-tip into the sandy bottom, angled so that the edge splits the current.</context>
      <utterance>If it's me you're worried about, don't. So my name has been entered, what of it? There are hundreds of girls. My name just won't be drawn. I know it won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks back to shore. All three watch the sword to see what will happen.</context>
      <utterance>Valerian, this isn't just for your sake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care. It doesn't matter. What you want to kill isn't flesh and blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it'll bleed, all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look to Galen. The apprentice's face is full of doubt.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know? No one's so much as even scratched it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll need the amulet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at her. The Princess.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian gives Galen a sharp look. Horsrik unrolls a parchment.</context>
      <utterance>I know. We've met.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Horsrik picks up a wooden staff surmounted by a carved dragon's head and stirs up the names. This done, a new chant goes up:</context>
      <utterance>Stir the tiles! Stir the tiles!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At a signal, a guard comes forward and cuts the sleeve from Horsrik's right arm. He holds it high. The crowd surges forward. The atmosphere is full of dread and excitement. Valerian looking pale and determined, is jostled and pushed to the edge of the platform.</context>
      <utterance>Bare the arm! Bare the arm!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment has come. Down goes Horsrik's arm and up it comes, holding one little wooden square, one young woman's fate. An expectant hush falls over the mob. The virgins of Urland tremble and wait.</context>
      <utterance>Draw the name! Draw the name!</utterance>
   <speaker>HORSRIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at the tile to read the name, but no sound comes to his lips. He looks back at the crowd, a cold sweat breaking over his face. He swallows, but still can't bring himself to speak. At his feet, Valerian is holding her breath. A new chant goes up.</context>
      <utterance>Now, my countrymen, hear me: behold, for I am chosen. I shall die that many may live. I shall lay down my life for family and fellows. I shall go to my grave for the love of our King and his wise policy. And my name is --</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now Horsrik is trembling. He stares down at the tile, his mouth set in a grim line. The King is getting annoyed. He gestures and the crowd falls silent.</context>
      <utterance>The name! The name!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Read the name.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian will not stand for such hypocrisy.</context>
      <utterance>That's not the name. It's been misread.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no mistake! The name's been chosen -- let it stand!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He quickly tosses the wood chip into a brazier at his elbow. Led by Valerian, the crowd cries out in protest.</context>
      <utterance>No, the good Horsrik has misspoke himself.  In fairness to this individual, whose name I can't make out, we'll destroy this tile.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! What better name than your own kin? At last we see justice done!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into the barrel and extracts another tile. He looks at it and his eyes widen. Betrayed, he swivels to face his daughter. The din of the crowd reaches a crescendo.</context>
      <utterance>Silence! We will have a new choosing. I will draw the name myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth takes the tile from her father's nerveless fingers, looks at it with satisfaction and holds it aloft.</context>
      <utterance>Let it stand! Let it stand!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King moils through the tiles, finding his daughter's name again and again.</context>
      <utterance>The name is as you heard it and as Horsrik read it: Elspeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian, chanting with the rest, falls silent. She looks at Elspeth with sudden interest and respect, then awe.</context>
      <utterance>The lottery is invalid. Another and another. What treachery is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>cacophony of shouts, whistles and excited conversation. Galen sees his chance: there's an unguarded door near the stable. He drifts toward it and slips inside.</context>
      <utterance>Hear me, good people! It is true, that my name appears on many of the lots. This does not falsify the drawing, it certifies it! I have learned that my name has been kept from jeopardy in all the drawings in the past. So I have put my name among the rest many times -- once for each risk that, over the years, you took and I did not. The crowd is dumbfounded. Gradually voices erupt in a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen whirls around to find the King standing in the doorway. The monarch looks shattered. Galen edges toward the split in the wall and finds that it has been shored up with timbers. At that moment Tyrian comes through the door, sizes up the situation and draws his sword.</context>
      <utterance>Don't go to all that trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm unarmed. If you want a fight, at least give me a weapon.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think not!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And you -- don't run away... please... The King's voice is cracking. Galen and Tyrian are equally taken aback. The King searches through the books remaining on the library shelves.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! Don't harm him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always had the greatest admiration for the black arts. You chaps with your mysterious spells... I didn't think it would be necessary, you see. Vermithrax is an old dragon. And that, I thought, was the beauty of my plan -- buying time. We'd wait her out. I'd live to see the end of her.  That's still going to happen. The King finds the book and takes the amulet out. With trembling hands, he passes it to Galen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sire!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He shall have it.  It's my daughter. Save her, I beg you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some workmen go by lugging new thatch. Malkin is with them.</context>
      <utterance>Holy of holies -- he did not die in vain. Can you hear me, brothers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We hear you, Greil.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malkin and the others stop to listen.</context>
      <utterance>Well and good, but I'm Greil no longer. Call me Gregorius, after the Bishop of Rome.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw him die. Like Our Lord Jesus on the cross he was, scourged by evil. But he showed no fear. Such is the power of the Holy Ghost.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen quietly shuts and bars the door. He moves deeper into the gloomy workroom where Simon is pumping a bellows to heat up the forge. Galen looks at the coals.</context>
      <utterance>Of what avail is magic? The old gods died with our daughters. From whence comest my help? My help comest from the Lord!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good and hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian is staring at the sword, sitting on the anvil in its silk wrapping. Galen uncovers it, holds it high, and puts his hand on the amulet.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bother. That's not the kind of fire we need.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sword starts to hum and to heat up. From the hilt outward the blade glows brighter and brighter: red, orange, white. It lights up the room, throwing long shadows into the corners. Galen lays the white hot steel on the anvil. Simon takes up his hammer and begins the reforging. Valerian sees their resolve. After watching for several moments she slips out the side door, looking sad.</context>
      <utterance>Nunc, per Potestatem Hermeticum -- ex flammis, ferrum sangrinarium!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An edge like no other on this earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon hands him a bundle of fighting equipment.</context>
      <utterance>Well done, Simon. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll say goodbye to Valerian for you. I'm sorry she's not here, but you know how she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other for what could be the last time.</context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man departs. Galen unfolds the bundle and brings out its contents: mail hauberk with coif, studded leather gloves, padded jerkin, a scabbard and a small wooden shield. He lays them out on the stream bank, then strips off his tunic and kneels down to splash some water in his face. As the cups the water between his hands, an image comes alive and shimmers on the surface: Valerian, stripping off her own clothes, shyly turning toward him, solemn and romantic.</context>
      <utterance>Fare thee well.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's as if the vision is speaking to him, but it's not. He spins around and sees her standing there, fully clothed, and possessed of a brisk and businesslike air.</context>
      <utterance>Galen.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws down a shield. It's remarkable in its construction -- overlapping layers of iridescent dragon scales have been ingeniously fastened to a leather-clad frame.</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen turns the shield over and over, marveling at it. He fixes her with a piercing look.</context>
      <utterance>It's a shield. I made it. Might keep the fire off you. Might not. You know, you're an idiot. You're going to die tonight. You'll be ripped limb from limb. This is the last time I'll ever speak to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerian wants to be bold, but on this final point, can't muster the courage.</context>
      <utterance>Hatchlings. They'll have to be killed too. Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in love, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right. I understand. She's very beautiful, very brave.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is? What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Princess. But I don't care. It doesn't change the way I feel.  Listen to me, Galen Bradwardyn, sorcerer's apprentice; you're going to be dead, the dragon will be worse than ever, there will be more lotteries, and I'm not a boy any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you'll be eligible because --</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen takes her in his arms; she is trembling. He tilts her face up toward his and kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>Because I'm still a virgin, and I want you to do something about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their image is reflected in the waters. Through the ripples she is visible pulling briefly away to remove her clothes. From afar, they are two tiny figures under the overarching oaks and willows. They embrace and sink down into the deep grass beside the water. The leaves continue their unhurried course downstream.</context>
      <utterance>I am in love. But not with the Princess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HORSRIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Horsrik blinks. There's a black stain growing in the middle of the parchment; all at once it bursts into flames. He cries out and flings the document away. There follows a flash of light and a puff of smoke and Galen is standing there, as if he had materialized out of thin air. Horsrik and his startled men backpedal down the slope.</context>
      <utterance>Now be it known throughout the kingdom, that the Princess, having been chosen by a deed of fortune and destiny --</utterance>
   <speaker>HORSRIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No fire, I beg you. Galen raises his hands in a menacing gesture.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's enough for Horsrik and company: he and the soldiers depart.</context>
      <utterance>Be gone!</utterance>
   <speaker>HORSRIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only one man remains behind the challenge the young sorcerer: Tyrian. He draws his sword.</context>
      <utterance>I declare these proceedings duly ordained...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew I'd find you here. Well, I'm not as sentimental as some. The kingdom, every one of us, need this sacrifice. If you intend to interfere, you'll have to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen draws his own sword. As it emerges into the night air it seems imbued with a blue phosphorescence.</context>
      <utterance>I've got plenty of reasons to kill you that have nothing to do with this sacrifice.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth twists around in her chains.</context>
      <utterance>Most impressive. Can you use it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen starts to reply, but as soon as his attention wavers, Tyrian is lunging toward him, sword point directed at his neck. Galen barely manages to parry the thrust before Tyrian is at him again, blade swinging toward his knees. Galen drops the tip of his sword to catch the blow. When the two steel edges connect, sparks fly. In a series of thrusts and counter- thrusts, each accompanied by a shower of sparks, Tyrian backs Galen up the mountain.</context>
      <utterance>Let it be! Please! Tyrian is right -- it's our only hope!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sure enough, at that moment the earth gives out a low moan and undulates in a sickening movement. Vapors begin rising from the lair.</context>
      <utterance>Tyrian -- both of you -- run! Flee! It's coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He might be right, for Galen turns and bolts across the slope. When he reaches the post with Tyrian two steps behind, he whirls and brings his blade down on Princess Elspeth's chains. The chains part in an explosion of sparks.</context>
      <utterance>In a trice! This is no swords-man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Princess darts from the piling as Tyrian swoops down to continue the attack. Galen dodges and the stake catches Tyrian's blow. The earth shakes again. Galen glances at the Princess.</context>
      <utterance>Run! Get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth is not running away down the mountain. Instead she is walking, slowly and deliberately, right into the smoking cave. Swoosh! Tyrian's sword comes down again. The dismayed sorcerer ducks back and Tyrian's blade again bites deep into the wood.</context>
      <utterance>No! Stop! What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's now or never. Elspeth is no longer in sight. Galen grits his teeth, grasps the sword with two hands and swings it as hard as he can in a wide arc. The blade never even slows down as it sails right through the post, lopping it clean off. The glowing sword flashes above Galen's head and eagerly buries itself in Tyrian's chest. The King's man is as startled by the amputated piling as he is by his own death. His eyes roll up in his head, his knees buckle and he topples backward -- the blade sliding free.</context>
      <utterance>You've failed, my friend, and I thank the gods for it. Come out from behind that post.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He winces in pain.</context>
      <utterance>You know what we have to do.  We have to leave Urland.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seems miles away. She turns aside, on the verge of tears. Simon is standing there, still holding the sword hilt.</context>
      <utterance>Not because of what happened. I brought you here -- it didn't work -- now I'm taking you away. Do you understand?  You said you loved me. Is it true? If it is, it's the only good we've done. Let's not lose that too.  Galen?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen looks at him; he has heard everything. He sits up and fondly regards Valerian.</context>
      <utterance>She's right. What kind of a life could you have here? It's too late for me, but you're young enough.  You know what I think? Magic is dying out, fading from the world. But that makes me happy. That means the dragon will be dying too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tucks the pouch away, throws some clothes on top and ties the satchel shut.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I was just thinking -- poor Hodge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FOREST PATH - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valerian and Galen trudge along side by side.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's your leg?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurts. That thing was small, but its teeth were sharp.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is small consolation, and Galen sighs.</context>
      <utterance>At least you killed it. You got all the young.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the big one's alive. Somewhere down in that burning lake.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches out to take his hand. But Galen is no longer at her side. She stops and looks back.</context>
      <utterance>Don't think about it. You had your fight, and you're still here. That's more than anyone else can say. Let's think about what lies ahead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen comes up with what he's looking for -- the leather sack. When he replies, it is not to her, but to Ulrich:</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You old trickster! The burning water! The lake of fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He regards her with astonishment.</context>
      <utterance>Galen, what are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had it planned. He knew this was going to happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did? What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads back down the trail, leaving his belongings on the road.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to go back, I want to talk to him!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hurries after him.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Galen pays no attention. In a burst of speed and fury, Valerian comes up behind and tackles him.</context>
      <utterance>Galen, stop! Please, I beg you!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen waves the leather pouch in Valerian's face.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! I won't let you kill yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps up and runs to the mouth of the lair.</context>
      <utterance>He couldn't walk -- he knew he couldn't make the journey. So he had us make the journey for him! Don't you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tackles him again.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, all right. You're going in there, I'm going too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Valerian springs to her feet and starts into the lair.</context>
      <utterance>What? Why? No you're not, this is my job. Absolutely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen pauses long enough to snatch up a discarded torch near the remains of the wooden stake, then charges after her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not afraid. And you're not going to stop me. After all -- I've been a man longer than you have.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down and down they go. Soon they reach Elspeth's body.</context>
      <utterance>Stay close.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she pulls the torch from his hand and goes over to see.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He darts off. In the flickering torchlight Valerian can see the Princess' remains all too clearly. She suppresses a scream.</context>
      <utterance>All right. Wait here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. The torch reveals several passages. She doesn't know which one to take.</context>
      <utterance>Galen? Galen? Where are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ulrich! Magister! Over here! I can see you! Over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The apprentice throws himself at his master's feet.</context>
      <utterance>Sic redit magus ex terra mortis.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonder of wonders -- you're back! I thank the powers that made me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad to see you, too. You didn't bring along anything to eat, by any chance?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Food?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? Oh well, no time anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GALEN &amp; ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ulrich raises Galen to his feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come along. There's much to be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, I have something to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs his head. Ulrich regards him steadily.</context>
      <utterance>No it can't. Listen: I thought I was a sorcerer -- but I wasn't. I thought I had power -- but I didn't. I thought I was you -- but I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads the way across the rocks to the shore and into the tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>Well said. Now hurry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dragon lifts its wings as if to menace them, then flaps twice and is airborne. The thing shoots overhead and, with a rush of wind, flies off into the gloom.</context>
      <utterance>Draco draconis...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen runs to her. They embrace. When they look up, Ulrich is at their side.</context>
      <utterance>Galen!</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen's hand locates the jewel under his shirt. He finds himself reluctant to part with it. With a hurricane howl, a column of flame touches down nearby and rushes toward them. They stagger back as the dragon sweeps past.</context>
      <utterance>Where's my amulet? Give it to me, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen hands his treasure over. Ulrich closes his hand around it.</context>
      <utterance>Be quick!</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen and Valerian approach. The old man's hand is suffused with an internal glow. Behind them, the dragon is turning for another pass.</context>
      <utterance>Come close to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be afraid. You have served me with great courage. Now you must show me you have even more.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voices seem to be coming from a huge distance. Starlike gleams whiz by, and fleeting glimpses of half-recognizable faces and forms. The wizard's eyes are like glittering crystals. Tiny motes and planetoids dance in the hairs of his beard. He seems wreathed in luminescence.</context>
      <utterance>Anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must destroy the amulet, and me along with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You brought me from the flames, you must send me back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dangles the amulet in front of Galen. Even more reluctantly than he let it go, he takes it back.</context>
      <utterance>When the time comes, you'll understand. Here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dips Simon's head under water.</context>
      <utterance>Make haste, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the background, half the congregation is staring through the burned-out walls, fervently praying and crossing themselves, wondering if they'll ever see the sun again. A cry goes up: a shape crosses the solar corona, wheels over the village and streaks away toward the mountains -- the dragon.</context>
      <utterance>Now be thou baptized in the name of the Father, Son and Holy Ghost. May the Lord our God light our way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. Do as he said. Smash it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if it means killing him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts the chunk of stone. Galen grabs for it.</context>
      <utterance>You heard what he said.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! You can't!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The members of the congregation fall to their knees.</context>
      <utterance>Let us pray.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen and Valerian look at each other. She takes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>We thank thee, Lord, for this divine deliverance. Verily is thy presence amongst us, fully manifest in this, thy great work.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen turns and leads Valerian away. They disappear into the mist.</context>
      <utterance>Arise, children of the Lord and forsake evermore the pagan mysteries. Rejoice in the true power of the Christian God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to rest?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You miss Ulricn.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the amulet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That too.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me. I'm glad it's gone. I'm glad you did what you did.  You may not be a sorcerer, Galen, but I love you anyway. I don't regret anything that happened. I just wish --</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you...!?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Galen climbs aboard. He reaches out to help her up.</context>
      <utterance>No. It must have been wandering loose. Or wild.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. I just wished for a horse and here it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks for a moment, then lets him help her up. Galen touches the horse's flanks with his heels and they ride off.</context>
      <utterance>You don't want to wish it gone, do you?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
