<movie id="180" title="Drive">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Plain Jane cheap like you asked for but with a hundred and sixty horsepower inside. You get any sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Shannon grins we feel the familiarity between them.</context>
      <utterance>Not this week.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can offer you some Halcyon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head past more cars -- Fords, Dodges, Buicks -- until they arrive at a plain looking Impala.</context>
      <utterance>Won't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver casts his eyes over the unimpressive vehicle then holds out his hand for the keys.</context>
      <utterance>There she is. Silver Impala. Most popular car in the state of California...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BASKETBALL COMMENTARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver reaches under the seat and pulls out a small handheld scanner. He switches it on, tuning it to the right frequency. Crackling police dispatches are interspersed with the basketball commentary now.</context>
      <utterance>...This is some comeback from the Clippers! Only a few minutes ago they looked dead and buried!...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SCANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...9 Adam 81, what is your current location?...Repeat, what is your current location?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASKETBALL COMMENTARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of the corner of his eye Driver sees two MEN approach. He doesn't react, expecting them. They cut through the fence with bolt cutters and approach the main building. Driver watches them pull on their masks, then one of them takes out a shotgun and blasts the lock to the front door. Instantly the alarm shrills. The only thing Driver does is to turn on his stop watch.</context>
      <utterance>...Another unbelievable three pointer from Davis and the Clippers are within five!...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASKETBALL COMMENTARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stop watching keeps ticking away, the siren blaring, the commentary continuing, the police scanner crackling. The storefront is hidden in shadow, impossible to tell what's going on inside. Driver looks at his stop watch. Almost three minutes. One of the masked men emerges now, carrying a duffel bag. He hurries over and gets in the back of Driver's car without a word. There's no sign of the other robber.</context>
      <utterance>...Time out Knicks...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>POLICE SCANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver swings sharply into 4th Street now, crossing the L.A. River again, heading back in the same direction he came.</context>
      <utterance>...Attention all units...211...Superstore on Traction Avenue...Suspects headed Eastbound on 1st Street...Driving a Silver Impala...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SCANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up ahead, the lights of Downtown L.A. glitter against the night sky. Hovering between the neon green glow of the skyscrapers Driver sees the red and white glint of a police helicopter. He switches off his headlights, turning left on Santa Fe Avenue.</context>
      <utterance>...Airships dispatched...Downtown and Boyle Heights...All units standby. Repeat, all units standby...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BASKETBALL COMMENTARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The passing head-lamps light up Driver's face. There's not a trace of emotion in his eyes -- even when he spots a patrol car approaching in the opposite direction.</context>
      <utterance>...Three thirteen left on the clock. Dunleavy calls a time out and it's the Clippers by one...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASKETBALL COMMENTARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two cars pass each other slowly. Driver sees the cops in the Black-and-White peering at the Impala as they head past. He turns down the basketball game and focuses on the scanner.</context>
      <utterance>...Buckle up your seat belts Clippers fans. This game really is too close to call...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SCANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the back seat, the armed robbers wait nervously for the police dispatch to respond.</context>
      <utterance>...This is 1 David 16...Silver Impala headed South on Broadway and Pico...Couldn't get a look at her license plates...Appears to be only one occupant...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SCANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As soon as he hears this Driver swerves sharply into the next street.</context>
      <utterance>...1 David 16...why don't you check her out...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>POLICE SCANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver threads his way through the vehicles in front of him, so smooth and effortless it's hard to tell how fast he's going. He glances up as he hears the dull rumble of a police chopper overhead. The helicopter is almost directly above him, swinging its search-beam back and forth to get a lock on his position. Driver pushes the car as fast as it will go, but there's no way of outrunning the chopper. Blue light floods the asphalt around him as he guns down Figueroa.</context>
      <utterance>...1 David 11...suspect headed West on Pico...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SCANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even now Driver doesn't panic, turning his attention back to the basketball game.</context>
      <utterance>All units...pursuit in progress...silver Impala...Headed North on Figueroa...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASKETBALL COMMENTARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver swerves sharply towards the sparkling lights of the Staples Centre.</context>
      <utterance>Thornton pulls up from behind the arc, misses. Rebound New York. One eighteen to play...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BASKETBALL COMMENTARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The jubilant commentary continues, but Driver isn't listening anymore. The game has served its purpose. More fans flood into the parking lot. Dozens of cars pull out of their places.</context>
      <utterance>...Gordon back to Davis...Davis for three...This is unbelievable!...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASKETBALL COMMENTARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver glances at the armed robbers and nods. It's time. They climb out of the car, merging in with the crowd. Driver watches them disappear, then slips on a Clippers cap, climbs out of the Impala himself and heads towards another car.</context>
      <utterance>...What a remarkable comeback...Outplayed for most of the game, the Clippers have shown incredible resilience...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver heads off, disinterested in the negotiations.</context>
      <utterance>...This is a whole new thing. He taps the fender any faster than fifty not only will she roll, she'll roll all the way to Baja.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A high risk stunt like that's worth at least a thousand five.</utterance>
   <speaker>AD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't go higher than a thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For all his charm we sense something of the hustler about Shannon.</context>
      <utterance>Done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver doesn't seem to care, focussed on the job.</context>
      <utterance>I managed to get them up to five hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND UNIT DIRECTOR O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon joins the rest of the crew, looking on.</context>
      <utterance>Camera ready, sound ready...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>2ND UNIT DIRECTOR O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some clapping and cheering breaks out, but most the crew couldn't care less, returning to their cell-phones and shot lists. Only Shannon seems interested in Driver, limping over and helping him out of his battered Black-and-White.</context>
      <utterance>...And CUT!...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver spits out some fake candyglass from the shattered windscreen.</context>
      <utterance>Nice work, officer...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you go, Mr. Rose.  Egg rolls, chicken chow mein, five flavor shrimp and Peking duck.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they remember the chop sticks?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the way the waiter hurries off we get a sense of Bernie's power and authority. He turns back to Shannon, resuming their conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't look like it, sir. Let me run and get the guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You run a perfectly good business. Why would you want to change now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie shakes his head but clearly has a soft spot for Shannon.</context>
      <utterance>You know how much my business made last year? Thirty Grand. Takes me six months to build a car and a couple of seconds for these jerks to write it off on a stunt that doesn't even make it into the movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me talk you through it first.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds like a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't have to be. The big money teams burn through three, four million a year but that's `cause they're using half a dozen test drivers and a stable of cars.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know anything about car racing but I assume there's a reason for that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, but it's not the only way. All I need is a hard-used stock car. We start off with the small-town action then work our way up. There's close to two thousand events out there and once we make the Show we're talking millions.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>`Millions'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie looks at his friend in mild exasperation then turns away as the waiter returns with a handful of chop sticks.</context>
      <utterance>There's a fortune to be made. Sponsorship. TV deals. We'll even name the team after you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Ron. You sure you don't want any of this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie waits for the waiter to leave then continues.</context>
      <utterance>No, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon hesitates but only for a second.</context>
      <utterance>You still haven't given me a number?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four hundred and thirty thousand dollars. Bernie Rose can't help grinning at his nerve.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I wouldn't come to you unless I was sure about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Shannon. How can you be sure? What have you got these big money teams don't have?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they got half a dozen Drivers you told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at his friend with quiet conviction.</context>
      <utterance>Not like this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been working with this guy a long time - I've never seen anything like it. I had the money I'd back him myself... Bernie Rose considers him quietly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't have the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything I own is in metal. I had to sell my Bullit car the other day just to pay the gas bill. I'm telling you, Bernie, put this kid behind a wheel there's nothing he can't do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon's about to reply when they're interrupted by a big bull of a man with a gruff voice.</context>
      <utterance>And what happens to my money if this kid gets hit by a bus?</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing eating Chink food in my restaurant?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a Jew doing running a Pizzeria? Worst fucking pizza in LA by the way. How hard is it to bake a loaf of bread?</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon smiles, intimidated by Nino, giving up his seat respectfully. Nino doesn't even acknowledge him.</context>
      <utterance>It's the fucking water in this city...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were supposed to be out of town anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm back.  Take a hike. I need to talk to my partner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be polite, Nino. I invited him here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie senses things are only going to get worse and dismisses Shannon gently.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry. How you doing, Shannon? How's the fucking leg?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll think about it but I want to meet your guy first...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which floor, ma'am?...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver presses the fourth floor button even though it's already lit. The doors shut and the elevator starts to climb. Driver stares out quietly. Irene takes a glance at him, feeling awkward in the silence. She looks relieved as the elevator doors finally open. Driver steps aside to let her out first.</context>
      <utterance>Fourth please...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver looks at her just long enough not to seem impolite, then continues down the corridor, not even glancing back.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, ma'am...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like a chocolate bar. You're gonna have to tell me if that's fast or slow `cause I got no idea... Shannon smiles to himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't slow...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STOCK CAR OWNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Told you she was a beauty...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie Rose pays no attention to their banter, his eyes fixed thoughtfully on the stock car as it finally slows to a stop.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe where you come from...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver shrugs. Shannon grins, turning to Bernie now.</context>
      <utterance>Looks a little long in the tooth to me. Think we should take her home?...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One look at Bernie Rose and Driver senses the power and authority behind his deceptively gentle eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Bernie, this is the driver I been telling you about...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old mobster holds out his hand, meeting Driver's gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Bernie's thinking of investing in our race team...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My hands are a little dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. So are mine...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STOCK CAR OWNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't see much wrong with that. You beat the fastest lap by more than half a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie's still studying him.</context>
      <utterance>You might wanna take a look at the suspension before we go again.  Nice to meet you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes stay on each other, then Driver follows the stock car owner and his mechanics back to the car. Bernie Rose stares after him quietly, thinking to himself. Shannon can feel he's getting interested.</context>
      <utterance>You too...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna give me the four?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you three for seventy percent...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you want me to put them?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver places the bags on the kitchen counter.</context>
      <utterance>Just over there. Thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like something to drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A glass of water?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pours him a glass of water and hands it to him.</context>
      <utterance>Sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks out of the room, leaving Driver alone with Benicio. The little boy stares at him fixedly. 36a INT. BATHROOM/ IRENE'S APARTMENT - DAY. 36a Irene closes the bathroom door behind her, looking at herself in the mirror, feeling a little uncertain.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me a second...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just move to LA?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I been here a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And before that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here and there...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver takes in the significance of this, then looks back at her.</context>
      <utterance>That's Benicio's father.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>What do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I drive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a limo driver?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, for the movies...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode>INCREDULOUSLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean all those car chases and stuff? He nods, a little embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seems thrown by her concern.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that dangerous?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just part-time. Most days I work in a garage.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reseda Boulevard.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should tell Benicio you're a stunt guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He interested in that kind of stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles softly and he realizes she's teasing him.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't all little boys?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irene takes the remote and changes the channel for him. Driver watches her quietly, then drains his glass of water.</context>
      <utterance>Mama, I don't like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like another glass?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He catches the disappointment in her eyes, but she covers it with another good humored smile.</context>
      <utterance>I should get going...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thank you for your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his empty glass and walks him to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for the drink...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEARDED REDNECK OFFSCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver looks up and sees a burly REDNECK with an unkempt beard and a wrestler's physique. The redneck slides into the seat opposite him.</context>
      <utterance>Mind if I cut in?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEARDED REDNECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Shannon's buddy, right? We met last year. You drove me and my brother back from Palm Springs...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BEARDED REDNECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver doesn't seem to hear him.</context>
      <utterance>Next run we hired another wheelman - I spent six months in jail, my brother got himself killed...  He wasn't much, mind you, just family...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEARDED REDNECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thing is -</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver looks up quietly, fixing him with his icy gaze. The Redneck's smile slowly fades. He considers his response for a moment, then decides against it, standing up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEARDED REDNECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver carries on eating as if the man didn't exist.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's good to see you again...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver smiles, popping the hood. As Shannon limps out of the vehicle he sees a battered Oldsmobile drive into the forecourt. He takes one look at the owner, then runs his hand through his white hair, breaking into a friendly smile.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds like a goddamn M-16...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gorgeous day just got even nicer. How can I help you, ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a problem with my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver turns around in surprise now, recognizing Irene's voice.</context>
      <utterance>I can imagine. That thing must be older than I am...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A mischievous smile lights up Shannon's face as he watches them.</context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You boys and girls know each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're neighbors.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver ignores the sly look in the old man's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I see...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what seems to be the problem, ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either it doesn't start or it stalls.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, why don't we park her over there and take a look... Driver is still watching Irene quietly.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can come back later if you're busy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon gives Driver another sly look as he takes her car keys.</context>
      <utterance>He's busy, I'm not...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Just my opinion, but I think you should consider buying a new car...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances round and sees Benicio standing in the forecourt with Driver, watching him work on his own car now.</context>
      <utterance>That would be great...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BENICIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That thing doesn't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benicio watches him sullenly, more intrigued than he lets on.</context>
      <utterance>You think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benicio considers a moment, then turns and calls out to Irene.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Get in the car...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irene looks over in surprise, not sure what to say.</context>
      <utterance>Mama, can I go in the car?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mom said you like movies?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever see the Terminator?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benicio shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Grease?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna see where it was shot?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long has he been working for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, ma'am, your son'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon smiles to himself, sensing her interest in Driver.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean it like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We been together about five years now. He showed up out of the blue one day, no references or nothin', asking me for a job. I offered him half the wages I normally pay and he didn't even blink. Been exploiting him ever since...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode>HE GRINS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only thing he knows is cars...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares back at her in the silence, both of them looking a little uncertain.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry if I put you on the spot, you know, just showing up like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes stay on each other, the attraction palpable. Driver finally breaks the tension, making a tentative move towards the door. Irene opens it for him, looking up into his eyes. Driver knows he could kiss her, wants to, but something inside holds him back. Instead he just offers his help.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benicio sits in a dentist's chair, looking nervous. Irene sits beside him, mimicking his expression, trying to make him relax.</context>
      <utterance>You need a ride anywhere over the weekend I'm not doing much... 50a INT. DENTISTS/ NORTH HOLLYWOOD - DAY. 50a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>53 CONTINUED: 53</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He grins, looking at Driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought maybe we'd take her for a run Thursday or Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't make Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Why's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told Irene I'd drive her to Burbank.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Irene, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode>TEASING HIM</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're seeing quite a lot of the young lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're taking a long time to fix her car...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's telling him if he doesn't leave the earth alone he'll fight him. Irene calls out from her bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver looks back at the screen. Werewolves appear now, surrounding the hero.</context>
      <utterance>I'm almost ready...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like he's in trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as the fight begins the color on the TV screen flickers.</context>
      <utterance>He's okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benicio watches curiously as Driver gets off the couch and kneels beside the TV.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna show you another trick...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benicio nods. Driver suddenly gives the TV set a hard smack and the interference stops.</context>
      <utterance>This is pretty complicated. You watching?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benicio grins. Driver smiles back then looks away as he hears the phone ring. Irene walks out of her bedroom, dressed in her waitress's uniform, and answers it.</context>
      <utterance>Think you can remember that?...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver sees the look of surprise on Irene's face as she listens to the voice on the other end. The doorbell suddenly rings. Irene catches Driver's eye and asks him to open it. He heads over, checks the spy-hole, then opens the door. A YOUNG WOMAN who's sitting for Benicio walks in, looking at Driver curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?...Yes?...Yes, this is she...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>IRENE'S FRIEND</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irene's friend heads past Driver and scolds Benicio affectionately.</context>
      <utterance>Hi Cindy...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE'S FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's 8:30. Teeth. Pyjamas. TV off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver looks back at Irene now. She puts down the phone, forcing a smile but still looking distracted.</context>
      <utterance>It's not the TV. It's a DVD...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never come this way before...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a short cut...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at Driver, watching him quietly, then looks away again.</context>
      <utterance>The park looks pretty at night...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irene takes a long time to answer, still staring out of the window.</context>
      <utterance>You okay?...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to sound casual. Driver takes the news quietly, even though it hits him like a sledgehammer.</context>
      <utterance>That was my husband's lawyer on the phone. He's getting an early release...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver knows she's trying to explain herself but doesn't say anything, driving in silence. Up ahead the traffic lights turn red and the car slows to a stop. Inside, the silence is unbearable. Irene pauses, then looks at Driver. He's even more handsome in the shadowy half-light, something achingly lonely and melancholy about his stillness. She hesitates, then moves her hand towards his, brushing the back of his hand, then slipping her fingers between his. The gesture is tiny but charged with emotion. They both stare out in silence, fingers clasped, then Irene gently withdraws her hand, as if nothing's happened. Outside the lights change to green.</context>
      <utterance>I'm happy for Benicio...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His self-deprecating humor gets a chorus of laughter and agreement from the guests. Irene is standing next to her friend Cindy, looking a little uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>...I'm touched and grateful that you're all here today -- even though I know it's probably for the food not me...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Anyhow, now that I've completed my MBA in catering from Chino Business School...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads into the bedroom to take the call. The voice on the other end is accented and unfriendly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I can't hear you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard pauses, looking concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Can you hear me now, you cunt?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across the crowded room, Irene is looking for Standard. She sees him in the bedroom, switching off his phone, and heads over.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna come see me tomorrow, you understand?...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Benicio wants you to put him to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a warm smile.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was that on the phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My parole officer. He thinks he may have found me a job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns around and sees her standing there with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about the noise. I was going to leave a note under your door warning you we were having a party.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I won't complain.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes stay on each other, the music pounding in the background.</context>
      <utterance>I wish you would. Maybe the cops'd show up and send everybody home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The car works great by the way. Hasn't stalled once.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another awkward silence, so much she wants to say but can't.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, if you're hungry we got plenty of</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins at his wife, then looks over at Driver, his smile hiding whatever he feels inside.</context>
      <utterance>I thought if we emptied the trash everyone would get the message and go home...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the new neighbor, right? Benicio's told me all about you... Driver seems unsure how to respond.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a great kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard rests his hand gently on Benicio's head, still staring at Driver.</context>
      <utterance>I can't take any of the credit. He's got a great mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He tells me you drive for the movies?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be pretty good?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get by.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not like a nine to five gig, huh?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to take that?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes are still fixed on Driver.</context>
      <utterance>No, we got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to come in, join us for a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got some things to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At this hour of night?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard doesn't respond, still holding Driver's gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Standard, he's busy...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slips his arm around his son now and continues down the corridor, brushing past Driver on his way to empty the trash. Driver looks at Irene, then heads off in the same direction as Standard and Benicio to take the elevator. The two men stand there in charged silence, one emptying the trash, the other waiting for the elevator, only Benicio oblivious to the tension.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if we're still going by the time you're back you know where we are. It's good to meet you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...We paid three hundred fucking grand for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I paid for it. Out of my own pocket. Anyway, that's just the shell. You start with the shell, then you build the frame, then the motor.  I paid three hundred for that. The money goes on the inside not the outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon smiles nervously, worried Nino's going to sabotage his deal with Bernie.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck that. If I'm gonna blow three hundred I wanna make sure everyone can see it. Go waste your money on something else...</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...How about that fucking pussy mobile over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the far end of the garage Driver hears them laughing, too busy working on his car to pay any attention. Shannon opens the door of the Thunderbird and invites Nino to take a seat.</context>
      <utterance>You buy it. Shannon sell him the car...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try her out. She's more comfortable than a water bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits heavily in the car and starts prodding and pressing all the control buttons as if he wants to break them.</context>
      <utterance>I already got a fucking water bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does this fucking thing do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Windshield wipers.</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie Rose shakes his head at his partner's foul language then looks away, observing Driver quietly. Driver applies a blow torch to his car, so absorbed in his work he doesn't hear Bernie Rose approach.</context>
      <utterance>How about this little clit? I don't know whether to fuck it or drive it. Fuck it, I'll drive it...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver hears him and turns off the blow torch, standing up respectfully. Bernie Rose gives him a friendly smile.</context>
      <utterance>How you doing?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, when's our first race?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's something gently challenging in his gaze.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna be ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope so...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver smiles but doesn't respond. Bernie Rose finds him as hard to talk to as everyone else. Across the garage, Nino sits in the T-Bird with Shannon, still fucking with him. Bernie watches them.</context>
      <utterance>Cautious man. Like myself. Don't wanna make promises you can't keep...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ever tell you how we met?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's about to continue when they're interrupted by a familiar voice.</context>
      <utterance>I did some producing back in the 80's. Interesting pictures. Kind of European. Shannon arranged the cars for us and did all the stunts. I knew he was overcharging me but I loved having him around. His next business venture he tried the same thing with some of Nino's friends they broke his spine. He never had much luck...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver turns around and sees Irene's husband, Standard, heading towards him with a confident smile.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a minute? I want to -</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie Rose barely raises his voice but it's full of quiet menace and authority. Standard pauses, stung, but instinctively senses this is someone you don't mess with.</context>
      <utterance>We're talking...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie Rose watches him leave with a look of contempt, then turns back to Driver with a smile, resuming their conversation.</context>
      <utterance>I'll wait outside...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes stay on each other with just a hint of tension.</context>
      <utterance>The reason I'm telling you this is because he's got a lot invested in you. So do I...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver nods. Bernie Rose studies him a moment, then finally walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Anything you need just let me know...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Irene told me you'd fixed our car. How much do I owe you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver senses the quiet pride in his voice, and lets it go.</context>
      <utterance>I do worry. I like to pay my debts.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard counts out some bills from his tattered wallet, his eyes lowered.</context>
      <utterance>Call it fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking of trading her in for a new car. Something fast and cheap.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't have both.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even though he smiles Driver senses just a hint of tension on his handsome face.</context>
      <utterance>Alright then, fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver isn't sure what he's getting at.</context>
      <utterance>You must think I'm an asshole?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles ironically, his gaze still fixed on Driver.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I am. Six months inside for holding somebody else's stolen shit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a thinly veiled message that he's back and here to stay. Driver stares back at him when Shannon emerges from the garage with Bernie Rose and Nino, calling out.</context>
      <utterance>I appreciate what you did for my family when I was away but I don't plan to fuck up a second time...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver and Standard stare at each other a moment longer then Driver breaks off.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, kid! Come say goodbye, the money people are leaving!...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver walks off, leaving Standard alone with his thoughts. Shannon watches Standard curiously as Driver approaches.</context>
      <utterance>See you around...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Irene's husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode>GRINNING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I tell you about married women? Nino can't resist another dig at Shannon.</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck do you know about married women?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they continue their banter, Driver glances at Standard. He's walking back to his car, dialling someone on his cell phone.</context>
      <utterance>Can you for once say something without the word fuck in it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes stay on each other, oblivious to the noise.</context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We haven't seen you around in a while. You must have been pretty busy?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, glancing at the tables she's supposed to serve.</context>
      <utterance>You look pretty busy yourself...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I get you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His concern touches her and makes her uncomfortable at the same time.</context>
      <utterance>I already ate. I just wanted to see how you were?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver stares back at her with his intense gaze.</context>
      <utterance>We're okay. Standard thinks he may have found a job so I can give up my night shift...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the way she says it she could almost be talking about herself.</context>
      <utterance>Benicio misses you...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He keeps asking me to invite you for dinner...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His gentle gaze is finally too much for her. She grins, excusing herself.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's only when she has her back turned that we see how hard this is for her. Driver watches her walk away, lost in thought.</context>
      <utterance>I better serve some food...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you move?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Benicio?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver glances at Benicio. He looks terrified. Standard raises his head painfully and looks at his son.</context>
      <utterance>He's right here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver watches the boy struggling to hold back his tears.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, Benicio. I'm okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode>GENTLY</mode>
      <context>Benicio nods, too choked-up to speak. Standard turns to Driver.</context>
      <utterance>Don't say anything to your mother, you understand? This is between you and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I use your bathroom to clean up? I don't want Irene to come home and see me like this...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's still shaken but tries to pass it off with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Sorry about getting all this blood everywhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver watches him, unconvinced.</context>
      <utterance>Fucking punks took me by surprise...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucking punks didn't look like they needed to... Standard looks at him in surprise now.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver doesn't answer, waiting for him to continue. Standard hesitates, still not sure whether to trust him.</context>
      <utterance>You saw them, huh?...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever been inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I owed some protection money in the joint. Driver begins to see how worried he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want twenty thousand. I told them I couldn't pay so they want me to do a job for them...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard stares back at him.</context>
      <utterance>Is that why you need a car?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say you were inside for?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, then he finally opens up.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver stares at him in surprise now, more concerned than he shows.</context>
      <utterance>It's a pawn shop in the valley. I tried to back out tonight, they said they'd come after Irene and Benicio next time...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you take them away?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where would I go? Irene finds out I fucked up again I'll lose everything... He sounds upset, angry with himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver stares at his battered face and the blood stains on his t- shirt, then walks out of the bathroom to check on Benicio.</context>
      <utterance>This lousy job's my only way out...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little boy nods without turning round, still frightened by his ordeal.</context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benicio shakes his head, trying to hide his tears. Driver heads over, then stops as he notices something in Benicio's hand. The little boy is clutching it as if he's afraid to let go.</context>
      <utterance>You want something to drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benicio holds out his hand to reveal a small bullet. Driver stares at it, then looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>What have you got there?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who gave you that?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver gazes at the little boy's frightened face in concern now, his eyes faraway, thinking to himself.</context>
      <utterance>One of those men. He told me not to lose it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard sits next to Driver, holding his ground even though he's clearly intimidated by the Albanian.</context>
      <utterance>I've got you to do this fucking job for me, why do I need to pay someone else?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll pay him out of what's left of my share. I can't do something like this on my own.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins, looking at Driver now. Blanche doesn't even seem to hear them, hung-over from the previous night.</context>
      <utterance>You got Blanche...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look like you're hard to work with?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if we understand each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver stares at him quietly, finding it hard to conceal his contempt.</context>
      <utterance>What's to understand? It's my score. Either you sign on or you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blanche gets up from the table before Cook can respond.</context>
      <utterance>I drive. That's all I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've forgotten my Coke.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll bring it. Sit down.  Standard, why don't you hire a fucking taxi cab?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard looks worried, trying to diffuse the tension.</context>
      <utterance>He didn't mean it like that, man...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver looks him calmly in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>So, what does he mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard seems surprised by Driver's professional patter. So does Cook. Even Blanche looks interested for once.</context>
      <utterance>You tell me where we start, where we're headed, where we'll be going afterwards. I don't take part, I don't carry weapons, I drive...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard hesitates, but has no choice. As he leaves to fetch Blanche her drink, Cook starts to write something down on the palm of his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Standard, get Blanche her coca cola.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the palm of his hand to Driver, the words Fuck Off written in marker pen.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, here's the deal. This much for Blanche, this much for that asshole minus what he owes me, and this much for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver looks at him, all his instincts telling him to walk away, but he stays where he is, thinking of Irene and Benicio.</context>
      <utterance>You still interested?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver stares back at him with his clear blue eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Anything else?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cook looks surprised at first, then laughs at his nerve.</context>
      <utterance>We do this job he's paid his debt. You leave him and his family alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you say, boss...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I was such a jerk the first time we met. We're at this party and I see the most beautiful girl I ever laid eyes on and I walk over and say, `Hello Miss, my name's Standard Guzman'. She takes one look at me and asks, `Where's the deluxe version?'...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode>HE LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It took me like a minute to get it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He ruffles his son's hair then pours himself another shot of tequila. Irene notices he's drinking, turning to Driver.</context>
      <utterance>You don't get it either do you, Benicio? Hope you didn't inherit your Papa's brains.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like some more chicken?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes stay on each as she serves him. Standard sees the look between them but his only reaction is to drain his glass and tuck into his food.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now this is what I call a deluxe chicken. Irene and I are gonna open a restaurant together once I raise the money. That's why she's working in that Mexican joint. Figure out how it's done. She's got more ambition than anyone I know, more smarts too...  We're gonna drive all those fucking Mexicans out of business -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse my language, Benicio...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the movie going?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irene looks at Standard as he pours himself another drink.</context>
      <utterance>Fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think that's enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, we're celebrating. I've got my family around me and our new friend...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you working on anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop asking the poor guy all these</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, I will. This time next week I'm gonna take you and Benicio away with me... Irene stops and looks at him in surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His quiet confidence concerns her even more.</context>
      <utterance>Where you wanna go, Benicio?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Disneyland.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget Disneyland. I'm gonna take you and your mother away from this bullshit city -</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Benicio, it's time for bed -</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your papa's got it all figured out -</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Benicio, you heard me -</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard gets up from the table, lifting Benicio up in his arms and carrying him back to his bedroom. Driver watches them. Even in this kind of mood Standard's clearly devoted to his son. Irene waits until they're gone, then turns back to Driver.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. I'll take him...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates, torn, then looks up at him again, needing to confide in someone.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver sees the deep concern in her eyes and feels even more torn. Irene gets up, clearing away some plates.</context>
      <utterance>Every time he makes that speech about taking me and Benicio away from here he's in some kind of trouble...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to make light of it but doesn't sound convincing. Out of his window he sees Blanche cross the street and enter the pawn shop and looks even more nervous now.</context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Irene and Benicio think the world of you, you know that, right?... Driver glances at him, sensing his anxiety.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard's still staring ahead, but Driver can sense his fear.</context>
      <utterance>Say something happens to me, you think you could find a way to take care of them?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standard considers a moment, then shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>It's not too late...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He forces a smile, slips on his sunglasses, then finally opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta do this for them...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got five minutes...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDARD</speaker>
      <mode>GRINNING</mode>
      <context>Driver watches him cross the street with a strong sense of foreboding. Standard enters the pawn shop. Driver starts his stopwatch now, listening to the seconds tick away. He casts his eyes around the street, observing the smallest details -- the number plates of other vehicles; the windows of overlooking buildings. The white hot sun blazes down, reflecting on the pawn shop windows, hiding everything inside. The police scanner crackles but picks up no activity. Driver listens to his stop watch, in his own world. He starts the engine and sets off, cruising slowly past the pawn shop, heading for the corner where he told Standard he'd be waiting. He pulls over by the curb when suddenly he notices something. Parked a hundred yards down the road he sees another vehicle glinting in the sunlight. To the ordinary eye it's no different from the other cars parked nearby, but to Driver it stands out. For one, it's a Chrysler. Secondly, it has reinforced bumpers and racing tires. Driver's stopwatch shows four minutes now. He looks away from the Chrysler, gazing at the doors of the pawn shop, expecting Standard and Blanche to burst out at any moment. But there's no sign of them. The seconds tick away. Five minutes. Driver hesitates, all his instincts telling him to drive off, but he stays where he is, thinking of Irene. Suddenly he sees Standard and Blanche emerge from the pawn shop, Standard clutching a big black gym bag in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you in four...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLANCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are literally stacks of hundred dollar bills crammed inside the gym bag. Driver catches her reaction in the mirror, but his attention is focussed on the Chrysler. Up ahead, at an intersection, the lights turn red. Driver thinks about running them, but decides against it, braking sharply. The Chrysler draws up beside him, its windows glinting in the sunlight.</context>
      <utterance>...Christ, there wasn't supposed to be this much money!...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver ignores her, still watching the Chrysler out of the corner of his eye. The lights change to green but Driver doesn't move. Nor does the Chrysler. Behind them, other cars start honking their horns. Suddenly Driver roars off, swerving left at speed. The Chrysler reacts, screeching off in pursuit. Driver floors the gas. On speed and power his vehicle may be no match for the Chrysler, but in traffic the odds are even. He weaves his way past the slower cars, putting obstacles between himself and the Chrysler. The pursuing car matches him move for move, staying on his tail. In the back seat, Blanche looks terrified, buckling herself in.</context>
      <utterance>Move for Chrissakes!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much did Cook tell you you could expect to net?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at the bag, staring at how much more money there is. Driver switches on the cheap TV set with the remote, flicking through the news channels. There's no mention of the robbery yet. He zips up the bag and heads out.</context>
      <utterance>Forty Grand...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blanche nods, too shaken to protest.</context>
      <utterance>Stay here. Don't answer the door...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BENICIO'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver hears the tremor in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Benicio?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your mom there?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BENICIO'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>85a INT. IRENE'S APARTMENT/ ECHO PARK - DAY. 85a In the living room we can see Irene sitting on the couch with a male and female POLICE OFFICER, looking dazed, taking in the news of Standard's death.</context>
      <utterance>She's talking to the police...</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Driver pauses, still on the phone to Benicio.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her I'll call later...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TV REPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver listens to the report in silence. Blanche seems upset again, confronted with the reality of what's happened.</context>
      <utterance>...The armed robber was pronounced dead at the scene. He was identified as Standard Guzman of Echo Park, Los Angeles...</utterance>
   <speaker>TV REPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver switches off the TV, staring at the blank screen in surprise. He turns to Blanche.</context>
      <utterance>...Other details are unclear but the owner of the pawn shop told reporters that the robber had no accomplices and that the items he'd taken had been recovered. In other news...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The guy saw you grab the money and jump in the car -- why didn't he say anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've no idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any idea there'd be another car waiting?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BLANCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already told you everything - Driver suddenly slaps her -- hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his hand to slap her again and this time she talks, tears welling in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You just got a little kid's father killed. You think I won't hurt you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver stares at her quietly, beginning to put the pieces together in his head.</context>
      <utterance>...Cook told me another car would hold us up...but he never said anything about this much money or anyone getting killed...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods guiltily.</context>
      <utterance>You were gonna rip us off and split the take?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you known him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a couple months. We were fooling around. I've never been mixed up in anything like this -</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know his real name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told me it was Chris, but I just called him Cook.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, terrified, tears running down her face.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to take me to him right now, you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver nods distractedly, his mind racing. Blanche heads over to the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>....Can I go wash up?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All he hears is silence on the other end.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me?...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans back against a car.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess it's done now...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How big's the take?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One million I guess...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks dazed by the thought of so much money.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better bring it over.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hurt. I need a doctor to patch me up...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver looks up at him warily from Shannon's pull out bed.</context>
      <utterance>...Looks like you got more metal inside you than a ten ton truck...  You'd be better off with a mechanic not a medic...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc picks up his bottle of scotch from among his bowls of Peroxide and Betadine, takes a drink, then offers it to Driver.</context>
      <utterance>Relax. Just having my fun with you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver shakes his head, closing his eyes. Shannon watches him quietly, concerned for him but also curious about the money.</context>
      <utterance>Take a hit off that. Chances are you'll need it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do with the cash?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon hesitates, but can't help himself.</context>
      <utterance>It's safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver doesn't answer, gritting his teeth as Doc pulls out the largest shard of glass.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to look after it for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just think what we could do with all that</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two guys just tried to kill me for it. I want to find out who it belongs to first... Shannon nods, coming back down to earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy Cook got a real name?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Chris. Probably not...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll ask Bernie if he's heard of him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver doesn't reply, his eyes fixed on the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>I wish you'd talked to me first...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lotta guys fall for other mens' wives, but you're the only one I know robs a joint to make it up to the husband...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon looks tense but tries to hide it. From next door they can hear the sound of raised voices. Bernie Rose grabs the TV remote and turns up the volume to drown out his neighbors.</context>
      <utterance>No, thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've been going at it ever since they moved in. She's such a nice lady but it's a lousy Shidach. It's a wonder they haven't killed each other...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode>A BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what's your interest in the Seventh Heaven? Shannon doesn't understand, looking confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even though they're close, Shannon's wary of giving away too much information.</context>
      <utterance>It's a strip joint on La Cienega. Your friend Cook runs it. Why're you curious about him all of a sudden?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend of mine owes him some money. I was wondering if you knew him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know him. He's a crazy Albanian. If I were your friend I'd pay up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wake me up this early this friend must be a close friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode>HESITATING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's our car by the way?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're all set for next month.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And our driver?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's doing great.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon smiles back but Bernie senses how distracted he is.</context>
      <utterance>That's what you should worry about...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want my advice? Let your friend work it out for himself. Don't take pills for other people's headaches...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode>HE GRINS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got twenty minutes? I need you to run down to the market and get me some milk...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cook moved office again?</utterance>
   <speaker>STRIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver smiles gratefully, then heads towards an office at the end of the corridor. He knocks on the door. A voice calls back.</context>
      <utterance>That one over there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COOK O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver takes a hammer out of his jacket, then starts turning the door handle as if he can't get in.</context>
      <utterance>It's open...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hears Cook striding impatiently towards the door now. He waits, then suddenly kicks the door open, right in Cook's face. Before Cook can recover, Driver storms into the office, smashing him across the shoulder with the hammer. Cook collapses in a heap. Driver's about to hit him again, when he sees that Cook's left hand is broken and there are cuts and bruises on his face. Someone's clearly given him a beating since the robbery.</context>
      <utterance>It's open, goddamit!...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should've figured you for a shill. Who were you fronting for?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver smashes the hammer into Cook's right hand now, breaking it too. Cook screams. Some of the strippers have gathered at the door but Driver couldn't care less.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you -</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose money am I holding?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver smashes the hammer into the metal plates supporting Cook's left hand. He screams like a stuck pig.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. They'll come get it. You don't know who you're fucking with -</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's money am I holding?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The strippers look stunned and riveted at the same time. Driver bends over Cook and rifles through his pockets. Finally he finds what he's looking for. Cook's cell phone. He scrolls down the call log and finds the same number appearing again and again.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could, but your boss won't be happy when he finds out you've kept him waiting... Tan Suit looks curious now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask what this is about?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have something that belongs to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that would be?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a pause on the other line now.</context>
      <utterance>A million dollars...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAN SUIT O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please hold...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NINO O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice is unmistakable. Driver stares quietly.</context>
      <utterance>You have something that fucking belongs to me?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems that way...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're calling me why? You expect me to buy my fucking stuff back from you?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not selling. I give you a time and place, you come collect your stuff...</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do you get out of it?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nino's thinking to himself, looking more concerned than he sounds.</context>
      <utterance>Just that. Out of it. You put a muzzle on Cook, forget your zombies at the Motel, forget we ever had this conversation...</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your partners happy with that?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have partners...</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You discuss this with anyone else?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nino begins to relax now, still calculating.</context>
      <utterance>Just you...</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not very good at this, are you?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't what I do. I'll call again with instructions... Driver switches the cell phone off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little boy nods, watching his Japanese cartoon. Irene's friend, Cindy, is also there, gazing at them both in sympathy. Irene looks up at her.</context>
      <utterance>...I'll be back before you go to bed. How's that sound?...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to be okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irene gets up to leave when the buzzer rings. She walks over and opens the door then stops in surprise. Driver stands there.</context>
      <utterance>We'll be fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him in a daze.</context>
      <utterance>You got a minute?...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares back at her in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Where have you been?...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to reach you. Standard's been -</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes stay on her, as if he's trying to tell her something more. She looks confused, staring back at him curiously when a small voice interrupts.</context>
      <utterance>I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENICIO O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver looks over at the little boy.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benicio nods. Driver keeps staring at the boy but can't find any more words of comfort. Irene watches him, still stunned. He looks back at her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about your father...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't talk now. I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him in dismay, close to tears.</context>
      <utterance>Can I give you a ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The car's working fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wants to say no but can't.</context>
      <utterance>Then let me walk you down...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver misunderstands, thinking she's talking about Standard.</context>
      <utterance>Why?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was into one of the prison gangs for a lot of money. He was trying to protect you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks faster now, striding towards the elevator. Driver follows her.</context>
      <utterance>Great job...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still have the money. Whatever you need - She turns around and slaps him hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you, a bank? I work for a living. I don't need your widow's pension!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell me one thing. How did he talk you into it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't talk me into anything. I've been doing this my whole life. It's what I do... She stares at him in deep disappointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns away when the elevator bell rings. The doors open, revealing TAN SUIT. Neither Driver or Irene recognizes him but we do. He smiles, pretending to look confused.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid me...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I'm supposed to be going down...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps into the elevator. Driver follows her in.</context>
      <utterance>So are we...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which floor?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tan Suit presses the button and the doors slide shut.</context>
      <utterance>Parking lot, please...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving. I want you to come with me... Irene can't believe what she's hearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's almost too stunned to speak, walking even faster now.</context>
      <utterance>You and Benicio...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy. I don't even know you -</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head, fighting her feelings for him.</context>
      <utterance>You will. Once I straighten out this thing I'm getting out for good. We'll go some place. Anywhere you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't work like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds his gaze with regret. Driver's about to respond when suddenly he catches a fleeting movement out of the corner of his eye. A beat -- then he suddenly lunges -- grabbing Irene and pulling her to the ground. In the same instant Tan Suit appears out of the darkness, opening fire with his automatic. Bullets spark as they hit the concrete floor and the other parked vehicles. Driver drags Irene behind a car now, covering her with his body as Tan Suit fires another burst. More sparks light up the darkness, the bullets penetrating the car with ease, narrowly missing Driver and Irene. Driver moves again, dragging the terrified Irene behind him. Tan Suit loses sight of them in the darkness, striding past rows of parked cars.</context>
      <utterance>Because people like you never get out. And I don't want my son to grow up like that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon takes a moment to reply, looking dazed.</context>
      <utterance>Nino's guys came after me. How did they know about Irene?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called Bernie...I asked if he could help. Him and Nino are like brothers. I told him you weren't interested in the money, that you only did it for the girl...  I wanted to make sure once you returned the money that was the end of it... Driver doesn't seem to hear him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me talk to Bernie again. They probably didn't listen to him -</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too late... Shannon says nothing now, knowing he's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna come after you to find me. You have to leave... Shannon takes this in slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver doesn't answer, but from his silence Shannon can guess.</context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna do?...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at Driver with quiet regret.</context>
      <utterance>How the fuck did this happen? We're supposed be in Charlotte or Daytona drinking champagne out of trophies and getting laid by pit lizards...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nino and Cook sit opposite him, both of Cook's hands broken now.</context>
      <utterance>...I already gave you my advice. You should have taken your money and left this guy alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not that simple, Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now that it's bounced up in your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Paolozzi, I owe you this guy. Just give me the okay and I'll -</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like taking orders, go shut the blinds. He looks at Cook's broken hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nino doesn't look at Cook, a clear indication he should do as he's told. Cook stands up, humiliated, and walks over to the windows. Bernie Rose waits for Nino to explain.</context>
      <utterance>Sun's in my eyes...</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights in the restaurant gradually fade as Cook shuts the blinds.</context>
      <utterance>...The money belonged to a half assed wiseguy from Philly. I had a tip-off he was keeping a million in a pawn shop and was gonna invest it here in LA, try to run a rival operation. I wanted to teach him a lesson...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode>INCREDULOUSLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stole from the East Coast mob?</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stole from a jumped up punk who was gonna step on our business -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where did this punk find a million dollars? You ever consider he may have consulted some higher-ups? You even bother to check? -</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't give a fuck who gave him their blessing. This is my city -</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your city? This is a big city, pal, and last time I checked we were partners! -</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are partners -</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cook sits back down at the table, having closed the blinds. Nino looks almost embarrassed for once.</context>
      <utterance>Then why the fuck didn't you come to me before you set up your dummy robbery or hired this fucking amateur?!...</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was off to the side, Bernie. I didn't wanna involve you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, now you fucked up I am involved. Anyone finds out you stole from the family they'll kill both of us -</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What family? These fucks still call me a kike to my face. I'm fifty nine years old, they pinch my cheek, treat me like a fuckin' kid. They're the reason we left New York in the first place. Decrepit old men waving us over to their dinner and domino tables to complain.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those old men gave us the funds to move out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I made them a lotta money. I made you a lotta money too... He stares at Bernie, genuinely indignant now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a hint of sympathy in Bernie's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I pay them half of everything I fucking earn and then they set up some fucking kid from Philadelphia just because he's a fucking wop!</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He calls Nino by his childhood name now, emphasizing the fact that they're both outsiders in this organization. For the first time Nino's tough guy act slips and he looks anxious.</context>
      <utterance>The money always flows up, Izzy. You know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why this driver has to go. Him, and maybe your friend Shannon, are the only two people who can tie me to the robbery.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't even bother to look at Cook.</context>
      <utterance>What about this prick?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Paolozzi -</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two friends stare at each other as if Cook didn't exist.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you asking my permission?</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at Bernie apologetically, appealing to their friendship.</context>
      <utterance>I'm asking for your help. I shoulda' come to you first, Bernie. I know that. We're a team.</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll pay you back the three hundred you spent on the race car.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares out quietly, torn.</context>
      <utterance>It's not about the money...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nino nods in gratitude.</context>
      <utterance>All right...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode>TO COOK</mode>
      <context>Cook hesitates, thinking Bernie's fucking with him for having two broken hands. He stares back dumbly and it's the final straw. Bernie suddenly grabs a stainless steel fork and rams it in his eye. As Cook screams, Bernie takes a knife and buries it in his neck. He twists the knife deeper for good measure, then with one powerful sweep of his arm clears Cook off the table. Cook's not dead yet, just writhing on the floor, choking on his own blood. Bernie Rose keeps his eyes fixed on Nino.</context>
      <utterance>Pass the salt...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>110a EXT. TRAILER/ FILM SET/ SAN PEDRO/ LOS ANGELES - MORNING. 110a The CREW are setting up for their first shot of the day. In the background we see a DIRECTOR blocking out an action scene. Driver walks past without even a glance, heading towards the make-up trailer. He opens the door and walks in, looking around the trailer until he finds what he's looking for -- the SFX mask he saw previously on the film set.</context>
      <utterance>Your turn to clean up after me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All these priceless cars, you should get better locks...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie Rose heads towards him with his hands in his coat pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Door's always open to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thinking about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for your driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You break in like this I figure it's bad news.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's bad luck. Two thousand heists in this city a year, he had to pick the wrong one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He tried to put it right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops, facing Shannon.</context>
      <utterance>Picked the wrong guy for that too. My partner's a belligerent asshole with his back against the wall...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at his old friend.</context>
      <utterance>Right now so am I. I don't take care of this I'm in big trouble...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any idea where he is?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably across the border by now. Mexico. Belize. That's where I'd go... Bernie Rose smiles, not believing a word.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just walked out on you after everything you've done for him, took all the money?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie Rose can't help grinning, fond of Shannon despite everything.</context>
      <utterance>That's gratitude, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ever tell you how long Izzy and I been friends? Since we were six. Only Jews in a neighborhood of wops. Long as I can remember he was getting me into trouble and I was getting him out of scrapes... He looks almost apologetic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone else I'd take your side...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie Rose watches him with a mixture of affection and regret.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone else I'd do the same...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon shrugs, no idea himself.</context>
      <utterance>What's this fucking kid to you anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I leave here without finding out where he is, there'll be others coming after me. I guarantee they'll be too stupid to figure out you won't talk and drag this out unnecessarily...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie Rose holds his gaze, then looks away, admiring the shiny stock car.</context>
      <utterance>Then I'm glad you got here first...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's too bad, I was getting excited about our race team, having my name all over the car. I think we could have made something of this business...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon smiles, reconciled with himself. Bernie Rose grins, and extends his hand. They shake hands firmly, like old friends, when suddenly Shannon recoils, as if he's been stung. We see now that his shirt sleeve is covered in blood, his vein cut all the way from his elbow to his wrist. He looks dazed, paralysed with shock. Bernie Rose holds a razor knife in his hand, the blade wet with Shannon's blood. He takes Shannon gently by the arm and sits him down against the boot of the stock car.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, I'd have fucked it up too...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannon stares out numbly, the life ebbing out of him. Bernie Rose watches him quietly, wiping his bloody razor with a handkerchief.</context>
      <utterance>You won't feel a thing. Close your eyes and you'll fall asleep...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bernie Rose, next apartment over -</utterance>
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know. I'm kind of busy here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's something threatening in the old mobster's eyes now. The husband moves to close the door but Bernie jams it open with his elbow, shoves him aside, then looks over at the wife.</context>
      <utterance>I heard...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman nods without meeting his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You all right, Shonda?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie doesn't give him time to finish, clamping a powerful hand on his throat.</context>
      <utterance>Get the hell out of my -</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your fucking name?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NINO O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bernie?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?...</utterance>
   <speaker>NINO O/S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the only fucking person in the world I trust. I love you, man... Bernie shakes his head, the same old apologies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver shoves his face back under the water, keeping it there until Nino's body finally stops thrashing.</context>
      <utterance>It was Bernie...Bernie Rose killed your friend not me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nino?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie Rose stares out in silence. Whatever he thinks of Nino, a part of him has died. We feel the regret in his eyes but there's no trace of emotion in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like me, you and your girlfriend are the only pieces left on the board...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd say this has gone far enough. See any reason why it should go on?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't have to...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we should talk. You know a place called the Great Wall -- out on Sherman Way?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie pauses, staring out.</context>
      <utterance>I can find it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A charged silence, then the line goes dead.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you there at one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver doesn't smile, gazing back at him across the table. Bernie Rose doesn't seem to care.</context>
      <utterance>Care for a glass?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He delivers the last line with a pointed smile, then turns away, calling over a WAITRESS.</context>
      <utterance>I can recommend the duck. Hell, I can recommend everything -- Walnut prawns, shredded beef, Velvet chicken -- but the duck's to die for...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The duck, please. For two.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waits for the waitress to leave, then turns back to Driver.</context>
      <utterance>No, thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been on a roll. Cut yourself quite a swath out there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never asked for any of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver holds his gaze, the tension palpable, laughter and conversation drifting over from the other tables.</context>
      <utterance>We usually don't. But it comes down on our heads regardless. Look at Shannon...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Question is where does that leave us?</context>
      <utterance>Anyway it's water under the bridge now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bring the cash? Driver nods. Bernie Rose studies him quietly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver hesitates, betraying a hint of concern. Bernie sees it and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me something, how does someone with no interest in money get mixed up in a heist?  Shannon told me it was because of the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. Nobody else knows about her. Just me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode>A BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still see her?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles again, looking into Driver's eyes with just a hint of sympathy.</context>
      <utterance>She's got her head screwed on right. I got two ex-wives, three kids, four grandchildren. Not one of them speaks to me now...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is what I'll do for you. You give me the money, nobody knows she exists. But it's a different matter with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like we have a problem...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes are fixed on each other, deadly enemies but kindred spirits of a kind.</context>
      <utterance>And just when we were getting to know each other...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...We shake hands, say goodbye, it's the start of your new life. Sooner or later they'll come after you. No end to it. Someone gets tired, somebody else takes their place. It goes on and on. Whatever dreams you have, whatever plans, you might as well forget `em, because this is what it's gonna be like till the day you die...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode>A BEAT</mode>
      <context>Driver stares back at him quietly.</context>
      <utterance>I just thought you should know...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you suggest I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First time I heard about you, Shannon told me you drove. Fast. That's a start... He keeps staring at Driver, then smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either that or you choke on the duck...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much does something like this cost?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine, ten thousand. If you can find one that still runs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins, then holds out his hand for the gym bag.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'll take yours. Part of our deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver reaches out to give him the bag, when suddenly Bernie's hand snakes out of his pocket, twisting a switch-blade into Driver's gut. He pulls it out, ready to stab again, but this time Driver catches his wrist, slowly forcing the knife up to his throat. Their eyes are fixed on each other for a moment, with something like regret, then the blade pierces Bernie Rose's neck, sinking deeper and deeper. Driver holds the old man in his arms as he dies. They stay like that, locked in a fatal embrace, then Driver lowers Bernie Rose gently to the ground, out of sight. Blood seeping through his shirt, Driver picks up the gym bag and puts it back in the trunk, slamming the door shut.</context>
      <utterance>Guess we won't be seeing each other again..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>164 CONTINUED: 164</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Irene stares in surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She says nothing but stays on the line. Driver continues painfully through the maze of cars.</context>
      <utterance>Don't hang up...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irene looks confused as she hears the quiet urgency in his voice, then reaches inside her handbag. Sunlight glitters on the roofs of the parked cars, dazzling Driver's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You got a pen? I need you to write something down...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irene writes down the details, looking even more confused.</context>
      <utterance>It's the license number for my car. I've left it in a parking lot on the corner of Culver and Lincoln. Section M 10...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER'S VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a bag in the trunk with some money. Keys are under the left rear wheel...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver walks with difficulty, finding it hard to breathe.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to do with it?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All around him the Chevys, Dodges, and Fords glitter in the sunlight.</context>
      <utterance>It's yours. It's safe to keep it...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blood seeps through Driver's shirt, dripping on the tarmac. Irene hears his labored breathing now, looking concerned.</context>
      <utterance>I told you, I don't need your money...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Driver's skin looks deathly pale, his eyes a haunting shade of blue. He keeps walking through the maze of cars, casting his eyes from one vehicle to the next, looking for the perfect ride.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally he spots a beautiful white Camaro up ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Just out of breath...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time we see the Echo Park fountain sparkling in the background.</context>
      <utterance>How're you doing?...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irene can no longer hold back her tears, heartbroken. Driver stops in front of the white Camaro, unsteady on his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. I'm in the park with Benicio...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go Irene...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meeting you was the best thing that ever happened to me... Irene smiles sadly.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was nice to meet you too...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
