<movie id="181" title="Drop Dead Gorgeous">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MALE PAGEANT ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Blue-toned stock footage of a long row of beauty pageant contestants on stage. MALE PAGEANT ANNOUNCER (cont'd) Sarah Rose knows you have an unusual talent. Sarah Rose knows you're a teenage girl. Blue-toned stock footage of the row of contestants parading down some steps from the stage as CAMERA TILTS</context>
      <utterance>Sarah Rose knows you're a beautiful person....</utterance>
   <speaker>DOWN.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROUSING PATRIOTIC MUSIC. FAST PACED CUTS feature SMILING TEENAGE CONTESTANTS dancing and waving American flags.</context>
      <utterance>MALE PAGEANT ANNOUNCER  Mmm, and she definitely knows that you are ready for the ultimate teen glamour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ADAM WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TITLES FADE ON SCREEN: Adam West, TV's Batman, then FADE</context>
      <utterance>The American Teen Princess Pageant has been enriching the lives of American- made girls since 1945.</utterance>
   <speaker>OUT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The American Teen Princess Pageant provides personal growth, scholarship, travel, and you... Numerous contestants stand up in SHOT and SURROUND ADAM. ADAM WEST (cont'd) ...might even meet a few celebrities. At the national level, thousands of seventeen year-old girls like yourselves. and compete around the country in places like:</context>
      <utterance>ADAM WEST</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE PAGEANT ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beautiful Mount Rose, Minnesota.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lincoln, Alabama, to compete for the title of American Teen Princess. LIGHTS come UP on the teenaged girls in the pageant as they pause. As they WAVE AMERICAN FLAGS. Adam West turns back to the camera. ADAM WEST (cont'd) And now, a few words from last year's host, Mr. Adam West. Contestants strike a pose around him. THUNDEROUS CANNED</context>
      <utterance>And make it all the way here to</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GLADYS LEEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good God, Iris, you taped your shows over it.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gladys turns to the GIRLS in the bleachers.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GLADYS LEEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now ladies, the rest of the tape - which is now gone forever - goes on about startin' this great American journey we call American Teen Princess...Yah-so, any of you young ladies who'd like to start on that journey, you just come right down here and sign up. And please...help yourselves to some coffee and bars...</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Showtime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think that most people would say that teenage beauty pageants are a good idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yah-sure, I know what some of your big city, no bra wearin', hairy-legged women's libbers say, "Pageants are old- fashioned" and, uh, and "demeaning" to the girls --</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Civil Servettes stare at her a beat.</context>
      <utterance>What's sick is women dressin' like men!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... You betcha, Iris.  Yah-I think yous boys'll find that things are different here in Mount Rose... Civil Servettes AD-LIB AGREEMENT. GLADYS  For one thing, y'know, we're God fearin' folk - every last one of us... Civil Servettes AD-LIB AGREEMENT. GLADYS  You won't find a back room in our video store... Servettes AD-LIB "AMEN. YAH-YOU BETCHA." etc. GLADYS   ...that filth is better left in the "Sin Cities."</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL AWAY from MINNEAPOLIS SKYLINE to COUNTRYSIDE.</context>
      <utterance>A.k.a. Minneapolis - St. Paul.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Today's "To Do" list includes a trip to the Mall of America. We need outfits for the "Physical Fitness" number --</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothin' too showy!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Servettes react with pleasure.</context>
      <utterance>Y'betcha, Iris. We still need a third judge and we need to think of a theme.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gladys -- Gladys! Look out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my!  Hello, Father Donigan! Sidewalks, sidewalks? Iris mimes drinking, "glug, glug." GLADYS  Iris, stop!  It's not his fault. The communal wine just proves too temptin' for some of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why we Lutherans use grape Koolaid for the blood of Christ.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, there's a parking space over there. Oh, no, that's just a compact. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gladys pulls into a HANDICAPPED SPOT. Servettes and CAMERA stand outside the car. Iris points at the sign.</context>
      <utterance>You'd think they'd build the parking lot of America to go with the Mall of America!</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a two-hundred dollar fine!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said I'd move if a cripple came. Let's just run in the store and pick out some outfits.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Iris and the Servette stop.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait! I just thought of the theme.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! What is it? GLADYS  "Proud...to be...an...American." Servettes react with pleasure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what was the theme of the pageant last year?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last year? It was, "Buy American."</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the year before that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"U.S.A. is A-okay."</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you remember the theme of your favorite pageant?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Can I? I'm Amer-I-Can!" People ask me where I get this. I don't know, it's...maybe a gift from God or somethin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you do any of the, uh, embalming?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God, no. Oh, God. I just do the hair and makeup on the deceased.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you decided what your talent is going to be yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna sing and dance to, "New York, New York." See, I fell in love with The Big Apple last summer when I was visitin' my brother. He followed his dream to New York. PICKS UP 8x10's, shows to camera. LISA  This is Peter as Liza. This is him as Madonna. Oh, here's me with him as Barbara...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... I don't know what my talent's gonna be yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER: CONTESTANT #3, TESS WEINHAUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>TESS  Kenny. Kenny, come. Come, Kenny. A DACHSHUND enters and jumps on her lap. TESS  This is Kenny. Spike, my German Shepherd, went to live with a nice family on a farm after he attacked me. It wasn't his fault. I had beef jerky in my front pocket.  They re-made my belly with skin from my butt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... So we adopt Molly three year ago when we come to America, to help acclimate us to American.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Howard laughs.</context>
      <utterance>To America, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She all-American girl. She our American Teen Princess girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Howard's biological daughter (they renamed her "TINA") ENTERS FRAME. Although she's the picture of beauty, grace, talent and charm, she represents their old life.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mom...</utterance>
   <speaker>TINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Father, Mother, when are we moving back to Tokyo? I can't stand this place anymore. They put butter on everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>English! English, you stupid little retard! We America now, Tina!</utterance>
   <speaker>TINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Dad, but with all due respect, my name isn't "Tina," it's Seiko.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tina! Tina!! TINA!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Robert," settle down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, I just finished the third movement of that concerto I was working on. I put, like, this techno beat on this Japanese folk tune - wanna hear it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! We not like to hear it! Go to your room and shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>TINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I almost forgot...  I got my acceptance to Tokyo University.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you deaf? I say shut up-shut up-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Molly, tell movie man what you talent do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be line dancin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Country western!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clint Black! Ruff!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what he got I not got?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Yah-I'll be performing a dramatic monologue.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER: CONTESTANT #2, MICHELLE JOHANSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MICHELLE  Right now, I'm thinkin' "Othello" or... "Soylent Green." Lots of girls make a smooth transition from pageants into actin', y'know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JANELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...My talent will be an interpretive dance while I sing, "Through the Eyes of Love." I have a dream of spreadin' sign language around the world... Mom? Would you be so kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER: CONTESTANT #8, JANELLE BETZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yeah. Well, see, uh, I have a dream of spreading sign language around the world. (to Mrs. Betz) Mom, would you be so kind. Mrs. Betz quickly puts down the bars and goes to the piano where she starts "Through the Eyes of Love." Janelle begins to gesticulate and sign words in an overly dramatic performance that looks like a bizarre seizure. SOUND occasionally DIPS OUT as the BOOM OPERATOR reaches for bars.</context>
      <utterance>JANELLE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TAMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you bet I do. I mean, maybe other people think I can't win a beauty pageant. But other people didn't think I could beat out Becky Leeman for President of the gun club, either. And I did. I-I-It's just like Anthony Robbins says, "I'm a winner. Nobody can stop me but me!"</utterance>
   <speaker>TAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>KABLOOM! Tammy's John Deere thresher BLOWS UP!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, I think everyone's doing really well considering the fact that she was so young.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's always hard to see the young ones called home, especially on an exploding thresher. It's just so odd and gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know that sometimes it's hard to understand God's great plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Iris pats Gladys on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE MOURNER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I have a tissue?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the show must go on.  I gotta get a hold of Ted and ask him if we can use that barn light as a spot again. So you watch the Jell-o salad, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRY GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Oh, yeah-right. I ain't gonna be in no goddamn pageant! Look what happened to that dork-ass farm girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREGNANT FRY GIRL</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tammy Curry?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRY GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah-yah. Everyone says this is a big accident? She got iced because she wins everything, and this time someone didn't want her to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREGNANT FRY GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This pageant's like a roach motel.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRY GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girls check in, but they don't check out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREGNANT FRY GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And they say smokin' is bad for your health.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRY GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHLORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And tendu. Close. Tendu. Close. Tendu. Close. Plie. And repeat. Suck in the belly, girls, and tuck in the tushes!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER: CHLORIS KLINGHAGEN, CHOREOGRAPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CHLORIS  Close those legs! You look like a bunch of bowlegged cows! Other side. And...tendu. Close. Tendu. Close. Tendu. Close. Plie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Amber does my hair...once a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber mouths, "Shhh! Don't tell!" to camera as she tries to pull the clump of hair from the brush.</context>
      <utterance>Huh? Oh...Uh, just a little snarl...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds the mirror for Mary.</context>
      <utterance>There we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beautiful... Maybe next week... a perm.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber gives a kind but worried smile to camera. Suddenly, Becky Leeman enters with a large box of chocolates. She's fully aware of the cameras from the moment she enters.</context>
      <utterance>Yah... sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's in full make-up.</context>
      <utterance>Hellooo, Little Mary Sunshine!  What?! Oh-oh my God! Lights! Camera! And me without a stitch of make-up on. What are you guys doin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Amber, like you're the only one who visits Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Who are you?!" Oh Mary, you kill me.  She always says that. It's a little game we play. Every week - same dippy little look on her face. "Who are you - who are you?" Just like that.  It's me - Becky - and I brought your favorites. Becky puts the chocolates on Mary's lap, a few spill. Throughout the following, Mary slowly reaches for them as if they're forbidden fruit and she's a very hungry Eve.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Becky roughly puts her hands over Mary's ears, who's now gently petting the spilled chocolates in her lap.</context>
      <utterance>How nice, Becky, she's anorexic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's skinny, not deaf, Amber.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Yah-1963. Her beauty worked against her when she started as a reporter in Louisville, her hometown. Those were different times.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Amber, y'get my smokes?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNETTE ATKINS, Amber's mom - sexy, but tired - OPENS THE</context>
      <utterance>That's my mom.  I'll get kem in a sec.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're from L.A. They wanted to see my room and film me for their movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... How quickly they grow up.  Hey, if they ask you to take off your shirt, get the money first. Annette is gone. ANNETTE   And go get my smokes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You betcha. S'posed to be colder-n- a witches tit tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Lester. He loves his weather, y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, ya like it? Open it...Yah-the globe. Pull at the equator there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Banging and fumbling. A CORKSCREW flies into shot - CREW GUY quickly ENTERS SHOT and grabs it.</context>
      <utterance>We're not in the showroom, Dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fits three full-size booze bottles. The cassette deck pulls outta Afghanistan, there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommm...</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lester?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, all right  How soon they forget where all this comes from.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Japan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough, young lady.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lester returns to the couch, large drink in hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'll field that one - Rebecca's saving her voice. Becky smiles admiringly at Gladys. GLADYS  You-betcha, Rebecca's ready. She's been singin' and dancin' since she was knee high to a pig's eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah-she's damn near as good as that little black fella - with the glass eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sammy Davis, Jr., honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, the Jew.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice one, Dad. He's dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gladys is distracted by the HARD, YOUNG bodies. All are.</context>
      <utterance>...Yah-then, for the "Judges Interview," each girl has a ten minute get-together with the judges before the pageant...</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, the Judges Interview.. Each girl has a ten minute get-together with the judges prior to the pageant. Then we have the... A HUNKY WRESTLER, TONY, waves. GLADYS  Hello, Tony.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Hey" to the folks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Judges Interview.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you've, uh, you've judged a lot of pageants over the years?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. No. Uh-uh. Never judged a pageant before in my life. Nope. No way. Never around young girls. Even if I was, why would I wanna be, y'know? I-I-I don't get off on that kinda thing and that's really why you're askin', right? S-someone say somethin'?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you judge the pageant every year?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Nope. Never judged nothin' afore --</utterance>
   <speaker>HANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we on "Cops?" Are we on "Cops?" Are we on "Cops?"</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harold CUFFS Hank.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Hank. This here's business.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow, Harold - Mom said not the head.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Mom's dead, so shut your fly trap.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will if you shut your piehole.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harold raises his hand, Hank FLINCHES and</context>
      <utterance>Don't make me kick-ya where the good Lord split-ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are you excited?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Hank runs full speed into the window. BAM! He falls to the ground inside.</context>
      <utterance>...Oh you betcha! We're happier than the day Hanky got acquitted. I get made a judge, then the furniture store hires us to paint the whole damn thing.  We're gonna use the money to get our mamma a proper headstone. Oh, and move her out to the cemetery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lester smacks Jean on the ass.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Tim, Carla - if yous kids don't try to Jew me down none, I'll throw in a matchin' hutch. The COUPLE smiles excitedly. LESTER   See, that there's my specialty. Don't pay me less and I'll give ya more.  Secret is, the hutch is included in the price. Ain't that right, Jean?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER: JUDGE #3, JEAN KANGAS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>LESTER  Take a memo, sweetheart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you gettin' her? Uh, the third one, the blonde one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brett slaps Pat on the back.</context>
      <utterance>See? Right over there. Right over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave him alone, leave him alone. It's okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Brett, do you wanna go to the lake with me on Thursday?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, actually, I got practice on Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Yah-well, maybe Friday, then. A bunch of us were gonna go cow-tippin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Becky notices their attraction and goes from flirt to uber-bitch in a heartbeat.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brett looks at Beck, then at Amber, not wanting to make her clean his tray.</context>
      <utterance>Giver her your tray, Brett. You're holdin' up the line.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it to her!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, I'll take it. It's my job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Becky THROWS her tray on the counter spraying Amber with food as she storms off. BRETT (cont'd) Oh man, you got leutefisk in your hair.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you're supposed to put it in the...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it must be Wednesday.</utterance>
   <speaker>IONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leutefisk is Cod Fish that's been salted and soaked in lye for a week or so. It's best with lots-a butter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, uh, I-I'm not really busy Friday. I just said that - y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if, uh, you wanted to do somethin'...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AMBER/BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shocked at the coincidence, they share a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Huntin' season.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, I'm cuttin' out early today to do a little duck huntin'...but, uh, maybe I could call you tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah-sure, fine...fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...well, bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber smiles, gives a shy little wave - then, to camera. AMBER (cont'd) Oh, God - you don't think Becky saw you guys, do you? (nervously looking around) Look, you just shouldn't be in here...</context>
      <utterance>Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. Doreen gave us hair nets.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around and motions them to rush off.</context>
      <utterance>No, listen.  We shouldn't talk here. Stop by my house tonight, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, they take out her butt?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus H. Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we on "Cops" again?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could be quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just the guys that are...you know, makin' the movie about the pageant. I told you about kem.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, naw. Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This here's Loretta.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell Annette, I says, "You talk to me durin' my stories, you might as well be talkin' to the wall."  You guys want a beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thank you. Is Amber here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You just missed her. Amber got called in to the bone gardens tonight. You just missed her. She's in a helluva mood today, anyways.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, yous boys been to the Leeman's?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loretta, shut it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, if you have, you got all the pictures of the winner you need.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut it up, Loretta.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette begins to comb out Loretta's hair.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Christ, it's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just say who should win, who deserves to win is Amber.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you paint a big red target on your ass, Loretta.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the prettiest, y'know. The best damn tapper. The most smartest...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette takes Loretta's beer, starts to push her out.</context>
      <utterance>"Most smartest?" Oh, that's good, Loretta. Make sure you get a picture of that. "Most smartest." We're cuttin you off and sendin' you home.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, excuse me, Annette, but I'm braggin' up your kid, here.  Amber's gonna be the next Diane Sawyer, y'know...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back. See ya later. CAMERA follows Annette and Loretta. ANNETTE  They're makin' a movie, here, goddamn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, they're makin' a movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know where this is gonna...</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a hairdo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think that Becky's going to win?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I think Becky'll win? You're talkin'...  Don't pinch!.  You're talkin' kbout the richest family in a small town. It's front page news when one of kem takes a shit.  Can one of yous boys give me a ride home?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't fall for it. She lives two trailers down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? Be real easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on home, Loretta. Come on. Go on, the party's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you know, Brett just got shot in the head.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did? Well, huntin's dangerous...So, anyways, my mom gave me this 30-aught for my sixteenth birthday...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amber, I need Stella now!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I just thought she might not wanna meet her Maker lookin' like a cheap whore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, your "cheap whore" is this family's "lovin' mother."  The Clemens said to make him look like he just came from snowmobilin'. Pink cheeks, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Larson PULLS Stella's coffin out.</context>
      <utterance>-- red nose and ears. I know, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I couldn't talk today kcause...I'm scared, okay?  I open my locker right after first period and there's a picture of Tammy Curry taped inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TWIN OFFICER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-yah, helluva way to go, there. After some extensive investigation, we figure the Curry girl musta been drivin' and smokin' and KABLEWEY!</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIN OFFICER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts a pinch between his cheek and gum.</context>
      <utterance>Not enough left of her to fill a tin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A crew guy walks IN FRAME and hands her a make-up jar. AMBER (cont'd) Man, I can't wait for fishin' season... Mr. Larson bursts in, white as a corpse.</context>
      <utterance>Yah-sure, Tammy liked to driver her dad's thresher - she said the heavy vibration helped her think, y'know? But I know for a fact she only smoked after a good drive. You ask me or anyone else who isn't scared to talk about it - Tammy was murdered.  God, I bet Diane Sawyer never had to deal with crap like this...  Toss me "Caucasian 5," would ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amber...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, don't say it. Another stray bullet to the head. She adjusts Brett's red plaid hunting cap. AMBER  I'm gonna need more caps.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hafta go home. There's some kinda emergency at the trailer park.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, that's my ma's code for, "Bring home milk and a carton-a Luckys."</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs the keys and RUNS OUT.</context>
      <utterance>No. Loretta called. There's been a... a fire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearse SCREECHES to a halt. We hear a THUD, then MOANS from in back. Amber jumps out. Camera follows, a la "COPS." It's pandemonium with fire trucks, neighbors, an ambulance, etc. AMBER (cont'd) Mom! Mom!? MOMMMM! Loretta runs up to Amber as TWO FIREMEN approach.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God - no! Is my mom okay? Was she home?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIREMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You family?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, she's just screamin' "Mom, Mom!" kcause she's got Tourettes... She's Annette's kid, dipshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Mom okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's alive, sweetie.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera pans over to see a semi-conscious Annette as they load her stretcher into the ambulance, shut the doors and start to pull away. Amber runs after them.</context>
      <utterance>She's right over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommmm! I'll be right behind you in the hearse!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let that worry you, Annette!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, doctor, is this sort of an unusual injury here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Removing BANDAGE to reveal BEER CAN, still held in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh you betcha, this was a doozy. Right now, our chief concern is to stabilize Annette, then, in surgery, remove this here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mom, it's so ugly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ruined a brand-new pair of Lee Press- ons.  Well, I sat down for a beer and KA- BLEWEY! Next thing I know, somethin' blows through my kitchen window. Next thing I know, I'm ass up in Loretta's flower bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROCKER KID #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah-dude, put another fuckin' book under it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCKER KID #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES, then steadies. We see all of Rocker Kid 1. Rocker Kid 2 runs into the shot with his guitar. ROCKER KID 2 (cont'd) kKay-dude, hurry. We gots like two fuckin' minutes left on the battery.</context>
      <utterance>Don't say "fuckin'." My ma's got the windows open.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCKER KID #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUDDENLY Annette's' trailer EXPLODES behind them! Rocker Kids turn to see a BODY (Annette's) FLY through the air.</context>
      <utterance>A one...two...one-two-three...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shoved your tap shoes in my jeans before I was blown outta the house, Honey. Check with the guy who cut my pants off. He should have kem.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber starts to cry and runs out.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, uh, about that...I-I'm-oh God...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-Jesus-Mary-n-Joseph, she's pregnant!  If you are - come back, sweetie. Mommy wants to talk, then KILL YOU!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annette, why don't you just see if there's any beer left in that can and relax a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're what?!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-I'm quittin' the pageant.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard you, I was just tryin' to scare you into changin' your mind. Oh for Chrissakes, Amber, the woman clung to your tap shoes while flyin' through the air like a Goddamn lawn dart!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A candy striper approaches them.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God, I'm dead...</utterance>
   <speaker>CANDY STRIPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, lil' Miss Sad-pants and her friend Serious Sally, how kbout some nice cool mints to turn those frowns upside-down. "S."</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what do I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simple. Just say, "Mom, I know you sacrificed everything - relationships, dreams - your tummy, ass and thighs - all to bring me into this world. All so I could have tap lessons and be in the pageant - the same one you were in. But, y'know what? I'm quittin'." There. Easy as pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. I'm so dead...</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you betcha...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on! Get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber sits on the bed. Annette grabs her shirt. AMBER (cont'd) Mom!</context>
      <utterance>Mom, look, don't say anything. First of all, I'm not pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't lettin' go ktil you tell me what's up. I'm reaching' a point where I'd kill someone for the nicotine on their fingernails.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Yesterday I...I got this picture. So I kinda, y'know, I'm thinkin' no. I'm gonna, I-I-I'm gonna quit the pageant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hits Amber with her beer-canned hand.</context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would yous boys excuse us a second? Loretta, you too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice mouth you got there, Mom, but I- I'm not goin' through this again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not goin' through this again? You? You're not the one who knows how Jiffy Pop feels.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, c'mon... First the picture of Tammy, then Brett Clemens, now this? It's scary.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you "scary," Amber. Look at me. Do you wanna look like you been rode hard and put away wet at my age? I'm a "lifer" here. Best I can hope for is to end up in a descent "raisin ranch" where they'll change me twice a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it, I'm goin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber sits on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Honest to God, if I got to do it over? I'd start walkin' outta this town the minute I took my first step. Practically the only thing I wouldn't do different is have you...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God I hope that's you and not your concussion talkin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me...I just don't want this to be the thing you'd do over. This pageant's your ticket outta here. I know you can win, Amber. ANNETTE  C'mere. I love you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette hugs Amber.</context>
      <utterance>I love you much.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell-no, she ain't quittin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Mom said if I did, she'd look up my dad and marry him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So has your mom kept your dad's life a secret?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. She never hid the fact that my dad picked his career over us. What'd she used to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Once a carnie, always a carnie."</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-yah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIN OFFICER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Atkins fire? Foul play? Shit-no. After some thorough investigatin', we determined it musta been a bad wirin'. Mosta them trailer-folk plug a TV, VCR, crock pot and Fry-daddy into one outlet and don't think nothin' of it ktil KABLEWEY!</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIN OFFICER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not enough left to fill a tin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Bad wirin'?!" Well, if that ain't the biggest crock-a-shit ever.  Ooowwww-Jesus! Did K-Mart have a sale on dull needles?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANDY STRIPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-I just need one more "do-over."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, remember the three most important parts of a good interview...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, everybody, listen up!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number one, American Teen Princess' don't cross their legs like streetwalkers. The girls put their knees together. GLADYS  Excuse me, Miss Penthouse Ninety- eight, put your knees together.  I could drive a boat show in there. Gladys paces. GLADYS  Ankles together. Hands resting lightly on your laps. Good. Sit up straight. Smile!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Number two: the judges are as nervous as you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are you about ready to start the judging - start the interview, there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, I-I guess I could answer that. Yep. We're ready. So, we should probably get the young girls in here, then. Y'know, to start the interviews...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, "if you could be any tree in the woods, what kinda tree would you be?"</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dogwood.</utterance>
   <speaker>V.F.W. - BACK ROOM - MONTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ON MOLLY HOWARD, seated.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bonsai.</utterance>
   <speaker>V.F.W. - BACK ROOM - MONTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ON LESLIE, seated.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Green?</utterance>
   <speaker>V.F.W. - BACK ROOM - MONTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ON MICHELLE JOHANSON, seated.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins vocal and facial warm-up exercises.</context>
      <utterance>A tree? I can be any tree you want. Gimme a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>V.F.W. - BACK ROOM - MONTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ON BECKY, seated.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One with strong roots in a community like Mount Rose, a solid Christian trunk and long leafy branches to provide shade for handicapped kids on a hot summer day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Who would you pick to be president, dead or alive?" PAN OVER to Molly Howard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Emperor Hirohito.</utterance>
   <speaker>V.F.W. - BACK ROOM - MONTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ON LESLIE, seated...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brett Favre!</utterance>
   <speaker>V.F.W. - BACK ROOM - MONTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ON BECKY, seated.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother, kcause she could solve world hunger with one of her blue- ribbon rhubarb pies, create world peace with one of her prayers and still find time to look beautiful...for my dad, Lester Leeman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is she trying to say?  Say it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Judges turn and look at Hank.</context>
      <utterance>The ktards pants are completely off!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close up shop. Close up shop, Hank.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harold!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close up shop!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You Amber Atkins?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>All judges turn a page on their clipboards.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes I am. Thank you, hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Name and spell all the United States in alphabetical order." PAN OVER to a stunned Amber.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seriously?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Amber can't believe what she's hearing.</context>
      <utterance>Ah-yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, ah...Alabama. A-L-A-B-A-M-A. Alaska. A-L-A-S-K-A. Arizona. A-R-I-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pan over to Judges. They can't believe it. Hank CLAPS retardedly. He loves her.</context>
      <utterance>West Virginia. W-E-S-T-V-I-R-G-N-I-A. Wisconsin. W-I-S-C-O-N-S-O-N. Wyoming. W-Y-O-M-I-N-G.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-okay, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nurse gives her a hit of oxygen. Mary smiles and gives a THUMBS UP from behind the oxygen mask.</context>
      <utterance>With two weeks until the pageant...  I was practicing my talent. Finishing my costume, brushing up on current events, and running eighteen miles a day on about four hundred calories. I was ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-yah, really nervous. It's been about two months. I haven't told my boyfriend yet. How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant, nervous about the pageant?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses a photo and GIGGLES.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! Nervous about the pageant! Yah sure!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janelle Betz, wearing a flowing, nymph-like dress with ballet slippers, glides up to Amber.</context>
      <utterance>And, uh, this is my lucky bolt. They think it fell from a DC-10. The doctor said I was lucky the flat side hit me, um, otherwise it coulda gone right through my head.  I know, I know, gives me the willies, too. I guess the explosion...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amber? Can we switch numbers? I need to go first.  My cousin just had a deaf baby and I get to go see it!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah-sure, eight's my luck number anyway. Diane Sawyer was number eight at her local.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be honest. This is a hard time for me. This is the part of the pageant when you realize that tomorrow night, all but one of these girls will walk out of here a loser. It's hard for me to know how that must feel, but I'm sure it doesn't feel good. In b.g., a BIG STAGE LIGHT FALLS on Janelle's head. CRASH! Gladys and CAMERA rush the stage. "Through the Eyes of Love" continues throughout.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loretta enters, portable phone and drink in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you get it? I was supposed to go first. I was contestant number one. That light was meant for my head. If Janelle hadn't wanted to change numbers... God, I owe my life to that deaf baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was your mom. She wanted you to have this.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, Loretta?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You-betcha.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mom wanted me to have this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shut up. I thought it might help you get some sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loretta, never have kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loretta pulls a bag out of a closet and hands it to Amber. LORETTA (cont'd) Here, your ma did want you to have this since your other one got toasted and all. Amber pulls out an ELEGANT GREEN GOWN.</context>
      <utterance>Well God-love-ya for thinkin' I still could.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hugs Loretta.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...my...God! It's just like Diane Sawyer's! kCourse it's not a size ten, Diane was a little hippy back then. Oh, thank you! Thank you! Thank you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind them Leslie Miller's boyfriend, PAT, and a group of ROWDY GUYS approach.</context>
      <utterance>Go Molly! Go! Number one daughter!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whooo! Leslie kicks Teen Princess ass! Go Muskies!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she steps away from the mic, Tess Weinhaus, wearing a huge ball of twine headdress, dances up to the mic.</context>
      <utterance>Atomic power makes me, Molly Howard, proud to be an Asian-American.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ball of twine falls to the floor and rolls off the stage, still attached at one end to her head.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, this, uh, my Uncle Phil's World's Largest Ball of Twine, in Bundy Minnesota, makes me, um, it makes me proud I'm American - I kinda misunderstood the assignment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay! Listen-up. Coupla notes from last night's dress rehearsal.  Number one, Gladys says a coupla yous are gettin' sexy with your hips durin' the "Physical Fitness" routine...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Commotion stops. Becky continues to get ready.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! My-my tap costume's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Amber? We're not puttin' on our Talent costumes. You need to put on your "Physical Fitness" outfit. And let's shake a leg, ladies.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Becky freezes, staring daggers at Amber.</context>
      <utterance>No, wait. It-it was here before the openin' number...wait. What am I sayin'? I should just ask you, Becky. Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other contestants slowly clear a path between them.</context>
      <utterance>You heard me. Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're gettin' at somethin', you better just say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to slowly circle each other - a cat fight's brewin'.</context>
      <utterance>Well then, you better be willin' to back it up, kcause you're talkin' like crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-oh, you bring me some of that snotty attitude, Becky - bring it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, as my mother says at Sunday dinner, "Come and get it," bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're moving ever closer...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll "get it." I'll "get it" all right. I might even take seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want seconds, then I'll make sure it's hot enough for ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girls! Girls!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me your stringy-ass hair!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get you!</utterance>
   <speaker>CREW GUY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, don't stop kem now...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're choking my, you fucking bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, I-I don't think yous boys should, uh, should be in here while the girls are changin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate her!</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all do. Now let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Applause! Gladys exits. TAPED MUSIC "It's My Turn." A NURSE pushes MARY JOHANSON out in her wheelchair, complete with portable oxygen. Mary wears a gigantic black wig and silver gown which hangs off her boney body. She moves her lips to the words as the nurse pushes her emotionally around the stage.</context>
      <utterance>Yah-so how kbout a big round of applause for last year's Mount Rose American Teen Princess, in a farewell performance. Who could forget her lip- synching to "Don't Cry Out Loud," by Melissa Manchester. And here she is, Mary Johanson!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, why don't we take up the stepladders, all right? For the Physical Fitness number?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, my hands are stuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, I'm kinda dizzy from the fumes.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hold kem away from you so it doesn't get on the outfits.  What kinda mental retard paints step ladders the morning of a pageant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here come the judge - pinch, pinch - here come the judge - pinch, pinch - here come the judge...</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get back! Get back, you total retard!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go Hank!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay, I'm okay - dress is fine. I'm okay...well, our other judges are Jean Kangas and John Dough...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, guys, I think we all got some. You just take it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, I didn't get any.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, have some.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hand me another white one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, you guys, don't go int the bathroom. Tess blew chunks all over. Man, she ate a big dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Becky storms off.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe she shoulda shoved that lucky bolt down her throat for desert.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I'd like to take you back seventeen years, when a peanut farmer was in the White House, a group-a boys callin' themselves kQueen' topped the record charts and Gladys Leeman was Gladys Wood and she was Mount Rose American Teen Princess!" Gladys enters wearing sash, tiara and plaid culottes. Applause. A SLIDE is shown of her at 17.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, thank you. You know, I won the talent contest by sewing these culottes, Butterick pattern 7-4-3-2. Can you believe it? They still fit!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had a big ass then, she's got a big ass now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>APPLAUSE. Tess is pushed on stage.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, thank you. Our next eontestant is ready, so let's welcome her: Tess Weinhaus!</utterance>
   <speaker>BACKSTAGE - LEFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amber paces. ON STAGE Tess drones on at the mic.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The beagle is known for it's howl. "Aaauuuuuhhhh." The Pekinese has it's own distinctive bark. "Yip, yip, yip." Not to be confused with the Chihuahua's, "Yap, yap, yap." But none can compare to the greatest bark of all - the German Shepherd...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHLORIS KLINGHAGEN enters, small bag in hand.</context>
      <utterance>...Yah-it's just gone...  I mean, I-I just wanna tap, y'know? I'm not sayin' I'm the best, or that I'd even win, but shouldn't I at least get a chance to compete?  I just wanted my Mom to see me dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amber - Amber, c'mere.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Mrs. K, I got so much Vaseline on my teeth, I'm gonna be smilin' for a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chloris pulls a simple BLACK LEOTARD from the bag. CHLORIS (cont'd) It's nothin' special, but talent like yours doesn't need to hide behind sequins.</context>
      <utterance>No. Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. K--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber, overcome with joy, gives her a big hug. CHLORIS (cont'd) Not so hard, sweetie. I heard somethin' snap...</context>
      <utterance>You're... you're special and... Ah hell, go out there and kick some Leeman ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Clark, why are you doing this to me? Why're you pretendin' you don't know what's goin' on?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amber, I'm sorry. I really am. But you know the rules. All talent costumes hafta be okay'd by Gladys before the pageant.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, doesn't someone taking your costume so you can't compete, overrule that rule?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I-I don't make the rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This, this... This is bullshit!</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amber Atkins! That is not American Teen Princess language!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber storms off.</context>
      <utterance>Good, kcause this isn't an American Teen Princess Pageant - it's, it's Nazi Germany!</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do they get this stuff...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Leeman?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-I'm wearin' this costume. I'm, uh, I'm gonna do my talent tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really - I don't think so.  Uh, Amber, I hate to be the bearer of bad news, but rules state that a costume must be okay'd at least a week in advance. And this...  This is why we have the rule. My goodness gracious, I couldn't allow a neckline this low on stage. We have kids in the audience.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>But, you - I mean... It's not my fault. I-I... Please? I didn't do anything wrong...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doubles over. She's given it all. APPLAUSE.</context>
      <utterance>That's why... I must say...  Soylent Green... is... people.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gladys starts out on stage as Molly Howard, dressed like a red, white and blue cowboy, runs up next to Amber. She's twirling toy guns on her fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Oops, that's my cue.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish me luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of Molly's guns flies off her finger. She goes to retrieve it.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Molly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Amber...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-I-I-I-I-, j-uh-j-uh-just wanted to compe-e-e-e-ete.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Getting an idea, Lisa starts to take off her jacket. LISA (cont'd) Amber? Here.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe this is happenin'. I can't believe she said you couldn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Here," wh-wh-what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My jacket. Take it kcause, y'know, I got my costume okay'd before the pageant. You can wear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man, Lisa, I wouldn't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're never gonna let you perform naked. I asked.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, yous guys. Look, Amber, I'm not gonna win. And let's be honest, a family only needs one "Liza" and you know Peter's got much better legs than me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your parents'd kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh c'mon, I love kem, but you know they only had me kcause Peter needed a kidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lis, I want to, I really do, but... Oh, I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then do it for Peter. Mrs. Leeman used to call him a "skinny little fag" when he'd bag her groceries. He'd pop his Nancy-belt if his old jacket somehow, I don't know, got her back.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah?</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber hugs her and takes the jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Oh-you-beccha.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STAGE GOES BLACK. SPOT HITS BECKY, who sits at the edge of the stage, holding a mic. She's head to toe sequins in her poodle skirt, sweater, saddle shoes, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Now, it's with overwhelming pride that I introduce contestant number six, who also happens to be president of her class - two years running - a member of the honor roll and the new President of the Lutheran Sisterhood Gun Club - Rebecca Ann Leeman!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Lisa. You're up next.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taped music ENDS. APPLAUSE. Gladys, mic in hand, joins Becky for a big hug.</context>
      <utterance>I quit. And, uh, since my costume, y'know, was okay'd a month ago? I'm givin' it to Amber. Amber breaks a smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Becky exits, pulling the wheeled Jesus behind her. GLADYS (cont'd) Voice of an angel, that one. Iris runs self-consciously out on stage, whispers in Gladys' ear, then runs back off stage. GLADYS (cont'd) ...Uh, I was just told that contestant number seven, Lisa Swenson, has quite the pageant.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, I'd hate to follow that. Wow!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD REACTS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, these things happen. At any rate, we still have one more contestant - number eight, Amber Atkins. Gladys exits. A taped hip, hot DRUM BEAT starts. Suddenly, Amber glides into CENTER SPOT. (Now wearing Lisa's costume, sleeves rolled up.) Her feet burst into an amazing routine. The loud drum beats seem to fly from her hands and feet as they punctuate the rhythm. There's no glitz, just unbelievable skill. It appears effortless as she floats around stage. Like watching Michael Jackson moon walk for the first time, you can't take your eyes off her. She concludes, center stage, with the GREATEST THIRTY SECONDS OF HER LIFE. The audience goes WILD! Amber takes bow after bow - they love her. Gladys enters quickly, mic in hand. GLADYS (cont'd) Okay, okay, okay! Well, now, it's finally time to say good-bye to our judges, so they can go make the toughest decision of their lives. PAN TO JUDGES. They look nervous as hell. A relaxed Hank sniffs from a paint soaked bag.</context>
      <utterance>GLADYS</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who get's the crown? How are you going to figure this all out?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, we're gonna, y'know, compare scores and uh, figure out a-a winner. kCause we don't know the winner yet... I mean, I-I don't know who Jean and Harold picked. No idea. Did Gladys send you in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know the winner! I know the winner! I know the winner!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nerves shot, John suddenly LAUNCHES himself across the table at Hank.</context>
      <utterance>No you don't! Shut your goddamn mouth, you son-of-a-bitch!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hank freezes, then starts to wail!</context>
      <utterance>You shut it! You goddamn retard!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hank stops crying and goes back to the bag.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Hankey here can't help it if he was born crazier than a shithouse rat!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hank begins crying again.</context>
      <utterance>For fuck's sake, why didn't ya leave him with a sitter?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real nice. You know the sitter's dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, anyone talk to Janelle?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Girls ad-lib SHOCK.</context>
      <utterance>Yah-I brought her some flowers this morning. She's in the room next to my mom. She's super happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh -- the blow to her head made her deaf... Girls ad-lib "Oh, I see. Okay-then." etc. Another LONG BEAT of SILENCE follows. Becky gets up to re-touch her make-up.</context>
      <utterance>Why happy? AMBER</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Contestants stare at her in shock. Iris enters.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, good Lord! What're they doin'? Lettin' the retard count votes?!</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's time, ladies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PAT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Audience laughs. Leslie waves.</context>
      <utterance>You rule, Leslie!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taped DRUM ROLL. Contestants (except Becky) take hands. Iris gives Gladys an envelope and trophy. GLADYS (cont'd) And the First Runner-up is - (opening envelope, face drops) Contestant number eight, Amber Atkins. Ad-lib audience shock and disbelief. Contestants are stunned. Amber steps forward, humbly takes the trophy and stands beside Leslie. Audience finally quiets. GLADYS (cont'd) And finally, the moment I know I've been waiting for... Iris hands Gladys a LARGE TROPHY and envelope. Mary Johanson is wheeled out wearing sash and tiara. GLADYS (cont'd) With a scholarship of five-hundred dollars, courtesy Leeman Furniture, and all expenses paid for next weekend when she'll be competin' for the title of Minnesota American Teen Princess... Taped drum roll. Gladys opens the envelope. GLADYS (cont'd) Our new Mount Rose American Teen Princess is contestant number - ah heck, she's my daughter - number seven, Rebecca Ann Leeman! Polite audience applause. Becky rushes forward. Gladys RIPS the tiara and sash off Mary, places them on Becky.</context>
      <utterance>Our next prize, a seventy-five dollar scholarship -- Audience ad-libs amazement. GLADYS  ...will be awarded to the First Runner- up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you so much!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDIENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loretta and Annette watch on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We was robbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Take her purse.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We was robbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mom's okay. They're just givin' her a ride back. She almost blew outta the back of Loretta's pick-up on the way over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God for bunge cords.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Yah-well, at least, y'know, I got to perform. And Mom got to see me.  I guess number eight only worked for Diane Sawyer... Loretta puts her arm around Amber. They walk off as Leslie and Pat approach.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey-hey, I'm Second Runner-up! Whooo! I got second place!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Third.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lisa passes by with her parents. They look pissed.</context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it was worth it. Amber shoulda won.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell ya one thing. Peter never woulda pulled a shenanigan like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs off. Her parents stop DEAD IN THEIR TRACKS.</context>
      <utterance>Well, y'know what, dad? Y'know what? Peter's gay!</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>OLDER MEN turn and look at camera, then take out a pen and note pad.</context>
      <utterance>So, how does it feel to be the new Mount Rose American Teen Princess, Becky?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's all happenin' so fast. Goodness-gracious, it hardly seems real, y'know? I mean, I won! I'm the winner! I'm going to State!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the winner and we're going to state.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRY GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a surprise. Gladys Leeman's finally gonna go to State. And she'll probably ride on Becky's ass all the way to Nationals, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREGNANT FRY GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder how she's gonna fix that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you ladies going to the parade tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREGNANT FRY GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah. I think I'm like, due or somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the b.g., Gladys holds a bullhorn, clipboard and points to a LARGE SWAN FLOAT.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh. Beautiful as a whore's ass today. Eh, boys?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Turn that float around. You think a swan's gonna swim ass first up Main Street?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah-Gladys had me order that swan special made from Mexico  in case Becky won. I do a lotta business with those people. I always offer to pay kem in tacos.  Whoo, they love that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get this straight right now. We wouldn't have been late at all if it wasn't for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to have the big bag of little donuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get nothing, Hank, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to get the big bag of little donuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harold rushes off for the parade, joining other folks carrying baskets, lawn chairs and flags on the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>There's your paint can. The next time you drink window cleaner, I'm just gonna leave it in ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Rebecca, you wanted it. Now get up there. Ride it side-saddle if you have to - like a horse. C'mon, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It smells funny. Like gasoline.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh for chrissakes, everything smells like that in Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dress'll reek.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, little missy, this cost your dad a pretty penny. Now get your ass up there and show me some teeth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amber, if I die from these fumes, will you be sure to cover the hickies on my neck?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the bite marks on my ears?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it doesn't matter, but on my inner thighs.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Leslie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SWAN FLOAT. Gladys approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Help...Hank! Help...Hank! Help...Hank! Help...Hank!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I designed the float, you know. And, what's gonna happen here is that this is going to look like a glistening lake beneath the swan.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Gladys?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need more bars!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is -- what?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enid ate a whole pan!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear to God she can't do anything by herself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eventually, Gladys tries to climb up on the float. Iris pulls her off. GLADYS (cont'd) Get offa me, you cow! Gladys spins and notices the silent CROWD. GLADYS (cont'd) What're you lookin' at? Huh? A whole God Damn town of losers! That's what I'm lookin' at! Crowd reacts. Gladys notices Amber and runs up to her car. GLADYS (cont'd) You! You piece-a-shit trailer trash! This shoulda been you! Damn, I shoulda killed you when I had the The crows reacts again. Gladys spins, noticing someone. Lester approaches. GLADYS (cont'd) Hey, Ted, sorry. I didn't know your family was in the garage when I set it on fire!</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! My Baby! The swan ate my baby!  Ow-ow-ow! Get up, Rebecca! Get outta there! We've gotta go to State! Oh hot!  Oh, damn. I like this blouse. Rebecca! Get up, angel face. Time to go to State! Ow-ow-ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gladys! Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs a BURNING 2X4 off a float and starts swinging it. GLADYS (cont'd) At least you've got another daughter. CROWD GASPS. Then stunned SILENCE. CAMERA CIRCLES Gladys and Lester getting reaction shots of the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Guess it wasn't a garage sale as much as it was a bake sale. Ah- hahahahahahahaha! Lester tries to pull her away from the crowd. GLADYS  Let go-a-me, you old bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So help me, Gladys.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Becky was my only shot at state!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWIN OFFICERS, followed by "COPS" TV CREW, run up and aggressively tackle Gladys. As the struggle on the ground continues, crew guys go over and shake hands with the "COPS" crew - obviously knowing them. GLADYS (cont'd) (pointing to Lester) He sells reproductions! His furniture's as fake as my orgasms! The COPS crew begins to mingle with the DOCUMENTARY crew.</context>
      <utterance>Let go! Let go of me. Oh my God, it's COPS!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, how're you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi! What's up, Scott? You remember Bruce, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long time, no see.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCUMENTARIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bruce, that's Roy.  Roy, Bruce.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the TIARA on AMBER. Loretta FLASHES pictures.</context>
      <utterance>As, uh, actin' President of the Mount Rose Civil Servettes, it's my duty since Becky can't fulfill her duties - kcause she's dead-n-all - to make you Mount Rose American Teen Princess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn around and let me see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is wrong with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I just didn't wanna win like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stop right there. You are a good person. Good things happen to good people.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's pure bullshit, sweetie. You're lucky as hell, so you might as well enjoy it. Let's get you a root beer float.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you guys want some shots? I'm buyin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never liked her, but she didn't deserve to die in the belly of a swan like that. The whole thing's just kinda sad and lame at the same time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This came for you, sweetie.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber rips it open and holds up a color brochure with COLLEEN and TERRY in a glamour shot on the cover. AMBER (cont'd) (paging through packet) It's all the stuff I get to do. Oh my God, oh my God... Okay, okay... We get a "personal consultation" with a make- up artist -- Eeeh! Okay, um, there'll be a choreographer to the stars and, oh no -- No way. Oh... My... God!</context>
      <utterance>Ah! It's from State! Oh my God!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? For chrissakes, spit it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be stayin' overnight at... The Airport Howard Johnsons!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right by the airport - Oh, Amber...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's an indoor swimming pool! Ahhhh! Loretta joins in the screaming. AMBER  Oh crap - I only got four days. I gotta practice!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, say "Airport Ho-Jo."</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Airport Ho-Jo!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it! Yeah, why don't ya take a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loretta, don't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. They're just starin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta work with these women.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, sweetie, that's all right. Let's go. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mount Rose American Teen Princess.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny, you don't look dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay ladies, listen up. I'm Colleen Douglas and this raving beauty on my right --</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a mirror.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Correction. This spunky monkey on my right is Terry Macey. And we are your Minnesota American Teen Princess State Board.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're also the co-founders of the Minnesota Modeling Academy. Applications are at the tiki bar. We'll wave the fifty dollar application fee if you list a friend and put her address.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm-hm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terry and Colleen stand in front of the stage.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. Look at her, she's awesome. I should just go home now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUDDENLY Miss Minneapolis FREEZES.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, that's enough - I get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS MINNEAPOLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs off toward the RESTROOM.</context>
      <utterance>Oh - oh my God...  I gotta go!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're gonna have to do somethin' with those nerves before Nationals. Thirty-million people aren't gonna wait while you run to the john. Other waiting contestants suddenly double over, ad- libbing "oh no! oh my God!" "I'm gonna puke!" etc. More contestants grab their bellies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CREW GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' beauty queens blowin' chunks everywhere. I've never seen anything like it before, and I live in L.A.  Hey, Ed.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Follow REPORTER as she runs over to Amber, Colleen and Terry. All three look dazed. Reporters SHOUT questions.</context>
      <utterance>Can you tell us any thing about the controversy? Is there a controversy here? Has there been sabotage?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People, people - wait, wait a minute, here. Uh, while we haven't ruled out sabotage from neighboring state pageants - Iowa, Wisconsin, North Dakota...</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dakota.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohio...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That bitch from...</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wisconsin.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to reveal we're:</context>
      <utterance>The important thing is that we have a winner...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode>ON T.V.</mode>
      <context>The place ERUPTS in CHEER! ON TV: Terry sets a tiara on Amber's head. FLASHES.</context>
      <utterance>And, on behalf of the Minnesota Modeling Academy, we proudly present Amber Atkins. Your new Minnesota American Teen Princess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah, ain't it just a kick in the fuckin' ass!?!? I'll be a snake's prick if tragedy and pageants ain't got a way of bringin' folks together...  Yous boys tell me when want me to start, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FEMALE REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON T.V.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amber, how do you feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Townsfolk laugh and cheer.</context>
      <utterance>I, uh... I feel like... I, uh, I need a shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus-Mary-n-Joseph I hope Gladys Leeman hangs herself in her cell when she hears this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. ON THE PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah - I just wanna say - that little bitch better watch her back at Nationals kcause I'm makin' friends on the inside... Yah-friends who have friends on the outside...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE PRISONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your sweet ass off the bunk, Cinnamon.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. ON PHONE</mode>
      <context>Click. DIAL TONE.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just, I just can't believe it. I'm Minnesota's American Teen Princess!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our baby's going to Nationals! Lincoln, Alabama - look out!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annette opens a beer with a new HOOK replacing her hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna be on TV! Just like Diane Sawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annette, just use your hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They told me to practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amber MIMES inhaling a cigarette and Annette embraces her.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, ready? Here's the signal I'm gonna give Ma when I'm on TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My little Carol Burnett.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FEMALE REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are here in the sixth hour of a shoot-out between Gladys Leeman -</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN AT FOOD SHACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The female reporter suddenly stiffens and falls over.</context>
      <utterance>Get down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLONDE NEWS ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Peter Aitchison.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they smile and laugh, we:</context>
      <utterance>And I'm Amber Atkins for WAZB News. SUPER: ...was given her job. AMBER  Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
