<movie id="193" title="Entrapment">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now we see her. From the rear. Slouched at her station. Looks like a skinny teenager in tousled tawny hair, rumpled oversized workshirt, vintage jeans. GIN (O.S., from the rear) Actually. Yeh. Not a kid's voice. Throaty. Music and whiskey and sex and effortless confidence. Even the voice turns us on. CRUZ (glances at his watch) What took you so long, Gin? I called 4:30 this morn... And stops. Because she turns with a look that would freeze anyone to stone.</context>
      <utterance>Baker. You got it solved?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now we really see her. Delicate bones and features, slender body, radiating the power of a natural heart-stopping beauty. GINGER BAKER is 32, ethereal and feral at once. Electric green eyes crackle with an intellect and a will that are not to be fucked with.</context>
      <utterance>I was with someone, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is not kidding. Stainless steel beneath the dapper. They are a matched team.</context>
      <utterance>So? This is work.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he smiles. Maybe she's lying. He likes her.</context>
      <utterance>Hector, I hardly know the guy. Why be impolite to strangers?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He means the cops on live feed.</context>
      <utterance>Look at those assholes...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the Vermeer were lying on that table, they'd toss their doughnuts on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, well, they didn't insure it, so they don't</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He came in through the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not possib...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's not possible is entry through the doors or the vents. That would have triggered instant alarm.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The windows are wired, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's listening. He always does with her.</context>
      <utterance>Only for trauma. They used smart glass, where the sensors respond to violation of the panel's integrity.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sounds awfully positive. Then again, she always does.</context>
      <utterance>I think he scaled the wall, popped the frame. In one piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, he only had to deal with heat and motion sensors. They were on 60-second delay, so the owner wouldn't trigger the alarm just be walking arou...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pane weighs 200 pounds, the building's 1100 feet high.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Almost as if she knows who. Cruz shakes his head...</context>
      <utterance>This particular guy is the best. The best there ever was.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. First time. Even at one-tenth power, it is dazzling light. She touches the panel before her... GIN (gently) I wrote a program and ran it, Dumbo. The live feed is replaced by a red-outlined rotating three- dimensional DIAGRAM of the living room. The alarm box glows green. One window pane glows lavender. She touches the panel, and the window SHATTERS, the alarm instantly emits a PIERCING SCREECH. Reset. As he watches. This time the window SLIDES AWAY into thin air. No sound. A stick figure appears, crawls through the opening, and the alarm begins the slow BEEP we heard last night. Cruz just stares.</context>
      <utterance>Popping the frame would trigger the alarm.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Live feed replaces the diagram. Our camera ZOOMS toward a VASE of lilies by the window. All the flowers are tilted in one direction. Over the lip of the vase, away from the window.</context>
      <utterance>Here's how I figured it out...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>No one arranges flowers like that. It was the draft from the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she is beaming. Excited. And just above a whisper...</context>
      <utterance>You said. This particular guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delighted at his stupefied reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Andrew MacDougal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not Houdini? Or Pretty Boy Floyd? Maybe Jesus Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His slow smile. This fucking kid.</context>
      <utterance>Because they couldn't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For ten</context>
      <utterance>He's been out of the business.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be a putz. This is his</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head, sadly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I get it. He has no interest in Vermeers, so that proves he stole one. By that logic, he oughta be a suspect most of the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Touches her panel. The big screen now shows a grainy VIDEOTAPE of...</context>
      <utterance>You love to embarrass yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The auction. Where our client</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans WAY back in the molded chair. Lifts her long legs up onto the console. They end in slender bare feet. The toes wriggle.</context>
      <utterance>Staking it out. Why bid, when you can mark the buyer, and jack it within the month?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At this moment, he is winging on JAL flight 307 to Narita,</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Touches the panel. The big screen now holds three faces, three names.</context>
      <utterance>Bet your ass. At Vegas odds.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>One face and name disappears. Two remain. KOICHI NARUHITO.</context>
      <utterance>Research reveals three known fences, still at large, who are believed to have brokered Vermeers to black market buyers. Sandrine Palmer is hospitalized in Malta with ovarian cancer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tiny, dry, adorable, shrug. Which says, bingo.</context>
      <utterance>The other two. Live in Tokyo.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grinning small at each other. She can't help that hers is hot. She never can. CRUZ (murmur) Plus. You were polite to a stranger. One of those moments when his attraction to her is too obvious to ignore. Best to defuse by pretending it's a joke... GIN (soft and playful) Sounds like you're sorry you're already a friend. Said as banter between pals. Which doesn't make her wrong.</context>
      <utterance>And you did all this since 4:30 this morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes scan the length of her gown. Her body.</context>
      <utterance>Uh. I'm showing off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is minus a comeback.</context>
      <utterance>Something of a habit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the alleged value of this piece from some fucking</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Virginia Romay...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gin, actually, Gin Romay. I was named after a card game.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That laser, unsmiling stare. Beyond sexy. She gets lost in it for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Or a cheap cocktail. She blinks. His brows raise... MAC  As in. I'll have a Gin Romay, please. With a twist.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're supposed to be charming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glances back to her card. Reads...</context>
      <utterance>I'm supposed to be selective.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks up. Still no smile.</context>
      <utterance>Art and Antiquities Acquisition Advisor, how alliterative...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And am I the antiquity?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sighs. Achingly lovely.</context>
      <utterance>In mint condition.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I've studied you, I know... pretty much...everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Made your first millions selling scrap metal. Then, gold mining concessions, gems, art, and lately strategic metals for new technologies - platinum, zirconium, titanium...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Huh? Oh.</context>
      <utterance>You said. Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guileless smile.</context>
      <utterance>The cat burglar stories? Why would anyone...with so much to lose...take those kinds of risks?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A held beat. His glance lifts beyond her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>You'd have to be. Stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And walks off toward a sleek custom TOURING CAR just pulling up. She goes after him.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know Porsche made things like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tipping the valet. Sliding in...</context>
      <utterance>Well, they don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shutting the door. Through the open window, she hands something from her bag. A plastic rectangle which OPENS into a slide viewer. She presses the light ON. He looks at the slide.</context>
      <utterance>...as a rule.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Recognize that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans closer.</context>
      <utterance>My seller is in Shinjuku, we can go there tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands it back. Looks in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>He wants 4.6 million. I can get it for three.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And TAKES OFF. Her jaw drops slightly, but in one fluid motion... She's hailed a cab.</context>
      <utterance>No, you can't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...only it's not bloody</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him the great smile.</context>
      <utterance>My favorite thing in life. Coincidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now he smiles. First time ever. A little chilling, the way he does it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm staying here, what's your excuse?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In one motion, he flags the bartender...</context>
      <utterance>Staying here, as well. You are in room...? GIN  One thirty-eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses some currency into the barkeep's hand. Turning back...</context>
      <utterance>Will you send a half-bottle of Chateau d'Yquem '67 to Room 138, please? And some berries and chocolates for the lady to enjoy it with.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. She's shocked. He agrees...</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I was just across the room, dickering with a gentleman over the purchase of an interesting Spitzweg. Until I determined the painting was apparently stolen...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Goes against my grain. The DeKooning in your slide, the 4.6 million you can get for 3. Can you get it for 2 and a half?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as if he believed her...</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His smile evaporates. He is gone before she can say...</context>
      <utterance>My checkbook is in my safe. You wait here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'll wait here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens it. One eye on the road, he begins to rummage...</context>
      <utterance>That's my purse.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She SNATCHES the bag away from him, he GRABS it back, the car SWERVES LEFT, and... ...CRASHES VIOLENTLY into a parked pure white Bentley. Metal BUCKLES and TEARS, both ALARMS go OFF, a cacophony of horrific</context>
      <utterance>Just want to see if I'm with the person you say you are. Can't be too caref...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOISE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People come RUNNING, but our focus is drawn to the refined elderly COUPLE who were just returning to their precious Bentley. Their WAILS and ANGUISH would be suitable if all their grandchildren had been crushed beneath Mac's wheels. Mac and Gin are OUT of the car. As he exits, Mac has palmed a small BLADE, and in a quick unseen motion, RIPPED a jagged tear in his left trouser leg. The old couple RUSH to Mac, SHRIEKING their rage and grief in Japanese, Gin is trying to calm them as bystanders gather, but Mac cuts through... MAC (subtitled Japanese) We'll go in there, and call the police. And HOBBLES off toward the nearest building, a block-square 30-story skyscraper bearing the name FUJITSU. The couple, the crowd, all race after the limping Mac...</context>
      <utterance>MAC  Oh, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer, he looks dark enough to rain. INTO the public lobby of the huge industrial complex. Two night GUARDS come hurrying from their desk, as the small mob POURS in. Mac in the lead, a commanding presence, tells the guards in a loud, clear voice... MAC (subtitled Japanese) I have damaged the car of these kind people. Please help them call the police... One guard leads the hysterical couple toward a phone. Mac pulls up his trouser leg, and Gin GASPS to see a bloody GASH. Mac drops the trouser back over the wound. Asks the remaining guard... MAC (subtitled Japanese) May I use a washroom, please. The guard nods absently, disoriented by the chaos. Mac hands his billfold to Gin...</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are my papers, passport, car registration. If the police arri...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Soft words, genuine concern. And his eyes flicker. As if somehow seeing her for the first time. A small spark, but she feels it. Softer still...</context>
      <utterance>You're going to need stitches, let me get you to a hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look holds.</context>
      <utterance>Really, this can all wait. I'll handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His first real smile. It was worth waiting for. MAC (to a guard, subtitled Japanese) Might you have a First Aid kit, of some kind?</context>
      <utterance>That's actually. Very sweet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No sound. Uh-oh.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. MacDougal? Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The security guard BARGES IN.</context>
      <utterance>Uh. Mr. Ma... MAC  Just 'Mac'. And whatever became of a gentleman's privacy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The guard starts railing at Gin a mile a minute. She calmly takes a WAD of bills from her purse. Hands them to the guy... GIN (subtitled Japanese) Stand outside. That door. Two minutes... He does. Alone again.</context>
      <utterance>My God, more females?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was worried, it's been twenty...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighteen, actually. The leg is fine, but I got sort of...woozy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woozy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CUT INSIDE the stall. He is just re-taping the folded clean suit and hood to the small of his back.</context>
      <utterance>Lost my stomach once or twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Awkward silence. He smiles at that, much amused. Slips on his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>I'm an old man. You probably noticed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UNLOCKS the door. Remembers...</context>
      <utterance>You should see me without my teeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's not what he forgot. He pulls OUT the coiled black satin cloth strip, SNAPS it free, microchips snug to the underside. And fits it neatly... ...DOWN his trouser leg. The perfect tuxedo stripe. OUT the door. To meet her gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Ah. Mustn't forget to zip up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to her. Offers his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Odd place, this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes it, wrapping both hers through.</context>
      <utterance>What do you suppose they make here? Video recorders?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door. Ushers her through...</context>
      <utterance>Microchips, I think, for computers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Follows her out...</context>
      <utterance>Bad investment. The best ones are here today...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Closed door. Quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Gone tomor...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking straight ahead. Contemplative. She stares at his profile...</context>
      <utterance>This isn't the way to my sel... MAC  I've changed my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind telling me why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't get it for me at 2.5, can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we can tr...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs. Never looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>You were setting me up. The correct price is 2.8. You conspire with the seller to start at 4.6, so I'll be grateful when you 'bargain' him down to three. Close enough to fool some people. unfortunately...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She keeps staring.</context>
      <utterance>I'm old. I know what everything is worth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where are we g...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thinks. Admits...</context>
      <utterance>I am going to the airport. You are going on to the rest of your life. Which...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her turn to think.</context>
      <utterance>...should be interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You forgot your lugg...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little twist on that.</context>
      <utterance>The hotels deal with that. The things I need are always waiting at the next one.  I don't carry. Baggage.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sensible. And you're off to...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He still stares straight ahead. The taxi pulls onto a freeway. Toward Narita Airport. Time running out. And in her dearest, most vulnerable, voice...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's highly personal.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the fingertips of her left hand. On his chest. A silence. No reaction. GIN (hopeful) I'm still hoping... And he smiles. Turns to her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I did so hope to impress you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And softly. Fits her mouth to his. The green eyes close, as she tastes him. Nothing predatory in this kiss. It is tender, exquisite. A kiss of deep longing. Of true love. His arms slip around her. And in less than five seconds... TAXI DRIVER (O.S., racist accent) Still on fo' airport? Nobody. Says. Nothin'.</context>
      <utterance>Young lady. I am old enough to be your grandfather. She shakes her head. Uh-uh. GIN  My father. Leans her mouth in for the kill. GIN  That's part of the rush.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She curls down into the billowing coverlet, just against his body. Sets her things beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Here. A reward.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A reward for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a lovely smile. He studies it for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>For not being old. After all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And kisses him. It takes awhile. She seems to enjoy it. With him, it's harder to tell. When she pulls back... ...he picks up a chocolate. Tears it in half. Offers her the larger piece.</context>
      <utterance>You mean. Not as old as I look. She traces her finger along his cheek. GIN  Yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. He puts the chocolate into her mouth. With great tenderness, he traces the line of her lower lip. As she swallows.</context>
      <utterance>Do I deserve a reward?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he just looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>It's so hard to find good casual sex, anymore. I'm probably out of practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And leans closer. Just above a whisper...</context>
      <utterance>What's hard to find. Is someone you truly want to be with.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her. Beautiful and deep, the way he does it. And when he pulls back, she is staring at him. As if at a loss for something to say.</context>
      <utterance>Even for awhile.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swallows. Because his gaze is unrelenting. As if not forgetting that she's changed the subject.</context>
      <utterance>It's lucky we stopped by my room, for the wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Otherwise, we'd never have found my bag was stolen. Until tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. His face looks kind now, not formidable at all. Maybe she's wondering if she actually likes him.</context>
      <utterance>Would that make it more stolen?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They even got my prescriptions.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does look concerned. And therefore sweet. She kisses his nose.</context>
      <utterance>Something you need? There are all-night chemists...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets her old smile. The soft, wicked tease.</context>
      <utterance>I take Prilosec. For stomach acid. And an inhaler. For asthma.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her. Cocks a finger, like a gun, right between her eyes. Pantomimes pulling the trigger. GIN (softly) Ouch. I had that coming. She pivots, and snuggles her back comfortably into his chest. He wraps strong arms around her. Pulling her close.</context>
      <utterance>But since I didn't have to work all that hard tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would someone steal</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such as...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A flicker. In her eyes. And she cuddles back. As if enjoying the humor.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Wannabe dealers make excellent fences.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He thought I had a stolen painting. In my bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kisses the top of her head.</context>
      <utterance>I'm joking, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes widen. Just a little.</context>
      <utterance>The Vermeer wouldn't fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns all the way around. Their faces are inches apart. Each reading the other's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Why, did you do something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said. Vermeer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His turn. To kiss her nose.</context>
      <utterance>The most famous painting stolen this week.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And lowers her gently onto her back. Still staring in her eyes, he winds her legs around him. Her mouth parts, but... ...he fills it with his own. This conversation. Is over.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't keep up on your craft. You'll miss all the jokes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up. Trademark dry grin...</context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad I didn't leave Tokyo.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands over her. Smiling. What he meant was...</context>
      <utterance>I love a guy who knows how to sweet talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A call.</context>
      <utterance>There was a call. While you were sleeping.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An art dealer I know. He has a Monet. Minor, but it</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now her eyes come up. She says nothing. Hesitant.</context>
      <utterance>If I'm there, he'll haggle. You just hand him the debit card, with that...luminous smile. And say, take it or leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, dear. I thought you so wanted to make a good impression.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought I already did th...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And along with making an</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any problems. Just give me a ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stolen painting is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And on his way out the door...</context>
      <utterance>Of course not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it was. I wouldn't pay more than three.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>OKATI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The best we can say for the pudgy, balding fellow in the Hawaiian shirt and spectacularly baggy trousers, is that he does not seem to be the guy who is selling you a Monet. Even a minor one.</context>
      <utterance>You doin' it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think there's some mista...</utterance>
   <speaker>OKATI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops. Jesus. The guy COUGHS horribly.</context>
      <utterance>You from Mac?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm from Mac.</utterance>
   <speaker>OKATI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme see card.</utterance>
   <speaker>OKATI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wow. He slaps his hand on the table. Lay it down, toots.</context>
      <utterance>Four million, six hundred thirteen thousand, five hundred?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs. Lifts straight up, from beneath the counter... ...a brown paper-wrapped rectangle. Not much larger than two feet square. She can't even believe she's here, doing this. Gestures to him. Open it up! He obliges, COUGHING grossly all the while. Unwrapped, the painting</context>
      <utterance>You first.</utterance>
   <speaker>OKATI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And from within her pocket. The cellular RINGS. She takes it out. Puts it to her ear.</context>
      <utterance>This as real as it gets, lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it? GIN  Is this an audition, a joke, or a rip-off? I'm staring at an obvious forgery, here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>This gives her pause. Then, cradling the phone against her shoulder, she does as she's told. To see...</context>
      <utterance>Turn it over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there an envelope? Taped to the back? In a Ziploc bag? Sure is. GIN  Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She does. Carefully unfolding several sheets of paper, maps... GIN (reading into phone) Shikoku Naru, a freighter, it says, Yokohama to Jakarta...dates, statistics...specs on some kind of machine, diag...</context>
      <utterance>Detach the bag. Read what's in it. Aloud.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papers</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She begins to.</context>
      <utterance>While he's checking, look around the room casually, as if searching for the cheesy handbags...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the while laughing, as if you are chatting with someone you actually</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Call out cheerily to Okati, in English, 'Where's the toilet?' GIN  Can I say, 'little girl's room'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>GIN (calls out, cheerily)</context>
      <utterance>Wing it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get going. Now. GIN  Mac, the painting isn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She turns the corner. Filthy corridor. Restrooms at opposite ends.</context>
      <utterance>You've got what we bought, are you out of their sight?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jump? HEAR now, from the corridor, footfalls POUNDING. She looks down through the piss hole. The surf ROILS thirty feet below. GIN (into phone) It's too small.</context>
      <utterance>Jump.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he says nothing. Pulls out a water-tight duffle. Hands it back to her, without looking.</context>
      <utterance>I guess you're gonna explain all this, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the bag, confused.</context>
      <utterance>Dry clothes, you'll need them. In five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm supposed to change?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are a million</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gin looks around as they float through the maze of watercraft. No one seems to be paying much attention. What the hell. She unzips the bag, pulling out... GIN (astonished) These...these are mine! He never looks around.</context>
      <utterance>You probably won't be dating any of them, so what the hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at the back of his head. wondering. He is stripping off his slickers. A neatly-tailored SUIT beneath.</context>
      <utterance>Found 'em in your room. Perhaps the thief wasn't your size.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Okay. She pulls her dress off OVER her head.</context>
      <utterance>We have a business appointment. In four minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She ignores some nearby WHISTLES and SHOUTS. Begins drying herself with a fluffy towel from the bag. MAC (never turns) Time has come to tell you. What business. I'm actually in. Uh-oh. Paydirt.</context>
      <utterance>Business, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can scarcely</context>
      <utterance>Uh. Am I gonna like th... MAC  I'm a thief.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slips the dry dress OVER her head.</context>
      <utterance>Or...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you can spend the most interesting three weeks of your life. Training.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Training for wha...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...followed by the most exciting</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins taking off her wet underwear, underneath the dress. We suspect unseen hordes crestfallen at her modesty.</context>
      <utterance>From now on. You can valet park.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I refuse? MAC  Don't. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, you won't</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What could you possibly steal in 18 min...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-five</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stole your suitcase when I left you at the bar. I have since sent it on to the States, with</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holy. Fucking. Christ.</context>
      <utterance>They receive. An anonymous. Tip.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's entrapment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can feel her heart pounding from here.</context>
      <utterance>No, entrapment is what cops do to robbers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have glided up beside the gangway of a gigantic FREIGHTER. It is at water level, the steps they use for their tender. He points up to the name...</context>
      <utterance>Blackmail. Is what robbers do to schmucks. And leans. To kiss her mouth. MAC  Even adorable ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SHIKOKU MARU. She nods, slowly. Pulls the Ziploc bag from her purse. Hands it over. He removes the sheets of paper. Begins to peruse them...</context>
      <utterance>Pop quiz.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Admit it's a rush. The best day of your heretofore drab life.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances up.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers his hand. She rises, hops lightly to the steps of the gangway in her bare feet. He pulls dry shoes from the duffle. And as she slips them on... ...he FLIPS a switch, and the Jetski begins to FILL with water, Mac stepping to the gangway beside her. They watch... ...the Jetski rapidly SINK out of sight. No evidence. A thorough guy.</context>
      <utterance>...accompanied by related foreplay. And gives him the smile. What a gal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MacDuff, yes?</context>
      <utterance>Nickerson Carlsby, Mr...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little man pauses. A tic in the well-oiled smile...</context>
      <utterance>Banquo MacDuff. This is my associate-fiancee, Ms. Duncan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is...fiancee</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE...Carlsby leads the way along a narrow catwalk, which ends at a steel door. He presses his thumb to the I.D. panel, and speaks into the voice box... CARLSBY (confidential code-voice) In Penny Lane, the barber shaves another customer... The door CLANGS open. They go through it, as a gangway leads toward an open five-foot-thick VAULT DOOR, where two ARMED GUARDS rise from their seats. Carlsby ignores them as if they were furniture. THUMPS the door...</context>
      <utterance>I'm a Scot. It's a different country. Culturally and historically. I see. CARLSBY  Well. They've brought you to quite the wrong place, I see. MAC  Thank God.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five feet thick with hidden rein- forcements, no way to drill through! GIN  Impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They do.</context>
      <utterance>Only the tip of our security iceberg. See these two Brinks locks...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Captain keeps one key. The other is continually forwarded: to the Chief of Security at next port. There is no way to enter during voyage.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carisby glances to Mac. He is stone.</context>
      <utterance>I like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best armed guard, rotated every six hours. A redundancy, of course, but we would rather be safe three times over than merely two.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. Carlsby leads them through the open door, into... ...the maximum-security HOLD. Primo. The steel coated with sleek, matte, black all-grip paint. Tubby points up...</context>
      <utterance>Sound mathematics. MAC  What if there's a fire? In the chamber.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sprinklers. New design. Incredible power. The entire chamber is water- proof, fireproof, airtight. If the ship</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wine.</context>
      <utterance>Wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Actually. He has.</context>
      <utterance>The bloody Japs bought up half the premium clarets in the universe. You may have heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlsby gets the romance of it all.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in charge of shipping some 14,000 bottles, most quite rare, to a number of premium hotels in Hong Kong, Bangkok, Singapore, Phuket, and Penang.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And turns to the man. With laser, disapproving eyes.</context>
      <utterance>All of which are destinations on your October voyage. Five months from now. However...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man beams. Gestures to a series of PLATFORMS, each SWAYING at different heights, in different directions.</context>
      <utterance>Wine. Doesn't prefer. To be jostled.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pointing once more...</context>
      <utterance>Our 'delicate treasure' platforms, suspended on gimbals. Your cargo remains unruffled by roiling seas. Then, on arrival, is plucked...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...a huge circular hatch cut into the hull. Mac's eyes stare blankly at it. A long beat. He pronounces it all...</context>
      <utterance>By that forklift, and gently deposited on dock through the cargo hatch...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then turns once more.</context>
      <utterance>Adequate. I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On deck?</context>
      <utterance>Did we see...a bathing pool.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mac. Thinks this over.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, sir. The Shikoku Maru carries sixteen luxury suite pas- senger cabins. The finest cuisine. For valued clients who prefer to cruise in privacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mildly. Interesting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adequate. I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mac pulls from his pocket the folded sheets that had once been taped to the back of Okati's Monet. Peruses them casually.</context>
      <utterance>But dearest, in five months, we'll be in Cape Town.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And looks up. To a man dumbstruck. By coincidence.</context>
      <utterance>Anything sooner? That goes perhaps from...say, Sri Lanka? To Jakarta.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, yes. In three weeks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to see them both in jumping suits. He's checking her gear. She's eyeing the expansive grid of fields below.</context>
      <utterance>You seem depressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At your insistence, I'm leaping to my death, and I don't know</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not jumping until you</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it do, make gold?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're nearing the targ...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why won't you trust me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stares in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>How do I know who you are, hmmn?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares back. Dead straight.</context>
      <utterance>For all I know, your name isn't Virginia Romay. Maybe you're a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His smile is light, affectionate. Gently, he backs her to the edge of the doorway...</context>
      <utterance>Why would a cop do all th... MAC  Entrapment, remember? What cops do to robbers. GIN  Oh. That.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She THROWS her arms around his neck. Holds him close.</context>
      <utterance>One...two...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vulnerable and touchingly real. His arms slide around her.</context>
      <utterance>Mac, I'm afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And JUMPS, Gin SHRIEKING in his arms, as we... FOLLOW them, TUMBLING in FREE FALL, until he releases her, and bot EXTEND their arms and legs, as if flying, as if gliding face down, her shriek CONTINUING. He floats at the end of their tether, a few feet above her. And at last... ...her SCREAMING STOPS. We see the pure adrenaline rush. Shouts back...</context>
      <utterance>Of you. MAC  Smart girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She blinks the spray from her eyes, and deftly SEARS the wire dividing those two numbers on the board. As Mac keeps waving it, she goes off line. Concentrates. Gets it right. The wire PEELS away...</context>
      <utterance>All right, six and seven...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three and four...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives this some reflection.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are we building?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A chalet, I think. Or an outhouse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she FLIPS OVER, submerging her head and torso, and we go... ...WITH her underwater, upside-down in the kayak, she STRUGGLES to FREE a group of tools which are tethered to her wetsuit. Fumbling to BREAK the seal on a slender TUBE, which BURSTS, sending a GLOW of yellow-green LIGHT in all directions. She fits the flexible tube around her head like a headlamp, pulling out... ...a small ELECTRIC FAN with side HANDGRIPS of black metal. Buffeted by the current, Gin manages to flip a small switch on the housing of the fan, and... ...nothing happens. Again. Nothing. And again. SHIT! With a supreme effort, she tries to ROLL herself upright, but... ...can't quite make it. Blind PANIC now, blowing bubbles, FLAILING at the kayak, which suddenly... ROLLS upright, manipulated by Mac. She sputters and tries to THROW the tethered fan at him, but it snaps back and SLAMS her across the shoulder. She is furious.</context>
      <utterance>Forty seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She nods, got it. Focused. suddenly, in the clearing before her, a HOSTAGE SILHOUETTE TARGET pops up, the outline of a terrorist shielding himself with a hostage, Gin's arm rising with a BLUR and... ...BLAMM, BLAMM, BLAMM!!! The paper terrorist is NAILED in the head. Two out of three. She lets out a thin stream of air. Proud of herself, but too cool to gloat.</context>
      <utterance>This time, when you raise your arm. Don't breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns slowly.</context>
      <utterance>Very, very nice. Had a tour with the Mosad, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His enigmatic, yet fond, smile.</context>
      <utterance>Where does this fit in the game plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A quiet wink.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it doesn't. But one never knows...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might need it with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This one, I will</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something in the way he looks at her. Her return gaze is naked. It looks like love.</context>
      <utterance>Quite remarkable.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And kisses her again. Her eyes close.</context>
      <utterance>Take the rest of the evening off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Webber Assurance.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is oh-four-six-one. Hector Cruz, please, on a secure line.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mac's laptop screen in printing. WEBBER ASSURANCE...HECTOR CRUZ...</context>
      <utterance>Please hold.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>So do Mac's eyes. Click the scanner OFF.</context>
      <utterance>Thank y... The line goes DEAD.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...no way I'm telling you shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baker, this is an extremely</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I tell you</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes are stone cold. We've never seen her like this. She looks like Mac.</context>
      <utterance>Right to the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're over your head, Baker.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's pulling out a different piece of plastic. A drug store phone card.</context>
      <utterance>Only romantically. I'll write to him in prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, it's your funeral. Next time I see you, I owe you a spanking.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her cold eyes through his chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>Ooooo. Is that a promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While you're on secure, do you want a transfer?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And hangs up. Collects her thoughts. Inserts the phone card. Dials from memory. Fifteen digits. She must be calling Mars. At last... ...a man's VOICE. In a strange sing-song language. GIN (subtitled Mandarin) Is it over?</context>
      <utterance>Nope. I'm headed back to the hot tub. I'll call again, if I'm in the mood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to see her in climbing harness, scaling a nearly-vertical CABLE, three feet in diameter. Enveloped in fog which reveals, then conceals.</context>
      <utterance>I'm freezing my tender parts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PULL WAY BACK to see him below her. The two of them climbing the GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE. They are near the top, more than 700 feet above the silvery black BAY. A precarious, dizzying sight.</context>
      <utterance>I'm relieved to hear you have some.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's amazing, is that only eleven workers died during construction of this thing... GIN  ...thanks for sharing...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gin keeps her focus on the small railed PLATFORM just above her. A gutsy gal. MAC (loving it) Now, as for the suicides, they always jump</context>
      <utterance>Of course, the others were saved by a safety net.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One act of fucking human kindness...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he swings lightly up beside her. The fog has rolled past. There are several million stars. Transcendent beauty. She slows her breath...</context>
      <utterance>Call it a lapse.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how does</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He clicks her glass. She stares straight in his eye. Shows no surprise, no fear...</context>
      <utterance>To Ginger Baker.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And takes a sip. Cool as a goose. Licks her lips.</context>
      <utterance>I'm partial to drummers. If they played with Clapton and Winwood.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he's not drinking. Only staring. The wind has picked up.</context>
      <utterance>The prescription bottle. When you stole my suitcase.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes another sip. Good wine.</context>
      <utterance>Armand Baker was my husband, May 13 to October 27, 1982, he played alto sax, I was 17 years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He named me Ginger. He likes drummers, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Every time you order drugs.</context>
      <utterance>And you get sentimental for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have I.D. in that name. I use it for various things I don't want traced. When credit unions turn their computers my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly, he reaches to an inside pocket, watching to see if she flinches. Her eyes do flicker. And follow. He withdraws not a pistol, but a handful of...</context>
      <utterance>I could listen to you lie all night. She toasts him. GIN  Same here, fella.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nine DIAMONDS, so large, so exquisite, she has to keep her eyes from bugging. Wow.</context>
      <utterance>Do you like diamonds?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holy. Christ.</context>
      <utterance>You asked. Does the machine. Make gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes travel her body...</context>
      <utterance>Gold is shit. It's six thousand dollars a pound. Worth your weight in gold...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would put you at seven hundred thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he leans. Looks in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Would you pay it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She liked that. Maybe a lot.</context>
      <utterance>When the light hits you just right. I'd pay more.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer.</context>
      <utterance>The machine. That we are stealing. Makes diamonds?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real ones?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He toasts Blessed Japan to the East. Takes a hit.</context>
      <utterance>Gem quality. First ever. God save Japan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He means this. She is transfixed.</context>
      <utterance>A diamond reactor takes graphite, runs it through a combination of lasers, electron beams, and scanning- tunnel mg microscopes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks down at the diamonds in his palm. His fist CLOSES.</context>
      <utterance>This one uses krypton-fluorine laser, with a new isotope of krypton.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his fist UPSIDE-DOWN. And LETS GO! She GASPS as the brilliant stones FALL toward the sea. Watching, watching, long after the moonlit glimmer has evaporated. A hush.</context>
      <utterance>The atoms are rearranged. And the molecule of graphite becoznes a molecule of...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate it. When you make a point.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STEWARD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to see Mac and Gin dressed as tropical tourists. She hangs on his arm.</context>
      <utterance>All right, then. All set.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will keep your passports in our safe until Jakarta.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are Suite 16...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The steward doesn't get it. Gin shrugs, sorry.</context>
      <utterance>...and never been kissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had booked Suite 9.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mac consents. A little wary.</context>
      <utterance>16 is our Tokugawa Suite, far superior, trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You luggage is</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He means a tiny grouping of LIGHTS. Way down there, against the darkness. He switches on the AUTOPILOT. Goes back to... ...Gin, waiting in her jump suit, sitting on a large pack of gear just beside the window of the jump door. Next to her, a pack that is even larger. No fear in her eyes tonight. Pure adrenaline.</context>
      <utterance>Down there. Ten o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you dumping fuel?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she stands, he begins to strap the huge pack ONTO her body. Jesus. With her chute, and the other gear attached, the load makes us uneasy. Not her.</context>
      <utterance>Changed my mind. There's nothing on the instruments downrange. The longer she flies before she ditches, the less chance they notice on the Bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should lose the oxygen tank at 8000 feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to an altimeter device on his wrist. It says 12,000 feet. She cuts him a look.</context>
      <utterance>And how do I judge that? Babe's intuition?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out an identical device. Strapping it to her wrist...</context>
      <utterance>So I just ask you on the way down? Or were you planning to e-mail me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He straps the even-larger gear pack to himself. Checks the path of the tiny lights far below. Then, looks in her eyes... MAC (simply) You can do this. Not merely reassurance. Affection. Something connective between them. You are my partner. Her eyes send back that personal bond, and she nods. I can do this. Good girl. He pulls on his oxygen mask, goggles. She does the same. He OPENS the door, air BLASTING in. One more look down below, and he holds up ten fingers. Counts them down, nine...eight... She moves to the edge. Watching him. And on zero, she... ARCHES out INTO the starry VOID, and we go... WITH HER, the incomparable RUSH of freefall, straining to see him FOLLOW, skillfully altering his position to gain on her, coming close. She is looking between him and her altimeter, as... ...his oxygen tank FALLS AWAY, and she CUTS hers loose, the air RUSHING past her, she looks DOWN... ...the lights below are beginning to take the shape of the freighter. Back up to Mac, as he... PULLS his CHUTE, it is black and square, and JOLTS him to what seems like a full STOP far above her, and she YANKS her cord, but... ...nothing. It doesn't open. She is ROCKETING down, looking back up to see Mac make an exaggerated CUTTING sign across his body, and she closes her eyes, PULLS her secondary chute, which... POPS open, JARRING her violently, and she GASPS with the shock. He is well above her now, she isoff course, frantically trying to manipulate her trajectory, seeing him swooping closer, the freighter LOOMS in distance, she looks down and suddenly... ...the sea is RUSHING at her, she FIGHTS her braking mechanism, SHOUTING at herself...</context>
      <utterance>I hate a crybaby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes are wild.</context>
      <utterance>It's over, it's over...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees the FREIGHTER now, a black mountain CUTTING the sea, a huge WAKE pluming from its bow. She grabs his waist with all she's got.</context>
      <utterance>Catch your breath, quickly. Hang on for the wake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I were you, I'd watch the desserts.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I'll bet you were in shape before you got old.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And pulls himself up to the second rung, so that he is standing an the first. Offers her his hand...</context>
      <utterance>Too long ago to remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suit yourself. They begin to climb up the rungs, like a tilted backwards ladder, re-attaching their clips as they go.</context>
      <utterance>I can take it from here, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you'd packed my primary chute right, I wouldn't ha...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up, up. And stop. They are nearly halfway to the top. Looking across the curved hull to... ...a large circular HATCH. Thirty feet away. The goal. Mac pulls from his pack... ...their SUCTION CUP gear. With practiced speed, they fasten cups to the balls of their feet, take hold of the hand rods with cups attached, and Mac takes the lead as they begin to... ...move LATERALLY across the hull's surface toward the hatch. Mac is amazingly agile at the arduous process, scuttling sideways like a crab across the precariously tilted-back hull. Gin is deter- mined, but falls well behind, intent on making every suction seal solid one. Dark water RACES by beneath her., By the time she looks up at the hatch... He is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you would. You're a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She looks UP sharply. He is ABOVE the hatch, attached to the hull by the balls of his feet, hanging down like a bat. Noting her astonishment...</context>
      <utterance>Anytime you're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That it is. He has pulled a thick cylinder from his pack. It's a battery-operated AIR WRENCH, and with a menacing WHIRR, only partially masked by the ship's wake, he begins to swiftly POP all the rivets around the hatch. Gin has pulled out the slender WELDING TOOL we saw in the shower, and begins CUTTING through the metal seals around the hatch's rim. At thecrucial moment...</context>
      <utterance>Better angle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which she BARELY does, as the hatch door PLUMMETS past her to the sea. BIG splash. Gone. When she turns back, Mac is already THROUGH the opening and she follows, their yellow-green headlamps partially revealing... ...the maximum-security HOLD. We've seen this with Carlsby. The fork lift. The shadowy multitude of PLATFORMS on their gimbals, all SWAYING, in different directions with the plunging of the ship. Gin just stands, staring everywhere, like she's broken into Fort Knox. The ROAR of the engines is louder here, and he moves close to her to speak beneath it...</context>
      <utterance>You might want to move aside...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Slightly embarrassed at her lack of split-second efficiency, she tries to find the thing in her gear. After watching her fumble for a bit...</context>
      <utterance>May I trouble you for the torch? Or would you rather just dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...he just reaches in and pulls it out. A small LANTERN which he FLICKS on, brilliantly ILLUMINATING the entire hold. Scans the platforms...polnts to a CRATE wrapped in 4-ply heavy duty plastic membrane.</context>
      <utterance>I know I packed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coal into diamonds. A wealth machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know that's it? MAC  It's 12 by 9 by 7 feet. And it's the only thing worth waterproofing, in case the ship sinks. GIN  ...you twit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmn?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's heading toward the swaying platforms...</context>
      <utterance>I'm just finishing your sentence. Can't you answer a question with- out making me feel stupid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is climbing onto a lower platform, easily vaulting up to the magic crate. She follows, but it isn't as easy as he's made it look. She has to scramble, almost falling. He's already pulled from his gear... ...six rubber POUCHES. She hands him her welding tool, and he begins attaching the pouches to the top and sides of the crate. The plunging ship has the platform really rocking. GIN (concerned) They don't</context>
      <utterance>Why would I bother?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swallows. Hard.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get one thing straight. I don't work with partners much, because basically, I find most people to be idiots.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches the effect of that play across her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You, in contrast, are first-rate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises. JUMPS down to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Precise coordinates. You could find a golf ball in the Gobi Desert.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you g... MAC  Fork lift.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't they hear it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She hurriedly secures the last of her Kevlar lines.</context>
      <utterance>Over these engines? Through five feet of steel?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He is driving up in the rickety fork lift. Weaving around crates and equipment.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, if they do, they don't have the second key to get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hops lightly from the fork lift, reaches up, and she jumps down INTO his arms. Quickly, the switch places, Gin climbing into the idling fork lift, as Mac clambers up to UNBOLT the crate's pallet with his air wrench... Gin moves the fork lift into position. Mac bracing his legs against neighboring cargo, using all his strength to hold our crate steady. He is</context>
      <utterance>Thank God for redundant security.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She LIFTS the crate, but the boat LURCHES, and she nearly LOSES it off the fork. But she doesn't. SWINGS her load around now. Heading for the open hatchway, the roiling sea racing by. Picking up SPEED, slightly...</context>
      <utterance>You gotta work on that impatient streak. ...and slips them straight IN. First try. GIN  How professional.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now she is really ROLLING toward the wide open spaces...</context>
      <utterance>Uh. Thing on the left is the brakes? MAC  Or the thing on the right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...TIPPING at the hatchway lip, the crate sliding OFF the prongs, our forklift TUMBLING OUT the hatch to the sea, just as Mac... ...SNATCHES Gin by her HAIR, pulling her FREE of the falling forklift, CATCHING the rim of the hatchway with his free hand, Gin SCREAMING in fright and pain, BLINDLY grabbing his arm to be... ...jerked BACK to safety. Clutching Mac, she watches the sea behind them. Where the crate and the forklift disappeared.</context>
      <utterance>JUMP, for God's sa...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her head WHIPS around. Aghast.</context>
      <utterance>You did activate the floaters.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Activa...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>floaters'. Surely, you heard me. Her life. Flashes before her eyes. As behind the ship... ...the crate BOBS to the surface. We can see the tiny red light on the transponder from here. MAC (softly) Oh. Guess I did it m'self. She WHIPS back, and starts POUNDING at him with her fists. He is laughing so hard, he takes a few good shots before he can GRASP her wrists. She SPITS in his face. He strikes back by... ...kissing her hard. She struggles for a beat. And then she lets him. When they finish, he reaches to UNZIP her jumping suit. All the way. Pulls it down gently, revealing... ...her evening gown. A wrinkle-free material which slips down across her legs from where it had been bunched across her hips. He is unzipping his outfit as well, revealing formal wear of his own. He stuffs the suits into his gear pack, removing only... ...her evening bag and shoes. Then lifting both packs, he...</context>
      <utterance>I did say, 'Finish up on the</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...FLINGS them into the black ocean. Gone.</context>
      <utterance>Um...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So he turns. She looks really stunned. And scared.</context>
      <utterance>...I wouldn't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points. To where no suction things are lying. GIN (a mouse) ...so I put 'em in my pack? His eyes WIDEN.</context>
      <utterance>Well...I saw our suction things. Lying...over...there?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tilts her head. Gives him a great smile. Is he enraged? His dry grin says, not hardly.</context>
      <utterance>Or maybe. I put 'em there. And points. To where they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then again. You can never tell.</context>
      <utterance>I like a quick study.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...no matter how many stones we make, the diamonds are just an appetizer. GIN  And the meal...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She blinks. Hit by a ton of bricks.</context>
      <utterance>My contract. With DeBeers.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my G...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He WHIRLS her in a tight spin. The geriatic Germans can only watch and envy.</context>
      <utterance>Sensible folks, DeBeers. A world monopoly in diamonds based on one simple principle...something's only priceless if it's scarce.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These guys dig up all the diamonds on the planet, just to keep them</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imagine the chaos</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gin likes the ring of that. Green eyes dance with delight.</context>
      <utterance>We're sort of bounty hunters.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our machine is worth</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you missed cocktails.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You twit.</context>
      <utterance>Or my name's not Banquo MacDuff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...well, I</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thinks about this. And then...</context>
      <utterance>Time has come to tell you. What business. I'm actually in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holds out his hand. She hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>It only looks dangerous...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gives her the smile. She puts her hand in his, and they hop UP to the platform. Walk its length to the very end. He turns now, leans casually against the fragile railing. They are inches apart.</context>
      <utterance>You couldn't fall off. Unless someone threw you over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gin looks down at the plume of wake leaping off the bow.</context>
      <utterance>More intimate. For a confession.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up. To his eyes. Into them.</context>
      <utterance>What business. You are actually. In.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh. I'm not an art dealer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And tilts his head. Just to one side.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. You're a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An insurance investigator for Webber Assurance, your boss is an idiot named Hector Cruz, you've been there four years and ten months, you're quite the rising star. GIN  Nope. His head tilts. Just a little farther. MAC  Nope?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holds the look.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a thief, Mac.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face absolutely neutral. Unreadable.</context>
      <utterance>For five years, I've used the database of every client Webber has to plan my jobs. Museums, banks, jewelers, rich people, I have floor plans, alarm codes, passwords, the works.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've made a fortune. It's not enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why n...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He falls silent.</context>
      <utterance>Why wasn't it enough for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No smile at her lips. Strictly business.</context>
      <utterance>The Vermeer that was stolen from Hancock Tower? That was my job. I scaled the building with electromagnets, and parachuted down an air vent...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a partner. For the biggest, smartest, job. Ever. The one you retire off of, because nothing else could ever compare with the rush.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever. Is such a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a job that can only be done in</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not a real trusting guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I tried so hard to hide that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's two jobs. The first steals something priceless from the National Palace Museum in Taipei. We don't keep that. We trade it in for our ticket to the show.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One moment in time, you s...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now. She has his interest. She can see that.</context>
      <utterance>Midnight, July 1, 1997. Eight days from now. The moment that Hong Kong is annexed by china.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>80-20 split.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be so hard on yourself. It's your plan, you should take at least thirty perc...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna do with six billion dollars that you can't do with four?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This. He likes. So much that he leans to kiss her, with surprising tenderness.</context>
      <utterance>Hold the record. Alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hard stare. And then, she smiles. Just barely. Still in his arms...</context>
      <utterance>Your share is 50%. And one dollar.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like what you left. In the hold.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't even see wha...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is the most taken with her that he has ever looked. She leans up and kisses him. Whispers...</context>
      <utterance>A lump of coal. A pair of pliers. A note that said, 'Squeeze hard'.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Squeeze hard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator JOLTS to life.</context>
      <utterance>That's Madame Chiang Kaishek, she's my bud. An evil streak a mile wide.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They CLANG upward. Mac seems utterly relaxed. Gin paces a little, hugging herself. Her features tense. MAC (gently) Tired? She blinks up. He is straddling the bike. Smiling at her.</context>
      <utterance>No surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. Well...</context>
      <utterance>I have a lot on my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seems to mean that. And it seems to melt her a little. She sags against the wall, closing her eyes, as... ...they JOLT to a stop. She PULLS the heavy LEVER, and the door SLIDES noisily open, to reveal... ...a gigantic LOFT. She flicks on a dim light, but we see only part of the cavernous space. She strolls, Madame Chiang trotting along behind. Mac follows, looking around, then down to see... ...a pile of MAIL, cables, packages. The unopened MAILING TUBE we saw in the Hancock Tower penthouse. He crouches, lifts the tube in his hands...</context>
      <utterance>You look beautiful doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna buy a Vermeer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rather steal it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He nods to himself. Guess so. He rises to see her framed against the gaping starlit opening of a huge LOADING DOOR. The twinkling island lies below. But here, Gin stares down at... ...an elaborate architectural MODEL. Fifteen feet across, it features an imposing yellow, pagoda-roofed BUILDING, built into the side of a model MOUNTAIN. Formal gardens, fountains, tiny Kuomintang flags. Stretching away from the building, a large portion of the CITY, with shops and alleyways elaborately detailed. As Mac joins her...</context>
      <utterance>Been there, done that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bends to lift UP the detachable roof. All the rooms are detailed within, down to exhibit cases.</context>
      <utterance>National Palace Museum, Taipei, Taiwan. Repository of four thousand years of Chinese culture...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Works of gold, bronze, jade, onyx, pots and scrolls, paintings and porcelains and lacquer work. Every treasure the Kuomintang could loot before the Reds took over.  Ever rob the place?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes him by the hand, and leads him toward the gaping doorway, walking straight toward it...</context>
      <utterance>No. If memory serves.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our ANGLE closes on the doorway, to see OUT now, sitting like a jewel against the hillside... ...the NATIONAL PALACE MUSEUM, looking exactly like the model. The town spread out beyond. Just as in the model. And now we TILT sharply DOWN to see... ...a loading PLATFORM, suspended above the island, only a few feet below our opening. Like a balcony without a railing. Mac and Gin already sinking down onto a waiting futon. Looks like he's made his pick. Among limited options.</context>
      <utterance>You need to eat something, or are you ready for sex? And just at the edge of it... MAC  The options seem so limited. They jump THROUGH the opening. And VANISH.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LOST in another brief subway rumble. He lightly VAULTS up through the doorway. Looks around, no Gin. Goes to the model. Lifts the note pinned to the Vermeer... MAC (reads) This lovely parting gift can be yours. If the price is right. Stumped. Not in his cultural database. He looks at the model, to see that the stretch of city between museum and mountain has been lifted away, revealing... ...an underground RAILWAY TUNNEL between the two. Mac examines the tiny train, the tracks, the winding route. From the side walls, well above the tracks, huge VENTILATION PIPES open onto the tunnel. Starting at the museum end, they are labeled VENT 1, and so on. There are five. The last one shortly before... ...the mountain. Where a cavernous opening is labeled BARRACKS. Tiny toy soldiers kneel on a landing, rifles in position to shoot at the oncoming train. And as Mac studies this curiously... ...the nearby SUBWAY RATTLES the walls once more. Sounds like it's in the room, somehow. Mac rises. Saunters across the loft, and we see for the first time the enormity of this space. Suddenly, the floor ends, and we are looking down nearly thirty feet onto... ...a spacious HANGAR, outfitted with 150 feet of RAILWAY TRACK, at the far end of which sits a full-sited TRAIN CAR, exactly like the one in the model. And just below us... ...Gin crouches on a concave platform of corrugated metal, eighteen feet above the track. She holds a remote control device, which she uses to REV the train's engine, far down the line. She looks really tense.</context>
      <utterance>Ginny...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She startles slightly. Shuts OFF the train's engine. As she looks up to him now, the silence is noticeable. He crouches down, only a foot or so above her...</context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite a parting gift. I would have settled for roses.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's clueless. But smiling.</context>
      <utterance>It's a joke. You know, a joke? People who have a sense of humor make them?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're rich, go buy an American, have him fill you in on the culture.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah. American culture. Well, that</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is it?</context>
      <utterance>Is it easier now? Not pretending.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Effortlessly, he hops down to join her. Never losing eye contact.</context>
      <utterance>Not pretending you're an innocent. Not pretending you...like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Settles next to her. Bodies touching.</context>
      <utterance>Here's a tip from an old-timer. Never forget who you are...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Okay? She nods, slowly. Her eyes moving over his face. Maybe more feelings going through her than she can sort out. MAC (still soft) So. Our train runs from the museum, through an underground tunnel. To a mountain.</context>
      <utterance>It gives you someone to be. When you stop pretending.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because the museum displays 10,000 relics at any given moment. But there are 60</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The train shuttles relics to and from storage. It looks exactly like that. So Mac looks down the line. At the train car.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been down the air ducts four times. The train always has two armed guards. Always travels between 32 and 36 miles per hour. Relics don't like to be jostled too much. MAC  Your model has five vents.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We go down the first. Back up the third, if you're lucky. If not, we</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems like overkill. For one simple jump.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flicks ON her remote. Down the track the engine REVS. Like crazy.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's an eight billion dollar jump. You miss the train...you've missed the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Once midnight passes on July 1st...</context>
      <utterance>We've got five days to grab the Bones, trade them for the Scan, and pull our 8 billion out of Hong Kong.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bones? The Scan?</context>
      <utterance>...we've missed the train, yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Have I neglected to fill in the details?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An oversight.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLICKS the remote, the train LEAP5 forward, 36 MPH never seemed so fast! She has a split-second to LEAP down, the train SAILS beneath her, Gin's feet GRAZE the back end of the platform at the rear of the car, she SWIPES DESPERATELY with the magnets, can't connect, and is THROWN into a ROLL along the side of the tracks. She's UP on her knees, watching the train SLAM into the massive blue PADS at the end of the track. She is bruised, shaken, but most of all, really worried and</context>
      <utterance>Which I learned from the master. Hey. Wish me luck...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm too</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In answer he GRABS her ass, and she YELPS with delight, attract- ing attention all around. His turn to whisper, as he massages her backside...</context>
      <utterance>Five years, you won't need make-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We agreed. No underwear.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops. Gives the long legs a dubious twice-over.</context>
      <utterance>Overkill. I can do it with legs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd lose the underwear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cuddles close to him. They approach a tour group, the female guide speaking in four European languages. Really loud.</context>
      <utterance>The Oracle Bones date back to the Shang Dynasty, 3500 years ago. They are writings...carved into ox bones, tortoise shells...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The oldest Chinese writing any- where, the first proof of Chinese civilization.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A separate display room. A single steel pedestal. Under the smart-glass security case, one single object. It is a fragile, yellowed fragment of bone. The shoulder blade of an ox. Covered with tiny script.</context>
      <utterance>There we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No tourists in the display room. A velvet rope is up. Three GUARDS mill at the entrance. This exhibit is off-limits.</context>
      <utterance>Last year, ancient artifacts were discovered in the Gulf of Mexico. An Olmec civilization, 3200 years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sign explains, SORROWFUL TO INFORM ORACAL BONE CLOSE FOR TRAVEL</context>
      <utterance>Amazingly, markings on these Olmec figures were identified as Shang Dynasty writing...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glances up. Mac is eating heartily, happily.</context>
      <utterance>...no, I don't think that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and I suppose you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stuffs his mouth full. Talking around it...</context>
      <utterance>Get lonely? Sure, all the time. It's healthy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's studying him as he eats. Since he's not looking at her, Gin's eyes are thoughtful, appraising.</context>
      <utterance>What's unhealthy. Is denial.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he looks up. Direct to her eyes. A dead straight, heart- stopping look. Before the wonderful smile.</context>
      <utterance>Be real. you could never see yourself...you know, quitting the game. Settling...down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cuts him a hard look. Not funny.</context>
      <utterance>Why, Ginger. This is so sudden.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is holding something dull gray and small. It looks like a trun- cated nerf football with one end pointed and the other cut blunt.</context>
      <utterance>You're in charge of ego and worrying. I'm in charge of keeping you alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has four of these. Gives her three.</context>
      <utterance>These are plasma jet. All the force is directed forward, instead of dissipating in a sphere like a grenade.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out, gently...</context>
      <utterance>I don't need th... MAC  Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Touches her face.</context>
      <utterance>You don't trust me, you won't get through this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stares in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Try to adjust to that for three more days. After July 1...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And smiles. One more whisper...</context>
      <utterance>...you'll never have to trust again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something. To look forward to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INCONVENIENCE?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The train LOUDER, closer, the alarm BLARING...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>THEY'VE GOT AN</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>BUTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And leads them around the side of the house. They walk slowly, a distance behind the butler, taking everything in.</context>
      <utterance>Will you please come this way?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice is strong, calm. No hint of a smile.</context>
      <utterance>I like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like wha...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks equally serious. Just more tense.</context>
      <utterance>Not being told what the fuck we're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>breathtaking view down the slope of Victoria Peak to Hong Kong and the harbor. Kowloon across the water.</context>
      <utterance>You're on a 'need to know' basis. You'll get each step in time to execute, I thought you agreed to those condit... MAC  I like your not trusting me. Because it frees me to do the same. They come upon the spacious GROUNDS behind the mansion. A</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I trust you. I only need to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass a towering row of perfect ROSEBUSHES. Mac SNAPS OFF a giant blossom.</context>
      <utterance>...remain in control.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And hands it to her. Their eyes meet.</context>
      <utterance>Which is a sign of weakness.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the edge of the garden, above the commanding view, a luncheon TABLE has been set. Spread with delcacies. Two SERVANTS attend, also British. Only the host is seated. He does not rise.</context>
      <utterance>I like that, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Col. Qiu glances up from his meal. Green PLA uniform, absurdly decorated, wraparound Gautier sunglasses. We recognize him as the man who took Gin's call in his Mercedes in Tienanmen Square. The man who accompanied the poor Minister of Finance to the ophthal- mologist.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel</utterance>
   <speaker>QIU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look lovely, Ginger. Is the rose for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And leans prettily. To fasten it in the buttonhole of his lapel.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing his real name, Mac cuts her a look.</context>
      <utterance>Col. Qiu Lai Chuen, this is Andrew MacDougal.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she sits. Close to Qiu. Mac looks around at the property, the view.</context>
      <utterance>Real names here, darling. The Colonel and I have every incentive to keep each other's secrets.</utterance>
   <speaker>QIU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like the place, Andy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Colonel smiles. First time. Like an alligator. Mac notices that the tablecloth is actually... ...a Union Jack. He fingers the flag.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Mr. MacDougal will do.</utterance>
   <speaker>QIU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This way. Doesn't matter if we spill.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits.</context>
      <utterance>My sentiments exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>QIU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place was a gift. From its former owner. A Brit whose business will now happily continue to function. Perhaps...even expand. MAC  Planning to spend much time here?</utterance>
   <speaker>QIU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tho it has required many sacrifices.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Colonel has divorced his wife. To facilitate the necessary entertaining of Western women.</utterance>
   <speaker>QIU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And runs the back of his knuckles up the length of Gin's bare arm.</context>
      <utterance>Tho some are more entertaining than others.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which brings Qiu's eyes over. Really?</context>
      <utterance>Colonel. You are touching the woman I love...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And pulls up the Halliburton case. Handing it across the table. As Qiu takes the case in his lap, opens it...</context>
      <utterance>From time to time.</utterance>
   <speaker>QIU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a Scot. Would you like some 25-year-old Macallan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Qiu glances across the lawn to the butler, who stands behind the bar trolley. As the drinks are prepared, the Colonel studies the Bone.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, I'll take a case.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Colonel told his Minister of Culture that he could mount a surgical raid to liberate this treasure from Taiwan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah. How much was the Minister told the raid would cost? QIU  Counting equipment, personnel, bribes, an even fifty million American. All in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The drinks arrive.</context>
      <utterance>Which you can now keep.</utterance>
   <speaker>QIU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And lifts from beneath the table, a leather POUCH.</context>
      <utterance>He would have paid twice that. But my needs are modest.</utterance>
   <speaker>QIU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drops it into Gin's lap. She opens the pouch to reveal... ...goggles. Like one would wear in a tanning salon. Only these are flesh-colored with one small hole in the center of each lens. Slightly larger than the size of a pupil. She slips them on. A bright smile.</context>
      <utterance>Unlike. The woman you love. From time to time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Mac smiles. In return.</context>
      <utterance>How do I look, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a woman. Of mystery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And one for me.</context>
      <utterance>In the Hong Kong and Shanghai Bank Building. Is a room with two computers. One for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad I have a function, here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The room is a vault on the 14th floor. Access codes to that room are changed daily, computer pass- words on the hour,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From her pack, she pulls a slender black rectangle. Opens it to reveal a shiny metallic DISC.</context>
      <utterance>Our trade for the great train robbery. All right, let's say we're in the door. Now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holds up the metallic disc.</context>
      <utterance>Hong Kong has a huge portion of its holdings invested in foreign banks. In hundreds of separate accounts...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This CD ROM is programmed to send, instantaneously,</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two or three million at a crack, in odd numbers. Total, eight billion. And change.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you've set up a laundry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every wire transfer gets rocketed through a series of multiple switches, Austria, Uruguay, Antigua, The Channel Islands, the Caymans... MAC  Seychelles? GIN  I left that out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're forgiven.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. As soon as each deposit lands somewhere, it's shot somewhere else, til the</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, the foreign banks know they sent out some money. But they think Hong Kong knows it, too. And since we're leaving plenty</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well...</context>
      <utterance>Admit it, so far you're blown away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And his fingers reach out...</context>
      <utterance>It does sound like the beginning of a beautiful friendship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Touch her hair. Her face. She swallows. A raw moment. A hoarse...</context>
      <utterance>Pity it will be over. In 21 hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he's just staring in her eyes. The look pins her. She can't wriggle off. A murmured...</context>
      <utterance>Bet you say that. To all the one-night-stands.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans to her...</context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Only the best of them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is guiding him toward one of the multiple hors d'oeuvre stations. Half the celebrants seem to be armed PLA soldiers, many with rifles slung boldly across their shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Nice of the Colonel to provide an invitation...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I promised him a bonus. Five million. Comes out of your share.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mac loads up on six hors d'oeuvres, piling them on a napkin, as she takes two flutes of champagne. They step away from the mob toward a potted plant near the wall, and Mac... ...drops his snacks with a SPLAT. Shit. Bending to clean the mess, he slips from his waistband a flat CIRCUIT BOARD with a bank logo and a three-pronged plug. In a single motion, he plugs it INTO a socket concealed by the pot, scoops up his canapes, and we CUT TO...</context>
      <utterance>...long as I don't have to have sex with him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks irritated. He is smiling, gently.</context>
      <utterance>So all that time, sitting at your computers. All the research, the access codes your job allowed you to steal, floor plans, schematics... setting up all your bank accounts...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks away. The elevator stops.</context>
      <utterance>Years of work, comes down to....  ...six minutes. Don't be nervous. Easy come, easy go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your share prob'ly works out to, what? Dollar and a quarter an hour? Me laughs. The door opens. She is pissed off.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now they're staring at each other. An open elevator door. An empty dim hallway. They see only each other.</context>
      <utterance>What's your point? MAC  That I like you, Ginger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out the crook of his arm. As a gentleman escorts a lady.</context>
      <utterance>The dedication, the skill, the guts...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes flicker on that. So he grins...</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to see you get everything you deserve.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks in his eyes. Her body seems to relax, just a little. She takes his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Woman. If you can't have fun, right now. You're in the wrong business.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WITH Mac now. Typing the words CONTROL PANEL. The screen now shows icons for time setting, and he clicks his mouse to create a CLOCK in the center of the screen, labeled LOCAL TIME, and reading 11:57:19, changing with each second that passes...</context>
      <utterance>Uploading. And you've got... two minutes, fifty seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT...frenzied activity in a large war room filled with computers, wall screens, every worker functioning at top speed... CONTINUE to hear Mac over this...</context>
      <utterance>So let's see. Across town at the British Consulate...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CUT BACK to Mac in the vault. He clicks his mouse to create a clock at the LEFT of the screen, labeled BRITISH TERMINAL TIME. It is, of course, showing the same time as the local clock.</context>
      <utterance>...everyone is working frantically to complete transactions before they go off-line at midnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT...an even larger war room, even better staffed and equipped. Everyone...doing...nothing. Staring at blank monitors and wall screens.</context>
      <utterance>...then, deep in the high-tech bowels of the Bank of China Building, just across the square...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CUT BACK to Mac in the vault. He clicks his mouse to create another clock at the RIGHT of the screen, labeled CHINA TERMINAL TIME. Shows the same time as the other clocks. 11:58:22.</context>
      <utterance>...the Chinese are sitting on their thumbs, waiting to come on-line at midnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLICKS the mouse, and the BRITISH TERMINAL TIME begins FLASHING.</context>
      <utterance>I feel for these boys. Let's give them a breather, hmmn?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the flashing clock reaches 11:58:30, and Mac HITS the key four times, advancing the British clock to 34 seconds, four seconds</context>
      <utterance>We'll let the Brits go off-line 4 seconds early.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LOCAL TIME...11:59:00. One minute to midnight.</context>
      <utterance>Playing God here, Ginger. We've created 8 seconds that do not exist, anywhere but in this room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns around. Her eyes are waiting. Across the room.</context>
      <utterance>8 seconds, where no one is on-line but your little CD-Rom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when, eventually, everyone discovers what transaction XJ6 was</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She squints across at his clock.</context>
      <utterance>Liable to be an ugly international incident.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His smile returns. Bittersweet and real...</context>
      <utterance>Britain off-line in 18 seconds. We're bulletproof.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look holds. He turns back to his screen. She lingers on him for an instant. Then, back to the mainframe, finger poised above her ENTER key...</context>
      <utterance>Baby girl. Nothing. Is bulletproof. Ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Britain goes bye-bye in 6...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PROCESSING.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesus God, it's going through. MAC (watching his clocks) Hong Kong midnight, happy new year. Except at China Bank. GIN (to her screen) C'mon, c'mon... Her screen flashes TRANSACTIONS XJ6 COMPLETED, hear her SHRIEK of ecstasy, as we... INTERCUT...Bank of China where dark screens suddenly LIGHT with the same stupid PARTY LOGO. Only nobody cheers. They just get to work. BACK TO the vault...</context>
      <utterance>GIN</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But across the way, Gin is JAMMING a button. Again. Again.</context>
      <utterance>Feel like a nightcap?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Houston. We have a problem.</context>
      <utterance>The CD won't come out of the driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GIN (jamming it)</context>
      <utterance>Relax, don't jam it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't panic, now, there's no rush...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't leave it IN THERE, it's got all our</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sirens are EAR-SPLITTING. We know that elsewhere in this building, all hell must be breaking loose. Gin is YANKING Mac's arm out of the socket...</context>
      <utterance>There's a rush.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yeh. She stares at it. Really scared.</context>
      <utterance>The disc. Is still in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her. In one motion, he SNATCHES a stapler from the desk and SMASHES the driver with all his strength. It pops open. Calmly, he plucks her CD from the tray. She mouths a barely audible...</context>
      <utterance>We can't help it, we...we've gotta...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But just as she's about to bolt...he holds up one hand. Slips another CD from his pocket. We see the words KENNY G.</context>
      <utterance>What a guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was wondering where to leave this... Pops it IN the drive. SLAMS it shut. MAC  Time to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He PLUNGES his hand into her shoulder bag...</context>
      <utterance>They don't know we're the bad guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pulls OUT two PLASMA GRENADES, and FLINGS one toward the elevator cables three floors down and it... ...EXPLODES in a horrifying FIREBALL, causing PANDEMONIUM in the lobby below, the elevator cables BLOWN AWAY, cars PLUNGING, the yellow smoke momentarily screening us from the soldiers far below, and Mac HURLS the second grenade... ...STRAIGHT DOWN and the fireball WIPES OUT the staircase, a huge section of ninth floor landing RAINING down on the lobby.</context>
      <utterance>Time they find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. How do we get down?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grabs her hand and they RACE to the staircase, as smoke BILLOWS everywhere below. UP they go, two stairs at a time, the lowest glass-and-spiderweb-steel CANOPY is three floors above us, the cacophany of SHOUTS below is like an amplified insane asylum. He is dragging her now, up, up, BULLETS are flying blind through the smoke, CHEWING up metal and glass all around us, up, up, and as the smoke at last clears, they have reached... ...the canopy floor. They can see the army down below. Clutching her hand, Mac leads her OVER the railing, ONTO the canopy itself, and together they RUN... ...straight ACROSS the heavy glass toward the far side of the building, like space-walking above the throng 150 feet below, BULLETS now TRACING their path from beneath, SLAMMING OFF the underside of the bulletproof canopy, Gin SHRIEKING with fright as they go. We see ahead... ...three EXECUTIVE ELEVATORS beginning to climb the far wall. These are glass-enclosed tubes, all filled with soldiers, the car in the lead already at the tenth floor. Mac keeps running straight TOWARD them. GIN (out of breath)</context>
      <utterance>Down? I never liked down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They LEAP across five feet of open air to... ...LAND squarely on the car's metal roof, Mac WRAPPING his free arm AROUND the cable, and UP we go. The ant colony below us receding fast. Gin is hanging onto the cable, petrified. Mac is looking up toward the roof.</context>
      <utterance>You can do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now what? MAC  Shut up. You're on a 'need-to- know' basis.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her. Just now, she seems more miserable than afraid.</context>
      <utterance>Mac, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't smile. Passing the third canopy.</context>
      <utterance>Turns out, I'm a screw-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks back up. Forty-first floor. Six to go.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Something to be said for being self-aware.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She blinks. Huh? So he reaches into her bag, pulls out the grenade, and THROWS it... ...STRAIGHT up. The roof above them EXPLODES in a FIREBALL, and SHIELDS her body against the wall of their shaft, as a huge SECTION of roof comes RAINING down. We watch as it... ...CRASHES through the upper canopy, TONS of roof and glass PLUNGING to... ...BLAST through the middle canopy, everyone below SCRAMBLING for shelter, as the whole shebang... ...EXPLODES through the lowest canopy. Gin can only GAPE at the incredible display. Mouthing a silent WOW. They've passed the second canopy, thirty-sixth floor. Still climbing. The other two elevators maybe five floors below us.</context>
      <utterance>May I have the last grenade, dear. It's about to rain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, banking</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to shimmy up the few feet of cable. At the top, he reaches out with one hand toward the lip of the remaining roof, GRABS it, LUNGES with his free hand, and... ...DANGLING 47 floors, he pulls himself UP, swings ONTO the roof. Reaches back down. She is only twelve feet below him. Frozen with fear.</context>
      <utterance>How refreshing. The night air.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares up at his eyes. He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You can. If I say so.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And starts to climb the cable. Not so easy in a ball gown, but the adrenaline is pumping. Gets to the top. Here's the hard part. One hand reaches out... ...GRABS his. She lets GO. And she is DANGLING in space.</context>
      <utterance>If you stay. You'll have to pay for the damage... She looks down at the mess below.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that split. Did we say</utterance>
   <speaker>60-40?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...the roof. Two-thirds of it remain. At the far edge, a gigantic MAINTENANCE CRANE, itself two stories high. But between here and the crane... ...a HELICOPTER. Big and beautifUl and empty. She looks like she's seen God. Mac starts to jog toward it, she runs to follow but sees him go... ...straight PAST the chopper.</context>
      <utterance>And with all his strength, hauls her up onto...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>Got the keys?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guess not.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you could...hot-wire stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And keeps walking. Toward the monster CRANE.</context>
      <utterance>They fix those things so you can't steal them...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moving fast, he points off to his right. Her eyes follow a long CABLE, leading from the arm of the crane, across the roof, attaching by a huge HOOK to a massive WRECKING BALL.</context>
      <utterance>These, they're not so worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches the crane's cab. Turns back to see she hasn't moved.</context>
      <utterance>Go grab that hook.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me rephrase that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna lower me over the side.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He THROWS a lever and the crane's arm begins to SWING in a circle, finally taking the ball WITH it, and as she SCREAMS, Mac... ...POUNCES out of the cab, RACING along the edge of the roof, NOT toward the ball which is sweeping the hysterical Gin in a widening ARC, but toward the point where he thinks the ball will clear the edge, and JUST as it does, he... ...LEAPS aboard, throwing one arm around the hook, the other around her, and they go... ...OVER the side, WHOOSHING DOWN in a gigantic, every-increasing LOOP, as the endless steel cable UNWINDS from its huge drum like a fishing reel hooked onto a killer whale.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. Now close baby eyes...  Suit yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He YANKS her loose, and they drop... ...four feet. The ball SWINGS OFF lnto space to some unknown mayhem. Clutching Mac, Gin looks WAY down to the street, and realizes they are standing on... ...a rooftop. Quiet, safe. Alone.</context>
      <utterance>Let go NOW!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She WHIPS around, GLARING death at his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Planning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She COLLAPSES in his arms, every muscle trembling in spasm, sobbing...</context>
      <utterance>And dumb luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds her tenderly. Kisses the top of her head. MAC (softly) Good. I hate you, too.</context>
      <utterance>God, I hate you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="63">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. It is easy, but dazzling. Atypically soft.</context>
      <utterance>Except it never is, really. Quite. Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah.</context>
      <utterance>Well, one hopes not. The Bristol, huh? In...Paris?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going back to Mr. Cruz, and the nine-to-five?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amazing how little it costs.</context>
      <utterance>Not hardly. I've arranged to be killed in a car crash. On Taipei.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a breath. Scared, in an excited way...</context>
      <utterance>Well. You want to watch those pennies.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at his watch. Takes her hand. Leads her to the subway steps.</context>
      <utterance>I could arrange for two. In that crash. His smile back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, for a bitch. You can be awfully sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>mean, it's not the Ritz...</context>
      <utterance>Woman of mystery. What do you say? I like the Bristol, just fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, all night I've been wrestling with something...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his big tourist shopping bag. Puts it in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Not the most flattering way to put it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are descending now. Into the vast underground train station.</context>
      <utterance>I've changed your travel plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Got that?</context>
      <utterance>Instead of taking the subway to the airport, you change at Jordan Station for Kowloon Tong. Got that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jordan is only 90 seconds up the line. Like a wire transfer, you're gone. Vanished. He holds up a silencing finger. Listen to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes moving over his face. What is this?</context>
      <utterance>In this bag are passports, tickets, papers. An amber wig, a good one. A dress you can slip on in five seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're on a tight connection to the Trans-Siberian Express, be in Europe in a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mac, wh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're at the booth. He pays their fare. Through the turnstiles, now.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh. You always talk too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiles at her. As they enter a tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>Time has come to return the favor. One last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And in an instant of blind panicked clarity. She gets the whole thing. GIN (hushed) My God. You're a cop. MAC (very softly) That's my girl. Keep walking. People are everywhere. But they are alone in the world.</context>
      <utterance>Tell you. What business. I'm actually in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs.</context>
      <utterance>See, my profession was cover, too. A notorious thief has access to colleagues, their plans...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking around the tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>I've turned in...well, couple hundred. over forty years. Scotland Yard, Interpol, FBI...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought I might retire. After you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And all the...microchips, the diamond machine...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the chips were returned. The machine was just a box, did you</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those were</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Well, the State Department liked that one. They have more fish to fry with Beijing than Taiwan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops walking. She has to know...</context>
      <utterance>So they're taking credit for letting it go through. Tho I'm afraid your Colonel may be in for a career disappointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. That.</context>
      <utterance>And the 5 billion.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gently, takes her arm. Leads her onto the endless train platform. Walking slower now.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't told them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down the platform they stroll. As her eyes wander...</context>
      <utterance>I said you hadn't revealed the job. That it wouldn't take place until after the changeover.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her breath catches. Her eyes go down.</context>
      <utterance>Don't look, they're there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And my tickets. In the shopping bag?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her heart pounding through her chest.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Kept my options open. If I give you up, they don't matter, do they?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had lots of crazy thoughts. One was retirement. With four billion dollars. After all, I know some places where life could be private...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've stopped. Just two travellers in a strange land. waiting for a train.</context>
      <utterance>But you couldn't do that, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. Smiling pleasantly.</context>
      <utterance>Otherwise. They wouldn't be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We feel her adrenaline racing.</context>
      <utterance>Creature of habit. I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lots. Of thoughts, you s...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And so she smiles. As prettily as she can manage.</context>
      <utterance>Keep smiling. They won't move, until I raise my left arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A train is COMING. We HEAR it.</context>
      <utterance>I thought. Well, I've got the CD. I could contact the banks, reverse all the transactions...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SEE the train. Slowing. Pulling in.</context>
      <utterance>...except maybe. Leave you with... oh, a hundred million, say. To tide you over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a SHRIEK of metal. The train PULLS toward us.</context>
      <utterance>Then, I thought, nah. Not my style.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What the hell?</context>
      <utterance>I figured. What the hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The train STOPS. The doors OPEN. People come out, people go in. Pouring around them. They are alone again. The subway doors stand open. Two feet away. She looks at them...</context>
      <utterance>Let her keep the lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sixty seconds. And still smiling...</context>
      <utterance>No rush. The doors won't close for 60 seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She freezes to stone.</context>
      <utterance>There's a pistol in the bag. Reach in slowly. Take it out fast. Point it at my temple.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she...DOES IT. A blinding MOVE, the gun straight at his head, Mac miming fear, raising his hands to chill the agents we... WHIP PAN to see. Half a dozen, everywhere, but none too close. They REACT, pull their weapons, but it's a stand-off. BACK TO...</context>
      <utterance>You can do it. If I say you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two people. Alone in the universe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates. Does as he says. Passengers are screaming, cringing, bolting for other cars. Our world is FROZEN. His hands raised...</context>
      <utterance>Step onto the car, keep the pistol trained on my face.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gentle smile.</context>
      <utterance>Seems I was wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes are flooding. The gun is trembling.</context>
      <utterance>Entrapment. Is what robbers. Do to cops, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her pistol is shaking like she has palsy. Tears are on her cheeks.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty seconds. Shoot me in the shoulder, it'll slow them down.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oughta shoot you in the face.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, you can do it, if I sa...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sobs. She can't stand this.</context>
      <utterance>No way. Not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten seconds, hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no answer. There are no words. The doors HISS SHUT. She stares, training her pistol on him through the glass, his hands reaching back to hold off the agents, and the train... PULLS away. An instant to pick up speed, and it ROARS into a tunnel. Gone. Mac stands motionless as ALL HELL breaks loose around him, AGENTS rushing to his side, Mac shaking his head, calmly...</context>
      <utterance>When do I see you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still staring after the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walkie-talkies WHIP out. These guys are the same the world over. We begin to CRANE UP...</context>
      <utterance>Airport. Changing at Mongkok Station, we can cut her off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She might lose the wig, be looking brunette</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>But as the crowd parts. We can make out one lone man... Staring after. What has gone.</context>
      <utterance>I think you're wrong, but cover it. You got maybe four minutes. HIGHER still, the mob below an ant colony... MAC  No problem. She's trapped.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
