<movie id="194" title="Erin Brockovich">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even when she talks dirty, there's a heartland goodness to her voice. Like Kansas corn fields swaying in the breeze. As she grabs the ticket from the windshield, her sunglasses accidentally CLATTER to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When she picks them up, a fingernail snags on the pavement.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tony Marvin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus. Who's responsible for his pain and suffering this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His dry cleaners. You want him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs a gift-wrapped bottle off her desk, reads the card.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think? What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tequila. From your drug dealer friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carlos isn't a friend; he's a client.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed peers into his office. It's a mess -- papers everywhere, unopened mail. Standing in the middle of the room is Erin, in a teensy, leopard-print mini-dress. As she jiggles a spike-heeled foot, everything about her shimmies gloriously. Except her head, which is held in place by a neck brace.</context>
      <utterance>He's a low-life. Speaking of which, that's your nine o'clock in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa.  Remind me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she looks like such an honest girl, don't you think?</context>
      <utterance>Erin Brockovich. Car accident. Not her fault, she says.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't judge, Brenda.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ed heads into his office, Brenda picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Lap-dancers are people too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't find him, Tony. We'll have to call you back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin -- hi. Sorry you had to wait. Here, sit down, sit down. He clears a stack of papers off a chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed gives her a look of pro-forma sympathy.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks a lot.  I tell you, I never thought just standing would take it out of me, but ever since that shithead hit me, it feels like my whole body's put together wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out a pad and paper, gets ready to write.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, you poor thing.  Well, listen, you came to the right place. Whoever did this to you made one hell of a mistake, and you and me, we're gonna make him pay for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you tell me what happened?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... just wanna be a good mom, a nice person, a decent citizen. Just wanna take good care of my kids. You know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEFENDING LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventeen thousand in debt. Whew. Is your ex-husband helping out?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEFENDING LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's more than one?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin looks over at the jury. The personification of conservative family values. Oh, shit.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. There's two. Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEFENDING LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. You must've been feeling pretty desperate that afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed shakes his head slightly to her -- don't get mad.</context>
      <utterance>What's your point?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEFENDING LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin sees jurors nodding almost imperceptibly in agreement. She's on a sinking ship.</context>
      <utterance>Broke, three kids, no job. A doctor in a Jaguar must've looked like a pretty good meal ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Hey --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He came tearing around the corner, out of control --</utterance>
   <speaker>DEFENDING LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An ER doctor who spends his days saving lives was the one out of control --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That asshole smashed in my fucking neck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open and shut?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please, it was long over by then. God damn, he made me look like some cheap --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you the questions might get a little personal --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed notices her ranting is starting to draw attention.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. You told me I'd get half a million dollars. You told me I'd be set.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay -- let's try and settle down here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MRS. MORALES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands Erin the baby. It's BETH, Erin's 9-month old. Erin avoids the question by focusing on her baby.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Erin! You're back so soon. How was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, sweetie. Were you a good girl? Where are Matt and Katie?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MORALES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outside with the sprinkler. So it's good? The truth is too depressing to share.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be fine, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MORALES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ai, bueno. Because I didn't want to tell you before, with your worries --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MORALES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daughter, she's bought a big house with a room for me. I'm going to move in with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're moving away? When?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MORALES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next week.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, that's soon --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MORALES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh, God. In Erin's arms, Beth starts to COUGH.</context>
      <utterance>I know. But it's good for me. Now I can help my daughter take care of my grandkids. And it's good for you, too. Now you have money, you can find a good babysitter, huh? Not the old lady next door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like this part, it's all crusty.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin switches the plates.</context>
      <utterance>I like the crust.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put your napkins in your laps and eat up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cause there isn't enough food.</context>
      <utterance>How come you're not eating?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From her baby seat on the table, Beth COUGHS some more. Thick, sick-sounding coughs. Erin looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Mamma's gonna eat later.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go getting sick on me, baby. Okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the table beside her sit the classifieds. Row after row of want ads circled, then X-'d out in red. A WATER BUG crawls across the edge of the paper.</context>
      <utterance>Just remember. No matter what your Mamma does, lying and stealing is real bad. I don't ever wanna hear you doing something like that ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Cause there's no excuse for it, you hear me? No excuse at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pops her head in.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it!  Brenda!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs a tissue, swabs his shirt, then kicks at the box.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's those files you asked for.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean for you to leave them in the middle of the floor. Jesus. Look at me. What do I have this afternoon?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ed checks his reflection in the glass wall of his office, he notices, on the other side: ERIN, standing in the middle of the secretaries' area, in a miniskirt and leather bustier, talking to MARIO, the firm's mentally challenged office boy. Mario heads away from her.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing you can't show up for with a stain.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed goes to his office door and waves Mario over.</context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- Mario -- what's she doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed looks back at her -- what the hell?</context>
      <utterance>She works here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up close, the wear and tear of worry show on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Erin! How's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never called me back. I left messages.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did? Wow, sorry about that.  Listen, Mario's a little not so bright. He seems to think that you said --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glances skitter between the secretaries -- get a load of this. Ed lowers his voice.</context>
      <utterance>There's two things I can't stand, Mr. Masry. Being ignored, and being lied to. You did both.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never lied. I may have miscalculated -- that happens sometimes, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said things would be fine, and they're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about that. Really. But --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need pity. I need a paycheck. And I've looked, but when you've spent the last six years raising babies, it's real hard to convince someone to give you a job that pays worth a damn. So I figure, since you're the one who said I was gonna be okay, you should be the one to hire me. Ed sees everyone watching him, listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to escort her out, but she stays put.</context>
      <utterance>I'd love to help, Erin, but I'm sorry, I have a full staff right now, so --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's backing him into a corner here. He shifts gears.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. If you had a full staff, you'd have time to return your damn phone calls.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, look. If you really want to apply for a job here, you can do it the way everyone else does. Send in a rˆsumˆ, make an --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... what we do in here is keep track of all the case files. That way, at any time, we can find out a case's status -- where it is in the office, stuff like that. We file 'em all here, alphabetically --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hell.  I'm dyslexic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a joke, right? Erin shakes her head, no. Great, thinks Anna.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just last week, he told my sister we weren't hiring.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your sister look like?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns, sees her.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Masry?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wondering -- could you tell me who I'd talk to about maybe getting an advance on my paycheck? Just -- for the weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jane's the office manager. She handles payroll and petty cash. But she leaves early on Fridays.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed looks at her a moment, sees that it's far from okay.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Okay. That's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out his wallet, looks in.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, for Christ's sake ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I have is hundreds.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna take your money, Mr. Masry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps a hundred in her hand and leaves. When he's gone, she looks at the bill -- her life raft -- and gives it a great big kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit, you don't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy, can I get a flower?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweetheart, you can get a whole big bunch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hello to you, darlin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell do you think you're doing, making all that Goddamn noise?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just introducing myself to the neighbors.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guys on the porch chuckle. Erin turns and starts back to her house. George hops off his bike and follows her.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm the neighbors. There, now we're introduced, so you can shut the fuck up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooh, now, see, if I'da known there was a beautiful woman next door, I'da done this different. Let's start over. My name's George. What's yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just think of me as the person next door who likes it quiet, and we'll get along fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin shakes her head in disbelief and keeps walking.</context>
      <utterance>Now, don't be like that. Tell you what. How about if I take you out on a date to apologize for my rudeness?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Gimme your number, I'll call you up proper and ask you out and everything. She stops at her porch, turns to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want my number?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which number do you want, George?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got more than one?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, yeah. I got numbers coming out of my ears. Like, for instance, ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. That's one of my numbers. It's how many months old my little girl is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a little girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and heads inside. He calls out after her:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sexy, huh? And here's another: five. That's how old my other daughter is. Seven is my son's age. Two is how many times I been married and divorced. You getting all this? 16 is the number of dollars in my bank account. 454-3943 is my phone number. And with all the other numbers I gave you, I'm guessing zero is the number of times you're gonna call it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell do you know your bank balance right off the top of your head like that? See, that impresses me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed appears in the door, carrying the box of files.</context>
      <utterance>How long's she been crying like that? ... Well, she's got that tooth coming in --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give her a cold washcloth to suck on --  I gotta go -- there's a clean one in that bag -- I'll check back in a bit.  Sorry. My kid --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Anna?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out to lunch with the girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, look, I got this file I need valued. Real estate thing. A lady has some property next to a PG&amp;E plant that PG&amp;E wants to buy. I need to know what to ask for it. He plunks the box of files on her desk. She stares at it, with no idea of how to go about that.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees her staring at the box.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do know how to do that, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I got it. No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed heads out, but pauses before leaving.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you're not at lunch with the girls? You're a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I'm not the right kind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anna? With this real-estate valuing stuff - - could you remind me, cause I'm a little confused about how exactly we do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin, you've been here three weeks. If you don't know how to do your job by now, I am not about to do it for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she wipes the bug guts off the bottom of her shoe:</context>
      <utterance>Ugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She spots George on his stoop, with a six-pack beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, neighbor, wanna beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon. I bought 'em for you, to make up for that night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and follows her to her house.</context>
      <utterance>Return 'em. Maybe you'll get your money back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin turns to him. The kids are waiting at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Now, why're you giving me such a hard time? I'm just trying to be a good neighbor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a good neighbor, George. She was 60 and Mexican and she watched my kids for free. Something tells me you're not gonna be able to measure up to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George reaches out and grabs the box from under her arm.</context>
      <utterance>You need help with your kids? I could probably do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna leave my kids with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause I don't even know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's got a point there. After a beat:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and whose fault is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you got so many friends in this world, you don't have use for one more?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that stand for?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's for Harley Davidson. The best damn motorcycle ever made. Erin comes in from the kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I catch either of you anywhere near one, I'll knock you silly. Go on to bed, now -- I'll come tuck you in in a minute. They get up ...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Night.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATIE/MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... and head into bed. George starts cleaning up the cards.</context>
      <utterance>Night.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin bends down to help him.</context>
      <utterance>Great kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm probably ruining them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm never here. I gotta leave 'em with this weird sitter all afternoon who costs a fortune and smells like chicken fat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was serious before, you know. If you need someone to keep an eye on them -- after school or something -- I don't have a job now, so I'm around in the afternoons.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Another deadbeat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a deadbeat. I work when I need to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? And what do you do the rest of the time, live off your trust fund?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do construction, which pays real good. And I make it last by living cheap.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope that's not supposed to impress me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you this hard on everyone who tries to help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been a while. Maybe I'm just out of practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then lemme remind you, the polite thing is to say, thank you, that's a real nice offer, I don't mind taking you up on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why in the hell would you want to watch my kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause I like kids. I like hanging out with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts cleaning up the cards.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do. I like how they keep it all simple, you know? They don't get all complicated about life, like grown-ups do. A bicycle and an ice cream cone -- boom, done, they're happy. Erin thinks about the offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're around every afternoon?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tempting. Erin looks him over.</context>
      <utterance>Yup. Usually working on my bike.  No big deal. If it doesn't work out, you can send 'em back to the chicken fat lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't gonna get you laid, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we'll just see about that, won't we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin sees Ed pass behind Jane. She lowers her voice, so he won't see her asking for help.</context>
      <utterance>It was in this real estate file I'm valuing. And -- see, I know they're the medical records from the people selling the house -- but it talks about things like lymphocytes and T8 suppressers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, it's not a problem or anything, but -- I'm just a little unclear on what those things are. I thought maybe you'd know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Jane walks away with her coffee.</context>
      <utterance>What do I look like, Erin? A library?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSALIND</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Masry &amp; Vititoe, can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The librarian gives her directions to somewhere else.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Rosalind, this is Erin. Brockovich. From the file room? I was wondering if you could tell Mr. Masry that I'm following up on that real estate thing out of the office.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Paulsen?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Erin Brockovich. I was just over in the library there, asking a mess of questions about -- I guess they call it epidemiology? -- and the fella there told me to find you, cause you know all about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this a joke? Did Baxter put you up to this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Baxter?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did, didn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one put me up to anything. I was just hoping I could ask you a couple questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course! Oh, gosh, of course --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look, there isn't a ton of information here, but from what there is, I'd say that these two people here -- what are their names? Shanna and Ashley?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, I guess those are the kids --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've both got some immune system problem. Can't say what from, whether it's viral or genetic or what, but something's wrong. And these guys -- Donna and Peter --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their parents, I'm pretty sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wow. That's more serious than Erin was expecting.</context>
      <utterance>Well, from what this stuff says, I'd say they both have some form of cancer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>WIDEN to see Erin, phone to her ear, grabbing a carton of juice from Matt and Katie, who are fighting over it at the table. Just as she takes it from them, the phone picks up.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa! Easy, easy, easy --</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>BEEP. Erin thinks a bit, then hangs up and looks at the file. Scrawled on the cover is the Irvings' address, in Hinkley, California.</context>
      <utterance>Hi! You've reached the Irvings. Leave a message and we'll get back to you just as soon as we can. Bye-bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Donna Irving?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Erin Brockovich, from Masry &amp; Vititoe?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a lawyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, no. I hate lawyers. I just work for them. You got a minute?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a real nice place you got here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She comes out from the kitchen with a tray of iced tea.</context>
      <utterance>Well it oughta be, with all the work I put into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I added air conditioning, put in the pool, made all those pillows by hand ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna corrects the positioning on a couple of pillows.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? I should learn to do stuff like that. They make the place feel real homey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I think so too. That's why I'm being such a stickler on this house price thing. I don't mean to be a pain in PG&amp;E's backside, especially after all they've done for Hinkley, but I look around here and I think, if they want this place, they're gonna have to pay for it. And I don't just mean pay for the house; I'd like them to pay me for the trouble of starting over.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause first you gotta move, then there's decorating, and if the windows aren't the same size, you know -- you're making all new curtains. Honest to God, I don't know if I have the energy. You know, I've been sick. Me and Peter both have.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This would be the perfect opportunity for many to get self- pitying. But not Donna. Life's handed her a shitload of lemons, and darned if she hasn't made a shitload of lemonade.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm real glad you brought that up. I was going through your file here, and I ran into these medical records. They kinda surprised me --</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. They're more than a bit unusual. See, two years ago, Pete got Hodgkin's disease. That's a kind of cancer --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm real sorry to hear that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. It's in remission now, thank the Lord, but you never know. And then while that's going on, I end up having to have a hysterectomy. Plus a whole mess of lumps removed from my breasts. All benign so far, but still, no matter how positive you stay, an operation can still take it out of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll say. Holy moley.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the whole idea of selling the house -- don't get me wrong, I'd be glad to move to some better place, but if they aren't gonna pay us properly, I just don't see the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I can see that.  I guess the only thing that confused me is - - not that your medical problems aren't important, but -- how come the files about them are in with all the real estate stuff? Donna tops off their iced teas.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? With how our lives are, if I start subdividing files, I'll be sunk. I just kept all PG&amp;E correspondence in one place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, but -- I'm sorry, I don't see why you were corresponding with PG&amp;E about it in the first place.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they paid for the doctor's visit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They did?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet. Paid for a check-up for the whole family. And not like with insurance where you pay, then wait a year to be reimbursed, either. They just took care of it. Just like that. We never even saw a bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Why would they do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause of the chromium.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The chromium. Well, that's what kicked this whole thing off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>WIDEN to see Donna pulling the box down into the room.</context>
      <utterance>PG&amp;E came around a few years ago, told us they put chromium in our well by mistake. And since we shouldn't have to drink it if we don't want to, they gave us free spring water and offered to buy our house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's chromium?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a chemical they used over at that compressor station up the road there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hell, maybe that's why you all have been so sick --</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought the same thing, right off the bat. That's why we went to see the doctor. But hunh-uh. Turns out one's got nothing to do with the other. She rifles through the box.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands Erin a printed fact sheet. Erin scans it.</context>
      <utterance>This is the info they gave us. You'll see if you look through it, chromium's good for you. When I saw what they charged for it at the health-food stores, I about fainted.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems like an awful big coincidence -- your water being messed with and you being so sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not around here. This is a rough part of the world. Hard times, not a lot of money, not a lot of luck.  It's a challenge, staying healthy in a town like this. Heck, even our dogs up and die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head, amused by his persistence.</context>
      <utterance>Better safe than sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some coffee, George?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna put a dead bolt on your front door, too. This isn't exactly the safest neighborhood in the world, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for reminding me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin pours him some coffee, hands it to him.</context>
      <utterance>I guess we get what we pay for, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think it could make you sick, living in a place like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George settles in, helps himself to sugar.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was talking to this lady -- she and her husband both got cancer, and she thinks it's cause they live in a bad neighborhood. You think that's possible? That living in a bad neighborhood could give you cancer? George laughs a little at the thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Erin's still mulling it over.</context>
      <utterance>Man, I hope not. You got enough damn problems.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, y'all -- how you doing today?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hangin' in, baby. How about yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She settles down on the stoop with them for a chat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm okay, I'm just fine. I was wondering -- could I maybe ask you a couple questions?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and when I realized our area's just as bad as Hinkley, I thought maybe my neighbors are all sick too. So I went and asked.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin digs a pad of paper out of her bag.</context>
      <utterance>You did?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. Spent the last few days knocking on doors. And you know what? They're not.  I mean, they got problems, but none of this cancer stuff. And their pets are fine. So I don't know -- I just can't shake the feeling that it wasn't no multivitamin they put in the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you're talking about contamination, you're getting out of my area of expertise. Let me give you the name of a toxicologist friend of mine over at USC. Paulsen reaches for a notepad, scrawls on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta say, Erin -- first time I saw you, I did not peg you as the kind to go off and conduct her own epidemiological study.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go telling anyone. It'll ruin my reputation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FRANKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of chromium is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's more than one kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. There's straight-up chromium -- does all kinds of good things for the body. There's chrom 3, which is fairly benign, and then there's chrom 6, hexavalent chromium, which, depending on the amounts, can be very harmful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harmful, like -- how? What would you get?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rattles it off coolly. Just facts. Erin's stunned.</context>
      <utterance>With repeated exposure to toxic levels -- God, anything, really -- respiratory disease, liver failure, heart failure, reproductive failure, chronic headaches, bone or organ deterioration -- plus, of course, any type of cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that stuff -- it kills people.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. Definitely. Highly toxic, highly carcinogenic. Bad, bad stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, how do I find out what kind of chromium is up in Hinkley?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been to the water board?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunh-uh. What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every county has one. They keep records of anything water-related within their jurisdiction. You should be able to find something there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>County water board. All righty, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His line continues over:</context>
      <utterance>Good luck.  Oh -- I wouldn't advertise what you're looking for if I were you ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whew! God</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much. Aren't you a gentleman? Mr. ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ross.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ross. Real pleased to meet you. I'm Erin. She smiles. He can't believe his luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin. Cool. What can I do for you, Erin?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, believe it or not, I am on the prowl for some water records.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come to the right place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just tell me what you want to look at and I'll be glad to dig 'em out for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I knew. It's for my boss. He's fighting his water bill, and he wants me to find all manner of bills from all kinds of places. The easiest thing would probably be if I just squeezed back there with you and poked around myself. Would that be okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her a pen. He reads over her shoulder as she signs her name -- Erin Pattee Brockovich.</context>
      <utterance>Heck, yeah. Come on back. Just gonna need you to sign in here --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pattee? That your middle name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. Maiden.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're married.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and winks at him, then goes around the counter with him and looks at the stacks and stacks of files.</context>
      <utterance>Not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads down an aisle, reading the spines of the files. They're all town names -- Barstow, Victorville, Oro Grande, Helendale -- in no particular order. Finally, Erin spots one that says Hinkley. She pulls it down.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Here goes nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our mom gives us sandwiches on Fridays.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a sandwich.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's not!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up Matt's chicken, tears it in two ...</context>
      <utterance>Sure it is. Here, I'll show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... then places the broccoli neatly between the halves.</context>
      <utterance>Most people think a sandwich's gotta have bread on the outside. Not true. Chicken is a perfectly good outside for a sandwich.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katie and Matthew look at it, then up at George, and smile. This guy just might be all right, after all.</context>
      <utterance>See?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Where's my stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where've you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck did you do with my stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Erin's out the door before Anna can finish her sentence.</context>
      <utterance>Don't use language with me --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone stole my stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to see you, Erin. We've missed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane reaches under her desk for a box, looks through it.</context>
      <utterance>I had photos of my kids, plus a mug --</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- toothbrush, toothpaste, and a pair of hose. Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There may be jobs where you can disappear for days at a time, but this isn't one of them. Here, if you don't do the work, you don't get to stay. She hands her the box. Erin doesn't take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sets down the receiver.</context>
      <utterance>You said to fire me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin, you've been gone for a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I left a message. I've been dealing with that real estate thing. I was gonna write up a whole damn report and --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane follows her in, still carrying the box of stuff.</context>
      <utterance>That's not how we work here. You don't just leave a message and take off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I supposed to do, check in every two seconds?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's called accountability.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not talking to you, bitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to Jane, takes her box, and heads out.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, I'm trying to help here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. You're trying to feel less guilty about firing someone with three kids to feed. Fuck if I'll help you do that. And she leaves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads into the kitchen, weary and irritated.</context>
      <utterance>Fixing a leak under your sink.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't ask you to do that. Damn it, George, I don't ask you to do things like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin gets down on her knees and starts putting things away.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna clean it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can finish, a huge WATER BUG runs onto Erin's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Relax, Erin, I'll do it -- I'm not --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ugh --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bug skitters away from her, along the floorboard. Erin chases it, smacking at it repeatedly, missing it every time.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it --</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Erin keeps after it, corralling all her frustrations into killing that one bug.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it, I'll get it later.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bug crawls up onto the table, zipping behind the salt, the pepper, the napkin holder. Erin keeps after it, BANGING the table harder and harder with each SMACK of her shoe.</context>
      <utterance>Come here, you little motherfucker --</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, whoa -- relax --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not nothing, Erin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm sure as hell not what I thought I was gonna be. I was supposed to have one of those great lives, with everything all laid- out and perfect. I mean, hell -- I was Miss Wichita, for God's sakes. Did I tell you that? You live next door to a real live beauty queen.  I still got the tiara. I kept it cause I thought it meant something. I thought it meant I was gonna do something great with my life. I thought it proved I was gonna grow up to be someone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I'm not. Look at me. I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're someone to me.  You're someone real special to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man. Even your earlobes are beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He kisses one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got an interesting call this afternoon. It was from a Dr. Frankel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wanted you to know the legal limit for hexavalent chromium, is .05 parts per million. And that at the rate you mentioned, .58, it could be responsible for the cancers in that family you asked about. The Irvings.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that was nice of him. Isn't it funny how some people go out of their way to help people and others just give 'em the ax?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm sorry. You were gone. I just assumed you were off having fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, why in the hell would you assume that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Maybe cause you look like someone who has a lot of fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, are you ever a shitty judge of people.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ed takes a beat, copping to the charge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna know, you gotta hire me back. I got a lot of bills to pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He glares at her. Realizes he has no choice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't take a genius to look at those medical records and think something's wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What medical records?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ones in the box of files.  The box of files? The one from your office?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't see any medical records in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, you musta really fine-tooth-combed it then, huh?  And</utterance>
   <speaker>you fired me.  Jesus.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ed thinks for a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That document you found, the one that says it was the bad chromium -- you didn't happen to make a copy did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Course I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before getting it for him, she looks at him, weighs her odds.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme see it, will you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Erin, this is not the way I do business, this extortion nonsense.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin doesn't budge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the only thing you found?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So far. But that place is a pig sty. I wouldn't be surprised if there's more.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no way a son of mine hates Funky Town. It's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I hate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate it too. I hate this trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on, where's your sense of adventure? We're going someplace you never been before.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna hate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at them, frowns a little.</context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I'm realizing for the first time? You kids are a couple of downers. I mean, you are the real thing -- a couple of honest-to-God depresso-types.  Who in the heck raised you, anyway? Some kind of moron?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. A real moron.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some kind of half-wit, no-good, big-haired, bimbo, I bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now they're all smiling. Funky Town plays on.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God we got you away from her, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whining, fussing. Ross goes over to her.</context>
      <utterance>We'll go eat in a minute. Settle down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what, Erin? I got nothing but time here. Why don't you let me do that for you, and you can get your kids some dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands Ross the STACK OF DOCUMENTS.</context>
      <utterance>Ross -- you are an absolute angel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fax these to this number, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He continues into his office and closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>All of them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An on-site monitoring well? That means --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was right up on the PG&amp;E property over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you say this stuff, this hexavalent chromium -- it's poisonous?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- then it's gotta be a different than what's in our water, cause ours is okay. The guys from PG&amp;E told me. They sat right in the kitchen and said it was fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. But the toxicologist I been talking to? He gave me a list of problems that can come from hexavalent chromium exposure. And everything you all have is on that list. Donna resists this idea hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Hunh-uh, see, that's not what the doctor said. He said one's got absolutely nothing to do with the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, but -- didn't you say he was paid by</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hired her back. With a raise.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What??</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And dumb old me thought working hard and being loyal was the way to get ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, the minute Brenda sent the fax -- I'm talking the second she pressed that send button -- PG&amp;E claims department is on the phone to me, scheduling a meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you think we got 'em scared?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brenda pops her head in, ignores Erin.</context>
      <utterance>It sure as hell sounded like they were sitting up and taking notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David Baum from PG&amp;E is at reception.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin feels the chill Brenda's sending her way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brenda leaves without acknowledging Erin.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to see you again, too, Brenda.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>BAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In terms of land value out in Hinkley, Mr. Masry, we feel it's a more than fair price.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about in terms of medical expenses? 250,000 doesn't come close to what this family's gonna have to spend on doctors.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand they've had a bad run of luck, health-wise, and they have my sympathies. But that's not PG&amp;E's fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look at these readings for Christ's sake. PG&amp;E's own technicians documented toxic levels of hexavalent chromium in those test wells, on numerous occasions. Ed shoves them across the table. Baum doesn't look at them.</context>
      <utterance>You're kidding, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything the Irvings have had is a proven reaction to exposure to hexavalent chromium. They've had ... He stalls a moment. Erin jumps in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite their persuasiveness, Baum parrots what is obviously the party line:</context>
      <utterance>-- breast cysts, uterine cancer, Hodgkin's disease, immune deficiencies, asthma, chronic nosebleeds.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A million things could have caused those problems. Poor diet, bad genes, irresponsible lifestyle. Our offer is final and more than fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute -- I thought we were negotiating here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed looks across at this pissant little kid.</context>
      <utterance>250,000 is all I'm authorized to offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ed starts out:</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ.  I will present your offer to my clients. I doubt they'll accept it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Masry, before you go off on some crusade, you might want to remember who it is you're dealing with here. PG&amp;E is a 28- billion dollar corporation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Ed leaves the conference room. Erin follows him out.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I'll keep it in mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least they made an offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wasn't an offer. A million would've been an offer. When they send the God damn mail clerk down to jerk me off, waste my time, it's a fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get why they'd do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because they can. You heard that kid -- they have 28 billion dollars at their disposal. They can afford to waste all the time in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you can't?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind them, Baum steps out of the conference room.</context>
      <utterance>What, you think I'm made of money?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>plane leaves Burbank in forty-five minutes. Ed turns and looks at him. He gets a tiny smile.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you know where I can get a cab? My</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what, why don't you go on over to reception, tell them I said Mario should take you to the airport.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baum heads out to the reception area.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, excellent. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Masry, Mario gets lost going to the bathroom. They'll be driving around the valley for hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She watches him go into his office, impressed. Big smile.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Isn't that a shame?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'll be God damned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROSALIND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been reading for hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a slow reader, on account of the fact that I look at the word "dog" and see "god".</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSALIND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rosalind turns on Erin's desk lamp and heads out. Outside the big glass office doors, Rosalind stops to talk to a lost-looking COUPLE IN THEIR MID-30's. These are MANDY and TOM BROWN. He's a security guard uniform, with an envelope under his arm. Rosalind points to Erin. The Browns enter the office and approach her.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, just so long as you see Him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, are you Erin Brockovich?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Tom Brown. This is my wife Mandy. We used to live across the street from the Irvings. PG&amp;E bought our house last year.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIDEN to see Erin looking at them with Tom and Mandy.</context>
      <utterance>It's called wry neck. It's when they're born without any muscles in the neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. How many were born like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve, maybe thirteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When Donna told us about you, and what you told her about the chromium, we figured that might have something to do with this, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tucks them into a file, as if that's it.</context>
      <utterance>It sure could, yeah. Thanks a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something else, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. Mandy here's had nine miscarriages.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? My God --</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. It's an awful lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm surprised Donna didn't say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She doesn't know. No one does. It's not something you want to talk about, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured it musta been something I did, like when I smoked marijuana, maybe. Or took birth control pills. But then Donna told me you thought this chromium might be to blame for her problems, so I figured ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON MATT AND KATIE. They're awake and pissed.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. You guys still awake?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They still don't answer. She comes in and sits on a bed.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, now. No faking. George told me he just shut out the light a few seconds ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I know you're mad. But the way this job is, things come up at the last minute, real important things, and I gotta deal with them. Now I don't like me missing dinner any more than you do, but we're all gonna have to get used to it, cause the fact is, it's gonna happen sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It happens all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true; we had dinner together just last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were reading the whole time. He's got a point there. Erin feels like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, pumpkins. I'll try a whole lot harder to be around, okay? I promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whatever. Erin glances at the speedometer. Oy. So slow. His car phone rings. He picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>It's Sinatra's world, we just live in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hi, babys. Baby's fine. Yes, I did. I did, too, you just didn't feel it. He starts swerving across the lane markers. THWACK THWACK THWACK. Ed doesn't notice. Erin's getting nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses into the phone. Swerves. A car barely misses them. Erin's eyes widen. Not fun at all.</context>
      <utterance>You think I could leave without kissing my babys? Okay, here you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finally hangs up, smiling to himself. Erin clears her throat.</context>
      <utterance>Bye-bye ... bye-bye ... no, you. Okay, together. Bye-bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um -- you mind pulling over? Just -- for a second?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If PG&amp;E messed with our water, why would they bother saying anything about it to us? Why not just keep quiet about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To establish a statute of limitations. See, in a case like this, you only have a year from the time you first learn about the problem to file suit. So PG&amp;E figures, we'll let the cat out of the bag -- tell the people the water's not perfect; if we can ride out the year with no one suing, we'll be in the clear forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it was more than a year ago that they told us --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roy looks up from his retainer agreement.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. We're not suing. All we're doing is using this information to get you a real nice purchase price on your house, and get you two --  -- a comparable retroactive bonus added to your sale price. This way, and PG&amp;E can still look good to their shareholders, cause they're not involved in an ugly lawsuit; all they're doing is buying a little property.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't say here how much this whole thing's gonna cost us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin watches them look around at each other, stunned by the figure.</context>
      <utterance>My fee's forty percent of whatever you get awarded.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, do I know how you feel. First time I heard that number, I said you got to be kidding me. Forty God damn percent?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the one who's injured, and this joker who sits at a desk all day is gonna walk away with almost half my reward?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin's enjoying Ed's discomfort almost too much to stop. But just almost. She shifts gears.</context>
      <utterance>Erin --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at Ed. Well?</context>
      <utterance>Then I asked him how much he makes if I didn't get anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I don't get anything either.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When they hear this, and realize he's in it with them, they all reach for their pens and sign. They hand the agreements over to Erin, who takes them across the room to Ed. He stuffs them in his briefcase and closes it up. That's that.</context>
      <utterance>And I realized, he's taking a chance too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boy. Cold as ice. Erin stares at him, stunned by his brusque manner, then leans in to him, close.</context>
      <utterance>All right, then. Let's hit the road.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up a tray of iced tea and cookies and heads to the kitchen. Donna and Mandy follow, leaving Ed alone with Pete and Roy. He stands there, awkwardly. Then, finally:</context>
      <utterance>Donna, let me help you clean all this up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what's, uh ... what's new?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know that thing it says in here about rashes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this old neighbor of mine, Bob Linwood -- he ran the dairy on Community -- seemed like someone in his family always had a rash somewhere or other. I just figured it was something in the genes. And you know how it is -- you don't like to ask about things like that ... Erin listens, interested.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He sees Erin picking her way toward him in her high-heels.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. Are you Mr. Linwood?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps in a cow patty. Laughs at herself good-naturedly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Erin Brockovich. I work at the law firm that represents your former neighbors the Browns. They suggested I give you a call.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy howdy, did I ever wear the wrong shoes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and Mr. Linwood seemed to think that your husband had been sick as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. DeSoto has lung cancer. Never smoked a day in his life, neither.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. DeSoto said she wasn't sure exactly what it was that you had --</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not alone on that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they know what it is -- it's called fibrous dysplasia --</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bones start growing again. Gives her headaches like you wouldn't believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- they just don't know what caused it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... then Mike Ambrosino remembered seeing you folks at the hospital from time to time too, so I thought I'd just stop by.  You must be Annabelle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whew, are you ever a beauty. I mean, you must drive those boys crazy. Annabelle smiles a little.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunh-uh. Absolutely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's crazy -- why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I said no. Look -- the only reason PG&amp;E's even talking to us is cause this is a quiet little real estate dispute. We add plaintiffs, and suddenly we're in the middle of a toxic tort -- with a statute problem -- against a massive utility. No, thank you. They go into their office building.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, so here's what I'll do. I'll go on up to Ted and Rita Daniels -- two of the nicest people you'd ever hope to meet, who spend every single day watching their little girl fight like a dog against this cancer -- I'll tell them we can't help them cause you don't feel like working that hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not about working hard --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- It's about being realistic. Something like this, Erin -- it could take forever. They're a huge corporation. They'd completely bury us in paperwork. I'm just one guy with a shitty little P.I. firm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- who happens to know they poisoned people and lied about it. The doors open. Ed gets off. Erin follows.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this shit is bad news, Mr. Masry. Not only does it attack every organ of the body, it fucks with your DNA, too. That means these people's genes, and the genes of their kids, and the genes of their grandkids --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets to the Masry &amp; Vititoe doors. Opens them.</context>
      <utterance>I know how DNA works, Erin --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can get these people. With a little effort, I really think we can nail their asses to the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you do? With all your legal expertise, you believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, fine. I don't know shit about shit. But I know the difference -- He shuts his office door on her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves the messages aside and puts his head in his hands. He sits like that for a moment, GROANS to himself. Then he pushes himself up and heads over to his door. When he opens it, he finds Erin still standing there, exactly where he left her, arms crossed. She hasn't budged.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many families we talking about here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four more. Eleven people. So far.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think there's more?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed pauses, groans again, realizing what decision he's making.</context>
      <utterance>Well -- I found one document at the water board that had a toxic test well reading from 1967. A hell of a lot of people have lived on that land since then.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a whole different ball game, Erin. A much bigger deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kinda like David and what's-his-name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kinda like David and what's-his-name's whole fucking family.  Okay, here's the deal -- if, and only if, you find me the evidence to back all this up -- I'll do it. I'll take it on. She smiles victoriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're doing the right thing, Mr. Masry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads back to his desk. Erin follows him into his office.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah. Remind me of that when I'm filing for bankruptcy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Course, gathering evidence -- now, that's a big job. A hell of a lot bigger than just filing. I'm gonna be working a lot harder now, taking on a lot more responsibility ... He gives her a look. Knows what's coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another raise wouldn't hurt. And with all the time I'm gonna be spending on the road, I'll probably be needing my own cel phone, won't I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matthew and Katie fan out into the store. Erin keeps messing with the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You each can pick out four things. But nothing huge. Look at the price. Nothing crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can buy 'em all the toys you want, but come Monday, when you split again, they're still gonna be pissed. Erin looks over at him, weary.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George, I am just trying to do something nice for my kids on my one day off. Could you please not give me a hard time about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One toy per kid is doing something nice. Four is ... something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hell, I guess that's it, then, huh? They're scarred for life. They're gonna start holding up 7-11's any day now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you're saying, and I don't wanna hear it. I am doing the best I can. And she walks away from him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANKEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ON THE REPORTS: We catch a few words: "water sample A ...", "soil sample D ...", "frog sample A ...", "... traces of hexavalent ..." Brenda looks at Erin and sees her hem rising in the back.</context>
      <utterance>... collect 'em, label 'em, then bring 'em to me. I'll analyze 'em, see what we got.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin turns to Brenda, relishing the chance to irritate her.</context>
      <utterance>For God's sake, Erin, I can see your panties.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed, in his office, laughs. He's starting to like this gal.</context>
      <utterance>Liar. I'm not wearing any.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna quit cause of one creepy phone call, George.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Erin. A job's supposed to pay your bills, not put you in danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes to the living room, double-checks the window locks in there. George follows.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not in danger. I have a dead bolt. Remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, don't take this the wrong way, but don't you think you might be out of your league here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, see -- that's exactly what those arrogant PG&amp;E fucks want me to think -- that because they got all this money and power, we don't stand a chance in hell against them. But you know what? They're wrong. She heads into the bedrooms.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't have to be this complicated, Erin. There's a lot of jobs out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George reacts, a little stung. He follows her into:</context>
      <utterance>How would you know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mind telling me what that's supposed to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you got a problem with me taking care of your kids instead of getting some job, just say so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause I can get a job. I will. And you can start leaving the kids with the chicken fat lady again. Would that make you happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep your voice down.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what they can sleep through, Erin. I probably know it better than you. She gives him a glare, then leaves the room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ross. Tell me something. Does PG&amp;E pay you to cover their ass, or do you just do it out of the kindness of your heart?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ross is speechless. He just stands there. Erin drags the box to the floor and goes to work.</context>
      <utterance>The fuck you don't. No one calls me Pattee. That heavy-breathing sicko that called the other night could've only found out about me from you.  People are dying, Ross. You got document after document here, right under your nose, that says why, and you haven't said word one about it. I wanna know how the hell you sleep at night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>INTERCUT between Erin in her car, and George in bed.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so tired I'm about to drive off the road. Keep me awake, willya?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want, a joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no jokes, I gotta pee. Just tell me about your day. What went on back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, come to think of it, we did have a big event around here. Beth started talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?  Beth? My Beth?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin says nothing, just stares out at the empty highway, feeling all hollowed-out.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We were sitting around at lunch and she pointed at a ball and said, "ball."</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin just nods. Keeps staring straight ahead as a tear rolls down her cheek.</context>
      <utterance>I'd never seen that before -- someone's first word. Pretty intense.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what I think it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She lived on the plume. You never know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm bored, and so are the kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George drops the pamphlet and takes Beth from Erin. He heads over to Matt and Katie, sitting glumly on a log. As he steps away, a hand reaches down and grabs the flier he dropped. It belongs to a MAN IN A BLACK JACKET. He's in his 50's, strong and sinewy. Military-style dark glasses obscure his eyes. He scans the pamphlet, then watches Erin working the crowd. Watches her carefully. He slides the pamphlet into his inside pocket, and heads back his car -- the DIRTY OLD PICK-UP TRUCK that idled in front of the Water Board.</context>
      <utterance>Just a few more minutes, then we can go.  Take her, will you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was about to take a handful of these -- He shows them a bottle of prescription pills.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin nods, then leaves Ed with Mike and heads toward:</context>
      <utterance>It's a morphine thing -- for pain --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just -- the pain. It's only getting worse. I can't be a good wife. I can't be a good mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin sits down on the chair next to the bed. Takes a beat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm real sorry, Laura.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what I always thought I wanted outta life, Erin? A Jaguar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jaguar's a darn pretty car.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought if I could spend that kinda money on a car, it'd mean everything else was fine.  I don't even know how much they cost.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot. But you hang in there, maybe you'll get one. Laura shakes her head.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin watches her sadly.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't mean the same thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They used the hex chrom here, in these cooling tanks, as an anti-corrosive. Then they dumped it here, in these six ponds.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't remember seeing any ponds up there. She bites into a forkful of food, keeps talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They covered 'em over. And not too carefully either, cause you dig one inch under the surface, and the dirt is green as a fucking shamrock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's what caused the contamination?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't help, but no. The real problem's on the bottom. She reaches for a document, reads from it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, according to this, they were supposed to line the ponds so this shit couldn't seep into the ground. But guess what --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They skipped that step.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it was a little too inconvenient. So for fourteen years, this stuff flowed into the groundwater, free as you please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't even wanna ask what you did to make this Melendez guy talk. In response to the insinuation, Erin gives him a glare.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For your information, Frank cares what was in those ponds 'cause he used to spend half his day wading around them. That was his job.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- Suddenly, her eyes pop out of her head --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Then gimme another raise.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up, grabs his trash can, and moves around the room with it, cleaning up all the Chinese food cartons.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I got a staff to pay, plus rent, plus I haven't billed a minute of my time since I started on this case, so you can quit hitting me up like I'm rich or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give me that. You're gonna get plenty rich off of this, Mr. 40 percent. We got those PG&amp;E fuckers by the balls here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got the PG&amp;E fuckers in Hinkley by the balls. But nobody's getting rich unless we can pin this on the corporate PG&amp;E fuckers in San Francisco.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>PG&amp;E corporate is claiming they had no way of knowing what was going on in Hinkley.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, they knew. They had to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't have one.</context>
      <utterance>Show me the document that proves that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then they didn't know. And if they didn't know, we can't hit 'em for punitive damages. And punitive damages is where the money is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, Ed -- you know, the more I work on this thing, the more I realize what a crock of shit this legal system is. Here we got a company that poisoned a whole aquifer -- that built a pool for a town, then filled it with toxic water -- and</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? It makes me sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too. That's why I like it. It's been a long time since I had a case I cared about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't care about my case?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a long look.</context>
      <utterance>I would now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I like working with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both smile a little awkwardly. Take a beat. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Well, good, Ed. I like working with you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When'd you start calling me Ed?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying -- we have one night to ourselves, why do we have to spend it here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause it's my office party. If you had an office, I'd go to your party.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flicks on the lights. Brenda's desk is decorated and as a present on it. Erin's is empty.</context>
      <utterance>And here, ta-daa, is my desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maybe they didn't think you were coming. Erin shakes her head. She's surprised by how hurt she is.</context>
      <utterance>Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her. She leans into him. He kisses her some more.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Fuck 'em, babe. Who needs 'em, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs a little. He slides his hands up her skirt. She pulls him into her, tugging his shirt out of his pants.</context>
      <utterance>Good thing there isn't a present there, huh? That mighta hurt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Ed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lock the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her back into him, not wanting to move.</context>
      <utterance>No, I wanna say hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Erin pulls away ...</context>
      <utterance>We'll say hi later. Lock it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches her straighten her dress and take a step away from him. It's just one step, but it feels a hell a lot farther.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, George, it's a party.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your wife's real pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not my wife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wouldn't kill you to talk about something other than yourself and your own fucking job once in a while --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to talk about instead?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you. Just cause I don't spend all day trying to prove what hot shit I am --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is not what I'm --</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bull</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks down her shirt front.</context>
      <utterance>I'd got so used to having 'em come up benign, I guess I just didn't expect it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure wish I had longer to get used to the idea.  You think if you got no uterus, and no breasts, you're still technically a woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you are. You're just a happier woman, cause you don't have to deal with maxi-pads and underwire. Donna smiles a little. Then her face crumbles.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna get them, aren't we, Erin? You gotta promise me we're gonna get them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they've sent that little shmuck Baum again, I'm gonna be real pissed off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From their tone of voice on the phone, I'd say they're taking us more seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brenda leans her head in.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I heard that one before.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Sanchez, Mr. Webster, Mr. Buda, and Ms. Cooper, from PG&amp;E are here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. They look like the Secret Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're trying to intimidate us.  Tell them to wait in the conference room.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Counselors --</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SANCHEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed and Erin sit down and get to work. Mario and Anna, clearly told to just follow along, sit down a moment later.</context>
      <utterance>Counselors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mario and Anna exchange a look. This is getting interesting.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, see, now that pisses me off. First of all -- we got more'n a hundred plaintiffs. They may not be sophisticated, but they do know how to divide, and two million dollars isn't shit when it's split between them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin -- But there's no stopping her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she gets up and storms out of the meeting.</context>
      <utterance>And second of all -- these people don't dream about being rich. They dream about being able to watch their kids swim in a pool without worrying they'll have to have a hysterectomy at age 20, like Rosa Diaz -- a client of ours -- or have their spine deteriorate like Stan Bloom. Another client of ours. So before you come back here with another lame-ass offer, I want you to think real hard about what your spine is worth, Mr. Buda -- or what you'd expect someone to pay you for your uterus, Miss Sanchez -- then you take out your calculator and multiply that number by a hundred. Anything less than that is a waste of our time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, Erin?  Listen. Even though you're not necessarily my favorite person in the world ...  ... sometimes you're not half-bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna assume that was meant as a compliment, Anna, and just say thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. A new plaintiff called, wants to meet you. I told him we'd be out there Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'you get his name?  Course not. Jesus, Ed --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he'd be at the gas station at six.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, this job takes me to some of the best damn places, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the only station in town, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets in his car and drives off. Erin sits down again. Looks down the road in both directions. Nothing. Then she spots, behind some bushes across the street, a glint of chrome. She shields her eyes against the sunset and sees: the BEAT-UP TRUCK parked behind some shrubbery. Erin looks around, realizes she's alone. As she looks back at the truck, the ASH of a cigarette brightens in the cab. She realizes she's being watched. The driver's door opens. Erin bolts for her car, scrambling to find her keys. She jumps in, locks her doors, and tries to start her car, but it won't turn over. Panic. The Man in the Dark Glasses has gotten out and is heading toward her car. Erin looks around again. Not a soul. She tries the engine again. And again. Just as he gets to her car, the engine engages. Erin peels out of the gas station.</context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's following me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some guy in a truck -- he waited till I was alone, then he followed me, like, two miles. Jesus, I'm shaking. Get me a beer. Ed gets up and heads toward the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ed looks out the door, Erin collapses onto a bench.</context>
      <utterance>Beer, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of truck?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Big. Dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gone.  Did you get a license plate? Or a make?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Ed -- what with me running for my life, I didn't have time to check those things --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just asking. Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed looks at her. She looks terrible. Shaky, tired, drawn.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yeah, I'm ... fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, you look like shit. When was the last time you had a decent night's sleep?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods a little. Then before she goes into her room:</context>
      <utterance>Lock the door every which way you can. And if there's anything -- funny sound, whatever -- pound on the wall. I'll come right over.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's as tender as she gets, and he's moved by it. They look at each other. Maybe even considering. But after a long beat, she reaches for her door again. Moment over.</context>
      <utterance>I think you should know -- there's very few people in the world who don't piss me off 90 percent of the time.  You're one of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, goes inside. He watches her close her door behind her before going inside himself.</context>
      <utterance>I'm triple locking my door, so don't even think of trying to take advantage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Erin enters, having just gotten home, and sees the mayhem.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads out.</context>
      <utterance>George!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't answer. Doesn't move. She notices this.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, George, they're turning the kitchen into a hellhole. You know you can't leave them alone like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on? What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's very calm. He holds out a small jewelry box.</context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a pair of earrings. I saw 'em in the mall one day, and I thought, damn, those would look good on those beautiful earlobes. So I bought 'em. And I said to myself, next time Erin says something nice, does something nice, I'll surprise her with 'em.  Know how long ago that was? Six months. In six months, you haven't said one nice thing to me. That's a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I'm just working so hard --</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. But still. Six months.  I think you oughta either find a different job or a different boyfriend. Cause there may be men who don't mind being the maid and getting nothing in return, but I'm sure as shit not one of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't leave my job, George.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you can. You could just quit. People do it all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. Look -- this job -- it's the best thing that ever happened to me. I mean it. For the first time in my life, I got people respecting me. Up in Hinkley, I walk into a room and everyone shuts up just to hear what I got to say. I never had that. Ever. Don't ask me to give it up. I need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than you need me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, then stands, to leave.</context>
      <utterance>I need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only then does she see the packed duffel bag in the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you didn't like who you were before, Erin, but I did. That's who I fell in love with.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You already packed up your stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks it up and walks out the door, tossing the earring box on the bed as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>I pretty much knew what your answer was gonna be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's my paycheck?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been logging on?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I moved payroll onto the computer. It only knows to process paychecks for employees who log on in the morning and off at night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now how'm I supposed to do that when I'm not in here most mornings and nights?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin glares at her ...</context>
      <utterance>You're clever. I'm sure you'll think of something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... then turns and storms out of Jane's office.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe this --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want my fucking money --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I'm gonna have to put you on hold for just one second here --  Do you mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus. You wanna tell me what the problem is here, or --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my paycheck. Which I earned. Which I deserve. Which I shouldn't have to beg for. That fat-ass bitch won't give it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin, you're a big girl. If you got a problem with Jane, work it out for yourself. I don't have time to deal with --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you. Make time. Cause I bust my ass for you. I watch everything else in my life go straight in the toilet, for you. And what do you do for me? Huh? You see the way I'm treated around here -- but have you ever stood up for me once? Have you ever mentioned to everyone what good work I'm doing? Have you ever bothered saying, hey, Erin doesn't get paid the most cause she has the best tits; she gets paid the most cause she's the best God damn employee I've ever had?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed sighs. Realizes he's going to have to take this on.</context>
      <utterance>I want my paycheck. By the end of the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see what I can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might want to think real hard about the amount, too. My kids are sitting in the God damn parking lot right now, cause I still don't make enough to afford good child care. Makes me think about looking around for a job where I'm appreciated, for shit's sake. She storms out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I play roller hockey?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DOORBELL RINGS. Erin goes to get it. Matthew follows</context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Randy's mom said yes right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin opens the door. A MESSENGER is there.</context>
      <utterance>Well, God damn it, Matthew -- Randy's mom doesn't work eighteen-hour days, and Randy's dad didn't leave her, so figuring out who's gonna take who where is a little easier over at Randy's house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MESSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin Brockovich?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MESSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her a manila envelope. She signs for the package, then tears into it as the Messenger heads away. A CHECK and a SET OF KEYS fall out. She looks at the check. It's made out for $5,000. A note attached reads "HIRE A</context>
      <utterance>Package from Masry &amp; Vititoe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe it or not, I would've been satisfied with just the check. Ed turns, sees her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you go threatening to leave, I can't take any chances. You're the only person around who understands what I'm doing. Things come up, I gotta know I got someone to turn to. She sits, reading him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of things come up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things like the head counsel for PG&amp;E calling me with an offer.  20 million, plus attorney's fees. Take it or leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. No shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about 50 thousand per plaintiff.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking ... I wish someone else had to make this decision.  50 thousand bucks is more than any other California toxic plaintiff has gotten. Ever. But ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... but it won't cover Annabelle Daniels's medical bills.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's less than pocket change for PG&amp;E.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think we'd do better by going to trial?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. but maybe not. We still don't have anything linking this to PG&amp;E corporate. Plus, there's the statute problem. Plus, we're way short on manpower, so we'd need to bring on more lawyers ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plus, 40 percent of 20 million's a whole lot of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>It's eight million dollars, Erin. Eight million dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods to himself, and looks up at her, his mind made up.</context>
      <utterance>That's a fucking fortune, Ed. And you know I'm the last person on Earth to walk away from a big payday. But you and me didn't get into this to get rich. We did it cause we both have this voice in our heads saying, do the right thing; get these plaintiffs what they deserve -- the right to live and die in some kind of comfort and peace. If 50,000 isn't gonna buy that, then we gotta say no.  Trust me. If you don't do the right thing for these people, getting that 6 million dollars is gonna feel like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew I put up with your bullshit for a reason.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit. Who do they represent, God?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ed turns to check his reflection, a YOUNG LAWYER comes through the reception area. Erin watches him pass, then, still miffed, calls out to him.</context>
      <utterance>Don't joke. They might. So do me a favor and behave yourself for once.  Ed Masry to see Kurt Potter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lawyer double-takes on her, then retreats into the office. Erin turns to Ed, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Scuse me, sir, you got a real nice ass, you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry. Was that not what you meant by behaving myself?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ed. Good to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Theresa, hey -- this is Erin Brockovich.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When'd they file the demur?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a demur?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's PG&amp;E saying to the judge that we don't have a case. Their lawyers go --</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many counts?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty-nine. We've got good answers to all of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Counts?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reasons PG&amp;E thinks it shouldn't go to --</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the judge?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Corey.</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why good?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got a reputation for doing all his --</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin's starting to steam at Potter. Theresa sees it brewing, tries to intercede.</context>
      <utterance>How long's he gonna take?</utterance>
   <speaker>THERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin notices all her files in stacks against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>You know what? Why don't I take Erin down the hall, so we can start in on this stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- those are my files --</utterance>
   <speaker>THERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Okay, these people are starting to piss her off.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we had them couriered over. And listen, good work. They're a great start. We're just going to have to spend a little time filling in the holes in your research.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- Theresa, was it? There are no holes in my research.</utterance>
   <speaker>THERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No offense. There are just some things we need that you probably didn't know to ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to me like I'm an idiot, okay? I may not have a law degree, but I've spent 18 months on this case, and I know more about those plaintiffs than you ever will.</utterance>
   <speaker>THERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin. You don't even have phone numbers for some of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose number do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>THERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone's. This is a lawsuit. We need to be able to contact the plaintiffs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said,</utterance>
   <speaker>THERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annabelle Daniels.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Theresa starts to write it down:</context>
      <utterance>Annabelle Daniels. 714-454-9346.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>10 years old, 11 in May. Lived on the plume since birth. Wanted to be a synchronized swimmer, so she spent every minute she could in the PG&amp;E pool. She had a tumor in her brain stem detected last November, had an operation on Thanksgiving, shrunk it with radiation after that. Her parents are Rita and Ted. Ted's got Chron's disease, and Rita has chronic headaches and nausea and underwent a hysterectomy last fall. Ted grew up in Hinkley. His brother Robbie and his wife May and their five kids Robbie, Jr., Martha, Ed, Rose, and Peter lived on the plume too. Their number's 454-9445. You want their diseases? Beat. Erin glares at Theresa, indignant.</utterance>
   <speaker>THERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, look -- I think we got off on the wrong foot here --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all you got, lady. Two wrong feet. In fucking ugly shoes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She insulted me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. It was a misunderstanding. But instead of handling it politely, instead of treating her with respect --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed stops in his tracks, furious. He glares at her.</context>
      <utterance>Why the fuck should I respect her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On that, he gets in his car, slams the door, and drives off, leaving her standing alone in the pouring rain.</context>
      <utterance>Gee, I wonder why.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You're my ride!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Responsibilities, who should cover what --</context>
      <utterance>I've also been thinking about the team.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should makes some changes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT WITH Erin at home, still in bed, so irritated.</context>
      <utterance>Ed Masry's office ... Sorry, he can't be interrupted.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be a pain in the ass, okay, Brenda? Just put him on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSALIND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Erin, I thought you were taking a sick day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads toward Ed's office, but stops when she sees a meeting in progress in the conference room. Ed is on the side of the table facing her, flanked by Potter and Theresa. On the other side of the table, are FOUR SUITED BACKS.</context>
      <utterance>So did I.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSALIND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some meeting. With PG&amp;E people.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>PG&amp; -- Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSALIND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin feels this like a sock in the gut. She stares at the meeting, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Yup. They must be important, too, cause they came on a special plane.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CORBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... we would enter into binding arbitration -- judge, no jury -- with a settlement to be between 50 and 400 million dollars. Ed and Potter hear this and think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any preconditions on the settlements?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plaintiffs have to agree to it unanimously. And they're barred from ever discussing their settlement with anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>50-400 million dollars isn't a whole hell of a lot of money for your company, Mr. Corbin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you tell me to relax, I'm gonna kick your fucking head off --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin, it's just a meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People don't fly down in their own god damn plane for "just a meeting" --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you said you weren't feeling great. I thought you should rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. You'd drag me off my deathbed if it suited you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kurt thought, if it was just lawyers --</context>
      <utterance>Okay, look. It's an important meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He resists being dragged into an knock-down, drag-out fight.</context>
      <utterance>Kurt thought? What about you? Do you think anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, this is serious now. They're talking serious money --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, what, I'm not serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're emotional. You're erratic. You say any God damn thing that comes into your head. And I'm not saying that's bad. That can be great; that can be a lot of fun --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Fun?" Jesus, "</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's taking anything --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now the entire office is watching. As are the lawyers in the conference room.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. You stuck me in Siberia dictating to some God damn steno clerk so you could finish this thing without me. After all I've done for you, that's the thanks I get.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give me that. You've gotten plenty. You've been well-paid; you've gotten lots of perks ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perks? Jesus --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks over her shoulder, but the sidewalk is too dark. She pulls a U-turn in the middle of the street. A CAR HONKS. Erin scans the sidewalk, finally sees him again. Holy shit, is right. It's Matthew, wandering the streets at night.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls ahead of Matthew and bumps up onto the sidewalk, blocking his path. When he sees her car, he turns and runs the other way. Erin leaps out and follows him.</context>
      <utterance>Matthew --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Matthew!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I promise.</context>
      <utterance>We'll work out the roller hockey thing, okay? Whatever you want, we'll work it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always say that. Then you go to work and forget you promised.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never forget, honey. I try, real hard. It's just, for some reason, I don't seem to be able to organize things right and -- when it comes to you guys, I end up falling short.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never fall short for the work people. I guess maybe you just love them more.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lays her hand on his shoulder, but he shrugs it off and inches away from her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, sweetheart, no. There's nothing on Earth I love more than you. Nothing.  I promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They said that'd be tomorrow. They just wanna keep an eye on me another night.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. I'll drop 'em off tomorrow afternoon. A moment of thick silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she watches him reach for his motorcycle helmet, to leave, she's hit with a wave of regret.</context>
      <utterance>Mm-hm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a KNOCK at the door, and Ed enters. George looks at him. Not interested in her apologies.</context>
      <utterance>George, hang on.  Look ... I'm sorry. I just --</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Erin watches George leave the room, then turns to Ed.</context>
      <utterance>I'll drop 'em by tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're here to fire me, your timing's lousy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna fire you.  I wanted to. But then you got sick, and that woulda made me look like a shit.  You embarrassed me, Erin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I'm sorry.  Do I get to hear what happened anyway?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Between 50 and 400 million, definitely?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if you had to guess ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With nothing linking it to the corporate offices yet, I'd say we'll end up on the lower end of that. Still a lot of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why would PG&amp;E offer it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because. They know the evidence; they know they're gonna lose a jury trial. Maybe they wouldn't lose 400 million bucks, but once you factor in all they'd spend on this case in the next ten years, it makes a lot of --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, what do you mean, ten years?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five years, maybe, for a trial. Double that for the appeal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, are you saying that if this thing goes to trial, it'll be</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tuesday at seven, at the Hinkley firehouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, good. I think I should be the one to tell 'em, cause they trust me more than --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fuck I'm not. I don't care what the doctor says --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't doctor's orders. It's mine. I'm saying you can't come.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because Kurt doesn't want to work with you. He thinks you're a loose cannon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck Kurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm serious. You know what Kurt Potter is? He's the kind of guy who never would have taken this case in the first place. He's the kind of guy who would have sold these plaintiffs down the river when PG&amp;E offered 20 million. He doesn't work like us, Ed. There's no little voice in his head telling him to do the right thing. But his mind's made up. He stands to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't come, Erin. I mean it. If you do, I'm gonna have to fire you.  Just ... concentrate on getting well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PLAINTIFF</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then a jury decides?</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She climbs up on an old wagon for a better view.</context>
      <utterance>No, sorry, I should have mentioned that. There's no jury in binding arbitration. No jury, and no appeal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I said before, it will</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't want to speculate at this point.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Potter turns around and looks at Ed seated behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Ed -- what do you think it'll be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think ... Kurt's right. We shouldn't speculate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So then, what, that mystery number's divided up at the whim of some judge --</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GRUMBLE of discontent has overtaken the room. More whispering, more movement.</context>
      <utterance>Judges don't make decisions based on whim, ma'am. They make them based on precedent and evidence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted Daniels gets up from his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Look. Everyone. Is this a big decision? Absolutely. But I do believe that if you put a little faith in the system, you'll be quite pleased with the outcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops his agreement form, unsigned, then takes Rita's hand and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Potter, if you knew me from Adam, you'd know that being pleased isn't an option for me anymore. Now don't take this personally, sir, but I've never seen you before in my life. I'm not about to put my faith in anything just cause you tell me to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Employee gives it to her. Erin crosses to the copiers. She slips the release form into one, then taps in the number of copies: 635. Presses "START." The machine WHIRS to life.</context>
      <utterance>Can I have one of those counter thingies, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to stay here. It smells.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the kids wander toward the bathroom, Erin picks up the phone and dials. RING, RING.</context>
      <utterance>We got no choice. I'm not gonna make it home tonight. Now go wash up and climb into bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. It's me.  I got a favor to ask you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't do favors for you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not for me; it's for my kids. You're the only one I trust them with.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes it, glances toward the motel room.</context>
      <utterance>I got you your own room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a wad of cash.</context>
      <utterance>Hunh-uh. Not yet.  Look, don't take any of 'em on your bike, okay? Call a cab if you wanna go somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long's this whole thing gonna take?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thanks for helping me. I appreciate it. He nods. She gets into her car. Before closing the door, she turns back to him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Few days.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I miss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees how mad she's made him. Takes a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well -- good help is hard to find.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George softens, shifts. He steps toward the truck and gently closes her door, so he's standing close to her.</context>
      <utterance>I treated you real bad, George. I know that. But, my problem was -- I never been with anyone who deserved better than that. You're the first nice guy who ever liked me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just ... didn't know how to handle it. That's all. He thinks about this. Finally:</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think you could learn?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't be driving around, you know. You're sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, understanding. Then he taps the side of her truck and turns toward the motel room. She puts the truck in gear and pulls out.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I'm gonna get better. A lot of these folks aren't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Erin -- the way he was talking to us, telling us everything was gonna be fine -- I just didn't trust him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And after all we been through -- no jury, no appeal. It just makes me nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand all that. And I don't wanna force you into anything. If you don't want to sign, that's fine. But why don't we talk it over a little, cause I'd sure hate for you to turn this down for the wrong reasons.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't happen to have a little time right now, would you, Donna?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was gonna head over to the Browns now. I was thinking -- Mandy really values your opinion ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real early. We're just gonna take your car to get some breakfast. Erin forces herself awake.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I need my car --</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up Beth, takes Katie's hand, and calls across the room to Matthew.</context>
      <utterance>We'll just be a minute. Get a little more sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin turns to see Matthew holding one of her release forms.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, pal. Leave that alone, we gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he's reading it. And something has caught his attention. He looks up at Erin.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, baby, please don't play with that, okay? I got 'em all organized. Just put it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin gently takes the form away from Matthew, wanting to shield him from the harsh realities of this case.</context>
      <utterance>This girl's the same age as me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She replaces the form on top of the stack.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's one of the sick people?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matthew mulls this over a bit more.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. She is.  But you know what? That's why I'm helping her. So she can get some medicine to make her feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come her own mom isn't helping her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matthew thinks real hard about this, then heads over to the door, where George, Beth, and Katie are waiting for him. Before he leaves, though, he turns back to Erin.</context>
      <utterance>Cause her own mom's real sick, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at the group of them, feels their shift toward acceptance. Smiles, moved.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we'll bring you back some breakfast. You want eggs?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eggs'd be great, baby. Eggs'd be perfect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>WIDEN TO REVEAL Erin talking on a nearby pay phone.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna head out to Barstow and talk to some folks out there tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise you'll turn around if you get tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up. As she turns to get into her car, she finds herself face-to-face with the Man in the Dark Glasses.</context>
      <utterance>I will. Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's just standing there, a foot away, blocking her exit. She recognizes his truck as the one that chased her.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes past him. But he grabs her by the arm. He's a big guy; it's a strong grab. Now she's scared. For a moment, he does nothing. Just looks at her. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Okay, what're you gonna do? You gonna kill me? Dump my body in a ditch somewhere? Or maybe you just wanna inject me with some poison too -- why change tactics at this stage of the game?  Get outta my way, you make me sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARK GLASSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin takes a beat, realizing she completely misread him. She gently pulls her arm away.</context>
      <utterance>If PG&amp;E made someone destroy a whole lot of documents -- would that matter to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well ... I guess that depends on what the documents were.  I'm sorry -- I didn't get your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARK GLASSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Embry. Charles Embry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>EMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was working in the compressor, and out of nowhere the supervisor calls me up to the office and says, we're gonna give you a shredder machine, and send you on down to the warehouse. We want you to get rid of all the documents stored out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he say why?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. And I didn't ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get a look at the stuff you destroyed?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's pretty boring work, shredding -- you gotta find some way to entertain your mind. So yeah, I took a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And ...?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin tries to hide her excitement at this information.</context>
      <utterance>There was a lot of dull stuff -- vacation schedules, the like.  But then there were a few memos about the holding ponds. The water in them. They had readings from test wells, stuff like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you were told to destroy those?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Destruction of evidence. Pretty big deal. Erin plays it down. Wipes her mouth with her napkin, takes a sip of beer.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Course as it turns out, I'm not a very good employee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin stops, mid-bite.</context>
      <utterance>Well. There were a few documents that I somehow didn't get around to shredding.  That I kept instead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you didn't say anything when you found these things?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the time, I thought, I got six kids, some of 'em want to go to college. I can't afford to lose my job. I told myself I was being honorable.  But there's nothing honorable in what I did.  Maybe that's why they picked me for the job. Maybe they knew what kind of man I was.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ros, where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSALIND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Erin's spotted them and headed off before Rosalind can finish. Anna, Brenda and Jane notice the purpose in her gait. They watch her with interest.</context>
      <utterance>In the conference --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning!</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin? What are you --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE DOORWAY, Anna, Brenda and Jane appear, wondering what's up. A huge smile of appreciation slowly spreads across Ed's face.</context>
      <utterance>635. They all signed. Every single one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ho - ly - shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, now don't get all jealous, Ed. I got a little something for you, too. Erin hands Ed a manila envelope. He opens it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Potter and Theresa reel. Ed shakes his head in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Internal PG&amp;E documents, all about the contamination. The one I like best says, and I'm paraphrasing here, but it says yes, the water's poisonous, but it'd be better for all involved if this matter wasn't discussed with the neighbors. It's to the Hinkley station, from PG&amp;E Headquarters. Stamped received, March, 1966.</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did -- how did you do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she struts out of the room, leaving everyone slack-jawed. The CLIP CLIP CLIP of her heels carry her away.</context>
      <utterance>Well, what with me not having any brains or legal expertise, I just went on up there and performed sexual favors. 635 blow jobs in five days. Whew, am I ever tired.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin puts her hand in the door, keeping it from closing. He stares at her, in awe.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say you were wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say you shortchanged me and you shortchanged yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. Both.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say you'd be the luckiest son of a bitch on Earth if I didn't up and quit over all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down the hall at her, standing so tall and proud in the elevator. He walks toward her, stops right outside the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>The luckiest son of a bitch in the universe, Erin. The luckiest son of a bitch in history.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I know you're not gonna quit on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna turns, sees her. Smiles.</context>
      <utterance>How you feeling today?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a good day. I feel good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then -- if you're feeling up to it, maybe we should talk shop. Erin sits down on a rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The judge came up with a number.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A number for the whole group, or for us?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna sits down next to her.</context>
      <utterance>Both.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears of vindication spring to Donna's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>He's making them pay the maximum.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he's making them give five million of it to you all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five million dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reels. After a breathless beat:</context>
      <utterance>Five million dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even know how much money that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna wipes the tears off her face, then watches the light flickering off her girls playing in the surf.</context>
      <utterance>It's enough -- for whatever you need, for whatever your girls need, for whatever your girls' girls need -- it'll be enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can put them in a good school.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any school you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And get someone to help around the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna is overwhelmed. Erin pulls her close.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROSALIND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lost them. Her reaction indicates this isn't the first time. The front doors open and Erin enters.</context>
      <utterance>Masry &amp; Vititoe, can I -- shoot!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ros. Nice view, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSALIND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin heads on down a hall to:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm gonna start sleeping here.  Masry &amp; Vititoe, can I -- damn it.  Does anyone know anything about these phones?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Careful you don't spit from here; you could kill someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see your office?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yours is nicer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay. Here it comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here what comes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The extortion, the threats ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't gonna --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I can always find someplace else to work. Someplace that'll pay me a fortune and give me a view of the French Riviera ..."</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ed, I swear, I'm not --</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin does. Looks at it. Her eyes bug out.</context>
      <utterance>Take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two million dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at it, speechless. He goes back to unpacking</context>
      <utterance>The firm took in sixty. That's three percent. Seemed like a fair bonus to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, now I suppose you're gonna say it's not enough. Well, tough, Erin. Too goddamn bad. Cause this is absolutely, positively where I draw the line.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
