<movie id="196" title="Even Cowgirls Get the Blues">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE CHART KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is restless tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER INDIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She dreams of loving.</utterance>
   <speaker>STILL ANOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>View of the chartkeeper's drawings. One is of a crane with a very long neck. Another is a primitive drawing of a naked girl, who has long flowing hair. She also has, pointed out from her sides, thumbs that are three times normal human proportions. A MUSICAL CHORUS sounds at the sight of this drawing of a girl with the thumbs. The chartkeeper puts the finishing touches on the drawing. And the song "Happy Birthday to You" strikes up on country and western guitar and polka-like accordion. title</context>
      <utterance>She has the blues.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>UNCLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're lucky that you don't suck 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>DADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy is negotiating a fork full of birthday cake, dropping it because of her thumbs.</context>
      <utterance>Sissy couldn't suck 'em, she'd need a mouth like a fish tank.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The poor little tyke might have a hard time finding herself a hubby. But as far as getting along in the world, it's a real blessing that Sissy's a girl-child. Lord, I reckon this youngun would never make a mechanic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope, and not a brain surgeon, neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughing, the men walk to the kitchen to fill their glasses. Sissy is left to feel sorry for herself in front of her cake.</context>
      <utterance>Course she'd do pretty good as a butcher. She could retire in two years on the overcharges alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>This startles Sissy. A new word that tinkles in her head with a supernatural echo. Sissy looks at her thumbs.</context>
      <utterance>One thing, that youngun would make one hell of a hitchhiker...</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...if she was a boy, I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. DREYFUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is, if I may speak frankly, somewhat of a medical oddity. Due to impaired dexterity, her life activities and career potentialities will be reduced. It could be worse. Bring her back to me if there ever is pain. Meanwhile, she will have to learn to live with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HANKSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That she will. That she will. The Lord made them things big for a purpose. God don't never git tired of testing our kind. It's a punishment of some sort, for what I don't rightly know.  Oh Doc, if a young man ever shows up here with, a young man with ugly fingers, you know, something similar, a similar case, Doc, would you please...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. DREYFUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember the words of the painter Paul Gauguin, dear lady. "The ugly may be beautiful, the pretty never." I don't suppose that means very much to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HANKSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy beams serenely like a Christ figure.</context>
      <utterance>It's a judgement. She's gotta bear the punishment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside. Madame Zoe begins stubbing a cigarette in one of those enlightened little ceramic ashtrays that are shaped like bedpans and inscribed BUTTS. The trailer is cluttered, but not one knick-knack, chintz curtain or chenille-covered armchair seems to have come from the Beyond.</context>
      <utterance>I am the enlightened Madame Zoe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she notices the thumbs.</context>
      <utterance>There is nothing about your past, present or future that your hands do not know, and there is nothing about your hands that Madame Zoe does not know. There is no hocus-pocus involved. I am a scientist, not a magician. I, Madame Zoe, chiromancer, lifelong student of the moldings and markings of the human hand. I, Madame Zoe, to whom no facet of your character or destiny is not readily revealed. I am prepared to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Hankshaw and the fortune-teller turn pale and uncertain, while Sissy recognizes with a faint smile that she is in command. Sissy extends the thumbs as an ailing aborigine might extend his swollen parts to a medical missionary. Sissy's mama draws a neatly folded five-dollar bill from her change purse and extends it alongside her smiling daughter's extremities. Madame Zoe returns to her senses, and takes Sissy by the elbow to sit at a For mica-topped table of undistinguished design. Madam Zoe holds Sissy's hands while she appears to go into a trance. She opens her eyes momentarily.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus fucking Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a strong will. Will power and determination are indicated by the first phalanx. The second phalanx indicates reason and logic. You obviously have both in large supply. What's your name, dearie?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sissy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls her thumb to her breast.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. I'd say that you have an intelligent, kindly, somewhat artistic nature. However, Sissy, however, there is a heavy quality to the second phalanx- the phalanx of logic -- that indicates a capacity for foolish or clownish behavior, a refusal to accept responsibility or to take things seriously and bent to be disrespectful of those who do. Your mama tells me that you're pretty well behaved and shy, but I'd watch out for signs of irrationality. All right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mom speaks out from the couch she is sitting on</context>
      <utterance>I guess the most important aspect of your thumbs is the, ahem, over all size. Uh, what was it, do you know, that caused...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS HANKSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know; the doctors don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just lucky I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you study history in school? Galileo, Descartes, Newton? Lebinitz had very large thumbs; Voltaire's were enormous, but, heh heh, just pickles compared with yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Crazy Horse?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madame Zoe lets go of Sissy's thumbs and wipes her hands on her kimono.</context>
      <utterance>Crazy Horse? You mean the Indian? Nobody that I've ever heard of ever troubled to study the paws of savages. Well, I guess that about covers the three-fifty charge...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HANKSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Hankshaw withdraws a bill from her rat-skin bag.</context>
      <utterance>Husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beg your pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HANKSHAW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Husband. Will she find a husband?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madame Zoe takes Sissy's hand and gives it the old tall-dark- stranger squint.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises her eyes to meet Sissy's looking for an admission of the "tendency", but there is no signal. Mrs. Hankshaw does not approve.</context>
      <utterance>I see men in your life, honey. I also see women, lots of women.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Hankshaw, aghast, has heard plenty, and she ushers her daughter out of the trailer as if she were leading her from a burning cocktail lounge.</context>
      <utterance>A husband, no doubt about it, though he is years away. There are children, too. Five, maybe six, but the husband is not the father. They will inherit your characteristics.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going north?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns up the volume of his radio and rockets north.</context>
      <utterance>You bet your raggedy white ass I am. Sissy gets in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He eats the cheese, and worries about the thumbs. He tokes on the joint between his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>American Cheese. The king of road food.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you in show business?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was a successful model once.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For magazines?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was the Yoni Yum feminine-hygiene Dew girl from 1965 to 1970, but got laid off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now you're bummin' around?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hitchhiking?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the best?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was younger, I hitchhiked one hundred and twenty-seven hours without stopping, without food or sleep, crossed the continent twice in six days, cooled my thumbs in both oceans and caught rides after midnight on unlighted highways.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whooee!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man listening to her takes another toke on his joint.</context>
      <utterance>As I developed, however, I grew more concerned with subtleties and nuances of style. Time in terms of M.P.H. no longer interested me. I began to hitchhike in something akin to geological time: slow, ancient, vast. When I am really moving, stopping car after car after car, moving so freely, so clearly, so delicately that even the sex maniacs and the cops can only blink and let me pass, then I embody the rhythms of the universe. I am in a state of grace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the distance, Sissy spies her destination. NEW YORK CITY.</context>
      <utterance>Right off, I don't remember how old I was when I found out I was part Indian. My mamma's family, a lot of them, had lived out West, in the Dakotas, and one of them had married a squaw. Siwash tribe. My pleasure in Indianhood and my passion for car travel might be incongruous if not mutually exclusive........ After all, the first car that ever stopped for me had been named in honor of the great chief of the Ottawa: Pontiac......</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NEW YORK CITY. It's still a helluva town....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy Hankshaw takes a seat. The Countess lifts a dusty decanter.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down dear, do sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The decanter is empty, a stiff fly lies feet up on it's lip.</context>
      <utterance>Take a load off those lovely tootsies. Yes, sit right down. Would you fancy some sherry?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into a midget refrigerator beside his desk and pulls out some pop wine.</context>
      <utterance>Shit O goodness, I'm all out of sherry; how about some Red Ripple?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy manages a polite smile. She looks at a heavily finger printed glass.</context>
      <utterance>You know what Red Ripple is don't you? It's Kool-Aid with a hard on. Tee Hee.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To my own special Sissy. Cheers! And welcome. So my letter brought ya flying, eh? Where were you? Salt Lake City? La Conner? Well, I may have a little surprise for you. But first, tell me about yourself. It's been six months, hasn't it? In some circles that's half a year. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tired...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the very first time in the eons that I've known you that I've ever heard you complain. And now you're tired, poor darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A born freak can only go uphill.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freak, schmeek. Most of us are freaks in one way or another. Try being born a male Russian countess into a white middle class Baptist family in Mississippi and you'll see what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always been proud of the way nature singled me out. It's the people who have been deformed by society I feel sorry for. I've been steady moving for eleven years and some months. Maybe I should rest up for a spell, I'm not as young as I used to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit O goodness, you won't be thirty for another year, and you're more beautiful than ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Countess taps his monocle with his cigarette holder. He looks on his wall, and on a poster advertising a feminine hygene product, Yoni Yum Dew Spray, stands Sissy Hankshaw, her thumbs neatly hidden, chopped off by the borders of the photograph.</context>
      <utterance>Does that mean you might have an assignment for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were the Yoni Yum girl from, let's see,  from nineteen sixty-eight through nineteen seventy. You've always smelled so nice. Like a little sister. The irony has just killed me. You, the Dew Girl, one of the few girls who doesn't need Dew. I loath the stink of females! They are so sweet the way God made them, then they start fooling around with men and soon they're stinking. Like rotten mushrooms, like an excessively chlorinated swimming pool, like a tuna fish's retirement party. They all stink. From the Queen of England to Bonanza Jellybean, they stink.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bonanza Jellybean?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Countess's jaw muscles calm down, his dentures ease into a samba...</context>
      <utterance>What? Oh yes. Tee-hee. Jellybean.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a young thing who works on my ranch. Real name is Sally Jones or something wooden like that. She's cute as a hot fudge taco, and, of course, it takes verve to change one's name so charmingly. But she stinks like a slut just the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your ranch?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks out his window as a squirrel crosses Park Avenue.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my dear yes, I bought a little ranch out West, sort of a tribute to the women of America who have cooperated with me in eliminating their odor by using my vaginal products, Dew spray mist and Yoni Yum spray powder. A tax write-off, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sissy, Sissy, blushing bride, you can desist from wearing paths in those forgotten highways. The Countess has arranged a job for you. And what a job...</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A job for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Countess hands Sissy an article that she reads clenched in her fist.</context>
      <utterance>I am once more about to make advertising history. And only you, the original Yoni Yum/Dew Girl, could possibly assist me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Food and Drug Administration said Wednesday female deodorant sprays may cause such harmful reactions as blisters, burns and rashes. Although the FDA judges that the reported reactions are not sufficient to justify removal of these products from the market, they are sufficient to warrant the proposed mandatory label warnings.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy dares a sip of Red Ripple.</context>
      <utterance>Shit O dear, that's enough to make me asthmatic. The nerve of those twits. What do they know about female odor? Don't interrupt. Here's my concept. My ranch out West? It's a beauty ranch. Oh, it's got a few head of cattle for atmosphere and tax purposes. But it's a beauty ranch, a place where unhappy women -- divorcees and widows, mainly -- can go to lose weight, remove wrinkles, change their hair styles and pretty themselves up for the next disappointment. My ranch is named the Rubber Rose, after the Rubber Rose douche bag, my own invention, and bless its little red bladder, the most popular douche bag in the world. So get this. It's on the migratory flight path of the whooping cranes. The last flock of wild whooping cranes left in existence. Well, these cranes stop off at my little pond -- Siwash Lake, it's called -- twice a year, autumn and spring, and spend a few days each time, resting up, eating, doing whatever whooping cranes do. I've never seen them, understand, but I hear they're magnificent. Very big specimens -- I mean, huge mothers -- and white as snow, to coin a phrase, except for black tips on their wings and tail feathers, and bright red heads. Now, whooping cranes, in case you didn't know it, are noted for their mating dance. It's just the wildest show in nature. It's probably the reason why birdwatching used to be so popular with old maids and deacons. Picture these rare, beautiful, gigantic birds in full dance -- leaping six feet off the mud, arching their backs, flapping their wings, strutting low to the ground. Dears, it's overwhelming. And picture the birds doing their sex dance on TV. Right there on the home screen, creation's most elaborate sex ritual -- yet clean and pure enough to suit the Pope. With lovely Sissy Hankshaw in the foreground. In a white gown, red hood attached, and big feathery sleeves trimmed in black. In a very subdued imitation of the female whooping crane, she dance/walks over to a large nest in which there sits a can of Yoni Yum. And a can of Dew. Off-camera, a string quartet is playing Debussy. A sensuous voice is reading a few poetic lines about courtship and love. Are you starting to get it? Doesn't it make the hair on your neck stand up and applaud? My very goodness gracious! Grandiose, lyrical, erotic and Girl Scout- oriented; you can't top it. I've hired a crew of experts from Walt Disney Studios, the best wildlife cinematographers around. You're my eternal favorite. Princess Grace herself couldn't be better, not even if she had your personality which she doesn't; Anyway, dear, I'm out of photography now and into water colors. Ah how circuitous conversation is! We're back at the beginning. The exact man I've wanted you to meet is my artist the watercolorist.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't want me to pose for him, why do you want me to meet him?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Purely personal. I believe you might enjoy one another.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Countess...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Park Avenue again but doesn't make it. The uniformed chauffeur gets out of a limousine and holds the crushed animal up where it can be seen by an elderly woman passenger.</context>
      <utterance>Now, now. Don't get exasperated. I realize that you've always avoided all but the most rudimentary involvements with men, and I might add, you've been wise. Heterosexual relationships seem to lead only to marriage. For men, marriage is a matter of efficient logistics: The male gets his food, bed, laundry, TV, pussy, offspring and creature comforts all under one roof, where he doesn't have to dissipate his psychic energy thinking about them too much, then he is free to go out and fight the battles of life, which is what existence is all about. But for a woman marriage is surrender. The Countess refills his glass. The squirrel starts across</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But here you are, still a virgin -- you are virginal yet, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, yes, technically. Jack Kerouac and I came awfully close, but he was afraid of me, I think...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, well, what I'm getting at is that there comes a time when it is psychologically impossible for a woman to lose her virginity. She can't wait too long, you know. Now, there's no reason why you must lose yours. I mean, just ponder it a bit, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think this watercolorist and I would develop a romantic relationship?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't be certain that you would. But what have you got to lose?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, okay. I'll try it. I don't see the point in it, but I'll try it. Just for you. It's kind of silly, actually, me going out with an artist in New York City. However...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the Countess swivels in his desk chair and leans forward. Lowering his wine glass, he focuses directly, intensely into Sissy's blue eyes. His smile widens.</context>
      <utterance>Good, good, good... you'll enjoy it, you'll see. Julian is a gentleman.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A title:</context>
      <utterance>By the way, Sissy... he's a full blooded Indian.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm not scared of a little rain.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might as well brave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delores flicks her whip at a sweat bee that has taken refuge in the privy and hits the photograph of Dale Evans upon which it has lit. Jelly looks out the door of the outhouse across a cut green lawn to a bunkhouse where we can see a gathering of other cowgirls. There is a fly buzz and a distant polka yip. Way off horse lips flutter. Bonanza spies a picture of Sissy Hankshaw, an advertisement for Yoni Yum Dew Spray mist, on the privy wall.</context>
      <utterance>Right. I don't know about you but I'm sure not sweet enough to melt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someday...... if that Sissy Hankshaw ever shows up here, I'm gonna teach her how to hypnotize a chicken. Chickens are the easiest critters on Earth to hypnotize. If you can look a chicken in the eyes for tens seconds, it's yours forever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to complain that some of the cowgirls have been sleeping two to a bunk again, in violation of the agreement that "crimes against nature" are to be confined to the hayloft.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the younger cowgirls blush.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care who lay with whom or where or how, but the moaners, groaners and screamers ought to turn down their volume when others are trying to sleep or meditate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A round of support from the other cowgirls in the form of cattle calls.</context>
      <utterance>I want to complain about the food around here! It's rotten to the core.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But in a minute, others follow Debbie, everyone of them, in fact; the entire bunkhouse load of them, some thirty young cowgirls, squealing, giggling, They slide and roll on the wet grass, push each other into the mud that is forming by the corral fence, chase one another in and out of the thick folds of rain draperies, stamp their cute feet in puddles and do bellyflops into the overflowing horse trough. The cowgirls frolic until, as suddenly as it has come, the rain goes away. Play ceases. They are panting like puppies as they lean against one another or pick clods of mud from one another's hair.</context>
      <utterance>My sacred crocodile! She's flipped.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I move that the meeting be adjourned.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the end of the endless game, there is friendship.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the heck did she mean by that!</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just that in Heaven all business is conducted this way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RUPERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the red of embarrassment, Julian looks more Indian than he had previously. Wheezing, he speaks:</context>
      <utterance>We'd better take you home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon. I've been enthralled with your photographs for years. When the Countess hinted that you might like to meet me -- he never explained why -- I was ready to paint for him free of charge. And now I had to go and spoil it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carla nods. Everyone is piling into the taxi.</context>
      <utterance>This is dreadful.  You know, asthma attacks are brought on by emotional stress. Poor Julian is so high strung. The excitement of meeting you -- my dear, you look so stunning! -- must have upset his chemical balance.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUPERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Sissy, don't be afraid of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy is forced to suffer the indignity of riding in a vehicle she wasn't responsible for flagging with her own thumbs.</context>
      <utterance>I've never ridden in a cab. The whole idea of paying for a ride makes my thumbs hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be all right, dear. It isn't as serious as it sounds.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>RUPERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Sissy.</context>
      <utterance>There, that ought to beat them bronchial buggers into submission.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUPERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was a medic in the Army. I really should have become a doctor. Sometimes, though, I feel that pushing books is a whole lot like pushing medicine. Think of books as pills. I have pills that cure ignorance and pills that cure boredom. I have pills to elevate moods and pills to open people's eyes to the awful truth...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carla smiles as if she were joking, but she'd said it tartly. Rupert glares and takes a big bite of Scotch.</context>
      <utterance>Too bad you don't have a pill for bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you live, Miss Hankshaw?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm staying with the Countess.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but where do you reside when you aren't visiting New York?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks a bit astonished including the recumbent Julian.</context>
      <utterance>Well, no, I don't reside anywhere in particular. I just keep moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A traveler, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might say that, although I don't think of it as traveling.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you think of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How... unusual...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rupert bites into his Scotch again. Julian issues a watery wheeze. Then, silence.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy leaves her chair and wanders about the apartment. Which is full of books and shelves.</context>
      <utterance>Rupert, before you get too engrossed in your research on Scotch as a cure for aging, don't you think you'd better phone Elaine's and cancel our dinner reservations?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUPERT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would we do without you, Carla? Without our little efficiency expert, Carla, everything would just go to hell. Carla is thinking about running for mayor next year, aren't you, Carla?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up yours, Herr Doktor Book Salesman. Will the demands of your medical practice allow you to call Elaine's or shall I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sissy is intrigued by an antique here and an object d'art there, but she knows she is in an alien environment.</context>
      <utterance>Oh let me do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she blacks out. And the sound drifts away in waves, so there is only the whistle of a distant wind through the mortar of the apartment building... ...Until one by one, we see button necks freed. Soon Sissy can feel it. Someone is undressing her. In a voice webby with sleep she lifts her head up, and sees Howard and Marie.</context>
      <utterance>No Indian blankets... no Indian blankets...</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the others?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Rupert and Carla had a little hassle and went home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julian fell asleep on the couch; we covered him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy thinks this is nice, but wonders, however, why they are both in their underwear.</context>
      <utterance>We thought that we should make you comfortable too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Between the two of them, they have gotten Sissy out of her dress in no time. Sissy feels she should apologize for not having on a brassiere. Marie slips out of her own brassiere and moves her bare bosom close to Sissy's.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine are fuller but yours are more perfectly shaped.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Howard cups his left hand about a Marie breast and his right about one of Sissy's. He weighs them in his palms, squeezes them the way an honest grocer squeezes excess water from a lettuce, and spreads his fingers to sample their circumference.</context>
      <utterance>Highly debatable. I'll wager they're the exact same size.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm. Yours are larger, Marie, but Miss Hankshaw's -- Sissy's -- are more firm. You'd think they would have started to droop; I mean, from not wearing a bra.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marie seizes Sissy's free breast, quickly, like a monkey picking a fruit, rolling it about in her hungry little finger, rubbing it against her chin and cheeks... ...and... ...it was like her earlier days as a hitchhiker.... nostalgic..... tropical plums.</context>
      <utterance>Howard! Watch your manners. You've made her blush. Here, Sissy, let me compare.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this is what it's like... so this is what it's really like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julian and Sissy embrace and go at it under the covers But suddenly: Julian stops after a brief climax.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Sissy. I am sorry about all the fuss.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy cradles Julian and comforts him.</context>
      <utterance>I apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy sits up, her eyes moping about the apartment, looking but not seeing the macrame wallhangings, the volumes of Robert Frost.</context>
      <utterance>It is the measure of Western Civilization that it can encompass in harmony, balance off, as it were, such divergent masterworks as A MIDSUMMER NIGHT'S DREAM and THE AMERICAN DREAM, as the dome of the Sistine Chapel and the ceiling of the Paris opera.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a while Sissy answers.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. I'll turn down the air conditioner.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy gets out of bed and begins to dress.</context>
      <utterance>It's not the air conditioner that's making me cold. Nothing moves in here. Not even your birds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting dressed. I've got to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't want you to leave. Please stay. We can go to dinner. I owe you a dinner. And tonight... we can... really make love.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go, Julian.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Why do you have to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My thumbs hurt. I've made a mistake. I've been negligent. I haven't exercised. I have to hitchhike a little bit every day, no matter what. It's like a musician practicing his scales. When I don't practice, my timing gets off, my thumbs get stiff and sore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will hitch with you, out where tall birds wade in a lake named for my Siwash kin. Out where Smokey the Bear lay down his shovel to romp with more playful beasts. Out where starlight has no enemies and the badland wind no friends. Out where the boogie stops and the woogie begins.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julian is on the other end of the phone.</context>
      <utterance>So she left town. Well, that shouldn't surprise you. Leaving town is what Sissy is all about. But tell me, how did she strike you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Extraordinary!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's obviously that. Jesus! Which would you rather have, a million dollars or one of Sissy's thumbs full of pennies?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you! I'm not talking about her hands. They're difficult to ignore, I confess, but I'm speaking of her whole being. Her whole being is extraordinary. The way she talks, for example. She's so articulate.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's high time you realized, honey babe, that a woman doesn't have to give the best years of her life to Radcliffe or Smith in order to speak the English language.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Countess. I'm really in a dither. She's turned my head.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ninety degrees to the left, I hope. How does she feel about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she's disappointed that I'm not more, ah, sort of atavistic. She's got some naive, sentimental notions about Indians. I'm sure she liked me, though; but.... then she left town.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julian pauses for a very long moment.</context>
      <utterance>She always leaves town, you dummy. That doesn't mean anything. What about in bed? How does she like it in bed?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does she like what in bed?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Countess' teeth chatter in his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well.... er...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit O dear, Julian. Do you mean to tell me you didn't get it on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we didn't get it all the way on.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose fault was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose it was mine. Yes, it definitely was my fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do they do to you boys in those Ivy league schools, anyway? Strap you down and pump the Nature out of you? They can even press the last drop of Nature out of a Mohawk buck. Why, send a shaman or cannibal to Yale for four years and all he'd be fit for would be a desk in the military-industrial complex and a seat in the third row at a Neil Simon comedy. Jesus H.M.S. Christ! If Harvard or Princeton could get hold of the Chink for a couple of semesters they'd turn him into a candidate for the Bow Tie Wing of the Hall of Wimps. Oogie boogie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we Ivy Leaguers aren't earthy enough to suit you hillbillies, at least we don't go around indulging in racist terms such as 'Chink.' Next thing I know, you'll be calling me 'chief.'</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chink's the guy's name, for Christ's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, he's some old fart holyman who lives in the hills out West. Gives my ranch the creeps and the willies, too. But though he be old and dirty, he's alive, I'll bet, clear down to his toes. They don't have his juice in a jar in New Haven. Well I suppose that I'll have to write Sissy out on the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a pilgrim?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm more of an Indian The trio doesn't smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She means are you going to see the Chink?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I may and I may not. But seeing him is not my main objective out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good. Because he won't see you. We came all the way from Minneapolis to see him and the crazy bastard tried to stone us to death</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy walks on leaving the people in the bus arguing about whether the Chink's rock-shower and pecker-wag actually had been intended as spiritual messages.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I no longer believe that guy's a master. He's just a dirty, uptight old mountain man. Why, he pulled out his pecker and shook it at Barbara. I'd stay away from there if I were you, lady.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By any chance are you Sissy Hankshaw?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A chic middle-aged woman leans out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gloria nods at Sissy amicably but doesn't make a move to help her. Sissy swings her sack into the roomy vehicle. Before she gets in she flashes her thumb to hitch a ride. The instant that Sissy shuts the door the cowgirl chauffeur floors the Cadillac and it lurches away in a puff of dust.</context>
      <utterance>My goodness. Why didn't you telephone? Someone would have driven into Mottburg to pick you up. I'm Miss Adrian. From the ranch. The Countess wrote that I should expect you. Get in, won't you? You must be exhausted. Gloria, assist Miss Hankshaw with her luggage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little twit.  You really ought to have phoned. We were just in Mottburg escorting some guests to the afternoon train.  More guests leaving ahead of schedule. Three checked out today. They decided to transfer to Elizabeth Arden's Maine Chance spa in Phoenix, Arizona. It costs two hundred and fifty dollars a week less at the Rubber Rose, so why are our guests leaving and going to Elizabeth Arden's? Miss Adrian pushes a button that sends a partition glass between her and the cowgirl driver. Gloria starts laughing silently on the other side of the glass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you why, it's that plague of cowgirls. They've gradually infiltrated every sector of our program. The one named Debbie considers herself an expert on exercising and diet. With Bonanza Jellybean's permission and against my explicit orders, she's been coercing the guests into trying something called kundalini yoga. Do you know what that is? It's trying to mentally force a serpent of fire to crawl up your spinal column. Miss Hankshaw, our guests can't comprehend kundalini yoga, let alone do it. Yesterday, she ordered a new cookbook by a Tibetan Negro, entitled Third Eye in the Kitchen: Himalayan Soul Food. God knows what that will be like. The little barbarians are destroying everything that I've built, mocking all that the company stands for. And there's a new one, one they call del Ruby. She has the good will of a scorpion. I've considered it prudent to avoid a confrontation that might further upset the guests. But now that the season is practically over -- we operate April through September -- and the Countess is finally coming...</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our Ranch has all the latest in modern facilities...</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a facial wing, and next to that is the Hair Barn...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The receptionist hands Miss Adrian a key to Sissy's room. A COWGIRL makes a face at Sissy as she walks by carrying a tray of herbal teas. A representative of the film crew is being intimidated by a Cowgirl who is looking though his camera lenses and shaking them and listening to them like you would put a shell up to your ear to hear the ocean.</context>
      <utterance>Our special guest Miss Sissy Hankshaw is with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>COWGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another cowgirl, BIG RED, is lifting a piece of furniture and passes it to her accomplice.</context>
      <utterance>Cool! We're going to make a movie!...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miss Adrian looks on helplessly.... she grabs Sissy and leads her out of the lobby.</context>
      <utterance>Get rid of the furniture.... it's too masculine... Get rid of all the furniture and use it for kindling!!! Break away from these pig-like chauvinist masculine influences....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the FILM CREW MEMBERS is hanging out in the corral wearing a shiny jacket with DISNEY printed on the back. Miss Adrian grabs him by the shoulders and shakes him.</context>
      <utterance>O merciful Jesus! They're murdering the guests!</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the guests?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy, lady. They went on a short ride with the cowgirls. Rode over the hill yonder. You're Miss Adrian, aren't you? We need to talk to you about the filming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another CAMERAMAN spits out a wad of chewing gum.</context>
      <utterance>Not now, you fool, not now. Those crazed bitches have led innocent women out and are slaughtering them at this moment. We'll all be killed. Oh! Ohhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a slaughter going on all right, but it's not the fat ladies that are getting it. Your hired hands are killing the cattle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cattle? They're killing the cows? All of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A devilish young cowgirl is sitting on a fence nearby. Miss Adrian addresses her.</context>
      <utterance>That's what they said, Miss Adrian.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How dare you slaughter the Countess's cattle! What is a ranch without cows?</utterance>
   <speaker>COWGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to replace them with goats. Most of the cattle are diseased and in pain. We're just putting them out of their misery. According to Bon-an-za Jellybean, the Rubber Rose is in-di-cat-ive of the Countess's values. He has purchased a cheap weak strain of cow to begin with and with improper care....</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh heavens! I don't want to hear what Bonanza Jellybean has been telling you girls.... Come on Sissy. I'll show you to your quarters.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy sits up and rubs her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Miss. Do you care for your breakfast now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Maid puts the tray down, and the cloth that covers the food is lifted away to reveal a shocking display of grease and calories. A vase of prairie asters stands over a double-meat cheeseburger, a package of Hostess Twinkies, a cold can of Dr. Pepper and a Three Musketeers bar. Sissy is delighted.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I feel a bit hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Road food. How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it is a change of our usual grapefruit and melba toast, I'm sure. Sissy notices a card. It reads: Compliments of Bonanza Jellybean</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bonanza Jellybean....</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy devours her meal. Out her window she can see women on exercycles, women doing jumping jacks and women in beauty parlors. A FIST pounds on Sissy's door. IN SAILS Jelly, a cowgirl so cute she makes Sissy blush just to look at her. She wears a tan Stetson with an aster pinned to it, a green satin shirt embroidered with rearing stallions snorting orange fire from their nostrils. Her breasts bounce like dinner rolls that have gotten loaded on helium and, between red tinged cheeks, where more baby fat is taking its time maturing, she has a little smile that can cause minerals and plastics to remember their ancient animate connections. Jelly grasps Sissy's elbow and sits on the side of the bed.</context>
      <utterance>She will be up to see you directly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome, podner. By God, it's great to have you here. It's an honor. Sorry I took so long getting to you, but we've had a mess of hard work these past few days -- and a heap of planning to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Er, you seem to know who I am, and maybe even what I am. Thanks for the breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy sets her tray on the bedside table.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I know about Sissy Hankshaw, all right. I've done a little hitchhiking myself. Ah shucks, that's like telling Annie Oakley you're a sharpshooter because you once knocked a tomato can off a stump with a fieldstone. I'd heard tales about you from people I'd meet in jail cells and truckstops. I heard about your, uh, your, ah, your wonderful thumbs, and I heard how you were Jack Kerouac's girl friend...</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm afraid that part isn't true. Jack was in awe of me and tracked me down. We spent a night talking and hugging in a corn field, but he was hardly my lover. Besides, I always travel alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guests are huffing and puffing in between the pauses in conversation, in the background through the window in Sissy's room.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that doesn't matter; that part never interested me anyway. The beatnicks were before my time, and I never got anything outta the hippies but bad dope, clichs and the clap. But the example of your life helped me in my struggle to be a cowgirl.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About...</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About being a cowgirl. What's it all about? When you say the word you make it sound like it was painted in radium on the side of a pearl.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jelly lays her hand atop the oval mound Sissy's thumb makes under the covers.</context>
      <utterance>Cowgirls exist as an image. A fairly common image. The idea of cowgirls especially for little girls prevails in our culture. Therefore, it seems to me, the existence of cowgirls should prevail. Otherwise, they're being fooled. In the Rodeo Hall of Fame in Oklahoma City there are just two cowgirls. Two. And both of 'em are trick-riders. Trick-riding is what cowgirls have almost always done in rodeos. Our society sure likes to see its unconventional women do tricks. That's what prostitutes call it, you know: 'tricking.'</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're political, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment when the two girls feel something between each other.</context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am. No way. There's girls on the Rubber Rose who are political, but I don't share their views. I got no cowgirl ideology to expound. "Politics is for people who have a passion for changing life but lack a passion for living it."</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did that last comment sound too profound to be coming outta my mouth? It's not original. It's something I picked up from the Chink.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? The Chink, huh? I've gathered that you sometimes speak with him. What else have you learned from the Chink?</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jelly pauses.</context>
      <utterance>Learned from the Chink? Oh my. Ha ha. That's hard to say. We mostly.... Uh, a lot of his talk is pretty goofy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy's thumb twitches. Jelly swallows hard. They gaze into each other's eyes. A WHISTLE pierces the sunlight outside the window.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, now that I think of it, the Chink taught me something about cowgirls. Did you realize that cowgirls have been around for many centuries? Long before America. In ancient India the care of the cattle was always left up to young women they called gopis. Being alone with the cows all the time, the gopis got awfully horny, just like we do here. Every gopi was in love with Krishna, a good-looking young god who played the flute like it was going out of style When the moon was full, this Krishna would play his flute by a river and call the gopis to him. Then he would multiply himself sixteen thousand times -- one for each gopi -- and make love to each one the way she most desired. There they were, sixteen thousand gopis balling Krishna on the river bank, and the energy of their merging was so great that it created a huge oneness, a total union of love, and it was God. Wow! Quite a picture, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jelly walks to the window and exchanges hand signals with someone outside.</context>
      <utterance>That couldn't be Krishna, could it? A bit shrill for a flute. Just our rotten luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jelly spins her six-shooter in her kewpie fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta run now. Delores says I'm needed. Somebody's here. Maybe it's the Countess.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holsters her gun and blows Sissy a kiss, then is gone out the door. Sissy hops out of bed and from the window she can see cowgirls gathering in a circle. Someone or something is in the center of the circle. Sissy zips herself into a red jumpsuit and hurries outside.</context>
      <utterance>Sissy, cowgirl history is about to be made. I'm damn glad you're here to witness it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cute. Way cuter than a cow.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goats are always testing you. They're like Zen masters. They can tell instantly if you're faking your feelings. So they play games with you to keep you true. People should go to goats instead of psychiatrists.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gloria cuts in on Debbie and gives the beast a hug.</context>
      <utterance>It's so loving.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at those playfully wise eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooo! It licked me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses and looks around the group in the circle.</context>
      <utterance>More and more people are discovering that cow's milk isn't fit for human consumption. Billy West says if we can produce enough goat's milk on the ranch to make it worth his while, he'll run it into Fargo regularly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hurt, Sissy leaves the group.</context>
      <utterance>I'm aware that Tad Lucas rode broncs until her ninth month, but I don't think pregnant cowgirls are going to be any asset on this ranch. I hope you itchy clits who are sneaking down to the lake every night are taking precautions. It's bad enough we've got cranes coming; we don't need storks. I feel that those film makers should be removed from the Rubber Rose as soon as possible. Men can cause nothing but trouble here. I also feel that our guest  should be excused while we discuss this matter further.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>......Delores zonks out on peyote at least once a week, but so far her Third Vision hasn't happened. Niwetkame, the Mother Goddess has not gotten back in touch with her. Meanwhile she and Debbie are rivaling each other like a couple of crosstown high schools. Tension. Cowgirl tension! What a drag.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is Debbie's position?</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Debbie says that if women are to take charge again, they must do it in the feminine way; they mustn't resort to aggressive and violent masculine methods. She says it is up to women to show themselves better than men, to love men, set good examples for them and guide them tenderly toward the New Age. She's a real dreamer, that Debbie-dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't agree with Debbie, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jelly takes Sissy's hand, carefully avoiding the thumbs and helps her feel the depression in her belly. The depression is a dimple, like another navel. AFTER A HUNGRY STILLNESS, like intermission at a wolf dance, rhythms are established. Jelly and Sissy are socked into one another now, and they arch and push and corkscrew and jackknife softly but with pronounced cadence. Everything becomes scrambled. They rock each other in cradles of sweat and saliva, until we can see nothing. Noisy breaths buck out of Sissy: "Jelly, Jelly" but she can't hear Sissy because she is screaming. Hysterical from the scalding hot softness of girl-love.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't say that. I expect she's right, ultimately. But I'm with Delores when it comes to fighting for what's mine. I can't understand why Delores is so uptight about the Chink; he could probably teach her a thing or two. Ee! That grass tickles, doesn't it? God knows I love women, but nothing can take the place of a man that fits. Still this is cowgirl territory and I'll stand with Delores and fight any bastards who might deny it. I guess I've always been a scrapper. Look. This scar. Only twelve years old and I was felled by a silver bullet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sure enough across the yard, in the midst of the low-cal barbecue in progress, monocle reflecting sunlight, cigarette holder stabbing the air, stands the Countess.</context>
      <utterance>He's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at him. Perverse as a pink pickle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sick as a vice squad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jellybean chuckles sardonically and dismounts.</context>
      <utterance>He's in a snit. He wants to see you right after the barbecue.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy, confused, and loyalties torn in the face of an impending revolution, leaves the corral and</context>
      <utterance>Get the girls. He's gonna see me right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any of you ladies who would like to join us, you're welcome to stay on as a full working podner at the Rubber Rose. Rest of you get packed -- and I mean now. You've got fifteen minutes to move your lard asses off this ranch.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSIDE THE EXERCISE ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Women are reacting to the demands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INSIDE THE KITCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The help is joining the revolt.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSIDE THE HALLWAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Other women are running for their lives.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You pathetic little cutesy-poos. Do you actually suppose this exhibition of childlike melodrama is advancing the cause of freedom?</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You owe us this here ranch, as a token payment for your disgusting exploitations</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hands, who carry axes, picks, pitchforks and shovels, retreat. The Countess, still grinning, reaches for an hors d'oeuvre and subjects his cigarette to a measured, self- assured puff.</context>
      <utterance>Go for it, girls!</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to your bunkhouse and remain there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better reach for your spray cans!</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rather pale, his nose twitching, the Countess drops the caviar canap he has been holding. ON COME THE COWGIRLS, pelvises pumping, laying down what the trembling Countess believes to be a devastating barrage of musk. Miss Adrian, lost in her own hysteria, charges. A barbeque fork she hurls draws blood from Heather's eyebrow. Quick as a frog's tongue, Delores's whip cracks. It's lash curls around the ranch manager's ankles, pulling her feet from under her. She hits the sod in a jangle of jewelry and expulsion of breath. A Molotov cocktail thrown by Big Red says hello to the sexual reconditioning building. Within seconds, the structure is blazing.</context>
      <utterance>Not one of these pussies has been washed in a week!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AND THERE HE IS. Standing only ten yards away. The Chink's problem is that he looks like he rolled out of a Zen scroll, as if he says "presto" a lot, knows the meaning of lightning and the origin of dreams. He LOOKS as if he drinks dew and fucks snakes. Sissy and the Chink scrutinize one another with mutual fascination.</context>
      <utterance>Ha ha ho ho hee hee.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy is just about to speak, but before she does THE CHINK whirls, and scampers up the mountainside.</context>
      <utterance>Ha ha ho ho and hee hee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warily he stops and turns, poised to flee again. Sissy smiles. SHE RAISES her ripe right thumb. And jerking it and swooshing it, she hitchhikes the Chink and his mountain. THERE HE STANDS where Sissy's thumbs have stopped him. The Chink wears the wary look of a wild animal. He's not going to stay stopped long. It is Sissy's move.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chink pauses for a moment, then he slaps his thighs and giggles hysterically. Ha has, ho hos and hee hees squirt out of his nose and through the gaps in his teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Well, aren't you going to shake your whanger at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE TWO doggedly walk up the steep trail.</context>
      <utterance>Follow me. I'll fix you supper.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a friend of Bonanza Jellybean's.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? Well, there's been some trouble on the ranch. I came up here to get out of the way. It's so dark now I doubt if I could find my way back down. If you could help...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arms swimming, feet firecrackering, he dances and dances. When the song ends, the Chink puts the radio down as the news comes on.</context>
      <utterance>Yip! Yip! Ha ha ho ho and hee hee.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chink dances a little to the news, and then lifts Sissy by her shoulders and guides her onto his pock-marked dance floor.</context>
      <utterance>Personally, I prefer Stevie Wonder, but what the hell. Those cowgirls are always bitching because the only radio station in the area plays nothing but polkas, but I say you can dance to anything if you really feel like dancing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't know how to polka.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The radio strikes up the "Lawrence Welk is a Hero of the Republic Polka," and the Chink and Sissy dance arm in arm, their shadows reel against the curves of the depression in the mountain. Night birds fly past with fluttering feathers. A bat flies out of the cave. The Chink escorts Sissy to a dark side of the depression and sits her down upon a pile of soft stuff: dried wheatgrass, faded Indian blankets and old down pillows without cases.</context>
      <utterance>Neither do I... ha ha ho ho hee hee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clockworks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chink pauses to decide whether he should talk any further, then proceeds.</context>
      <utterance>Clockworks?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Clockworks is one reason that I am here on Siwash Ridge. I accepted the invitation to be initiated as a shaman by an aged Siwash chief who was the principle outside confederate of the Clock People.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Siwash, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy cradles her head in her arms, but is startled by a louder noise from the clockworks. The Chink is startled too. Bonk! sounds the cave, and then it chimes poing! The Chink smiles at the noise coming from his clockworks.</context>
      <utterance>He was a degenerated warlock who could turn urine into beer, and the honor that he extended me gave me rights of occupancy in this sacred cave on this far-away Siwash Ridge. I came to the Dakota hills to construct a clockworks of my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But unlike the clockworks of the Clock People, my ticks more accurately echo the ticks of the universe....  ......ha ha ho ho and hee hee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Clock People?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>During the Second World War I busted out of Tule Lake detention camp; as a Japanese-American, I had been put there and watched over. I found refuge with the Clock People, who discovered me in a snow bank, near dead, I had been climbing across the Sierra Nevada mountains.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then if you are Japanese, then why are you called the Chink?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Clock People mistook me for Chinese. And the name stuck. In the same way that all Indian tribes came to be labeled "Indians" through the ignorance of an Italian sailor with a taste for oranges, it is only fitting that "Indians" misnamed me. The Clock People, however, are not a tribe, rather they are a gathering of Indians from various tribes. They have lived together since 1906.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chink holds Sissy's thumbs in his hands adoringly.</context>
      <utterance>These people have no other ritual than this one. Likewise, they have but one legend or cultural myth: that of a continuum they call the Eternity of Joy. It is into the Eternity of Joy that they believe all men will pass once the clockworks is destroyed. The destruction must come from the outside, must come by natural means, must come at the will of this gesticulating planet whose more acute stirrings thoughtless people call "earthquakes."</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy interrupts the Chink for a second while he is worshipping her thumbs.</context>
      <utterance>The Earth is alive. She burns inside with the heat of cosmic longing. She longs to be with her husband again. She moans. She turns softly in her sleep. In the Eternity of Joy, pluralized, deurbanized man, at ease with his gentle technologies, will smile and sigh when the Earth begins to shake. I loved those loony redskins, but I couldn't be a party to their utopian dreaming. After a while it occurred to me that the Clock People waiting for the Eternity of Joy was virtually identical to the Christians waiting for the Second Coming. Or the Communists waiting for the worldwide revolution. Or the Debbies waiting for the flying saucers. All the same. Just more suckers betting their share of the present on the future, banking every misery on a happy ending to history. Well, history is ending every second - happily for some of us, unhappily for others, happily one second, unhappily the next. History is always ending and always not ending... ha ha ho ho and hee hee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you believe in then?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he says nothing. And his silence makes Sissy weep. They sit down on a grass floor, illuminated by the fire outside the cave. Then the Chink, without hesitation, grasps her thumbs. He squeezes them, caresses them, covers them with wet kisses, telling them how beautiful they are. Sissy is bowled over, frightened, stunned, elated, moved almost to tears. Sissy bends her head back and whispers.</context>
      <utterance>Ha ha ho ho and hee hee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as the Chink plunges into Sissy, she arches her spread bottom against the blankets and rears up to meet him halfway. Their bodies glowing in the firelight, they cast shadows of ANCIENT BEINGS, anthropomorphs making love through the night under the moon.</context>
      <utterance>If this be adultery, make the most of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sissy, don't play dumb with me! You're a good model but a shitty actress. The cowgirls are involved in this whooping crane disappearance. You know perfectly well they are. Last seen in Nebraska. Didn't make it to Canada. Siwash Lake is between Nebraska and Canada. The cowgirls have possession of Siwash Lake. And who else but Jellybean's wild cunts could possibly conceive of doing something so diabolical as to tamper with the last flock of some nearly extinct birds? How much do you know about it? Have they murdered those cranes the way they murdered my moo cows?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know anything about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy strikes the Countess with her right thumb -- with astonishing force. Immediately the thumb strikes again, this time shattering the Countess's monocle against his eye.</context>
      <utterance>Sissy. You're trying to protect those scuzzy bitches. Well, let your conscience be your guide, as my mommy used to say, but it won't work. Those stinking sluts are going to suffer...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COUNTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HIS DENTURES fall onto the shag rug. The left thumb strikes. Sissy is swinging her thumbs like ballbats socking flaming homers over the left-field fence. The countess is out on his feet. His eyes are closed. His legs wobble. He does a pathetic dance, like a drunken old fool trying to boogie with a chorus girl. He topples forward and meets Sissy's onrushing thumb of thunder which straightens him up, sends him over backward. Motionless, he lies on the floor, a crimson part in his thinning hair, a bright ooze at each nostril.</context>
      <utterance>Shit O dear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he's not out of danger, but I think we can safely say he's going to make it. I'd be pretty surprised if he didn't. However, there is evidence of injury to the frontal lobe, and I have reason to fear that this injury may be permanent. The patient may never again function as a normal human being.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brain damage? You mean he's going to be a vegetable?</utterance>
   <speaker>SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vegetable? Vegetable? I wouldn't say that, no. We won't ascertain the extent of the injury for some days. But there is a genuine possibility of severe and lasting behavioral defects. I wouldn't classify it in the vegetable category, however.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DR. DREYFUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I can't help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREYFUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, child, don't be dismayed. We all have problems these days. But as the painter Van Gogh said, 'Mysteries remain, sorrow or melancholy remains, but the everlasting negative is balanced by the positive work which thus is achieved, after all.' I don't suppose that means very much to you. I have retired. A victim of a malpractice suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In her embrace, the Doctor is presented with her thumbs.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Doctor! You've got to do it. You and nobody else should be allowed to take away my gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. DREYFUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LATER sitting inside his study, Dreyfus muses.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, the thumb.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. DREYFUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>The thumb the thumb the thumb the thumb the thumb the thumb. One of evolution's most ingenious inventions; a built-in tool sensitive to texture, contour and temperature: an alchemical lever; the secret key to technology; the link between the mind and art; a humanizing device. The marmoset and the lemur are thumbless; none of the New World monkeys has opposable thumbs; the spider monkey's thumbs are absent or reduced to a tiny tubercle; the thumbs of the potto are set at an angle of one hundred eighty degrees to the other digits.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. DREYFUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And so you are demanding at last the privileges of thumb that nature has perversely denied you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to be normal, give me that old-fashioned normality. It was good enough for Crazy Horse and it's good enough for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. DREYFUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VIEWS OF Sissy admitted to a hospital Blood analyzed in a laboratory. Powerful lamps turn on in an operating room. IV tubes are inserted in veins. Sissy is wheeled into surgery. An anesthesiologist sticks a needle into a curved and creamy ass. An anesthesiologist sticks needles into a long, graceful neck. A nurse scrubs an arm. A body and table are draped with sheets to create a sterile field. A tourniquet is placed on a slender right arm. An elastic rubber bandage is applied so tightly it squeezes most of the blood out of an arm. A tourniquet is inflated. A surgeon outlines in iodine an incision around the base of a thumb. Pale smooth skin is incised along a premarked line and dissected down to the bone. Woman flesh is sewn shut with four-ought nylon suture. A tourniquet is deflated, a bloody arm bathed. A young woman is rolled into a recovery room. A nurse and two surgeons, their attention directed by an intensifying pinkish glow, turn to stare into a metal pan, where a huge human thumb, disarticulated from the hand it has been severed from, is now flopping about like a trout, or rather, arching and thrusting itself in a calculated and endlessly repeated gesture, the gesture of the hitchhike.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, yes. Very well, my dear. Here is what we can do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep, the whooping cranes are here all right. They're in fine shape, and as you musta saw from your fucking whirly machine, unrestrained, free to go as they please. But this is private property and you aren't laying a foot on it. None of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be back with a court order and a fistful of search warrants.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just come back with a couple of people who know what they're doing and we'll let'em in for a nice close look at the birds.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AND OVER THE AIRWAVES an announcement is broadcast.</context>
      <utterance>And make sure at least one of them is female, and you better do as we say or there may be trouble.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>UNDERSECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will be my extreme pleasure to report to the President...</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDERSECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...who has been gravely concerned about the fate of our whooping cranes....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>UNDERSECRETARY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd cheers.</context>
      <utterance>...Siwash Lake and in apparently healthy condition.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDERSECRETARY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>....The cranes have built brooding nests around the whole circumference of the small lake, and have...</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDERSECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>....hatched chicks there. Counting the young birds, there are now approximately sixty cranes in the flock. While this is good news, it is also quite bewildering...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PROGRESS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sissy recognizes the voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Jellybean!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kym ropes the radio to her saddle horn and prepares to give it a ride across the Dakota hills. She gets on her horse and rides by the Ranch bungalows and spies Sissy sitting in the outhouse.</context>
      <utterance>Man, this is the stupidest music I've ever heard. This radio should have stayed in the privy where it belongs.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kym gets off her horse and hugs Sissy.</context>
      <utterance>Howdy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what you're getting into if you come over to the lake...</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THEY RIDE ACROSS THE HILLS. Then they stop at an outlook and Sissy sees the circular barricade in the field below.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but I want to be there. I want to see Jellybean. I want to see the cranes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We heard on the radio that the judge has set Delores's bail at fifty thousand dollars. Now she won't be here when we really need her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RADIO NEWS REPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SISSY RIDES INTO CAMP on the back of Kym's horse the way that John Wayne would have ridden into the Alamo; Heather, Bonanza Jellybean, Debbie, Elaine and Linda dance up to meet her. Before Sissy is completely on the ground, Jelly's tongue is in her mouth. She stumbles out of a stirrup into a wiggly embrace.</context>
      <utterance>The American Civil Liberties Union has requested an extension for the Rubber Rose Ranch. The government is aware of the inflamed situation and are afraid that all the marshals and agents might be too willing to uncork the bottle of blood...</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Debbie stokes up a big joint right now, as Jelly gets out her six guns and fires them in the air. Heather twirls and jumps through her rope. The "Unsung Hero Returns Polka" strikes up on the radio. Elaine rears up on her horse.</context>
      <utterance>Let's celebrate!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But as the Agent is saying this, viewing them from the ridge, a large rock tumbles down the hill and grazes his head, knocking him out. VIEW of the side of the ridge from where the rock came, but there is strangely nothing where we expect to see the Chink. BELOW: The cowgirls.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't that just like women.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like every time we get together things are in a mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So be it. It looks serious this time, though. All these guns... are you actually prepared to kill and die for whooping cranes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell no, the cranes are wonderful, okay, but I'm not in this for whooping cranes. I'm in it for cowgirls. If we cowgirls give in to authority on this crane issue, then cowgirls become just another compromise. I want a finer fate than that -- for me and for every other cowgirl. Better no cowgirls at all than cowgirls compromised.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did this business get started, anyhow? Why are the birds nesting here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were aware that we were feeding them, weren't you? We fed them brown rice and they stayed over a couple of extra days. Then we decided to try something different. We mixed our brown rice with fishmeal -- whoopers love seafood, and fishmeal is cheap. Then Delores suggested another ingredient, and we think that's what did the trick.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're drugged.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy frames the flock with the hole in the center of her cheese sandwich.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, come off it, Sissy. What do you mean, 'drugged'? Every living thing is a chemical composition and anything that is added to it changes that composition. When you eat a cheeseburger or a Three Musketeers bar, it changes your body chemistry. The kind of food you eat, the kind of air you breathe, can change your mental state. Does that mean you're 'drugged'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I guess not.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Drugged' is a stupid word.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the peyote is obviously affecting their brains. It's made them break a migratory pattern that goes back thousands of years.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The way I see it, is that the peyote mellowed them out. Made them less uptight. They were afraid of bad weather and humans. That's why they migrated and kept to themselves. But the peyote has enlightened them. It's taught them there is nothing to fear but fear itself. Now they're digging life and letting the bad vibes slide on. Don't worry, be happy. Be here now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear in wild animals is completely different from paranoia in people. In the wilderness ecosystem, fear is natural and necessary. It's merely a mechanism for maintaining life. If the cranes hadn't had a capacity for fear, they would have disappeared long ago and you'd be having to get loaded with common old everyday meadowlarks and mallards.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Sissy and Jelly hear a news broadcast on the radio.</context>
      <utterance>This here discussion is destined to become academic. Because we've got less than half a bag of peyote buttons left and Delores's run ended up in the Mottburg jail. So any day now we'll get a chance to see how the whoopers behave when they come down, to see if the peyote experience really changed them or not. But in the meantime, I want to say this about fear.....</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judge Greenfield, at the request of the ACLU, has granted a forty-eight- hour extension of the deadline by which the Rubber Rose cowgirls must comply with his order. Negotiations between the cowgirls and the government are expected to follow. Another item in, the forewoman of the Rubber Rose Ranch, a Delores del Ruby is now free on bond after having been arrested in Mottburg with more than fifty pounds of peyote buttons. Her bail has been paid by the owner of the besieged ranch, Countess Products, Inc. Miss del Ruby's bail having come from the tycoon's personal advisor, a certain Dr. Robbins of New York City.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Robbins?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every time I tell you that I love you, you flinch. But that's your problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I flinch when you say you love me, it's both our problems. My confusion becomes your confusion. Students confuse teachers, patients confuse psychiatrists, lovers with confused hearts confuse lovers with clear hearts....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delores cracks her whip then parades around the campfire.</context>
      <utterance>It isn't for ourselves that we take this stand. It isn't for cowgirls. It's for all the daughters everywhere. This is an extremely important confrontation. This is womankind's chance to prove to her enemy that she's willing to fight and die. If we women don't show here and now that we aren't afraid to fight and die, then our enemy will never take us seriously. Men will always know that, no matter how strong our words and determined our deeds, there's a point where we'll back down and give them their way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few of the cowgirls cheer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm prepared to win! Victory for every female, living or dead, who's suffered the temporary defeats of masculine insensitivity to their inner lives!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Red opens a can of beans with a Bowie knife.</context>
      <utterance>I'll fight the bastards.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delores snaps her whip again.</context>
      <utterance>I'll fight 'em with bean gas, if necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sun's going down. Let's those of us not standing watch get some sleep. In the morning we'll plan our fight. Tomorrow afternoon those of you who'd like can join me in the reeds, where the cranes and I will be sharing the last crumbs left in the peyote sack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delores holds up a card. The prairie moon illuminates its tattered edges. It is the jack of hearts. The forewoman seems to be tiring. Fumes of weariness stream from her black hair. Her voice is leaning against the wall of her larynx when she says:</context>
      <utterance>It is woman's mission to destroy as well as to give birth. We will destroy the tyranny of the dull. But we can't destroy it with guns. Or whips. Violence is the dullard's Breakfast of Champions and the logical end product of his or her misplaced pride. Violence fertilizes that which we would starve. No, we will destroy the enemy in other ways. The Peyote Mother has promised a Fourth Vision. But it won't come to me alone. It will come to each of you, to every cowgirl in the land, when you have overcome that in your own self which is dull. The Fourth Vision will come to some men too. You will recognize them when you meet them, and be their steady sidekicks in equal and ecstatic escapades of poetic behavior and romance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As graceful as a ballet for cobras, Delores turns and walks away into the night.</context>
      <utterance>First thing, you must end this business with the government and the cranes. It's been positive and fruitful, but it's gone far enough. Playfulness ceases to serve a serious purpose when it takes itself too seriously. Sorry I won't be with you at the conclusion. As you know, I've been sick and stupid for a long time. I have a lot to make up for, a lot to accomplish, and there's someone important that I've got to see. Now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Small protests from the circle of cowgirls.</context>
      <utterance>Well, what we got to do is one of us has got to go up that hill and tell them boys that America can have its whooping cranes back. Since I'm the boss here, and since I'm responsible for a lot of you choosing to be cowgirls in the first place, it's gonna be me that goes...</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cutest cowgirl in the world stood up and stretched out.</context>
      <utterance>No buts about it. It's getting lighter by the second. You podners keep your heads down. Ta ta.</utterance>
   <speaker>COWGIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Jelly is already on her way. BONANZA JELLYBEAN VAULTS over the carcass of a reducing machine and plants her Tony Lama boots in the stirrup of her saddle and straddles her horse and takes off.</context>
      <utterance>Jelly! Please!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THROUGH the scope of an FBI rifle, Jelly is drawing her gun out of her holster.</context>
      <utterance>Better get rid of these. Might give those greenhorn dudes a fright.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He squeezes the trigger, and Jelly is caught in the stomach with a bullet. She falls off her horse to the ground. THE CHINK sees Bonanza Jellybean cut down from a vantage point on the hill, and makes a beeline for the government barricades, SHOUTING. THE COWGIRLS scream and cry, and grab their weapons. A couple of them leap from the barricade and are immediately riddled.</context>
      <utterance>She's going to fire....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RANDOM G-MEN are sniping at the cowgirls, making it impossible to surrender. A stray bullet SENDS THE CHINK back down the hillside, beard, robe and sandals flying. IN THE HUSH that follows, in the echoes of the explosive fire, the whooping crane flock rises in one grand assault of beating feathers - a lily white storm of life, a gush of albino Gabriels -- swarm into the waiting sky, and circle the pond one time before flapping south toward Texas... ...they cast shadows over a dead Jellybean who is literally biting the dust. Sissy lifts Jelly out of the dust and holds her. Sissy lifts Jelly's satin shirt tail and pulls down the waistband of her skirt. Bright red blood is running out of her scar.</context>
      <utterance>You've got two minutes to come out with you hands over your heads!</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Confessing to Sissy.</context>
      <utterance>Right in the scar where I fell on a wooden horse when I was twelve. Haw, I wasn't really shot with a silver bullet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or was I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>1944-1973</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A brown paper bag is sitting on the side of the road.</context>
      <utterance>"Ha ha ho ho and hee hee" Title card: The brown paper bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>A VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>View of a bunkhouse trunk.</context>
      <utterance>The brown paper bag is the only thing civilized man has produced that does not seem out of place in nature. Crumpled into a wad of wrinkles, like the fossilized brain of a dryad; its kinship to tree  unobscured by the cruel crush of industry; absorbing the elements like any other organic entity; blending with rock and vegetation as if it were a burrowing owl's door mat or a jack rabbit's underwear, a No. 8 Kraft paper bag lay discarded in the hills of Dakota and appeared to live where it lay. Once long ago, it had borne a package of buns and a jar of mustard to a kitchenette rendezvous with a fried hamburger. More recently, the bag had held........ love letters.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hands lift the contents of the trunk away, rope, spurs, and blanket and find the hidden sack of letters.</context>
      <utterance>As a hole in an oak hides a squirrel's family jewels, the bag had hidden love letters in the bottom of a bunkhouse trunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the Cowgirl saddling her horse late in the day.</context>
      <utterance>Then one day after work, the button- nosed little cowgirl to whom the letters were addressed gathered bag and contents under her arm, slipped out to the corral...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the Cowgirl riding along a ridge.</context>
      <utterance>...past ranch hands pitching horseshoes and ranch hands flying Tibetan kites, saddled up and trotted into the hills.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And this we see also, the lonely Cowgirl feeding the letters to a fire in the dusky early night. We can see the cowgirl is Sissy Hankshaw.</context>
      <utterance>A mile or so from the bunkhouse, she dismounted and built a small fire; she fed the fire letters.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is crying now and feeding the fire, close of words like "always" and "forever" burning up.</context>
      <utterance>...one by one, the way her girl friend had once fed her french fries.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As words such as sweetheart" and "honey britches" and "forever" and "always" burned away, the cowgirl squirted a few tears. Her eyes were so misty she forgot to burn the bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She plunks a few notes.</context>
      <utterance>You know, podner, you can tune a guitar but you can't tuna fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the bunkhouse lights are turned off. There are some giggles from the cowgirls.</context>
      <utterance>God, but it's good to be a cowgirl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everything getting worse?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, everything is getting worse. But everything is also getting better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy shows a picture of the Countess recovering in a hospital bed, posing next to Doctor Robbins.</context>
      <utterance>The Countess has come to our aid. The Rubber Rose Ranch is officially deeded to all the cowgirls. And I have been asked to oversee the ranch. For $300 a week. And as it turns out, the Countess is not going to be the vegetable the doctors thought he was... here's a picture!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to go back to the Clock People. I kind of miss those fool redskins and wonder what they're up to. What's happened to Jelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had a one way-ticket to Kansas City.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chink mourns a bit.</context>
      <utterance>You mean she's dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's an old story now...... I can't believe that you would leave the Butte.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy come, easy go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chink looks over and sees that Delores is standing in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Wow, you sure have a way with words.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delores blushes.</context>
      <utterance>I can't help it if I grew up in an antipoetic culture. Language will be different when I'm with the Clock People though. They're from an oral tradition. And I'm not talking about what you horny hop toads do in bed every night. The Chink smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if the Clock People give you any inside information on the end of the world, drop us a postcard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to caress Sissy's belly. His eyes are smiling. Sissy is surprised.</context>
      <utterance>The world isn't going to end, you dummy; I hope you know that much.  But it is going to change. It's going to change drastically, and probably in your lifetime. The Clock People see calamitous earthquakes as the agent of change, and they may be right, since there are a hundred thousand earthquakes a year and major ones are long overdue. But there are far worse catastrophes coming... unless the human race can bring itself to abandon the goals and values of civilization, in other words, unless it can break the consumption habit -- and we are so conditioned to consuming as a way of life that for most of us life would have no meaning without the yearnings and rewards of progressive consumption. It isn't merely that our bad habits will cause global catastrophes, but that our operative political-economic philosophies have us in such a blind crab grip that they prevent us from preparing for the natural disasters that are not our fault. So the apocalyptic shit is going to hit the fan, all right, but there'll be some of us it'll miss. Little pockets of humanity. Like the Clock People. Like you two honeys, if you decide to accept my offer of a lease on Siwash Cave. There's almost no worldwide calamity -- famine, nuclear accident, plague, weather warfare or reduction of the ozone shield -- that you couldn't survive in that cave.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suppose that you bear five or six children with your characteristics. All in Siwash Cave. In a postcatastrophe world, your offspring would of necessity intermarry, forming in time a tribe. A tribe every member of which had giant thumbs. A tribe of Big Thumbs would relate to the environment in very special ways. It could not use weapons or produce sophisticated tools. It would have to rely on its wits and its senses. It would have to live with animals -- and plants! -- as virtual equals. It's extremely pleasant to me to think about a tribe of physical eccentrics living peacefully with animals and plants, learning their languages, perhaps, and paying them the respect they deserve.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How am I going to be the progenitor of a tribe when I'm living on an isolated ridgetop with Delores?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chink coughs.</context>
      <utterance>That's your problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to the way I'm babbling. That bullet must have loosened one of my transistors. Don't pay any attention to me. You've got to work it out for yourself. The westbound choo-choo leaves Mottburg at one-forty. I want to be on it. Will you drive me to the station?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He yells out the window of the moving vehicle.</context>
      <utterance>Schedules! Ironic how I have to follow timetables in order to get back to the clockworks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ever bet against paradox, ladies...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
