<movie id="198" title="Excalibur">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The forest around him weeps softly with the sounds that follow slaughter. Patches of undergrowth are smoldering. Small flames lick bark and branches. Smoke floats through the trees and hovers over the bodies of the dying and the dead. A huge knight reins up beside Merlin on a lathered horse. His armor is blood spattered. He is weary from battle. He looks down at Merlin, his countenance fierce. The blade of his sword glows with an unnatural aura.</context>
      <utterance>Lord Uther! Lord Uther!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's done. A truce. We meet at the river.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk. Lovers murmuring to each other...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DUKE OF CORNWALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther and the Duke of Cornwall glare at each other in silence across the river. Uther strains forward, burning with anger; but Merlin restrains him.</context>
      <utterance>I spit on your truce, Uther. If you want peace, throw down your swords.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should butcher all and every one of them. Merlin, what is this wagging of tongues?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther unsheathes his mighty sword, and brandishes it in the air high over his head. The blade hums disquietingly and leaves a lingering electric hue upon the air. The marvel instills dread in all present.</context>
      <utterance>Just show the sword.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behold the sword of power, Excalibur. Before Uther, it belonged to Lud, before Lud, to Beowulf, before Beowulf to Baldur the Good, before Baldur to Thor himself and that was when the world was young and there were more than seven colors in the rainbow.  Speak the words.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKE OF CORNWALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Uther, if I yield to the sword of power, what will you yield?</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin urges Uther hard.</context>
      <utterance>Me, yield!?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two knights glare at each other, rage contending with anger.</context>
      <utterance>He has given. Now you must.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The enemies lock eyes and Merlin watches anxiously.</context>
      <utterance>The land from here to the sea is yours if you will enforce the King's will.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKE OF CORNWALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All men from both sides break out in wild cheers.</context>
      <utterance>Done!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKE OF CORNWALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Lord King Uther, let us feast together. To my castle. Lord Merlin, you must join - But Merlin is nowhere in sight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DUKE OF CORNWALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Duke rises and goes to his wife, be-striding the center of the hall and Igrayne weaves circles of dance around him. He gloats with pride. The words escape his lips:</context>
      <utterance>I would wish you such a wife, Lord Uther, as my Igrayne. So innocent, but in bed, a furnace...</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lot spins to face him.</context>
      <utterance>I must have her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You're mad! What about the alliance?</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must have her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther is not one for politics, and Lot's words sail past him. The King lusts for Igrayne. A bell is struck not far away. The music ceases and the hall falls silent. The great door creaks open, revealing the dawn light, and a monk steps into the hall and waits by it. Muffled by corridors of stone, a choir of monks can now be heard singing the high, ecstatic harmonies of the Te Deum. Those who have fallen asleep at the table are roused, those drunk, helped up.</context>
      <utterance>And risk all you've won? This castle commands the sea gate to the kingdom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then a knight rides up and dismounts. It is Ulfius, a lieutenant.</context>
      <utterance>Merlin! Where are you!?</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you found him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULFIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he cannot finish. He is taken aback by the sudden appearance of a hideous hag who approaches, rattling a beggar's pan.</context>
      <utterance>No--</utterance>
   <speaker>HAG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a hurry you were in this morning, good sir. You forgot to give this old woman a coin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULFIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw you half a day's gallop from here. I asked you if you had seen Merlin. I returned here straight away. How did -</utterance>
   <speaker>HAG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure straightens, the filthy rags become a flowing cape, and the hair is swept back by the wind, andit is Merlin, laughing.</context>
      <utterance>--I heard. I have come. I am also Merlin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have walked my way since the beginning of time. Sometimes I give, sometimes I take. It is mine to know which, and when.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ulfius edges away.</context>
      <utterance>Dumb riddles, Merlin. I am your King.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Duke of Cornwall under siege. All this for lust. Selfish lust. Uther grabs Merlin.</context>
      <utterance>I know the storm inside you, and what it has wrought. The alliance I forged is wrecked.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin frowns pensively, his gaze searching strange distances and wandering; then focusing, blazing straight at Uther.</context>
      <utterance>For Igrayne. One night with her. Do it. Use the magic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther kneels and draws his sword and holds it up by the blade, a cross.</context>
      <utterance>You will swear by your true kingship to grant me what I wish. Then you shall have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear it. By Excalibur and the holy--</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--What issues from your lust will be mine. Swear it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin looks down sorrowfully at the kneeling King.</context>
      <utterance>I swear it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther starts to make the sign of the cross, but Merlin halts him with a gesture. Uther's hand drops, and he enters the circle with his horse. Merlin and Uther look out across the sea, to Tintagel Castle high upon the cliff. Merlin solemnly raises his arms toward that distant castle, and chants in an ancient language, the sounds of which he marries to the roaring and whining of the wind. The wind becomes stronger, and Merlin's incantations become more intense, and the wind in turn becomes wilder still. Until Merlin is charged with a fierce, nonhuman power, as the wind buffets his slight frame. And then, for all to understand:</context>
      <utterance>Come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hold the balance of all things in my summoning. Arise mists. Come fog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King does.</context>
      <utterance>Mount your horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther spurs straight for the edge of the cliff, then reins in his horse abruptly.</context>
      <utterance>Ride straight to the castle, across the sea of fog.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin rages, crazed.</context>
      <utterance>But the cliff, the sea...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The horse and Uther charge forward into a gallop and stepping off where the hidden edge of the cliff would be, hoofbeats ceasing and the horse dropping for the blink of an eye, they gallop across the fog.</context>
      <utterance>Ride across! Across the bridges of desire. Your lust will hold you up. For I have just woven it into the fabric of the world. This is magic - making solid what is in the mind, and unsolid, that which is already solid. He gives the horse a stinging blow with his staff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Igrayne is soon at her side, lifting the child from the bed, holding her tight.</context>
      <utterance>Papa... Papa...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father is dead...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, here is your father. It was just a dream, little one.</utterance>
   <speaker>'DUKE' OF CORNWALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Igrayne kisses Morgana, tucks her in and returns to her own room, closing the door. The child doesn't know whether to believe the truth of the dream or the waking truth.</context>
      <utterance>Come Igrayne.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did it happen? Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the camp of Uther, my lady, just after nightfall.</utterance>
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can't be. He came to me, to his bed, last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was his spirit, yearning for you in his hour of death, that visited you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pale with grief, Igrayne stares at her dead husband in silence. Then her hand drifts to her stomach. When she talks again, undone and resolved, it is to all and herself:</context>
      <utterance>His spirit?</utterance>
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgana shows no distress. She runs her baby hands across her father's face and closes his eyes. The intensity that was frozen in them is now added to her own pale and cunning eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Tintagel Castle falls to Uther. But what shall become of me, and the child I bear?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ladies slip past him to the door, and he goes up to Igrayne.</context>
      <utterance>Out!</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terrified of him, Igrayne faces him the best she can.</context>
      <utterance>What is it, lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther waves away her words but does sit down on the bed, exhausted. He notices Morgana, who stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>A boy, sir. Rest yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send the girl away.</utterance>
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is just a child -</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Igrayne draws the child to her and kisses her cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Out!</utterance>
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The child leaves silently, hatred in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Go now. Come back later.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grasps the newborn baby with his iron hand, and pulls it to himself. He looks upon it with wonder, with a gentleness that is unexpected.</context>
      <utterance>She watches me with her father's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't bring himself to say his name. She hesitates on the edge of tears, worried for the infant lying in its iron cradle.</context>
      <utterance>Igrayne, is he mine, or -</utterance>
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther draws a dagger. He lifts it.</context>
      <utterance>The night he died, a man loved me with great fierceness. He looked like my husband, spoke like, smelled like, felt like my own husband. But it was not he, for he was already dead. It wasn't his spirit, for this child, who was conceived that night, is flesh and blood. I know nothing more.</utterance>
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he uses it before Igrayne can move. He severs the leather thongs that bind the iron breastplate to his chest. He casts it to the floor. His chest is smooth and milk-white in striking contrast to his creased, weathered face. And beaming, he holds the baby to it.</context>
      <utterance>No--</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Igrayne's hatred for the man is at the very edge of becoming love. The baby starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Through him, I will learn to love them, for I am tired of battle. I will stay by his side and  his mother's...</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And his free hand opens her shift, and he holds a swollen breast in his gloved hand, squeezing gently. Milk bubbles from it and he thrusts the baby's mouth onto it. Igrayne weeps and Uther watches proudly as the baby suckles. Merlin advances from the window, his cape the same iridescent green-black as the feathers of the crows that were perched by the window.</context>
      <utterance>Here. It's hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merlin! Out of the sick sleep at last.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther avoids looking at him.</context>
      <utterance>Doing what I did for you, it wasn't easy, you know. It takes it's toll. It took nine moons to get back my strength.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you must pay me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther is shaken to his roots. Igrayne watches, trying to understand.</context>
      <utterance>The child is mine, Uther. I have come for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The oath. You didn't say--</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't ask!</utterance>
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uther, is it true? Don't let him take the child.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Igrayne suddenly understands. She glares at Uther.</context>
      <utterance>I swore an oath, Igrayne. I made a pact with Merlin.</utterance>
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther is caught, and turns to Merlin who is harsh and unswaying.</context>
      <utterance>It was you? You came to me that night. You are the father.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not for you, Uther, hearth and home, wife and child.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To kill and be king, is that all?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe not even that, Uther. I thought once that you were the one to unite the land under one sword. But it'll take another, a greater king...</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You strike me with words as hard as steel.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther wrenches the baby from it's mother's breast and hands him to Merlin.</context>
      <utterance>They are not weapons, my friend, but truths. You betrayed the Duke, stole his wife and took his castle, now no one trusts you. Lot, Uryens, your allies will turn against you. Give me the child, Uther, I will protect him. Go back to your war tent.</utterance>
   <speaker>IGRAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uther stops her with his bulk and she claws savagely at his chest to get past him. He weeps as he folds his arms around her.</context>
      <utterance>WHY?... Why must he have the baby?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hears his pursuers closing in.</context>
      <utterance>Merlin, where are you? To weave a mist, to hide us...</utterance>
   <speaker>UTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds it by the hilt with both hands, the blade pointing to the ground of stone. He flexes his knees. He lifts up his hands above his head. And with all the strength that rage and pain can muster, and more, he drives the blade of Excalibur into the stone, nearly to the hilt. His mouth widens in an awful silent scream, and then the foam of saliva pink with blood issues from deep within him, so violent was his effort. As the sword cuts into the rock, the earth shudders.</context>
      <utterance>No one shall have the sword. No one shall wield Excalibur but me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, ten crazed peasants emerge from the darkness, hurling stones and armed with clubs and pronged sticks. They surround the three riders. Sir Ector wheels around and slices the air with his sword to ward off the ambushers.</context>
      <utterance>It is a dark hour... everywhere lawlessness and destruction, and no one to lead us out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The peasants edge closer, working up the nerve to rush the horsemen. The sound of thundering hooves cuts through the clamor. A cavalcade of riders, armor gleaming in the moonlight, advances across the fields at a gallop. Immediately the peasants scatter. The old knight is on the verge of tears.</context>
      <utterance>Listen all. I am Sir Ector of Morven and these are my sons. You would wrong me, for I have never stolen from others, or destroyed the fruit of the land.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people's anger is just. It is sad that for our own safety, we will have to ride to the tournament with these robber knights.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fifteen year-old boy blushes.</context>
      <utterance>Arthur, where is Kay's sword? A good squire doesn't forget his knight's sword.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I left it in the tent, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy dashes off as Sir Ector shakes his head, not without affection beneath the sternness.</context>
      <utterance>Well hurry then, and get it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIR KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir Ector is dumbstruck.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Father. Excalibur. Does that mean that I am to be king?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you free the sword, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ector looks at his son amazed, wanting to believe but not able to.</context>
      <utterance>I... did, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With Excalibur in hand Ector of Morven heads for the stone, Kay following, and Arthur too, the boy flushed with excitement but a little worried, not understanding what is happening. The exchange between Sir Ector and Sir Kay has been overheard. Some have seen the sword in Sir Ector's hand. Rumor spreads like wildfire.</context>
      <utterance>We must go to the stone at once.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir Kay grabs the hilt and pulls without conviction, and the sword doesn't give. Eyes downcast, he lets go.</context>
      <utterance>Draw it, son!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I didn't draw the sword. Arthur gave it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arthur ?!  How did you get the sword, child?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir... Kay needed a sword. His was stolen. I saw Excalibur, and... I took it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You freed it, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to kneel but Ector pulls him up.</context>
      <utterance>I did, Father. I beg your forgiveness.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur is about to grasp the hilt when Uryens and Lot, and other nobles, Leondegrance of Camelyarde, and Sir Caradoc and Sir Turquine among the younger, stride up.</context>
      <utterance>Try the sword, Arthur.</utterance>
   <speaker>URYENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand back, Sir Ector, and take your children.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uryens, Lot, Leondegrance, Caradoc, Turquine - each in turn grapples with the sword, only to be defeated by its immobility. The crowd around the stone is thickening with common folk.</context>
      <utterance>We will try again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let the boy try the sword.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The demand is echoed by peasants and serfs. The great knights remain silent and bitter in their defeat. Sir Ector pushes Arthur to the sword.</context>
      <utterance>Let the boy try...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy hesitates shyly, and then takes the hilt of Excalibur and pulls out the sword with a great sweep. The throng is stunned. Silence falls. Some kneel, following the example of Sir Ector and Sir Kay, of the Bishop and Leondegrance. The other nobles stay back, confused, afraid, angered. Arthur stands there, little more than a boy, his cheeks flushed, his soft hair ruffled by the wind, his eyes shining with exultation, awe, and fear. Then, as if gaining confidence from the sword itself, he turns it in arcs above his head.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, boy. Don't be afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The commoners and some of the knights react with roaring enthusiasm. The others draw closer to Uryens and Lot and their supporters, closing ranks around them.</context>
      <utterance>We have our King, thanks be to God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir Ector rises, tears streaming down his cheeks.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Father, rise up. I was your son before I became your King... if I am King.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is quite a shock to the boy king, and to the onlookers.</context>
      <utterance>My Lord, you are King, all the more because you are not my son, and I am not your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin's name is on the lips of all those close by.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Merlin brought you to me when you were newly born and charged me to raise you as my own. At first, I did so because I feared Merlin, later because I loved you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is Merlin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From out of the forest strides Merlin, dramatic, cape flowing, eyes crazed as ever, laughing at his own entrance. A crow is perched on his shoulder, and it squawks loudly. Annoyed with it, Merlin swooshes it away.</context>
      <utterance>Speak of the devil!...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin interrupts himself when his eyes fall on the boy, who is taking in his performance raptly, half awestruck, half amused.</context>
      <utterance>I am Merlin. Counselor to kings. Wizard and beggar. Prophet and...  I have feasted on thunderbolts, I savored my death before I got myself born. I--</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose son am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The suspicion and confusion and envy of the lords erupts.</context>
      <utterance>You are the son of King Uther, and the fair Igrayne... you are King Arthur.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merlin, we haven't forgotten you. This is more of your trickery.</utterance>
   <speaker>URYENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're trying to foist a boy of dubious birth upon us. You want to shame us?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Leondegrance, join us against the boy. Surely you can see he is only Merlin's tool.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONDEGRANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camelyarde, saw the drawing of Uther's sword, and witnessed no trickery. If a boy has been chosen, a boy shall be king. The crowd of serfs and peasants cheer wildly, and their long suppressed anger against the nobles comes to the fore. They dare to press up against them, fists hammering on their shields as the chant Arthur King over and over. Dark and scowling, full of rebellion, all the lords except Leondegrance begin to withdraw their iron men surrounding them.</context>
      <utterance>No. I, Leondegrance, Lord of</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face shines with sweat, the horse is lathered. He dismounts and continues on foot into denser, more tangled undergrowth.</context>
      <utterance>...Merlin... Merlin...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A huge eye opens in the foreground of what had appeared to be shadow, bark and tufts of weeds is really Merlin's head.</context>
      <utterance>Merlin!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice is thin as he is awakening from a deep, exhausted sleep. Arthur finds him lying within the large gnarled roots of a great tree. The boy kneels before Merlin and lifts his hands and kisses them.</context>
      <utterance>You called, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saved me from the arrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not from your destiny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur blurts it out:</context>
      <utterance>That's not why you came.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merlin, help me. I need your help. I don't know how--</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The forest groans and creaks, alive with murmurs and shrill calls.</context>
      <utterance>I'm tired. Doing magic takes its toll, you know. My arms ache terribly...  Once--or is it yet to happen--I stood exposed to the Dragon's breath so that a man could lie one night with a woman. It took me ten moons to recover. I'm sure that story would interest you, since... Well, we'll have to talk about it another time. You're too busy now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is whispered in the forest that...  ...Leondegrance's castle is under siege by Lot and Uryens.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, I know that. Everybody does. Lord Leondegrance is my only ally among the barons and the great knights. I can't lose him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well there. You don't need me half as much as you think you do. You already know what must not happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must find the means to save him, then. I was hoping I could ask you for a little magic help, but if it makes you so tired...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Arthur tries again.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just that I have no experience, and no men to speak of. How can I--</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as suddenly, he is his amused, ironic self again.</context>
      <utterance>Because you must! You and only you. Have you forgotten that it was you who freed Excalibur?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur bows his head, confused and almost defeated. Merlin steals a look at him, and puts his arm around the boy.</context>
      <utterance>Besides, it will be a good lesson.  The best, if it's not the last.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He enjoys being cryptic.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you'd like to meet the power that gave you the sword?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How? Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the great book.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What book is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The book without pages. Open before you, all around us. You can see it in bits and pieces, for if mortal men were to see it whole and all complete in a single glance, why, it would burn him to cinders.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A deep cleft at the edge of the forest, where far below lava boils with a phosphorescence that lights up a great cloud, billowing upward.</context>
      <utterance>The dragon! There...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin points to the sky where roiling clouds appear to be unfurling of immeasurable wings.</context>
      <utterance>Coiled in the unfathomed depths, it emerges...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A terrific wave batters a coastline, spray shooting up, and as the wave recedes it exposes dark rocks and deep crevices.</context>
      <utterance>...It unfolds itself in the storm clouds...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin spins Arthur around, and they are transported into a storm swept forest. Lightning strikes.</context>
      <utterance>...it washes its mane sparkling white in the blackness of seething whirlpools...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The trees shine with wetness, as a great wind tosses their crowns, the branches groaning against each other.</context>
      <utterance>...its claws are the forks of lightning... its scales glisten in the bark of trees...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur is awestruck.</context>
      <utterance>...its voice is heard in the hurricane...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur's eyes shine with the brilliance of the vision.</context>
      <utterance>...it is so much more than a scaly monster. It is Everything!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I am to be King of everything, lord and commoner, beast, leaf and rock, I must use its voice, its claws, its power.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, it's the boy King.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONDEGRANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is. I will fight my way to his side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>URYENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>War-wise fighters, grown gray in battle, checkmated by a boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur and his men have been joined by Leondegrance and his knights, few in number.</context>
      <utterance>It's Merlin's trickery, nothing more. I won't swear faith to that wizard's brat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rushes alone at the enemy, shouting at the top of his lungs, Excalibur flashing over his head, prepared to die.</context>
      <utterance>Let's finish this with a show of force. We have no more tricks and no more advantages.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are in my hands, to slay or spare. I need battle lords such as you. Swear faith to me and you shall have mercy.</utterance>
   <speaker>URYENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur turns, searching for Merlin. He spots him watching from a distance. They stare at each other, Merlin implacable, Arthur's eyes pleading. It's obvious that Merlin isn't going to help.</context>
      <utterance>Noble knights swear faith to a mere squire?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unsheathes Excalibur and goes forward, kneeling before Uryens and offering him the sword.</context>
      <utterance>You are right. I'm not yet a knight.  You, Uryens, will knight me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then as knight to knight I can offer you mercy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur, kneeling, bows his head and Uryens steps up to him, his features set. He accepts the sword. Lot watches, a mad hope dancing in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What's this, what's this?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uryens swiftly lowers the sword on Arthur's neck; with the flat of the blade he gives Arthur the three strokes.</context>
      <utterance>I never saw this...</utterance>
   <speaker>URYENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur looks up.</context>
      <utterance>In the name of God, of Saint Michael and Saint George, I give you the right to bear arms, the power to mete justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uryens is deeply moved.</context>
      <utterance>That duty I will solemnly obey as knight and King.</utterance>
   <speaker>URYENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur rises and Uryens kneels and kisses his hands. Sir Ector turns away to hide brimming tears. Merlin pushes through finally, out of breath. Uryens embraces Leondegrance while Lot and the other enemy knights kneel in turn and kiss Arthur's hands.</context>
      <utterance>Rise, my King. I am your humble knight, and I swear allegiance to the courage in your veins, for so strong it is, it's source must be Uther. I doubt you no more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With water from the spring, she is bathing a large cut on his chest that has been stitched closed. Wounds on his arms, and one on a calf also show evidence of her neat sewing. She's just finishing, and she dabs his chest with a dry cloth.</context>
      <utterance>Owww...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't hurt too much, did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ye...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to get up.</context>
      <utterance>--I'm pretty good at stitchery. I've sewn my father's wounds more than once.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur shivers at the thought.</context>
      <utterance>Careful! You'll have to stay still for a few days or you'll tear them open.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I have to leave tomorrow. The forests are thick with rebels, invaders plunder our shores...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--And damsels in besieged castles are waiting to be rescued?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know Leondegrance had a daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur smiles at her, enjoying her jealousy, and it irritates her a little.</context>
      <utterance>Well, then, I shall tell you which knights have maiden daughters, so you can avoid their castles.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I think it's better if you just stay here to heal. At least a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches his lips with hers, her eyelids fluttering shut. He stares at her young beauty, and draws her into a long, slow kiss. A shrill almost human squeal pierces the air not far away. Arthur pulls away startled, half-rising. Guenevere giggles.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet, or I'll sew up your mouth too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her arms around him, drawing him close again, speaking in a half-whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Would you rescue me from a fiery dragon, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smile at each other, about to kiss. As they come closer:</context>
      <utterance>It's just a furry little rabbit that took the bait and sprung the trap.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll find him served up to you tonight, cooked in a most excellent sauce...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A king must marry, after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only then does he realize that Merlin has understood everything. He is annoyed at being so transparent.</context>
      <utterance>...of course...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love her. If she would be my queen, my dreams would be answered.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shadow of doubt crosses Arthur's brow.</context>
      <utterance>There are maidens as fair, and fairer than Guenevere. If I put my mind to it, I could see them now, many of them, weeping for love of you, watching the hills for you coming from the high towers of their castles. Offering you their every favor. Rich, clever--but if it is to be Guenevere, so be it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who will it be? Put your mind to it, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guenevere. And a beloved friend who will betray you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guenevere...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guenevere approaches, smiling and coquettish. She slaps her hands, and a servant sets down a tray of pastries before Arthur.</context>
      <utterance>You're not listening. Your heart is not. Love is deaf as well as blind.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at Arthur's embarrassment and confusion.</context>
      <utterance>They are only for you, for in them I mixed things that heal, but not too quickly; and things that make limbs sleepy, preventing escape, but keep one's mind sharp.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a cake and bites into it.</context>
      <utterance>What's in them?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guenevere offers one to Arthur, and he hesitates, looking at it.</context>
      <utterance>It is an ancient mixture, containing only soft, unborn grains, and flavored with roses. The rest is secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur bites into the cake, and Guenevere looks deep into his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Looking at the cake is like looking at the future. Until you have savored its bitterness and its sweetness, its texture and its perfume, what do you really know? And then, of course, it will he too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too late...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIR ECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is the mightiest and fairest of knights.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes past the knights and goes to his horse. Kay steps in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>We fought and won battles, and now one man defeats all my knights? I will go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur rises into the saddle and takes a jousting spear from the rack.</context>
      <utterance>A king must not engage in single contest. I'll go again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur gallops off in the direction Sir Ector came from. His knights are afraid for him.</context>
      <utterance>Where is Merlin? The squires are silent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have left you to fend for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur's hand is clenched tight around Excalibur's hilt.</context>
      <utterance>I had to weave a little enchantment on the bees so I could get some honey, and I didn't feel up to using any more magic just yet. Anyway, I was in less danger than you'll be in today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you were stealing their honey. They should have killed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come now. So much anger for such a little crime? Are you sure there is nothing else troubling you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers his arm and Merlin hoists himself up behind the King.</context>
      <utterance>You know full well there is, and I go to meet it now. Come witness my revenge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good day to you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move aside. This is the King's road, and the knights you joined arms against were his very own.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I await the King himself. His knights are in need of training.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am King, and this is Excalibur, sword of kings from the dawn of time. Who are you, and why do you block the way?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Sir Lancelot of the Lake, from across the sea. I am the best knight in the whole of Christiandom, and I look for the king who is worthy of my sword's service.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--That is a wild boast. You lack a knight's humility.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a boast, sir, but a curse.  Never have I met my match in joust or duel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move aside!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses himself.</context>
      <utterance>I will not. You must retreat or prove your kingship in the test of arms, under the eyes of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur wheels away, trembling with anger, and gallops to his edge of the field. He sees that Lancelot has already positioned himself and is waiting, lance down. Merlin watches, a spectator, as the two charge at each other. They collide with great force, their spears shattering. Arthur is jolted but stays in the saddle. Lancelot's jousting is impeccable. Arthur draws Excalibur.</context>
      <utterance>Then may He give me the strength to unhorse you and send you with one blow back across the sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pages come forward with new lances for Arthur and Lancelot.</context>
      <utterance>Hold! I offer you another lance.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur grabs the spear from the page's hands, and circles back to work the horse up into an all-out gallop. Lancelot spurs forward to meet him. Arthur is neatly unhorsed. He picks himself up from the ground in a rage, drawing Excalibur. Lancelot on his horse weaves circles around him.</context>
      <utterance>You joust well, sir. Battle learnt, but tournament fancy. You should ride more forward in the saddle, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yield. I have the advantage.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur charges Lancelot, a raging bull, but cuts and slashes only at the air as Lancelot stays clear of him.</context>
      <utterance>I will not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fight me from your horse or on foot, but fight me. Your avoidance mocks me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dismounts and draws his sword, and they clash. Shield and sword and armor against shield and sword and armor. The swordplay is furious, Arthur attacking, slashing, hacking, Lancelot parrying effortlessly, elegantly defensive. Arthur breaks the onslaught to catch his breath. Lancelot lifts his visor. His eyes are calm, laughing.</context>
      <utterance>I sought only not to harm you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, your rage has unbalanced you. It seems you would fight to the death against a knight who is not your enemy, for a length of road you can ride around.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So be it, to the death.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur goes forward attacking with terrible blows upon Lancelot's shield, and Lancelot holds his ground, shield high. And in its mirror-like metal Arthur can see his own reflection, a face distorted by uncontrolled passion. Arthur discards his own shield, grabs Excalibur with both hands, and with a frightening shout that speaks of all his rage, he swings a terrific blow upon the shield, cutting through his own reflection and the metal. And Excalibur snaps in two. A blinding blue-green light explodes from the broken sword. Lancelot, knocked back by the force of the blow, is stunned by the blast and falls to the ground unconscious. Arthur backs away, horrified, half of Excalibur in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>It is you, sir, who knows not the virtue of humility, as a true king must.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin approaches, pale, gripped by dread.</context>
      <utterance>What horror is this?  Merlin!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur picks up the broken blade, utterly undone.</context>
      <utterance>The sword is broken. Hope is broken...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin stands there, drawn, defeated, his hopes dead.</context>
      <utterance>My pride broke it, my rage broke it... Humiliation and defeat lie in ambush even for a king.  This excellent knight who fought with fairness and grace was meant to win. With Excalibur, I tried to change that verdict.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despairing, he flings the two parts of Excalibur into the pool. He kneels at the waters edge, and he cries.</context>
      <utterance>I have lost for all time the ancient sword of my fathers whose power was meant to unite all men, to serve the vanity of a single man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Arthur sees something that startles him. Beneath the surface, suspended in the blue-green water amid the dancing weeds, he sees Excalibur, intact. It is held by a maiden in flowing gown the color of water, her long hair rippling across her face, obscuring it.</context>
      <utterance>I am nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excalibur! Is it true?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur dips his hand under the water and grasps the hilt and the moment he does the vision in the blue-green water fades. He rises with Excalibur in hand, and Merlin speaks before Arthur can ask the question.</context>
      <utterance>The Lady of the Lake. Take it. Take it, quickly!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Lancelot stirs. Arthur rushes to his side. He loosens his helmet and removes it, uncovering damp curls. The young knight's eyes open, and his laughing charm once more animates his face.</context>
      <utterance>There are infinite worlds within the infinite coils of the Dragon. In one of them, which I have not traveled, the sword was forged. I only know that the King is returned to us through the instrument of his power. The game continues! And he laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks to God, you are alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, the best knight in the world, bested! This is a great day, for my search is over. I love you, my King. He embraces Arthur, who is overwhelmed by his childlike directness. The King helps him to his feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are still the best knight in Christiandom. You gained a hundred advantages over me. It is I who must love you, for through your courage and patience you taught me a bitter lesson.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then make me your champion and I will always fight in your place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But your life and lands are far from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thumps his breastplate.</context>
      <utterance>I gave up my castles and my lands!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My domain is here, inside this metal skin. And I would pledge to you all that I still own: muscle, bone, blood and the heart that pumps it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancelot draws his sword, holding it by the blade, a crucifix.</context>
      <utterance>And a great heart it is. Sir Lancelot, you will be my champion.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace, and Merlin watches.</context>
      <utterance>In the name of Jesus Christ and His holy blood, I swear eternal faith to Arthur, King.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur sees Lancelot in the throng and moves toward him. Merlin follows Arthur and is pushed and knocked around in the crush of spikes and iron. The only unarmored man in the crowd, he glares at the excited knights irritably.</context>
      <utterance>...We killed every one of them. Burnt their ship...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lancelot, how did you fare in the North?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur turns toward Uryens.</context>
      <utterance>We spared the lives of a few, so they could sail home and tell their fellows what fate they met at the hands of King Arthur's knights...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you, Uryens?</utterance>
   <speaker>URYENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victory!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lot, and you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We drove the invaders into the sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, Gawain, the East?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAWAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cheers greet each declaration.</context>
      <utterance>The East is ours again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amidst the celebration, a fracas is heard. A knight pushing forward to talk to Arthur has entered a shoving match with those in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>The war is over. One land, one King. Peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin is brutally jostled. He draws a fistful of powder from his cape and he tosses it into the air above him. He raises his staff into the cloud, cracking it like a whip. The tip of the staff catches fire, and the fire spreads through the powder in the air, stunning all into silence. Merlin shouts and snarls.</context>
      <utterance>Let me through. I fought the King's battle too. He must know my story.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin swings his burning staff into a wide arc. The knights back away, amused at first, then a bit afraid.</context>
      <utterance>Chaos... confusion... brutes... savages... troglodytes... Stand back... make space.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The knights have fallen back. Merlin stalks past each man, and Arthur too, holding the flaming tip of his staff before each pair of eyes, and staring into them with his gimlet gaze.</context>
      <utterance>The moon... the sun... the stars... they spin... they turn... they circle... around us... us...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The knights have formed a circle. They realize this. Awestruck, they whisper in astonishment, looking up at the sky burning with stars. Merlin brims with pride as he waits for Arthur to recognize his handiwork.</context>
      <utterance>You, and you, and you, take up your place. Be wedded to the world. Respect its perfection. All of you, together, be one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cheer rises. Arthur strides into the ring of knights.</context>
      <utterance>Your ancient wisdom and infinite sight have forged this circle, Merlin. Hereafter we shall come together in a circle, to tell and hear of deeds good and brave. I will build a table where this fellowship shall meet. And a hall around the table. And a castle about the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another bout of cheers goes up, and Arthur stops before Leondegrance, resting his hand on the old knight's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>And I will marry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leondegrance's eyes fill with tears of joy. A roar of cheers. Arthur draws the sword of power.</context>
      <utterance>And the land will have an heir to wield Excalibur.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancelot is drawn in by the King's enthusiasm. He unsheathes his sword and swoops it low in salute.</context>
      <utterance>Knights of the Round Table, good friends, brothers in arms. I send you on a quest harder by far than the battles we have fought together, a quest to uphold always, and everywhere, justice, honor, and truth. Each day shall bring forth a cause, and may each cause bring forth a knight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In quick succession all knights draw their swords, following Lancelot's example. Merlin struggles to put out the flame on his staff. He finally does it by smothering it with earth. When he looks up again, he sees the knights galloping off in all directions.</context>
      <utterance>I swear never to rest twice on the same pillow till all men live at peace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good day, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he also acknowledges with a nod the ashen-faced patriarch of the community. Lancelot spurs his horse on, and the knight sighs with relief. But then he reins his horse to a stop. He has sensed something. He turns his head, his hooded eyes on the knight and his men, and they squirm inwardly.</context>
      <utterance>Good day to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These men repented before God for their evil deeds. Those who would not, met their fate at the end of my sword.  Accept the fruit of my first quest as my wedding gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises and follows Arthur and Guenevere into the central pavilion. Pages draw its curtains closed as they pass inside.</context>
      <utterance>I do. Rise, Lancelot, come with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancelot sits, stiff and upright.</context>
      <utterance>Sit beside me, Lancelot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your deeds set an example for all other knights. For your gift, ask a gift of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guenevere overhears. She approaches and Lancelot jumps to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Only give me leave to ride out again, to do what I am most able to do, and happiest doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He must stay for the feasting days of our wedding, and tell his deeds himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I grant you your wish if you grant Lady Guenevere hers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin leans close to Arthur.</context>
      <utterance>I will stay Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The knights of Galys approach the camp. It would be politic...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises. Lancelot, who was about to sit again, straightens.</context>
      <utterance>...to ride out and meet them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will ride with Sir Kay. Lancelot, rest here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't start a war on my wedding day!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur and Merlin exit, leaving Guenevere and Lancelot. She looks at him, lively and amused, and he can't help smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Without Lancelot?!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancelot blushes.</context>
      <utterance>Look Lancelot. The maids and ladies whisper about you. They all dream of winning you, young and old, fair and ugly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't look at her.</context>
      <utterance>But surely that's no secret to you, dear Lancelot. You're the bravest and strongest knight they've ever seen, and beauty has kissed your brow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The well-kept secret is whether any of them has won your heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am a fighting man and I am married to the quest. That is enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And there is no maiden in the whole world who inspires you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is one.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I would swear my love to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To me? But why?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guenevere smiles, moved by his blunt innocence.</context>
      <utterance>I cannot love as a woman the lady who will be wife to my King and my friend. And, in pledging my love to you, I cannot love any other woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kneels, kisses her thigh, rises and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I will see you in all women, and I will defend them as I would defend you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Merlin, are you ill?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strangling a laugh he wrenches himself away. Just then Uryens and a small party of knights rides up through the tents and dismounts in front of the church. Uryens helps a lady off her horse and joins the cortege on foot.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, I need air.</utterance>
   <speaker>URYENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin, who was slinking away through the throng of bystanders, looks up. What he sees sends a chill through his body. At Uryens' side stands a young woman of sinister beauty, with bewitching eyes of ice. Merlin just stares at her, and she smiles back at him faintly.</context>
      <utterance>Merlin, don't you join the celebration?</utterance>
   <speaker>URYENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My wife, Merlin. Lady Morgana of Cornwall.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin laughs. Uryens shrugs and continues into the chapel with Morgana. As she enters she glances back, and just then Merlin steals a look, their eyes meet.</context>
      <utterance>I remember you, Merlin. I was a child. You took my brother away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You left your husband's side? You left your brother's wedding?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Mandrake, Lord Merlin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin smiles at last, and Morgana does, her eyes piercing, cruel and lovely.</context>
      <utterance>Can it truly be used for magic?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His gaze drifts toward the chapel.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... sometimes...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...There are many powers in this world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A din is heard to the forest, and it grows. Perceval glances around, panicked. The sound is the rubbing of leather upon leather, of metal on metal, for now a mounted figure in armor hovers over the terrified boy.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets the rabbit go free. The threatening figure dismounts. And Perceval, cartwheels backward, landing in the stream and scooping a fish out.</context>
      <utterance>Have I taken too much?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He returns the fish to the water. The figure steps into a pool of sunlight and a glorious halo streaks from the armor. It is Lancelot.</context>
      <utterance>I had rabbit yesterday. Today I'll eat fish... No?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval is overcome with astonishment, and he kneels.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancelot laughs and pulls the boy to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>You're an angel! Not a devil...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a man. A knight in the King's service.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval is beside himself with enthusiasm.</context>
      <utterance>You're a man?!  ...with metal skin!</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancelot rolls his eyes, amused.</context>
      <utterance>Can I grow metal skin?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got a lot to learn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancelot shakes his head and spurs the horse into a gallop. Perceval lengthens his stride, and keeps up! Lancelot reins to a halt.</context>
      <utterance>I'll learn... take me... to the King... What's a... King?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well. Climb up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will run.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, boy, it's more than twenty days from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty days!? The world is that big?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kay is not at all pleased; nonetheless he takes the boy by the ear and leads him across the drawbridge and into the castle.</context>
      <utterance>Who will give me my sword?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancelot smiles to himself, hesitation, lingering before the great gate of Camelot. There is a walkway suspended in the trees above, that also leads to the castle, and promenading on it is a group of women, Guenevere and her ladies-in-waiting. The Queen sees Lancelot and hastens toward him. Lancelot sees her, and mounts his horse and heads back into the forest. She stops, somewhat ahead of the ladies, and watches wistfully. Lancelot turns back and seeing her one last time, draws down his visor and spurs his horse into a canter. He passes two commoners who are heading for the castle, one fat and the other thin, and they are locked in hot dispute. Their wives keep them from coming to blows and their children spur them on, enjoying the excitement. Lancelot is swallowed by the forest.</context>
      <utterance>Kitchen knives and greasy spits will be your weapons, boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brew ale, sir--from old shoes--I am an honest tradesman sir. I must sell what I produce. He won't buy ale and he won't pay. Pay up! He leans over the barrel and sucks in the vapors. The vapors are mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIN MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur is both amused and exasperated.</context>
      <utterance>How would you know I, sir, have the misfortune to live next to this criminal... What loss in that? Not to me! Pay for what? Why?! They are floating on the wind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough!... What is a fair price for the smell of your ale?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why we have come to you, sir There's no one else who can tell us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it cost to get drunk on your ale?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur addresses the Thin Man.</context>
      <utterance>At least three shillings, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Thin Man is crestfallen, the smile gone from his face. He reluctantly hands the coins to Kay, who gives them to Arthur. Arthur tosses them in the air and lets them fall on a metal plate. He hands them back to the Thin Man, who is totally confused now, as is everybody else.</context>
      <utterance>Give me three shillings.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The knights roar with laughter and the Fat Man and the Thin Man look at each other in astonishment. Perceval lets out a raucous laugh that wins him a glance of disapproval from Kay.</context>
      <utterance>For the smell of your ale, the jingle of his coins.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin is in agony, a bug stuck on a pin.</context>
      <utterance>What did I see today in the wizard's eyes? Censure, because I enjoy a few words with a young handsome knight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, of course not. You are young...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not jealous!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's clear you are, and it irks me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Yes, I am. I am jealous. I want to write poems about you with moonbeams, make the sea sing your name...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lovestruck page!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does, laughing and in complete control. His hand immediately slides onto her thigh. She removes it, but holds it in her hand, toying with his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Shh... yes, yes. Sit with me, please... Morgana.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin looks at her, knowing already, sad yet eager.</context>
      <utterance>A steamy, panting, lovestruck page. But what good are songs and poems to me? They are the barter of ordinary love. A gift that reflected your greatness is the only one worthy of your love.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I showed you all my conjuring tricks...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The deepest secrets, the forbidden formulas...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin's thoughts have carried him far away, when he realizes that Arthur is addressing him.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe... maybe...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some knights laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Merlin, are you counselor to the King, or to my sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At your service, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then answer me this. For years peace has reigned in the land. Crops grow in abundance, there is no want. Every one of my subjects enjoys his portion of happiness and justice, even those whose tiresome misunderstandings we must resolve here each day. Tell me, Merlin: have we defeated evil, as it seems?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur is taken aback.</context>
      <utterance>Good and evil; there is never one without the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where hides evil, then, in my kingdom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He chuckles softly and Arthur is puzzled. A knight speaks out, the young knight with whom Morgana was flirting. His manner is sarcastic.</context>
      <utterance>Never where you expect it, that's all I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GAHALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we have peace and justice, why is Lancelot never with us? Why is he always riding out on his quests? He must know where this evil is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GAWAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could there be evil within Lancelot himself? To live above human folly, as is his aim, is to be overly proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GAHALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hall falls silent, all eyes upon the Queen.</context>
      <utterance>He pays no heed even to the Queens longing for his company.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur, ashen-faced, turns to Merlin for help, but he has escaped into sleep...</context>
      <utterance>Don't listen to him. You are the Queen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir Gahalt, answer the Queen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgana picks the bowl up and as she does so, unseen by any and with a magician's dexterity, she thrusts her fingernails deep into the top apple. She gives the bowl to Guenevere, who takes it and sweeps around to where Sir Gahalt sits, followed by Morgana. The young knight jumps to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>No. I meant not to be angry with you, Sir Gahalt. In the idleness that comes with peace gossip has bread its own evil. You merely repeat it. Please, sir, have one of those apples that Lancelot loves, and in that gesture partake of its goodness.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take one, Sir Gahalt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GAHALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is too shy to take the shiniest, most beautiful apple on top, and goes for another one. Morgana giggles, and he looks at her. She looks at the apple on top and then smiles encouragingly at him. Sir Gahalt takes it and starts eating as the Queen returns to her seat. With the third bite his is unable to breathe. His face goes red and he rises to his feet, attempting to call out. He falls, dying immediately. All leap to their feet, and Arthur rushes to the young knight. Merlin is asleep and far from human affairs. Arthur and Sir Gawain rise from the body of the young knight. Sir Gawain backs away from Arthur and points at Guenevere, trembling with cold rage.</context>
      <utterance>I am most honored, my lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GAWAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guenevere, white and with a broken voice, turns to Arthur.</context>
      <utterance>Hear me, Lord Arthur, and knights and chieftains: I charge Guenevere with the murder of my brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins to swoon and Morgana keeps her steady on her feet. Arthur slumps into his seat and Sir Gawain kneels before him.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't... I am innocent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GAWAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Enraged, Arthur reaches for Excalibur. But with effort he checks his impulse.</context>
      <utterance>I champion this truth: That Queen Guenevere murdered Sir Gahalt with the aid of sorcery.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Queen will be in my charge till a champion steps forward to fight on her behalf.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur cannot look at her.</context>
      <utterance>Not you, my husband?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GAWAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She must be burnt at the stake. That is the sentence for murder done with magic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one responds. Guenevere falls into her seat. Arthur searches the eyes of his knights and they evade him.</context>
      <utterance>It is. Lords and knights of the Round Table, as her husband I say that this deed was not done by Guenevere. Who among you will champion this truth?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The knight looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Sir Caradoc! You!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARADOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir Ector, old and feeble, weeps for Arthur. Someone speaks up. It is Perceval, who kneels before the Queen. His voice is unnaturally loud, and his eyes shine with held-back tears; he stutters.</context>
      <utterance>I am torn.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is overwhelmed by his own boldness. He looks around. All eyes are upon him. Guenevere smiles at him, sadly.</context>
      <utterance>I will champion you, my lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thank you, but you are not yet a knight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval hurries from the hall. Arthur looks away, ashamed, and his eyes fall on Merlin, twitching and mumbling in his sleep.</context>
      <utterance>I will find Lancelot! He will come!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys!... boys will be boys...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tomorrow. Sir Gawain...</context>
      <utterance>I have found you. The Queen. An apple.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two women set the chicken and the bread before the great knight, and stand back to watch him eat, flushed with excitement. Perceval falls silent, in awe of Lancelot.</context>
      <utterance>--It must wait, child. These good ladies, for whom I intervened once, will honor me with a meal. I am beholden to them now as I was when they begged my protection.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't you be my champion?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I am your judge, I cannot be your champion. When I act as your King, I cannot be your husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you cannot love me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The laws, my laws, must bind everyone, high and low, or they are not laws at all. Lancelot will come...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hides his anguish from her. Numb with hurt, she goes to a tall curtained window, and draws it open, and stands there looking out upon the surrounding forest, silent and still beneath the moon.</context>
      <utterance>And if he cannot be found, no other knight will champion me, though you beseeched each and every one of them. Why be king if there is no one you can call loyal subject but an eager boy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur hides his pain behind a rigid mask.</context>
      <utterance>He heard Lady Guenevere's request and he said nothing. That is all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SIR GAWAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Lord, the sun is upon the field. The Queen has no champion. I demand justice, as is my right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval leaps onto his horse.</context>
      <utterance>So it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me champion the Queen! Sir Gawain looks at the squire with contempt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval leaps from his horse and bends his knee before the King. Arthur brings the sword down on the boy's shoulder, giving him the three strokes.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, kneel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the name of God, of St. Michael, and St. George, I make you a knight. Rise, Sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gawain shakes his head disdainfully as Perceval mounts back into the saddle, his eyes burning with fervor. Sir Gawain and Perceval ride to opposite ends of the field. The spectators fall silent, all staring blankly, their senses dulled by the tragedy, at the uneven combatants. A cry goes up. Lancelot rides out of the forest. He rides up to the King and salutes him. Arthur smiles at his old friend, tears of joy in his eyes. Lancelot bows toward Guenevere and rides on to where Perceval waits. Lancelot reaches out to touch Perceval's cheek.</context>
      <utterance>...Perceval!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval cannot reply, his eyes affixed on the blood that trickles from Lancelot's hauberk. Lancelot raises his lance in salute to Gawain across the field. Gawain salutes in answer. The two huge knights charge at each other, each man's spear tip making contact with the other's armor, and in the violent collision both are unhorsed. Lancelot is slower at getting to his feet and drawing his sword. He is bleeding below the hauberk from his self-inflicted wound. In the first onslaught Lancelot fights defensively, falling back. He has to toss aside his shield and hold his stomach with his shield hand. Morgana watches with Merlin. Every terrible blow of sword on sword reverberates through her body pleasurable. Merlin is captivated by her cruel sensuality.</context>
      <utterance>It's my task to prove the Queen's innocence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guenevere kneels, and at her touch Lancelot's eyes flicker open. Merlin exits, and draws Arthur away with him. Arthur is deeply tormented.</context>
      <utterance>Flesh on flesh. You must press on the wound, Guenevere, hold it, and it will begin to bind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merlin, tell me. Now that Guenevere is returned to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin appears moved by the predicaments that Arthur has to face.</context>
      <utterance>What is it my child?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin stares off into the evening sky, where a lark sings high up.</context>
      <utterance>Will I have a son?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just yes? No mad laughter, no riddles, nothing but a simple yes? That frightens me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He taps his skull and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>A king should be afraid, always. The enemy is everywhere. Waiting in ambush in the dark corridors of his castle, on the deer paths of his forest, or in the gray and winding paths of a more tangled forest, in here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They miss the battlefield. I think we do too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guenevere cannot tear her eyes from Lancelot. He avoids her look. Arthur looks from Guenevere to Lancelot, and speaks softly to him, across her, and with stabbing directness.</context>
      <utterance>But one can still keep a sword sharp riding out in the name of the King's law.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, addressing the hall:</context>
      <utterance>It is not easy for the young ones to learn knightly virtues without the hard teaching of war and quest. It is only your example, Lancelot, that binds them now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is bent close to Morgana, whispering. Only when the hall rings with laughter does he look up.</context>
      <utterance>Which is the greatest quality of knighthood? Courage? Compassion? Loyalty? Humility? What do you say, Merlin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?  The greatest? They blend together like the metals we mix to make a good sword.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin looks from Arthur to Guenevere to Lancelot to Arthur.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't ask for poetry. Which is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An uneasy silence falls upon the feast. Guenevere and Lancelot cannot look at each other, and Arthur feels it. Lancelot jumps to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>All right. Truth. It must be truth, above all. When a man lies he murders some part of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guenevere stifles her dismay.</context>
      <utterance>Conversation and court life don't suit me. I must take my rest in the forest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hasn't Merlin mended your wound?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur is about to rise to embrace him, but checks himself.</context>
      <utterance>It is deep...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The exchange has become closely intimate, even though they stand apart and speak before everyone in the large hall. Lancelot leaves. Only Guenevere cannot watch.</context>
      <utterance>You will be sorely missed. Heal yourself and come back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves closer and he thrusts out his mailed fist to keep her away. She clutches it and presses the metal to her soft tear-streaked cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Why? You will destroy Arthur, and us...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The law forbids it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hungry with passion, she embraces the cold unmoving armor, kissing it.</context>
      <utterance>Love demands it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are things about love--</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps back, drawing his sword. He holds it up by the blade between them.</context>
      <utterance>--Nothing!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And before he can finish she grabs the blade to push it aside. He holds it fast. Blood streams from her bare hands. He cannot prevail without cutting them deeply. He lets go of the sword, and she lets it fall to the ground. She embraces his still and defeated hulk. She kisses the metal, and sensation shoots through him, dizzying him.</context>
      <utterance>By my knight's sword, I swore faith--</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He folds her in his arm, and their bodies lock together as though a trap had sprung. Their mouths meet, each devouring the other...</context>
      <utterance>Guenevere...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am alone and betrayed. By my wife, by my beloved friend, by my knights. And by you. Perhaps most of all by you. For you made me, you forged this wretched life. And like a child tired of a toy, you toss me aside, a babbling lecher trotting after my sister...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is my destiny. I have a destiny, too...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With all your powers, you are content to be ridiculed, laughed at...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My powers fade, Arthur. I resort to cheap tricks...  Yes! I enjoy every moment of my foolishness, I join in the making of it, so no one can betray me. But you! You betray yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? I have lived by the oath of king and knight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur looks up and in the rolling clouds maybe, just maybe, the form of a dragon is taking shape. Arthur draws Excalibur, intensity animating his dead features.</context>
      <utterance>You betray the boy who drew the sword, the boy who saw the Dragon... the Dragon who moves close by, coiling and uncoiling, restless, looking down, waiting for the King to be a king...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must do it myself. I must kill them both. Lancelot and Guenevere. Will you ride with me, Merlin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace. Merlin is on the verge of tears, his face immediately sad and finally ancient. Arthur exits. Morgana, who has been watching from the shadows, watching from the shadows, slinks up to Merlin's side.</context>
      <utterance>I cannot. I must not. Here I must stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin smiles knowingly at her.</context>
      <utterance>Crazy old fool. You think yourself a kingmaker. Ha! A meddler, more likely. Look what a mess you've made of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches to touch her lips. She cradles his hand in hers and doesn't allow Merlin to kiss her. She kisses his knuckles and stares into his eyes, stoking his desire.</context>
      <utterance>I? Perhaps, perhaps. I'm losing interest, Morgana... I have helped men--or meddled in their affairs, if you would have it that way--since the dawn of time. Now let them live by their own laws. Let them stand on their own feet. The gods of once are gone forever, it is time for men... Morgana, make a man out of me. Kiss me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I want. I want the secret of true magic, how to thicken the stuff of dreams and wishes with the flesh of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks away, provocative, alluring.</context>
      <utterance>That I cannot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I will not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't he kill us?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kneels before the sword, embracing the hilt to her breast.</context>
      <utterance>He has given up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The King without his sword, the land without a king...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancelot stumbles into the forest, berserk with guilt. He rages against a small tree, crying out, and he rips its roots from the ground, the terrible tearing and renting the symbol of his own inner torment. Guenevere sinks to the ground next to Lancelot's empty armor and his abandoned sword.</context>
      <utterance>We are to blame.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When Arthur built the castle, I carved out a place for myself, where I could laugh or sleep, and no one would bother me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>People make you laugh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans close to her ear, whispering into it.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is about to kiss her when he slips. He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>They don't know how close they live to the edge of delight or disas...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happiness or horror.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sweeps her up into his arms.</context>
      <utterance>In the folds of the earth where the forces that hold the world together are more alive, my power is strongest. Here I will possess you, as a man possesses a woman. And the god, the eunuch, the mule that I was, will be no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are truly magnificent!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He deposits her on bare rock. He kisses her. She pushes him away.</context>
      <utterance>Flattery! Do you think I am ignorant of your stupid little games? Preying on you weakness of others. That's your power, a petty evil. Mine is great. Great plans. Impossible dreams. Laughable endings...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merlin, the powers of Summoning, the true Name of the charms of Doing and Undoing. Show me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans forward and kisses his ear and whispers.</context>
      <utterance>I won't. You would misuse such power. I have paid enough for you, and I will have you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She draws closer, kissing him deeply. He breathes heavily.</context>
      <utterance>Make magic, my foolish wizard. For our love. Weave a marvelous room around us, a room worthy of our coupling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want? You must desire it for me to weave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgana falls silent as Merlin raises a hand, majestically intoning a harsh repetitive charm. The mineral veins of the cave begin to glow and fog seeps out from them enveloping the couple.</context>
      <utterance>Walls of shining crystals, burning with red fire, furnishings of metals and jewels never seen by man...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgana burns with intensity. Merlin utters a formula and the fog coalesces around them into the shimmering presence of crystal walls, fountains raining jewels, flowers made of scented air, a bed of glass shot with light and covered with skins of animals dead before the time of man, goblets of ruby, tapestries woven of golden hair. She reaches out to touch the wall and her hand plunges through the unmaterialized illusion.</context>
      <utterance>Desire it and it will be as you desire.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins lacing up her loosened gown.</context>
      <utterance>It's only a semblance. You disappoint me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does, a mad hope in her eyes. She kisses his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch the walls. Come close to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He utters the ancient charm, Morgana listening closely, memorizing it. The illusion is all of a sudden solid.</context>
      <utterance>Do it, Merlin, the deepest secret. Fix it with the charm of Making, for our endless pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs her hand across the hard crystal surface, her eyes gleaming. From outside the wondrous room they can be seen to embrace. He carries her to the magical bed where he makes love to her, as they disappear from view in its effulgent light. She comes out through the crystal door, burning with evil intent. She turns to watch him asleep in the bed. She utters the charm of Summoning learnt from Merlin, and the room melts into an eddying carmine fog. Within it, Merlin struggles to awaken from the torpor of love, alarmed. Outside, Morgana utters the charm of Making and the gaseous mass begins to crystallize. Inside, Merlin is rising to his feet, breathing the red fog, his movements slowing to a standstill, his mouth opening in a scream of horror. The cloud has metamorphosed into a magnificent cluster of red crystals. Morgana peers into its facets and there she sees, in fragments, Merlin's terror... an eye, the gaping mouth, a clawing hand--as he is entombed in the stone. She laughs in triumph.</context>
      <utterance>For you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Knights look up; those who meet Arthur's reddened eyes shake their heads. Arthur leaves. A knight whispers to another.</context>
      <utterance>Has no one seen Merlin?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see? The King was without Excalibur...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes around and she kneels in front of him. Before he can talk she silences him with a tender caress.</context>
      <utterance>I'll weep for you, brother, for a King must not weep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know what Guenevere's maids have whispered?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins untying the laces of his metal thigh and shin guards.</context>
      <utterance>That when the King returned from battle...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is stripping his legs naked, gently touching the flesh with her fingertips. He stares off, remembering.</context>
      <utterance>...Guenevere would unlace his armor and massage the burns where metal rubbed on flesh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur's eyes brim with tears. Morgana weeps, embracing his knees. He rests his hand gently upon her head, choked with remembrance, soothing her. But as she weeps, she incants a charm. Arthur looks down upon her, and the woman who looks up at him is Guenevere, a Guenevere with cold ice eyes. He is made weak by desire and weakened further by magic. He holds her face adoringly.</context>
      <utterance>...She would prepare a bath for you, mixing special ointment in the water...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guenevere! You are--</utterance>
   <speaker>"GUENEVERE"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She draws him to the floor and upon her body, holding him tightly to himself. Arthur trembles with excitement, pathetic in his desperate passion. As he takes her, she shudders, losing control of the charm, and her features change till once again "Guenevere" is Morgana. She holds him in a tight embrace so that he may not see her. She whispers in his ear.</context>
      <utterance>--Don't speak. A thousand words, a hundred thousand words, would only be prologue to the truth that must be. That you, King, and I, your Queen, beget a son to bond our love and to strengthen our weak kingdom with a successor. Come, my lord...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur wrenches himself away so he can see her, her arms still around his neck. He looks down upon her, aghast, incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>The moon flows in my blood to meet your seed. And already I bear him who will be King.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She presses her thumbs into his neck and he faints.</context>
      <utterance>I could easily kill you, brother. But I want you to live to see our son be King. In me, the blood of Cornwall will have its revenge; in me, the blood of Uther will show its dark side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gawain rises and draws his sword in salute.</context>
      <utterance>Who will ride the labyrinths of the forest, to the very root of his soul, to the very ends of the earth, to find the secret that will redeem us from the evil that has fallen upon us, and make this chalice, and ourselves, whole again?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GAWAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval, Kay and a few others draw their swords and touch their lips to the blades in oath. Sunbeams splash off their armor.</context>
      <utterance>I will ride forth in the name of that quest, and commit my strength and my soul to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rest of the fellowship draw their swords in imitation, but the resolution within them is not strong. Arthur comes forward to Gawain.</context>
      <utterance>I will go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He embraces Gawain, tears in his eyes. He turns to Perceval, and Perceval kneels.</context>
      <utterance>Gawain, a dreadful fear is upon me, that we may never meet again, that the fellowship will be no more...</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur kisses the young knight's brow. Then he turns to Kay.</context>
      <utterance>We will find the secret or die.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur and Kay watch the knights file out till the hall is empty, the harsh song of their armor growing distant.</context>
      <utterance>Kay, I know your heart yearns to go, but I am prisoner to my duties, and you must be to yours, at my side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval is galloping toward them when the ground gives way beneath the horse, and he and the animal plunge into a pit. The cheering crowd rushes to the edge of the trap.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Mordred, a true prize for the giant. The lamb rides into our jaws.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her knights drag Perceval, unarmed, into Morgana's presence.</context>
      <utterance>You must kill him, for this knight is dear to your father. You must do it and learn to enjoy your father's pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval doesn't answer, defiant and hiding his fear.</context>
      <utterance>Have you found what you search for? Have you found what Arthur seeks?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't, or you would be smiling now in the face of death. Your quest is an impossible one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That it might be impossible makes it all the more necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(to the men holding Perceval) Uncover him. I'll show you the mystery of life. It's death... (to Mordred) Do it, Mordred! Holding Perceval by his limbs and hair, the men force him down on the bloody grating, drawing back his head, exposing his throat. Morgana kneels by his head, and draws the boy beside her. She holds the tip of the dagger to Perceval's neck and takes Mordred's hand and wraps it around the handle. Perceval is choked with fear, his heart pounding in his throat.</context>
      <utterance>Fool!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy looks up at his mother. The vein in Perceval's neck pushes against the dagger's point.</context>
      <utterance>Feel the life through the dagger, child. It belongs to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy raises the dagger, and hesitates just a bit. Perceval resigns himself bravely. He looks the child calmly in the eye. Mordred brings down the blade without strength, just piercing the skin with the tip. He lets go of the dagger, afraid now of his mistake. The dagger clatters to the grating and slips away down the drain, before Morgana can retrieve it. She rages against Mordred. In the confusion, Perceval tears loose, the men holding him slipping on the blood-wet stone. Perceval runs through the crowd. Immediately, lance lowered, a knight is upon him. Perceval leaps toward him, catching the lance in his hand, and pulling down the rider with it. He jumps the rider and draws the knight's sword. Whirling the lance and cutting the air with the sword, he keeps back the other knights for a moment, giving him time to see his chance. He leaps onto the riderless horse and charges off through the crowd. He reins in abruptly, the horse rearing. He is wary of the ground before him; there could be a hidden pit. But there is no time to think. Knights and men on foot are rushing him. He spurs forward into a gallop, the horse striding mightily And its hind leg sinks into a pit, the animal losing its gait. But the momentum carries the horse forward, and it recovers from the stumble. Perceval gallops away. Morgana is enraged. She shakes Mordred by the hair.</context>
      <utterance>I feel it, Mother. I will give his blood to the giant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't kill him! You didn't kill him! But suddenly she begins kissing him tenderly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He just stands there emotionless, the dead center of her turbulent passions.</context>
      <utterance>My dear, sweet boy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts off again, into the patchless forest of dead trees. He is suddenly set upon by a wildman who, swinging a small uprooted tree, knocks him off his horse. Perceval crashes to the ground and before he can use his sword the wildman has knocked it out of his hand. It is Lancelot, demented, who furiously rains battering blows on Perceval's armor, bellowing with rage. All that Perceval can do is attempt to avoid the blows. Lancelot addresses Perceval as if the young knight were Lancelot himself.</context>
      <utterance>We'll become good friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Perceval can speak, Lancelot disappears again into the forest, his eyes blank, as though his encounter with the young knight had never happened. A knot of pain, Perceval pulls himself up. He tries to rise into the saddle. He is too hurt to do it. He starts off on foot, slowly, leading the horse.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you going, Lancelot, in your iron tomb? Still trying to save the world?  The best... the bravest... the greatest... fool that ever lived. Now the world rots. Death is king of the earth. And it is you who make it so, Lancelot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur comes alive.</context>
      <utterance>Your son Mordred is at the gate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At last...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't recognize him. You were trapped by Morgana's sorcery.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Gawain and Perceval, Bors and Bohort, Caradoc and Ector, and all the others--lost to me. Only the echo of their voices remains in this empty hall. All I have left is the memory of their fellowship. Echoes and memories. I am a ghost of the King that once was...  ...Mordred is real, alive, my own flesh and blood. I will see him, I must.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rise, Mordred.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have come to claim what is mine, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I recognize you only as my son, no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the huge lance. The page pulls a string and the hood drops, revealing a diabolically sharp spear tip, its metal glinting menacingly.</context>
      <utterance>And you are the great King? The lords have rebelled. Invaders attack the coasts. Crops don't grow. There is nothing but plague and hunger in the land. Only I am feared. I will be king. You may have lost Excalibur, but I have found my own weapon of power. There.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The very spear that pierced the side of Christ as he died on the cross.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mordred is thrown off by the doubt Arthur has cast. Arthur looks upon his son, desperately trying to read him.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother told you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cannot offer you the land, only my love...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur goes forward to embrace his son, a desperate attempt. Mordred recoils.</context>
      <utterance>And I offer only this, Father. To commit with passion and pleasure all the evils that you failed to commit, as man and king.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur is on the verge of tears.</context>
      <utterance>We will embrace only in battle. Father, and I will touch you only with the blade of my spear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will muster a great force of knights, and I will return to fight for what is mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and re-enters the castle, the drawbridge pulled up immediately behind him. He is hunched over, broken.</context>
      <utterance>So be it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peasants have emerged, surrounding him, and they hold axes and pitchforks.</context>
      <utterance>Illusions. I will never find it again... I am sorry, woman, that I frightened you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good woman, do you have any food? Some water?...</utterance>
   <speaker>PEASANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The little we had, we gave to Mordred's knights. He has taken this land. Tell the King that now we must look to Mordred.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND PEASANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At least ten peasants encircle Perceval and he is too exhausted to put up a fight. They grab him and carry him away. Other peasants pull his horse to the ground, and one raises and ax to kill it.</context>
      <utterance>But we will give you some water...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who does it serve?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have waited long for you. Once you almost saw, but fear blinded you. Why am I served from the chalice?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you and the land are one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am wasting away and I cannot die. And I cannot live.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval cups his hands around the chalice to lift it. But they close on nothing, and he draws back. The Figure's hands, although insubstantial, grasp Perceval's and appear to hold his hands around the cup.</context>
      <utterance>You and the land are one. Drink from the chalice. You will be reborn and the land with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval begins to kneel.</context>
      <utterance>But who am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blinding light vanishes, the music drifts away.</context>
      <utterance>You are my lord and King. You are Arthur.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir Kay stands by the vast fireplace where a small fire burns, and only now looks up and is aware of Perceval.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't know how empty was my soul until it was filled.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perceval, you have returned!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready my knights for battle; they will ride with their King once more. I have lived through others far too long! Lancelot carried my honor and Guenevere my guilt. My knights have fought my causes. Mordred carries my sins. Now, at last, I will rule.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away. No man is allowed beyond these doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old nun is amazed and starts pushing open the many bolts, mumbling and agitated.</context>
      <utterance>I am Arthur.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She weeps.</context>
      <utterance>Guenevere, accept my forgiveness, and put your heart to rest. We have suffered to long. I have always loved you, and I still love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I loved you much, as King, and sometimes as husband, but one cannot gaze too long at the sun in the sky.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, my wife, if you can. I was not born to live a man's life, but to be the stuff of future memory. The fellowship was a brief beginning, a fair time that cannot be forgotten; and because it will not be forgotten, that fair time may come again. Now once more I must ride with my knights to defend what was, and the dream of what could be.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUENEVERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She draws back the covers of her pallet, and there is Excalibur. Arthur is overwhelmed by emotion; he can barely speak</context>
      <utterance>I have kept it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kneels before her and kisses her thigh. She gazes off, remembering the life of long ago. He rises and looks off into her eyes, unable to find the words; he finally does.</context>
      <utterance>I never dared to hope all these years that it was in your keeping.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes Excalibur by the hilt and exits.</context>
      <utterance>I have often thought that in the hereafter of our lives, when I owe no more to the future and can be just a man, that we may meet, and you will come to me and claim me as yours, and know that I am your husband. It is a dream I have...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur smiles hiding the hurt. He points to an open pit, a huge devastation.</context>
      <utterance>It is only me and my son. All other knights of the dukedom have rallied to Mordred.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What horror is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mordred, sir. He digs for precious metals, with which he buys the loyalty of men at arms, binding them to his side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He falls on his knees in front of the stone, tired, between thinking and dreaming, and he bangs his mailed fist against it.</context>
      <utterance>I am outnumbered ten to one by Mordred's forces. Merlin, I need you at my side as you were once, my friend, to give me courage. There are no war tricks that will fool Mordred. He was weaned on blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than I ever did, I need you now. Where are you, Merlin? Is it true that Morgana has trapped you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hand ruffles the King's hair. He turns, and is face to face with Merlin, standing over him. Arthur looks at him without surprise, as though the intervening years never were. Merlin begins to laugh his hideous giggle. Arthur rises.</context>
      <utterance>What is this place? It is rumored Merlin, that you drew your power from these circles...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet. You'll wake the men, and they must fight tomorrow for their very lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I have heard noises and echoes through the stones...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this place, Merlin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He limps affectedly and stretches with exaggerated pain.</context>
      <utterance>It is like a tree. The roots of the stones spread out across the land and they draw on the thoughts and actions of men. Like sap those human matters course through the stones feeding the stars that are the leaves of the tree. And the stars whisper back to men the future course of events.  But the earth is being torn apart, its metals stolen, and the balance is broken and the lines of power no longer converge. In fact, I nearly didn't make it in one piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have you been these many years? Is it true that Morgana--</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Stories... You brought me back. Your love brought me back. Back to where you are now, in the land of dreams...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin smiles, turns and leaves, heading for Arthur's camp, giggling. Arthur starts off after him and awakens from the dream when he walks into one of the stones. It takes him a moment to realize that Merlin has vanished.</context>
      <utterance>Is this a dream? Tell me, Merlin!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries away toward the camp.</context>
      <utterance>Merlin?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merlin, will I live...?  ...I was dreaming...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of Merlin?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. He spoke to me. He said I would fight bravely tomorrow. I have never dreamed of Merlin before.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dreamed of him too... Merlin lives! He lives in our dreams now, in that dark and shadowy place that is as strong and real as this more solid one. He speaks to us from there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have returned, enchantress. You are beautiful, magnificent. Have you used up all the magic you stole from me to keep yourself young? Have you any magic left to do battle with Merlin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You provoke me, Merlin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merlin steps back, grandiose and melodramatic.</context>
      <utterance>What's behind that beauty? A wizened, cold-hearted snake.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his staff.</context>
      <utterance>You are a snake about to strike!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lowers the staff with dreamlike slowness and she slinks right up to him.</context>
      <utterance>And I am the staff that drives the snake back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She winds her fluttering hands around the staff, and the shadows they cast upon the tent give the illusion of licking flames.</context>
      <utterance>Burning with the fire of desire, I am the flames that consume the staff to ashes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the cloudburst that quenches the flames.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the desert, where water disappears--</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--I am the sea, which covers the desert forever under its weight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs at her cleverness.</context>
      <utterance>--I am the fog and mists that rise up from the sea, escaping...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fog and mist! You couldn't be that. You don't have enough magic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fog is rising, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises and goes out with the lieutenant.</context>
      <utterance>That cannot be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mordred enters his mother's tent.</context>
      <utterance>My mother has a sense for such things. She said there would be no fog.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgana, withered, old, lies dead in the bed, wisps of smoke rising from within her ruptured body.</context>
      <utterance>...Mother?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kay draws his sword in salute, elated.</context>
      <utterance>Kay, you will lead the attack. Perceval, you will stay with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spurs forward, while Arthur reins to a halt, watching him disappear. Perceval and a few knights stay behind and surround the King.</context>
      <utterance>Be cautious, my brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the swirling fog, clash of arms follows clash of arms. There is confusion, for each knight is unable to see if he is fighting friend or foe until they are upon each other. The battle becomes a series of vicious duels, a knight in silver armor against a knight in black-burnished armor, just glimpsed in the fog that is alive with the clang of sword on shield, the pounding of hooves, the cries of the dying. Squires drag away their wounded knights, their young faces pale at the sight of the carnage. Kay is unhorsed but picks himself up and mounts a riderless horse, rejoining the combat although he is bleeding.</context>
      <utterance>In this battle there is one thing I must do, that no one else can. Find Mordred and kill him. Ahead, the horrible din of joined battle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kay is glimpsed fighting on foot, hurt, barely holding his own, but then the sight is hidden in the fog. Kay overcomes his opponent and stops to catch his breath. He is amazed by what he sees. A knight, in old, battle-scarred armor whose pieces don't match, cuts down the knights in black in foray after foray, wheeling and turning in a brilliant and ruthless spectacle of martial arts. He fights without a shield, a lance in his left hand and sword in his right. Kay moves away in search of Arthur. Arthur and Perceval watch the lone knight meting out death with such terrible beauty, weaving in and out of the fog.</context>
      <utterance>There are too many on Mordred's side. We cannot hold out much longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can be no other.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spurs his horse forward to join him, but Perceval is quick to stop him.</context>
      <utterance>Lancelot?... It is Lancelot!</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, my lord. We seek Mordred.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kay rises onto a fresh horse and gallops away.</context>
      <utterance>I will join him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has anyone seen Lancelot?</utterance>
   <speaker>SQUIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur rushes off, Perceval following on horseback. Lancelot is mortally wounded, blood flowing from his abdomen, his eyes open but his gaze dead. Arthur falls to his side.</context>
      <utterance>He lies over there, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But there is no one now except the dead and wounded, and Perceval, who dismounts to watch over the King, sword drawn. Desperate, Arthur stops the wound with his hand. Lancelot's eyes are sightless, but tears spill from them.</context>
      <utterance>Squire! Here!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arthur.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tears off a piece of his tunic and staunches the wound with it.</context>
      <utterance>Lancelot, I will save you... Don't die.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My salvation is to die a Knight of the Round Table.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are that and much more. You are its greatest knight, you are what is best in men. Now we will be together--</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur takes Lancelot in his arms and rests his lips against the knight's brow.</context>
      <utterance>--It is the old wound, that has been opened. I have always known it would be the gateway to my death, for it has never healed. Let my heart do its job, my King, and pump me empty...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCELOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lies, closing his eyes, unable to look at Lancelot.</context>
      <utterance>Guenevere, has she come to you, is she Queen again?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A boyish smile settles over the features of Lancelot's face, and he dies. Arthur holds him to his breast, his eyes shut tight. A strong wind rises. Perceval kneels beside Arthur.</context>
      <utterance>She is, Lancelot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fog is lifting. Only we remain alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elsewhere on the battlefield, Mordred searches the dead, accompanied only by his lieutenant, who turns over the bodies of Arthur's knights.</context>
      <utterance>But for Mordred. Where is Mordred?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of Arthur's knights reaches out blindly for help. Mordred crushes his skull underfoot. The shaft of his huge lance is caked with blood, as are his hands. Arthur and Perceval see Mordred and his lieutenant, and the King restrains Perceval from going forward.</context>
      <utterance>Where is Arthur?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shield on his left arm, and Excalibur in his right, he starts toward Mordred.</context>
      <utterance>No, Perceval. Now it is time for me to raise my sword.  Mordred, prepare to meet your death.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mordred advances forward, the huge spear in both hands and parallel to the ground. Arthur goes straight for him, shield ready to receive the blow. Mordred keeps walking, his arms now tensed back and ready to strike. Once they are within weapon's reach of each other, Mordred dashes forward and thrusts the spear. It glances off Arthur's shield, slides under his hauberk and penetrates the King's body, and so powerful was the blow that the blade pierces him right through. Mortally wounded, Arthur's scream of pain becomes a horrible war cry, and he drives himself forward with all the strength he has along the spear shaft almost to Mordred's hands. Mordred is knocked back and to the ground and Arthur presses down on him, the butt of the spear pinning Mordred. Arthur lifts Excalibur. Mordred attempts to free himself, as the blade of Excalibur descends upon him and cuts through metal, flesh and bone. Mordred's head falls to the ground, rolling away. Mordred's lieutenant flees. Perceval races to Arthur's side, and supports the King who has fallen on his knees. Arthur speaks through the pain:</context>
      <utterance>I wait for you, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval holds the King tight to himself with one arm, while with the other he draws the shaft through and out of Arthur's body. Arthur sags but doesn't fall. Perceval begins to remove his armor to get at the gaping wounds. The King speaks slowly, softly, from outside his own pain-wracked body.</context>
      <utterance>Draw the spear from me. Do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is one thing left to do... Excalibur... And you must do it, Perceval. Leave my wounds, I command you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cannot--</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval, stunned by the command, doesn't move.</context>
      <utterance>--Take Excalibur. Find a pool of calm water and throw the sword into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval picks up the sword, mounts his horse and rides inland. Arthur watches him go, struggling with the pain, still kneeling, and then his head falls to his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Obey me, Perceval. You must act for me. It is my last order as your King. Do it, and be back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you threw it in, what did you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King looks at him with piercing power. Perceval blurts it out.</context>
      <utterance>...I saw nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My King, I couldn't do it. Excalibur cannot be lost. Other men--</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval leaves once more. The daylight is failing, the sun is near the horizon over the sea, bursting through clouds.</context>
      <utterance>--By itself it is only a piece of steel. Its power comes from he who wields it. For now there is no one. Do as I have ordered!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sun slips below the horizon. Night is falling, and the wind whips the wavecrests. He turns from the sea and wades back.</context>
      <utterance>Arthur! Will you return?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops at the edge of the water. In the uncertain light sky and sea become one. He draws the chalice out of a pouch on his saddle, and he holds it up before him.</context>
      <utterance>All the knights of the Round Table are dead. Excalibur is returned. Arthur is gone. Maybe he lives, maybe he will return...</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wind swirls and whistles mysteriously in the hollow of the cup. Music grand and melancholic grows from it. The chalice, etched in starlight, is the last thing that is taken from sight in the enfolding darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Only I remain, and this...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
