<movie id="614" title="eXistenZ">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to face an as-yet-unseen audience.</context>
      <utterance>Written like this. One word. Small e. Capital X, capital Z.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We now see Levi's audience, about seventy-five people, some standing, some sitting on plastic folding chairs. They are of very mixed age and type, but they all cheer and applaud enthusiastically. We are in the central playing area of a small, deconsecrated country church, and Levi performs on a broad, low, carpeted plywood dais. At the far end of the dais, a man and a woman - assistants to Levi - are carefully laying out about two dozen plastic modules that look somewhat like high-tech ski boots.</context>
      <utterance>eXistenZ. It's new, it's from Antenna Research, and it's here, right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A delighted stir from the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Wittold Levi, my friends call me Witt - and I'm the project manager for eXistenZ. I recognize some familiar faces - that's all right, that's all right. We won't throw you out. We encourage consumer loyalty, and we want you to help us with our product testing. We're a team, Antenna and you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those of you who have come to our invited seminars before will know that I normally lead the group through our new games, but</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>An unbelieving, excited stir. Could it really be?</context>
      <utterance>tonight, it won't be me. No, for the test launch of eXistenZ by Antenna, we have brought you a seminar leader who is rather special.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The small crowd is now tremendously excited, wide-eyed, murmuring, one or two have actually gotten on their knees.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it is. The world's greatest game designer is here, in person, to lead you, the first test enclave, through her newest creation, eXistenZ by Antenna...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Levi moves to the edge of the crowd, works his way into it until he has reached a small, unobtrusive figure who up to now has hardly been noticed. She stands next to a security guard who is dressed in a suit and tie but carries an electronic wand of some sort. His name-tag identifies him as Ted Pikul (rhymes with "Michael", not with "pickle"), and we will see more of him later. As Levi takes her hand and gently leads her out of the crowd, her fans applaud softly, touch her hem. They part like water as she passes amongst them, clutching her own personal game-pod case with both hands. She mounts the dais like a blind person led by her seeing-eye dog. Allegra Geller, early thirties, conservatively dressed, is bright, acutely aware, but wary and controlled. When she speaks, she is deliciously, sexily shy, serious, melodic.</context>
      <utterance>I give you, the Game-Pod Goddess herself - Allegra Geller!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world of games is in a kind of a trance. People are programmed to accept so little, but the possibilities are so great.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context>Excited murmurings from the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>You probably thought that tonight, we were going to test a new game that I designed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Confused, slightly disappointed mutterings.</context>
      <utterance>But there is no new game to test, at least, not in the usual sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd's spirit rises again. Levi steps forward, smiling, playing off the renewed energy.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, it's going to be much better than you expected, because eXistenZ is not just a game. It's an entirely new game system. Antenna Research and I developed it together - the eXistenZ System by Antenna - and it involves a whole lot of new toys, which you are going to be the first to try out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Levi turns to the chalkboard and writes the word.</context>
      <utterance>MetaFlesh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Levi turns again to the chalkboard.</context>
      <utterance>Written like this. One word. Capital M, capital F. MetaFlesh is what our new toys are made of - the MetaFlesh Game-Pod, only from Antenna Research. It connects with any industry standard bioport, which I know you all have or you wouldn't be here...  .using, however, a very non- standard connecting device which we call...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Levi writes the word out and then turns back to his by-now- salivating audience.</context>
      <utterance>.we call an UmbyCord. Spelled like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you can tell I started off as a schoolteacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>4</speaker>
      <mode>APPRECIATIVE CHUCKLES</mode>
      <context>With a theatrical flourish, Levi whirls around to face his two assistants, who have finished laying out their devices on the back table and are now standing crisply at attention at either end of it.</context>
      <utterance>But I never had anything quite so fun or so revolutionary to teach as what Allegra and I are going to teach you all tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are the MetaFlesh Game-Pods by Antenna Research ready?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how many of these precious prototypes did we manage to bring with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Levi's face clouds slightly. The audience does not hear the following exchange.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-one, Mr. Levi.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode>SOTTO VOCE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-one? I thought we had an even two dozen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>unhealthy.</context>
      <utterance>The first three we opened were...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Any chance that some of the others...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think we're clean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In response, the fan thrusts a card at him. Pikul takes the card, a complex invitation card which includes a holographic photo of the fan under which floats his name, Joel Dichter. Dichter anxiously looks past Pikul into the depths of the church, nervously adjusting the vinyl case slung over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it. Not so fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Did I miss the port-in?</context>
      <utterance>Oh, god. I hope I'm not too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just the first wave. You can be part of the second wave.  OK, Joel Dichter. Put your arms up. I have to scan you. Metal and heavy synthetics can't come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICHTER</speaker>
      <mode>INCREDULOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A weapons check?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's in this case?</context>
      <utterance>More for recording devices. Lotta money invested in these games. Industrial espionage happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brought my game-pod. It's got original Marway tissue architecture. It's kind of obsolete but I was hoping,...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DICHTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Pikul uses his wand to scan the vinyl case, then opens the zipper and feels around. In the case is a more solid, rubbery version of the new MetaFlesh pods.</context>
      <utterance>even though I couldn't afford the Antenna Fifteen upgrade, I figured out a method of virtual porting that I thought might...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dichter suddenly spots Geller on the dais. He almost faints.</context>
      <utterance>You won't need it tonight. Everything's provided for.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Migod! Is that who I think it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>.PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's her. She's something, isn't she?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why would a star like her come to a product seminar in a little one-horse town like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is where the real people live, Joel. Her real fans, like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dichter has scanned OK. Pikul waves him into the church to join the spectators who will form the second wave and re- locks the door. On the dais, in the center of the circle of linked game players, Levi nods at Geller.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, you said it. Just like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's in order. Are you ready, Allegra?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>PUMPED</mode>
      <context>There is giddy laughter in the room. Geller looks at every player-in the circle as Levi steps down off the platform and retires to the far edge of the small, watching throng.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. This is my favourite part.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the giddy laughter goes a touch nervous, uncertain, but it's too late. Geller depresses a nipple-like protuberance on the game-pod on her lap, and all the players close their eyes and go rigid, like members of a seance who have suddenly been contacted by the spirit world. The pods in their laps begin a rhythmic, peristaltic rippling. At the edge of the crowd, Pikul sidles up to Levi.</context>
      <utterance>I'm ready to download eXistenZ by Antenna Research into you all now. I'm warning you, it's going to be a wild ride, but don't panic no matter what happens. I'll see you all back here in no time at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>TO LEVI</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She seems to be very shy. It never occurred to me that a big star would be shy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She spends most of her time alone in a room designing her games. I think she'd like it best if she never had to show them to anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? She doesn't enjoy all the adulation?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She hates having to port in with her fans. It's too intimate.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why does she do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We make her do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEVI '</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode>SUDDENLY SUSPICIOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you with us or did an independent security company send you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Oh, I'm with your own management training program.  I want to end up in marketing and public relations.  The only thing I know about security is how to switch this thing on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode>SATISFIED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, for example, we've spent a fortune developing eXistenZ, but we all know it's a risky project. She might have to make changes. It's the only way we can convince her that there might be a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>PUZZLED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A problem with her new game?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>eXistenZ is a lot more than a game.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I heard that.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right, it's a game system.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we're worried that it's too intellectual, too complex, too weird, too artsy. That argument ; never bothers her until she faces her fans. She hates to be rejected in the flesh, so we make her come out sometimes to take the heat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>ADMIRINGLY</mode>
      <context>A strange, choral humming begins to fill the church. Pikul and Levi turn their attention to the dais, where the fans rock and sway with the pulsing of the pods in their laps.</context>
      <utterance>4 I've heard that she's very sensitive.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context>Haltingly, but gamely, Pikul tries to hum along.</context>
      <utterance>It's the new Antenna Research theme song. We thought this would be a good way to launch it. Everybody who plays eXistenZ is going to be very familiar with that tune.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Levi helps him out, and soon the whole room is humming along happily, warmed by the Antenna Research corporate theme song. The whole room, that is, except for Joel Dichter, who, at the edge of the dais, is more concerned with fumbling around in the vinyl pod-case hanging from his shoulder. In the case, we watch as Dichter tears open his obsolete game-pod to reveal a bizarre weapon, a pistol made of bone and gristle, almost like the half-decayed body of a small mammal - whose snout is the barrel, whose rigid hind leg is the trigger. Dichter takes his weapon out of its case, shakes off a few gelatinous strips of game-pod flesh, and steps up onto the dais. Pikul is the first to notice this. He glances at Levi, who's still blissed out and humming, then launches himself awkwardly through the crowd. Now in the middle of the circle, Dichter makes his way towards the blissfully unsuspecting Geller, raising his weapon as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>Catchy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death to eXistenZ! Death to Antenna Research! Death to the demoness Allegra Geller!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>TO DICHTER</mode>
      <context>Dichter turns to see Pikul stumbling through the small crowd, scrambling onto the dais. Distracted, Dichter hurriedly raises his weapon again and fires it at Geller. The first shot hits her in the shoulder and spins her off her chair, which collapses over her and takes the second bullet on its seat rim. The circle of players on the dais moans as one, swoons and jostles: they are all feeling the neural surge of Geller's traumatized nervous system. Peeking out from under her folding chair, Geller's eyes are wide with fear and confusion. She clutches her shoulder without being aware of it. Blood seeps in between her fingers Now Levi and his two assistants scramble onto the platform to get at Dichter, who fires wildly, hitting two of the players nearest Geller. The circle of players immediately goes spastic, screaming and twitching and dropping to the ground and writhing. Many of them are clutching their shoulders in the same spot as Geller, sympathy pain transmitting through their UmbyCords. Pikul manages to tackle Dichter, then starts whacking at him with the security wand. Dichter twists around and raises his weapon at Pikul, who immediately backs off in terror. But before Dichter can pull the trigger, the two assistants produce small, normal pistols from hidden holsters and empty their clips into the prostrate Dichter. Dichter manages to squeeze off one last shot at the approaching Jevi, hitting him squarely in the chest. Levi goes down and is lost amongst the jostling feet. The watching fans pile onto the dais and begin to help the players unplug from the game-pods which are obviously causing them distress. Three of the players attack the dying Dichter, dragging their game-pods after them, kicking at whatever part of him they can find in the confused mass of bodies. in the turmoil, Pikul is knocked to the ground. Amid the stamping, sliding feet, he finds himself lying across the stricken-Levi. Levi clutches Pikul desperately.</context>
      <utterance>No! Don't do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get her out of here! Save her! There might be more of them! Go on!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Me take her?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>SCREAMS</mode>
      <context>To his surprise, Geller laughs a dazed, hearty laugh.</context>
      <utterance>She's coming with me! I'm responsible for her! She's supposed to come with me!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I? With you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul pulls her to her feet, but she immediately dives back to the floor to find her game-pod and UmbyCord.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're coming with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's take my limo.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>WILD</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why no?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't trust the driver!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They cross the road and jump in the Defender. Frances, the driver, sixtyish, a retired lady farmer who moonlights, is apprehensive.</context>
      <utterance>You drive, idiot!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's goin' on in there?</context>
      <utterance>What's the commotion, Miss Geller? Say, are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need this vehicle, and we need it without you. But with the keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller pulls the weird gun out of an astonished Pikul's pocket. She points it at Frances.</context>
      <utterance>I can't do that. I can't abandon my vehicle.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out, Frances. You can say you were hijacked.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode>CHUCKLES</mode>
      <context>Geller fires two shots. One rips a hole in Frances's headrest.</context>
      <utterance>It'll take more than a dead squirrel to get me out of this seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to push the shift lever down to get it into reverse.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drive off down the country road, leaving Frances in the dust.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Frances.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I normally like the countryside, don't you? Normally, the country is relaxing and calm.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only if you don't really know what's going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is great stress and anger and violence in the countryside. Thousands of life forms all screaming ME ME ME and trying to kill and dominate and devour the other life forms. It's terrifying and exhausting.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>LAMELY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I like the countryside.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good, `cause you might end up spending a lot of time here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. If you go back home to the city, they'll probably be waiting for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. My assassins. They'd want to have a little talk with you about where I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping that was just one crazy guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear the way he screamed at me? He wasn't alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller goes silent.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody likes a conspiracy. It's more satisfying than just one crazy guy doing one crazy thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what are we going to do out here? Do you know your way around? You know any country people?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not country people. Games people. The countryside's full of games development people, project co- ordinators, little factories - you name it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's weird. I never knew that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The city's full of bad microwaves, bad thermals, bad electro-optics. You can't shield from it anymore. You can't get true readings. The whole industry moved out of the city years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you know your way around. We can hide out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. But it seems I have some enemies I didn't know I had. "Death to Allegra Geller." How'd you like to hear somebody with a gun screaming, "Death to Ted Pikul"?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow.  Hey, how'd you know my name?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're labelled.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know how to fire that, gun? I've never seen anything like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has a trigger. I pulled it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul glances at her. He hits a pothole and she bounces around in her seat, exposing her far shoulder to him. Her shirt is soaked with blood.</context>
      <utterance>Later. I think I'm gonna use it in my next game. If there ever is a next game.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an urgent buzzing from somewhere in Pikul's breast pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Migod, you're bleeding. I forgot you got hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my pink-fone. I'm not sure I should answer it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul pulls the pink-fone - it's soft surgical plastic, palm-sized - out of his pocket. When he squeezes it open, a diffuse pink light swells up from deep inside it.</context>
      <utterance>Answer it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>INTO PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted Pikul.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - PAUSE</mode>
      <context>Geller grabs the pink-tone from him. She fumbles around with it, trying to find the power button. She accidentally summons up a read-out, which she pauses to look at. What she sees makes her glance up at Pikul.</context>
      <utterance>You're kidding me. You're kidding me! God. 1 can't believe it. I can't do that. No, how can I do that? Well, I'm not really sure where we are because...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller finds the power button and pushes it. The pink inner light flutters out. She unceremoniously throws the pink-tone out the window. It lands in a rain ditch full of frogs.</context>
      <utterance>What? Can I have my pink-tone back?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>IN SHOCK</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do that for? That was our lifeline to civilization.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a rangefinder. As long as you have that, they know where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They? You mean head office?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard what Levi said to you. He said, "We have enemies in our own house." He said it as he was dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>FLUSTERED</mode>
      <context>Maybe he went unconscious...</context>
      <utterance>I don't think he died. I mean, do you? I think he maybe fainted...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was Alex Kindred, head of publicity and marketing, at Antenna HQ...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>WISTFUL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.on that very expensive pink- fone you threw away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>DEEP SIGH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said that some bizarre fanatical group called the Anti- eXistenZialists has put a price of 5 million dollars on your head, payable to anybody who kills you. It's been released to all the media now. Everybody knows about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>IN DISBELIEF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anti-existentialists?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Anti-eXistenZialists. Capital X, capital Z. They somehow found out about eXistenZ and they want to kill you for creating it. They say that the eXistenZ game system will "finally destroy reality", or something totally nuts like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>STRANGELY SATISFIED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It makes sense to you? You're not suprised?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear things. It's hard to surprise me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what else?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kindred said that I'm your bodyguard and the company is holding me totally responsible for your safety.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pikul, why don't you have a gun with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not armed. They told me you were my security but you have no weaponry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you that? I'm just a marketing trainee. My clinic master thought I'd learn something about marketing if I moonlighted as a security guard on one of your test previews.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck. I'm marked for death and they send me on the road with a PR nerd.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus! Marked for death!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't sweat it, Pikul. I'll handle it. We just have to disappear for a while. And right now, we have to stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>DEADPAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we can have an intimate moment together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it. Wow. Did somebody bite you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul holds the tooth out to her, but she just glances at it, then rummages around in her MetaFlesh game-pod bag.</context>
      <utterance>What I just dug out of you. It's a tooth. A human tooth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller pulls the strange weapon out of the bag. After a moment of study, she expertly pops the magazine out of the grip. The gristly magazine is packed with teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme see that weirdo pistol.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look - this one's got a cavity.</context>
      <utterance>Yep. The bullets are human teeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That thing was designed to get past any kind of metal or synthetics detector. It's all flesh and bone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose the smaller caliber pistols would have to fire baby teeth. The tooth fairy could go I into the arms business.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>INCREDULOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy really came there tonight just to kill you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whole gamesworld is in a kind of trance.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I remember you said that at the church.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>expectations. They have no idea what amazing things could be theirs.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you just now? What were you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wandering through eXistenZ - the new system, I mean.  I like it in there. Of course, without another player you're only a tourist. It's frustrating.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller gets up and goes over to Pikul. She pulls up his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Why won't you let me contact Antenna? They've got to be going crazy, wondering what's happened to you. I mean, it's not like we've done something wrong. We just ran because we didn't know how many of them there were, right? I think we owe it to Antenna to let them know you're all right, to get them to send somebody to help you who knows what he's doing... And besides, I can't... I can't just keep doing this, whatever it is, you know, forever, not having any idea when it's going to be...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul shrugs his shirt back down, starts tucking it in.</context>
      <utterance>Where's your bioport? Don't tell me you were never fitted. I can't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I was never fitted with a bioport. What do you care?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're hoping to get into the biz and you've never played one of my games. You've never played any game. That means you have no idea</utterance>
   <speaker>%</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>what a genius I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>LAMELY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My clinic master told me I don't need to play a game to know how to sell it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. Posturing. You don't play my games, you don't work for Antenna Research, I'll make sure of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I've been dying to play your games. But I have this - phobia about having my body penetrated - surgically. You know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not so sure I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting a bioport fitted... I dunno. I can't do it. It's too freaky. Makes my skin crawl.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, c'mon. They just pop your spine with a little hydro-gun. Shoot the port-plug into it. They do it at malls, like getting your ears pierced.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure. With only an infinitesimal chance of permanent spinal paralysis. I've read all about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses, then moves very close to him. She breathes her words slowly, intimately, into his ear.</context>
      <utterance>It's your chosen profession, geek.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>HOTLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's an intimacy involved in playing eXistenZ that is beyond description. It has to be experienced. And frankly, the two-player version is the most exquisitely intense. Wouldn't you like to play with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah, of course, but... Let me, uh, let me call Antenna...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They wouldn't want to talk to you if they knew you had never had a bioport installed. It's company policy, you know. They want you to be passionate about your work.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>VERY SEDUCTIVE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, once you're ported, there's no end to the games you can play.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>HE'S SWEATING</mode>
      <context>Geller sighs, then switches into her explaining-the-facts- of-life-to-a-child mode.</context>
      <utterance>You can't seriously want to play games now. Not here. Not while we're being hunted down by crazy people. _</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul takes a look. The pod is, in fact, quivering like a terrified hamster.</context>
      <utterance>My baby here took a huge hit in the church, Pikul. You see how she's quivering?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It... she, yes, she's quivering.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT' D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>out just as the game architecture was being downloaded from her to all those slave pods... that's a very vulnerable time for her. She could be crying out for help right here, right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>CHOKING UP</mode>
      <context>Are you friendly, or are you not?</context>
      <utterance>The only way I can tell if everything's OK - the game's not been contaminated, the pod, my baby, is not about to be crippled for life because of my negligence - the only way is to play eXistenZ with somebody friendly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context>(he might have found a way</context>
      <utterance>Sure, all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else I can do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Gas, you could check your bioport-plugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The what? The sparkplugs?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me. My friend here has a bioport problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode>COOL</mode>
      <context>Geller smiles a knowing smile.</context>
      <utterance>A bioport, now, that's a sort of a hole in your spine, isn't it? Lotta assholes `round here, but that's generally it. I don't know why you'd be talking to me about that, lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gas looks at her closely for the first time. His eyes widen in disbelief. He pulls a greasy wallet out of his overalls and flips out the card holders. Amongst various family photos, hot rod photos, fishing photos, is a photo of Allegra Geller clipped from a glossy magazine. Under the photo is the legend "Genius In A Game-Pod". Gas takes her hand in his and kisses it.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allegra Geller. You changed my life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was your life like before?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before it was changed by Allegra Geller.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I operated a gas station.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you still operate a gas station, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only on the most pathetic level of reality. Geller's work liberated me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liberated?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever play her game ArtGod? One word, capital A, capital G?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a bioport, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gas zips up his fresh overalls.</context>
      <utterance>"Thou, the player of the game, art God." Very spiritual. Funny, too. God, the artist. The mechanic.  Funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>UNEASY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are sterile, are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not to worry. They way they set things up, you could fire in a bioport in a slaughterhouse and not generate an infection.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why the clean overalls?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a mental thing. Helps me focus. The one thing you don't want to do is miss with the stud- finder.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode>BIG SMILE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, the mechanic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We call this thing a stud-finder.' It locates the spot on your spine where the x intersects with the y. We don't want to be even a micron out of whack. That's when you get troubles. It's a little radar/sonar/laser thingee. Marks you with a special range-finding dye.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never say dye.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lift up your shirt and turn around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, that didn't hurt, did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gas pulls the bioport insertion gun out of another drawer, this time a locked wooden one bolted under his metal-topped work bench. It is a scary thing, like a hydraulic jack designed by Giger, only smaller.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't expect that to hurt. I expect the next part to hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's what I expect will hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never crippled anyone yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many have you done?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three. Well, you'll be the third.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on, Gas?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, he's acting like I'm attackin' him. People usually pay me.to do this, you know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That swelling doesn't last for long. Tomorrow, you won't even notice it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul tries to get up from the wingback chair and promptly collapses into the arms of Geller and Gas.</context>
      <utterance>I love it. Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>PANIC-STRICKEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on? I can't walk!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they ease Pikul into a sitting position in the chair, Gas almost drops the insertion gun which he has been holding in one hand. He leans it against the wingback chair, and Pikul notices blood and flecks of skin on Gas's work gloves.</context>
      <utterance>The procedure comes with its own epidural, just like when you have a baby. Kinda like instant paralysis from the waist down? That's why it didn't hurt you. It'll wear off in about twenty minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking more like a butcher than a mechanic.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gas strides off towards the washroom with an air of great satisfaction. Geller eases her game-pod out of its case and starts to attach its two-player, Y-shaped UmbyCord to it.</context>
      <utterance>Things do get kinda confused these days, don't they? I'm gonna go wash up. You two make yourselves at home.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have to wait for the swelling to go down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While I'm paralysed?</context>
      <utterance>You're going to port into me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted to play my game, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Here? Now?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I did, and I do, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts up his shirt to reveal the new bioport. It already looks a bit less angry than it did before. Geller caresses it, prods it, plays with it. Then she takes out a little bottle of WD-40 and sprays it around and into the port.</context>
      <utterance>It's an instant-on world, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that for? It feels cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New ports are sometimes a bit tight. Wouldn't want to hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come bioports don't get infected? I mean, they open right into your body...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to what you're saying, Pikul. Don't be ludicrous.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>VERY NERVOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think you could call me Ted?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller gently works her UmbyJack into Pikul's bioport. She locks her eyes onto his, then squeezes her game-pod's ON teat. Instantly, her pod convulses and begins to flash and spark and crackle. White electronic smoke seeps from its crevices and a kind of bioelectronic fat sputters from its pores. Geller leaps up from the arm of the chair and rips her UmbyJack out of Pikul's spine. He can't feel it, but the furious force of her move twists him in his chair.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe afterwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>FURIOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, Pikul! I can't believe this! I trusted you and you blew my pod! You must have neural- surged!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>IN DESPAIR</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I jacked you into my pod and you obviously panicked. Now it's totally fucked! This is a disaster!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I.. I was nervous, but I didn't panic.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>FIGHTING HYSTERIA</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was forced to trust you and you panicked and you neural-surged, and you blew my pod.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can get a new pod...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pikul, in this pod is the only, the original version of eXistenZ, an entire game system that cost thirty-eight million to develop, not including pre-release marketing costs. And I'm locked outside of my own game! I can't get it out, or me in!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you serious? This is the only version that exists?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller uses her sleeve to clean the drool off the pod with tragic gentleness, as though it were an injured child.</context>
      <utterance>Security is everything these days. It's the only one and its stuck inside and it's your fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've devoted my five most passionate years to this strange little creature. And I've never regretted it, Pikul, because I knew that it was the only thing that could give my life any meaning...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gas strolls into the garage, still wearing his work gloves, which now hold an agricultural-looking shotgun. It is levelled at Geller.</context>
      <utterance>But why is it my fault? I'm telling you, I didn't, I did not neural-surge. I didn't. I didn't feel any surging.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul looks at Gas in disbelief. His feet begin to writhe in circles, but he still can't get out of the chair; Geller backs away from Gas, clutching her pod protectively.</context>
      <utterance>It isn't your fault. It's my fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>QUIETLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, Gas, not you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't try to use that bioport again, `cept maybe for a toaster or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're worth a lot of money. If you're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No questions asked.</context>
      <utterance>You know what I'm talking about. It's all over the countryside. Five million for her dead body.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, but... she changed your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup. And now I'm gonna change hers.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>STALLING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But wait... Why did you install a bad port into me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller decides to try another tack. She stops backing away and begins to slowly approach Gas.</context>
      <utterance>Seems there's a big bonus for killing Allegra Geller's latest game, or whatever it is. I think I just did that, didn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But can you kill a person? Can you do that, Gas? Can you kill me? Hide my body. Contact the crazies. Trust them to pay up. Hand over my now-decaying, fucking grotesque corpse. Really expect them to hand over 5 mil cash? Don't you ever go to the fuckin' movies?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gas cocks his shotgun. He's really going to do it. Except that Pikul shoots him right in the mastoid bone, just behind the ear, with the bioport insertion gun. The back of Gas's skull shatters and he goes down hard. Pikul drops the gun and launches himself out of his chair. He falls to his knees beside Gas's body.</context>
      <utterance>I like your script. I want to be in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, I think he's dead. I thought I could just distract him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did distract him.  Plug your toaster into that hole, corpse!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wanted to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's two people in one day who wanted to actually kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never been more popular.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allegra, we need help.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. I've got to get this pod fixed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going skiing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing in the countryside is what it seems. It's all appearance versus reality, and the reality here is something unique.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if somebody comes up here and really wants to ski?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody actually physically skis any more, Pikul. You know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Downhill racing, Austrian Alps.</context>
      <utterance>I've watched some ski shows.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>CONTEMPTUOUSLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace.</context>
      <utterance>My darling Allegra. I am so pleased to see you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiri Vinokur, this is my bodyguard, Ted Pikul.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, yes, I heard the ridiculous story about this fatwa against you. The company is desperately trying to find you. Is it really serious? Are you in danger?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm her bodyguard, then she's in grave danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There have been a couple of attempts on my life already.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode>SHOCKED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! That's unbearable. The company must stop this. They owe you every kind of protection.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if they can do anything about it. It seems to be open season on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR ,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you will be safe here, I can assure you of that. I will contact Antenna right away and have them send some people to come and collect you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiri, no, don't. You mustn't let anybody know we're here unless you have to. I can't be sure that Antenna is completely safe for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller pats her game-pod case.</context>
      <utterance>I understand. Yes. The company draws many eccentric people into its fold. You can hide in one of the guest chalets. As long as you like. I will make sure you get fresh towels...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.and make sure I don't lose everything I have in here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you port into?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pikul's bioport.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? That's what did all the damage?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Allegra says you can fix it.</context>
      <utterance>It was a flawed installation - my first. It... it neural-surged.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It fried some very expensive nerve boards. See? Here. These are kaput. It's a complex thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nerve boards?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We use the nervous systems of specially-bred insects to create the electronic circuits on our motherboards.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode>SMILES</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only Antenna Research has it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. And where do the batteries go?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not kidding. He's a total PR nerd.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>TO PIKUL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ports into you, and you are the power source. Your body, your nervous system. Your energy. When you get tired, run down, it won't run properly.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Landry here will finish up the pod-work. Meanwhile...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode>TO PIKUL</mode>
      <context>Vinokur hauls out a device that looks like a pair of spring- loaded fire tongs.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get that nasty bioport out of you and get a nice, fresh one in there. We have guest chalets out back. You're both welcome to stay. Now where did I put my bioport-plug puller..? Here it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode>TO PIKUL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lie down on that couch and pull up your shirt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It hurts. I think it's infected.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She attempts to jack her pod into his port using the Y- shaped UmbyCord, but he twists away from her.</context>
      <utterance>It's not infected. It's just excited. It wants action.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller sighs, then switches into her explaining-the-facts- of-life-to-a-child mode. They are both aware that they are replaying an earlier moment.</context>
      <utterance>But I really don't think that I want action. Me, I mean. The bearer of the excited bioport. What I want is... not now. Not here. I feel too... too exposed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul swallows nervously, then turns his back to Geller so that she can port in.</context>
      <utterance>My baby here has now taken three major hits, one in the church, one in the gas station, and one on the operating table. The only way I can tell if everything's OK - the game's not been contaminated, the pod's not fucked - is to play eXistenZ with somebody friendly. Are you friendly, or are you not?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me this thing will run off my body's energy?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>PORTING IN</mode>
      <context>Sure enough, he is. Geller deftly twists the second jack into her own bioport and takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>That's how they work. See? You're hummin' along already.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. eXistenZ. Only from Antenna. Here we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>APPREHENSIVE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got a bit of an unfair advantage, don't you? How can I possibly compete with the designer of the system?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller flicks the game-pod nipple, and the chalet begins to melt away around them.</context>
      <utterance>You could beat the guy who invented poker, couldn't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was beautiful. I feel... just like me. Is that kind of transition normal, a kind of smooth dissolve from place to place?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends on the style of the game. You can get jagged, brutal cuts, slow fades, shimmering little morphs...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is amazing. I had no idea. We... we're still ourselves, but we're in the game. Where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's basically a game store I used to hang out in as a kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're ported into a game-pod together, remember? eXistenZ has complete access to both our central nervous systems. Its game architecture will be based on our memories, our anxieties, our preoccupations...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>DISENCHANTED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You keep saying that.  Look at this. Games I've never heard of. Biological Father. Hit By A Car. Viral Ecstasy. Chinese Restaurant.  In Viral Ecstasy, you are a virus invading a specific human body. You create ingenious viral strategies to cope with the efforts of the body's immune system to destroy you..."</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. That reminds me. What precisely is the goal of the game we're playing now? I mean, the rules, the objective... Nobody's ever really said anything about what you have to do in eXistenZ.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The beauty of eXistenZ is that it changes every time you play it. It adapts to the individuals who are actually playing it. The result is that you have to play the game to find out why you're playing the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's kind of cheating, isn't it? Not to say confusing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. It's a much more organic approach to gaming than classic, arbitrary, rule- dominated games. It's the future, Pikul. You'll see how natural it feels.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>DISTRACTED</mode>
      <context>They are looking at a game-pod in a gel-pak that is even weirder than a tissue-pod. It has a logo and a name -</context>
      <utterance>Look at this. Could this be the future too?  Ever see anything like this before?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are delicate. You have to be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I can imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cortical Systematics is the latest and the hottest. Not just a new game, but a new system.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will it work with an industry standard bioport?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Haimische, isn't it? Funky?</context>
      <utterance>I haven't seen you two before, have I? This is my place.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUI,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're new in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Dorsey Nader's Game Emporium. I'm Dorsey Nader. Is there anything I can help you with?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're just looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode>FURTIVELY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have what you're looking for.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nader turns his back on them and walks to the back of the store. He stops at a warped and dirty door, turns, beckons to them urgently, trying not to be noticed by the preoccupied patrons. As Pikul and Geller follow Nader through the door, they do not escape the notice of the sour-faced young cashier, who writes something down hurriedly on a pad with an air of vengeful self-importance.</context>
      <utterance>Follow me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who sent you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>INSTANT RESPONSE</mode>
      <context>Pikul is shocked at his own response. He turns to Geller in horror, worried that he's blown the game already.</context>
      <utterance>It's none of your businesz who sent us. We're here, and that's all that matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, what happened? I didn't mean to say that!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>GIGGLING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your character who said it. It's a kind of schizophrenic feeling, isn't it? But you'll get used to it. There are things that have to be said to advance the plot and establish the characters, and those things get said whether you want to say them or not. Don't fight it. Just go with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But should you be saying that in front of him? Nader?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul does. Nader doesn't seem to have heard him. In fact, he doesn't respond at all other than to hum the Antenna Research corporate-song and tap his fingers repetitively, caught in a small behavioural loop. Geller chuckles at Pikul's confusion.</context>
      <utterance>Look at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>RE NADER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gone into a game loop, he's locked up, and he won't come out of it until you give him a proper game line of dialogue.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is tricky.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Start by repeating your last line. Include his name so he knows you're talking.to him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nader immediately comes out of his loop. He chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>We're here, Dorsey Nader, and that's all that matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul smiles, delighted. Now he takes a deep breath, closes his eyes, relaxes. The line comes.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. That is all tha matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Nader, you said you had what we want. We're waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to need these micro- pods to download your new identities. I assume that you both have had those industry standard bioports you mentioned installed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Here she pauses, looks at Pikul.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course, that's right. We both have bioports.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do, don't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I assumed we did. I mean, here. In the game. Of course, we might not.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Nader goes into game lock-up, Geller lifts up her shirt. Pikul takes a look. Her bioport is there, although slightly rougher, puckered, more organic than in non-game life.</context>
      <utterance>We'd better check.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller grabs Pikul's shirt and lifts it. His is there too.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's there. Looks a little different, but it's there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>TO NADER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, we both have bioports.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode>UNLOCKING</mode>
      <context>Pikul and Geller examine the pak, which bears the Cortical Systematics name and logo. It seems to be a miniature version of their real-life game-pod.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Port in and this'll tell you all you need to know for now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nader gets up to leave, pauses at the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to leave while you finish up here. It wouldn't be good for us all to be seen together.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nader chuckles a very theatrical chuckle, then leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do anything I wouldn't do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I assume that Nader is our entry point into the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Kinda disappointing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nader?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Not a very well-drawn character. And his dialogue was just so-so.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we blame ourselves for that? The bad dialogue? Or would it be bad no matter who was ported in?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The game engine is just getting used to us. It'll get more daring once it warms up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller delicately twists the end of the micro-pod into Pikul's bioport. The micro-pod changes colour, pulses, ripples, and then slowly flows and wriggles its way into Pikul's bioport until it has completely disappeared.</context>
      <utterance>OK. The pods are so small they plug directly into the bioport.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whole pod just disappeared into your back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>PANICKY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It disappeared into my back?! It... it's in my spine? It's winding its way around my spinal cord?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't panic, it's just a game. Do you feel anything yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They change positions. Pikul ports in the micro-pod and it duly crawls its way into Geller's bioport. Tenderly, as though kissing a cut to make it better, Pikul kisses her back, low near her bioport. Geller whirls around with sudden anger.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't. Not a thing. I don't feel a thing. Uh, do you want me to do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONFUSED</mode>
      <context>She pauses, then kisses him on the mouth, hard.</context>
      <utterance>That wasn't me. That was my game character. I wouldn't have done that. Not here, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. Our characters are obviously supposed to jump on each other. Probably to create emotional tension when danger happens. No use fighting it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>FIGHTING IT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about our new identities? Do you feel yours yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>CARESSING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll take care of themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context>Geller stops, sits up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm very worried about my body.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, where are our real bodies? Are they all right? Are they hungry? What if there's danger?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>kissing and caressing</utterance>
   <speaker>AGAIN)</speaker>
      <mode> AGAIN)</mode>
      <context>Just like meditating.</context>
      <utterance>They're just where we left them, sitting quietly, eyes closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>reluctantly kissing and</utterance>
   <speaker>CARESSING BACK)</speaker>
      <mode> CARESSING BACK)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I feel really vulnerable. Disembodied.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin to make seriously hot love amrngst the game paks and cartons of replacement UmbyCords. And then the game store melts away around them.</context>
      <utterance>Don't sweat it. All your senses are still operating. You'll pop right out of the game if there's a problem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul snaps his head up to see a long-haired, morose-looking worker sitting next to him, snickering. Mocking Pikul, he twists his own card around, comically bunching up his work shirt so he can read his own name, which is YEVGENY NOURISH.</context>
      <utterance>Tryin' to remember who you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nourish leans over to squint at Pikul's name tag.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it works! I must be Yevgeny Nourish!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you... you are new to the Trout Farm.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I... I'm... very new. Did you say trout farm?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know - raise baby trout from eggs and then stock the rivers with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>BROAD GESTURE</mode>
      <context>Pikul looks around him. The place is humming, but Geller is still nowhere in sight. The workers are small-town locals o_ a wide range of ages. Pikul looks down at his own hands, which seem to,know what to do: place glue on the boards, glue them down to a resin frame using a template, insert needle-like electrodes into the bodies of certain epoxied insects. The insect boards, Pikul notes, are actually whole insects coated in epoxy and frozen together like a sick collage. At least, here in the game they are. Pikul is now automatically doing flashy moves with the odd materials in front of him with great dexterity. Nourish takes note of this.</context>
      <utterance>Entire place used to be a trout farm. Seems like most everything used to be something else, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I  You might be new but you seem to know what you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>GENUINELY PERPLEXED</mode>
      <context>Nourish moves back to the insect motherboard that he has been working on, then leans over again exactly as he did the first time. It has the effect of an instant replay, but not in slow-motion.</context>
      <utterance>It surprises me more than it surprises you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>WITH ADMIRATION</mode>
      <context>Pikul realizes he hasn't given the right answer. He now just lets it come without thinking.</context>
      <utterance>You might be new but you seem to know what you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nourish unlocks and looks around with a delicate furtiveness.</context>
      <utterance>I, ah... I've been trained by the very best.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>FURTIVE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So have I. Where do you plan to have lunch?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm new here. I have no plans for lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH 11</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suggest the Chinese restaurant in the forest. Everybody knows where it is. Just ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't you be going there too?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have other plans for lunch. But I do suggest that you order the special. And don't take no for an answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nourish turns back to his task and begins to work away as though Pikul didn't exist. Pikul takes this cue to go back to his own board and is soon preoccupied with testing the board's circuits by porting it into a test UmbyCord that uncoils from the center of the bench. His strange reverie, watching himself work on auto- pilot at this bizarre task, is soon interrupted by a worker pushing a canvas and metal cart with bicycle wheels. The worker parks the cart behind Pikul and taps him on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>All right, I'll do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>STARTLED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The worker shuffles off, leaving the cart behind him. Pikul turns to Nourish.</context>
      <utterance>They need this in the back room. They asked for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>GESTURES</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means that they want you in the back room. They need more insect boards for the pod assembly bays.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I just get up and go there?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul gets up to go. Nourish grabs him by the arm and whispers intensely.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'll take care of your incoming boards.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember. The Chinese restaurant for lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I order the special.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GELLER,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul's expression shows that there is a return game line welling up in his mouth, tickling his tongue, perhaps. Perversely, he fights it, but it comes out anyway.</context>
      <utterance>I saw you make contact, Larry Ashen. What did the guy on the .l assembly line say to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told me where to have lunch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul and Geller exchange a look. Pikul shrugs OK.</context>
      <utterance>We have nice sea bass today. Shall I bring it for everyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter looks stunned. The others at their table look distressed. The waiter seems to lock up, almost freeze- framed.</context>
      <utterance>We want the special.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear me, Chinese waiter?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>SLOWLY</mode>
      <context>The waiter unfreezes, smiles grimly.</context>
      <utterance>We want the special.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The special is for special occasions. I cannot give you the special.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul pauses, waiting for the proper game line to materialize in his mouth. Finally, it does. He gestures towards Geller.</context>
      <utterance>But this is a special occasion. It's...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter locks up for a moment, then unfreezes.</context>
      <utterance>It's her birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter walks away. The others at the table get up and move away, drift over to other tables with occasional furtive backward glances at Pikul and Geller.</context>
      <utterance>A birthday is a special occasion. I will therefore bring the special for everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess the special isn't very popular.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you know, really, don't you? You don't have to guess. I mean, it's your game, your little universe.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. You have to understand that, to understand what we've really created with eXistenZ.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me, for example, that you don't know what the special is?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Correct. I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or why we ordered it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ordered it because another game character told you to. That's a clue we can't ignore. But that's just basic games playing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller just looks at him, puzzled. Pikul panics.</context>
      <utterance>I want to put the game on pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>PANICKING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The game can be paused, can't it? I mean, all games can be paused, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, yeah, but why? What's wrong? Aren't you dying to see what's special about the special?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm feeling a little disconnected from my real life. I'm kind of losing touch with the texture of it, you know what I mean? I mean, I actually think there's an element of psychosis involved here. I mean, I don't know where my body really is, or where reality is, what I've actually done, or not done.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a great sign. It means your nervous system is fully engaging with the game architecture. The game is a lot more fun when it starts to feel realer than real.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context>Pikul stands up and screams at the top of his lungs.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>SCREAMS</mode>
      <context>The Chinese restaurant melts away.</context>
      <utterance>eXistenZ is paused!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I do that? I guess I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how does it feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your real life. The one you came back for.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just sitting here, it feels completely unreal. I'm sure you knew that would happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're stuck now, aren't you? You want to go back to the Chinese restaurant because there's nothing happening here. We're safe. It's boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worse than that. I'm not sure here, where we are, is real at all. This feels like the game. And you... you're beginning to t1 feel a bit like a game character to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>SHARP</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Definitely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It feels like we did.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our characters did. I'm sure it would be very different if we did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I'm actually just like that in real life. You got the real Ted Pikul there, in the stockroom of the game store.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you didn't get the real Allegra Geller, I can tell you that. no</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him gently.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. In real life I tend to lose control. It can get messy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context>Pikul looks down at the pod. He flicks the PLAY nipple. The room melts down around them and is replaced by the Chinese restaurant.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the dishes are a variety of cooked reptiles, amphibians, fish and birds, all weirdly mutated and presented in a bizarrely beautiful fashion.</context>
      <utterance>Special order for the birthday girl. Hope you enjoy it very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I've lost my appetite.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A shame. Mutant creatures provide new and previously unimagined taste sensations.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode>SIGNIFICANTLY</mode>
      <context>Geller sees that this is a crucial game moment.</context>
      <utterance>Shall I clear all this away?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter nods.</context>
      <utterance>No, it looks terrific. Thank you. We're happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter leaves. Geller watches him go, suspicious. When she turns back to Pikul, she is shocked to see that he has served out most of the creatures to himself and is avidly stripping the meat off their bones.</context>
      <utterance>Very good. Enjoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pikul, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I find this disgusting but I can't help myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul looks up from his big bowl, which is rapidly filling with creature parts. His fingers are'slimy and sticky, but he doesn't stop, his fingers working expertly on their own.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, good!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good? You think this is good?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's a genuine game urge. It's something that your game character was born to do. Don't fight it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul is now snapping together bits and pieces of bone, gristle and flesh, a grotesque Lego set. When he's finished, he's made a gun very much like the one that was used in the attempted assassination in the church.</context>
      <utterance>I am fighting it, but it isn't doing me any good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Omigod, this looks awfully familiar. You sure this is OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>NOT SURE</mode>
      <context>Now Pikul reaches into his mouth, pulls out a bridge of three teeth - one of them gold-filled - and loads them into the gristly magazine.</context>
      <utterance>It should be OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have that bridge in real life?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not. My teeth are perfect. Don't ask me how I knew this thing was in my mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps the magazine into the handle, then pulls the slide back and releases it so that there is now a toothy round in the chamber. Then with a smile, Pikul points the weapon at Geller.</context>
      <utterance>It probably wasn't until you ordered the special.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>CASUALLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death to the demoness Allegra Geller.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul looks at Geller and sees that there is genuine terror in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>That's not funny!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller grips the edge of her bowl of hot-and-sour soup - the handiest weapon she has.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I couldn't resist. But you know... I do feel the urge to kill someone here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>TENSING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to kill our waiter.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>RELIEVED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well, that makes sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But everything in this game is so realistic. I don't think I really could...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't be able to stop. You might as well enjoy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Free will" is obviously not a big factor in this little world of ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- Pikul spots the waiter making his way across the room towards them, a big smile on his face.</context>
      <utterance>It's like real life - there's just enough to make it interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter arrives at their table.</context>
      <utterance>He's too nice. I won't do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To his surprise, the patrons actually turn back to their meals, albeit with a certain sinister reluctance. Pikul looks around wildly.</context>
      <utterance>St's all right, just a little misunderstanding over the check. Pay no attention and enjoy your meal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the porthole in one of the pair of metal-clad kitchen doors, Geller spots someone wearing a che'f's hat, someone who is wildly beckoning to them.</context>
      <utterance>I feel a serious game urge to get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Through the kitchen! That way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you like the meal I prepared for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It was very... revealing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It certainly was for me. You both passed our little test with flying colours.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did the Chinese waiter have to die?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A waiter hears many things spoken when people are relaxed and eating. A waiter has many opportunities for betrayal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He betrayed you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go out a side door, and find themselves walking along the river that links the Chinese restaurant and the Trout Farm.</context>
      <utterance>He betrayed us. Out this way, quickly!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pools are all alive with strange creatures, mutated fish, amphibians, and, along the small, muddy terraces that border the pools, reptiles. Like the dysfunctional insect at the gas station, these creatures do not work very well. They float and swim belly up, lie on their sides at the bottom of their pools, flop and flounder around, and in general, ostentatiously fail to function.</context>
      <utterance>See there, the breeding pools.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that where you caught today's special?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The restaurant is controlled by us. We raise these mutant creatures as food and that is our cover, but of course, we are also raising them as components for undetectable and hypoallergenic weapons. Right under the noses of our enemies. And speaking of our enemies, it's important that you go back to work at Cortical Systematics. We need to maintain as many agents there as we can. I'll take care of the mess at the restaurant.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Trout Farm is owned by Cortical Systematics?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>SOTTO VOCE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did that come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The game made me do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nourish is also impressed. He smiles broadly, then takes Pikul in his arms and hugs him, then Geller.</context>
      <utterance>I'm impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>PASSIONATE</mode>
      <context>Nourish turns around and walks back-towards the restaurant.</context>
      <utterance>We love you two now, now that you have proven to be true and trustworthy Realists. We'll be in touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Enemies of Reality"? Or does it really mean, enemies of eXistenZ? Are the Realists the game-life version of the Anti- eXistenZialists, desperately want to kill you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't take it too seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you wouldn't. But maybe you should.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL 1</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why is the name Cortical Systematics familiar?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We saw it everywhere in Dorsey Nader's game store, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. So that makes it the game- life version of our own company. Cortical Systematics is equivalent to Antenna Research in the real world.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's probably fair to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, then, do we meekly go back to work and say nothing? It sounds as though Nourish and his Realists are preparing to sabotage the Trout Farm. Before you know it, they'll be planning to assassinate game designers.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're just characters in here. Don't mix your real-life loyalties into it or you'll lose for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what do we do next?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for Dorsey Nader. Is he here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say that again?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cashier glances around the store, then locks the register.</context>
      <utterance>Is Dorsey Nader here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cashier leads them through the store towards the stockroom door. As they move amongst the customers, both Pikul and Geller feel that they are being scutinized carefully by shoppers who turn their eyes away from them at the last moment, so that they can't be absolutely certain. And as for us - have we glimpsed some characters from the game that we have already seen? Possibly even Wittold Levi from the first scene in the church, and Frances the limo driver, and Gas? We aren't positive.</context>
      <utterance>Come with me. He's in the back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nader lies dead, the unnatural purple of his face eerily matched by the veiny purple streaks in the UmbyCord around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>You want him, there he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Migod!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In response, the cashier starts rummaging around on one of the shelves. He soon finds what he was looking for, and turns around to face them. In his hand is a grotesque, slightly chewed gristle gun - the one Pikul assembled in the Chinese restaurant - in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't have killed the Chinese waiter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cashier toys with the gun's claw-like hammer.</context>
      <utterance>He was your contact at the Trout Farm. A damn good man.  His dog brought me this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we were contacted there by Yevgeny Nourish. He seemed to know exactly who we were.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because Nader tipped him off that you were coming. Nader was a mole for Cortical Systematics.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're with the Realist underground.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cashier puts the gun back on the shelf.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I was placed here to keep an eye on Nader.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Nourish isn't our real contact, who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nourish is a double agent for Cortical Systematics. He was working with Nader to subvert the Realist cause, and doing it rather well.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode>SNORTS CONTEMPTUOUSLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After all, he got you to assassinate your own contact. But now you're going to put a stop to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I assume that you both have had spinal port inserts, bioports, installed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode>PASSIONATE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you both realize that neither of you can be buried on hallowed ground because of these... these mutilations? Does your bioport manual tell you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to talk us into having them removed?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. In fact, you would be useless to us without them. We Realists are forbidden to have them, and so we have to use people like you on occasion.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. Are you wanting us to jack a game into our bioports?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Game? No. Not a game. A weapon.  You go back to the Trout Farm, and in a familiar place, you find a mouldy old wicker basket with a thread-bare canvas cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How will we know what to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone begins to knock loudly on a door very near by. The cashier is oblivious, but'both Pikul and Geller hear it. The stockroom begins to morph away as its objects are replaced one at a time by chalet objects.</context>
      <utterance>Even a child would know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode>0. S. </mode>
      <context>Pikul and Geller sit on the bed, game-pod between them, UmbyCord joining them to each other and to the pod. They look at each other. Pikul shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry to interrupt you kids, but I thought you'd better have something to eat. We knocked on your door a few times to invite you to dinner...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens slowly to reveal Vinokur, who stands there uncertainly, holding a large tray.</context>
      <utterance>Come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An awkward moment, as though Vinokur has caught the pair having illicit sex. Vinokur moves into the room towards the table.</context>
      <utterance>..and when we got no answer, I figured you were playing eXistenZ to try out your new pod, and your new bioport. Everything's all right, I take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vinokur puts down the tray, which holds several plates covered by smaller, inverted plates to keep the food warm.</context>
      <utterance>Can I leave this here for you? Don't bother unporting. I just had to be sure our star designer was in a good place and that she'd recovered her multi- million-dollar game system from her defective pod.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks so much, Kiri. This is very sweet of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOXUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recovered. eXistenZ.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, sure. That's why we're so spaced out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>TO PIKUL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were right into it, weren't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we were. And it's amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's a relief. I'll leave you two alone. You can leave the tray outside your door when you're finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that you've brought?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vinokur turns to go.</context>
      <utterance>Believe it or not, it's Chinese food. There's a great Chinese restaurant on the other side of the escarpment road.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiri?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you heard anything yet? I mean, about the eXistenZ test seminar and the shooting?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(a disturbed pause)</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. It's come over all the media now. You've never been more famous. Your face is everywhere, which of course just.makes it worse. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've announced the possibility that Antenna will delay the release of your new system indefinitely, until they can determine how widespread support for this fanatical group really is. I don't approve, myself. I don't think we should bend one degree to extremists.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Support for the fanatics? What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know. They're all coming out of the woodwork now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of people are taking the opportunity to jump on the anti- game bandwagon. They've now heard rumours about what the eXistenZ system is, and they say we've gone too far psychologically, medically, socially, you name it. And I'm afraid I wouldn't put it past our competitors to be involved in this, to try to whip up public opinion and kill our new system before it gets born.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure you don't want me to contact Antenna, even just to see what they have to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>SHAKEN</mode>
      <context>Vinokur smiles gently and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet, Kiri. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>gesturing towards the</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOR)</speaker>
      <mode> DOOR)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend Vinokur is getting shaky. I think he's going to turn, you in to Antenna.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like you might approve of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It might be the safest thing. Are you hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me neither. I'm terrified to look under the plates.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context>Maybe we should stop...</context>
      <utterance>This "support for the fanatics" thing doesn't sound too good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't stop. I've been noticing some new... glitches. I'm not sure what they mean. I'm not sure the game is OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>GENTLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, to be honest, I find your game very confusing. I'm not sure I want to go back in there, because I'm not convinced I'm going to keep coming out. Do you really like that feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>WITH PASSION</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It really will do that, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>HEAVY PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't hurt me, Pikul. Don't make me go back in alone. Play with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allegra, I'm worried that your game will wipe me off the face of the earth. I'm thinking I was right never to have a bioport installed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She mischievously flicks the pod nipple, and the chalet melts away around them.</context>
      <utterance>But you have one now. And you're ported in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was cruel. I don't want to be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't cruel, it was desperate. C'mon, Pikul. You've just got a bad case of first-time user anxiety.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like it here. I don't know what's going on. We're blundering around together in this unformed world, whose rules and objectives are largely unknown, seemingly indecipherable, or even Possibly non-existent, always on the verge of being killed by forces we don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are now close enough to the security cubicle'at the end of the corridor to see the workers ahead of them being frisked by hand, then scanned by a wand similar to the one that Pikul used at the church.</context>
      <utterance>That sounds like my game, all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds like a game that's not going to be easy to market.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's a game that everybody's already playing! Existence, it's wonderful!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cashier said it would be in a familiar place. Is there such a thing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They make their way to the last assembly bay and slip inside it. There is, for the moment, nobody else there, but several pods have been left on the work tables half-assembled. Pikul spots it first, in the far corner: a large, mouldy wicker basket in the opposite corner. Something lumpy in it is covered by a thread-bare canvas sheet.</context>
      <utterance>My assembly bay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stroll over to the basket. Geller kneels down and carefully begins to unwrap it while Pikul stands guard.</context>
      <utterance>Is that it over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The final wrap comes off. In the basket is a necrotic, purpled, very diseased-looking pod.</context>
      <utterance>I'd say it's exactly as advertised.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, it's ugly. Even for a game- pod.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a terrible urge to port into it. What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller steps over to a bunch of UmbyCords draped over a peg and strips one off. She sits down on a rotting wooden folding chair next to the death-pod's basket and ports in one end of the UmbyCord.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure. Yes. Desperate to port into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go. Wanna give me a hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>HORRIFIED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not serious! I mean, that's a diseased pod! Once you port into that, you become, you... you...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul kneels beside her as she pulls up her shirt to reveal her bioport. Geller hands him the free end of the UmbyCord and he ports it into her.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long does it take for the infection to take hold?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No time at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then you quietly port into all the other pods and spread the infection to them...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>SWOONING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something's wrong!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>SUPPORTING HER</mode>
      <context>Pikul tries to unport Geller, but her bioport has swollen and seized the jack. He gives the UmbyCord a tug.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna unport you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>RISING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to cut you free!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Pikul seizes a crude linoleum knife used for trimming oversized motherboards and, with three erratic slashes at the quivering UmbyCord, hacks her loose. Blood immediately pours out of both ends of the severed cord.</context>
      <utterance>No, don't, I'm afraid!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER C</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pikul. I'm bleeding to death.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>TERRIFIED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry! I don't know what else to do!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul twists awkwardly around to see Yevgeny Nourish standing just behind him. He is in the process of slipping a large propane torch off its wall hook.</context>
      <utterance>I know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nourish unscrews the gas valve and ignites the torch.</context>
      <utterance>I know exactly what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nourish turns the blazing torch on the pod in the basket. Where the cone of flame hits the pod, it begins to shrivel, crackle, sputter fat. The pod itself tries to ripple away from the searing flame as though it were alive. Nourish laughs and begins to play the cone over the entire surface of the pod. Geller sinks to the ground in exhaustion, holds on to Pikul's leg. The death-pod now swells and bubbles under the torch's flame, then explodes with a dull whump.</context>
      <utterance>Death to Realism!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>DYING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death... death to the demoness Barb Brecken... to the...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he fingers his ID card) Oh, yeah... Barb... Nourish drops the torch, falls to the ground and snaps into the foetal position. A wall of flame roars up around him, fueled by the straw, wood, canvas, pod-oils. Pikul jumps over to Geller and picks up the trailing cord, twists it in his hands until it stops bleeding. All four walls of the assembly bay are on fire now. The doorway is a flapping sheet of flame. Mixing with the swelling rush of the flame are the sounds of the entire plant going on alert: yells, screams, sirens, running feet, doors being slammed open and closed. Pikul holds Geller tightly. She is limp, weak, drained in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Death to who?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But now, strange, anomalous objects begin to appear out a nowhere in the flames - a chair, a tv set, a bath tub, a table, objects emerging into the game from the quest chalet. After a moment's confusion, Pikul smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I think we just lost the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And sure enough, the Trout Farm and its flames and its black cloud melt away.</context>
      <utterance>Or maybe not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Geller swims back up into full consciousness, she begins to talk, mumbling at first, then with terrible clarity.</context>
      <utterance>Allegra, we're back home. What's the matter, what's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>BARELY COHERENT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pikul. It's here, it's happened. It's come back here with us. We brought it back with us from eXistenZ.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brought what back? I can't understand what you're saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>WITH CLARITY</mode>
      <context>As though realizing the implications of what she's saying for the first time, Geller twists away from Pikul and begins to fumble with her UmbyJack.</context>
      <utterance>We brought the disease back with us. My pod is diseased.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul unports her, then begins to tug at his own jack. When he takes a close look at the pod, he can see that it looks - unhealthy. Geller jumps off the bed and yanks open her bag on the table. She pulls out a tiny hypodermic syringe, unwraps it, flicks the bubbles out of it, falls to her knees beside the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God, I'm really going to lose it, I'm going to lose my game! Unport me! C'mon, unport me!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>TO POD</mode>
      <context>Geller jabs the pod with the needle. As sne pushes in the plunger, she starts to massage it with her free hand, rub it, prod it. She's so close to it we think she might give it mouth-to-mouth.</context>
      <utterance>I'm coming, I'm coming!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this can't be possible. How can a game event emerge into real life?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>PANICKING</mode>
      <context>Pikul finally gets his UmbyCord unplugged.</context>
      <utterance>There's a very weird reality- bleed-through effect happening here. I'm not sure I get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in that needle?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unconsciously, Pikul scratches at his bioport. Geller fixes on him with strange intensity.</context>
      <utterance>It's an anti-viral serum. It sometimes works if you get it in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemme see your bioport.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul turns and shows it to her. She begins to examine it with microscopic, clinical attention.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme see it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what happened. It's Vinokur, that bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vinokur?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gave you a new bioport, didn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gave you an infected bioport so that my pod would die and so would my game-system.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm infected? Wait a minute!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>IN TEARS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The poor thing was trying to tell us that it was sick by introducing the theme of disease into our game.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The theme of disease? I'm fucking reall infected! Is it going to crawl up my spine and rot my brain?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brusquely wiping away her tears, Geller goes over to her bag and takes out a cork-shaped plastic capsule. She snaps open the capsule to reveal a knurled, plug-like electronic device.</context>
      <utterance>All right, don't panic. I've got something that will help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller bends over Pikul and works the device into his bioport until it's flush with his skin.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to seal up your bioport with this anti-viral resonator.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It uses the Umby pick-ups for power. Should cleanse all your porting channels of infection in a few hours. It'11 give you a little skin buzz when it's done. Of course, we can't play until then.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, great. Now, listen. This could be critical. Were you really saying that Vinokur is an</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>agent of the Anti- eXistenZialists? Because if he is, if he's with them, then we are really...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>WAILING</mode>
      <context>Sure enough, the thing is quivering, rippling, convulsing, turning purple.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God! Pikul, my pod's dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>WAILING</mode>
      <context>Geller falls to her knees beside the pod. As though triggered by this action, an explosion in the nearest chalet blows the windows and the door out of the guest chalet. Pikul and Geller are knocked to the floor by the impact of the blast. Waves of heat and debris billow into the room. A moment of eery silence, and then Pikul and Geller peek wide-eyed over the-edge of the bed. Flames now engulf the nearby chalet, all too clearly visible throught the shattered window frames. Sounds of pandemonium begin to well up from the hills below, and then a figure steps boldly in through the doorway. When the flamelight flickers over his face, Pikul and Geller are stunned to see that it is the cashier, and he is cradling a real-life submachine gun in his arms. The cashier screams at the bewildered and terrified pair.</context>
      <utterance>I can't help it! I can't do anything for it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode>SCREAMS</mode>
      <context>They'll be looking for you.</context>
      <utterance>The uprising has begun! The whole place is on fire! Let's go! You've got to get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>TO GELLER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cashier? He's a game character! How can he be here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cashier strides into the room and pulls her to her feet. She tries to pick up her pod, but the cashier tugs her away from it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know! I don't know!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave that rotting piece of meat here. It's done its job. Let it die.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cashier unslings his submachine gun, cocks it, and blows the pod into streaks of slime, flesh, and slivers of insect- board. Geller is in shock. Pikul turns her to face him, speaks' forcefully right into her face, shuts everything else out.</context>
      <utterance>But my game! My game's inside it. I don't want my game to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Molotov cocktail comes sailing into the room and shatters against the bed. The bed ignites with an explosive whump.</context>
      <utterance>Allegra, listen to me. I think we're still inside the game. I think your real pod's out there somewhere, somewhere safe. I think it's OK to let go of this one, this pod. It's not the real one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three of them scramble out into the fiery night.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody out! now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up here. We can see everything from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it that we're seeing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode>GLEEFUL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The victory of Realism. And you were part of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>DESOLATE</mode>
      <context>The cashier turns on her with his gun. He snaps out his old clip and slams home a new one. He cocks the gun.</context>
      <utterance>The death of eXistenZ. And we were part of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's just one more thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>HORRIFIED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? We're on your side.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode>FIERCE</mode>
      <context>(off their bewildered</context>
      <utterance>How could you be? How could Allegra Geller, the world's premiere game designer, be on our side?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something's slipped over the edge, here, Allegra. Something's all wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode>SMILES</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There. You see what I mean. You see the problem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to find you. Thank God I got here in time.  My dog brought me this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>BACKING AWAY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't get here in time. My game is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, just your pod. I replicated the entire contents of your pod when I fixed your nerve boards. They're in safe-keeping. They're all in one piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You copied eXistenZ?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allegra, come over to Cortical Systematics. Yes, yes, Cortical Systematics. I'm defecting and so are all the Antenna Research top brass, Pellatt, Melzack, Sherrin, everybody good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a spy for Cortical Systematics.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONFUSED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. Cortical Systematics is just the qame version, it's only...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>DEFIANT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only from Antenna Research.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller seems to have lost the thread. She wanders over to the cashier's body and disentangles his submachine gun from him.</context>
      <utterance>But why stay with them? Look at that mess down there. How could you trust Antenna again, when they've endangered you like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vinokur looks to Pikul for support.</context>
      <utterance>You know, this guy was actually going to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode>TO PIKUL</mode>
      <context>But before Pikul can respond, Geller, now sitting next to the cashier's body on the grass, opens fire at Vinokur with the submachine gun. Vinokur falls with a startled expression on his face. Pikul, absolutely horrified, runs at Geller and kicks the weapon out of her hand, picks it up himself.</context>
      <utterance>Can you talk to her? I mean, we can take you with us too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing?! You've killed him! Are you gonna kill me next?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS GIDDILY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Pikul. He's only a game character. And I didn't like the way he was messing with my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>SUDDENLY CALM</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you? You didn't like that and so you killed him?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was only a game character.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>QUIETLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Allegra. What if we're not in the game anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh? If... if we... we're not?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>STRANGELY HARD</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we're not, then you just killed someone real. A real person.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't an accident that you and I ended up on the run together.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not an accident? Pikul hefts the submachine gun in his hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>COLD</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why you never had a bioport. You were one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still am one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you have a bioport now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>IRONIC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought that was forbidden to Anti-eXistenZialists.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made the bioport sacrifice to get close to you, to make love to my enemy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To understand what I have to kill.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>QUIETLY</mode>
      <context>Geller produces a tiny electronic remote controller from the pocket of her shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Then. understand this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flicks up a safety cover on the remote's tip, revealing a toggle switch. Pikul's hands tense around the submachine gun.</context>
      <utterance>Understand that I suspected who you were from the moment you made that fake phone call to yourself in the limo. Understand that I knew you were my real assassin when you pointed the gun at me in the Chinese restaurant.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geller flips the toggle switch. The base of Pikul's spine blows out, his shirt billowing with blood as his bioport explodes.</context>
      <utterance>And understand that you're dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>GLEEFUL</mode>
      <context>His eyes frozen in a death stare, Pikul falls, rolls down the hill into the underbrush. Smoke creeping up from the fires below curls over him like a blanket. Arms raised in the air, Geller dances around on the top of the hill, looking down on the flames and the chaos.</context>
      <utterance>Death to the demon Ted Pikul!</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hill, the trees, the flames melt down around her.</context>
      <utterance>Have I won the game? Have I won? Have I won?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MERLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man whom we knew in the game as Yevgeny Nourish immediately stands and takes charge. But it is a different Nourish, exuberant, sensitive and artistic.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all back?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Throughout the following round of comments from the garners, whom we now realize have been, up to now, playing characters in a game, we hear nothing from Pikul and Geller. These two, who sit next to each other and are now holding hands, remain enigmatically silent.</context>
      <utterance>We're back, Merle. Although I have a feeling some of our crew might not realize it yet. Shaky laughter from some of the players.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Anybody here want a bowl of hot and sour soup?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VINOKUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will, if you make sure there</utterance>
   <speaker>R</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>are some insect boards in the</utterance>
   <speaker>F(</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>rice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FEMALE ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long were we gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About twenty minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DICHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seemed like days. That's fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. If you stayed in the gameworld for most of your life, you could live to be five hundred years old!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is general agreement amongst the garners about this compliment to Pikul and Geller. The pair just smile sweetly and bob their heads modestly at the smattering of applause.</context>
      <utterance>The twists and turns at the end made my head spin. Maybe there were too many, to fast to absorb.  Hey, but you two were fantastic. You guys are game divas! I think you both deserved to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well me, I was really bummed out at first. I got knocked out of the game so soon. It was fun to watch the rest, though. I liked that part where the ones who got knocked out of the game early got to be spooky customers in the game store.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you were so wonderfully bad. So scary and crazy. I had a lot to do in that first scene in the church but I thought my character was kind of boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, I'm a gas-jockey in real life, so I was kind of disappointed that I was basically the same thing in the game. A little more fantasy, there, fellers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERLE</speaker>
      <mode>NODDING SAGELY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting. Interesting. Hold that thought for the focus group.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(appreciative laughs and</context>
      <utterance>Can I keep this? I've never felt anything like it! And I love this little thumb-hole. It's fantastic!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice try, but you're going to have to turn them in because they're beta versions, pre- production hand-made specials, and we need to study them after use for wear and tear and other things. But you'll get a certificate for helping us out here - I'm right about that, aren't I, Merle?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLE</speaker>
      <mode>NODDING ENTHUSIASTICALLY</mode>
      <context>Amidst applause and general excitement, Merle turns to the tripod-mounted chalkboard standing, as in the first scene, at the back of the dais. There we see the words that she has already written: TranscendenZ by PilgrImage.</context>
      <utterance>And that will entitle you to reserve one of the first batch of the TranscendenZ by PilgrImage game modules to hit the market, and at a seriously discounted price. You're gonna love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember - it's written like this. Capital T, capital Z. TranscendenZ. It's new, it's from Pilgrimage - capital P. capital I, and it's coming soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>SHYLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd just like to say thank you to Mr. Nourish for giving me the chance to play the role of a star designer. I guess the game picked up on my ambitions to be like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>well, let me first say that I'm kinda glad I lost this game. I don't usually play such nasty characters.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHTER</mode>
      <context>Amid the renewed good-natured laughter, Geller blushes. She reaches out for Pikul's hand.</context>
      <utterance>And, Allegra, you were so good in that role that I suspect it won't be long before PilgrImage is after you to sign a designing contract.  And maybe you should take your friend Ted, here, Mr. Pikul, with you. He's obviously good in a crisis, and when you design games, there are plenty of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you all could tell that Ted and I had a relationship prior to our coming here. We really do like to play together.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(laughs from the security</context>
      <utterance>We do, but I'd like to assure everybody here that Allegra wouldn't really jump into bed with a security guard unless he was me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>INTENSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merle, I was very disturbed by the game we just played.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It had a very strong, very real anti-game theme. I mean, it began with the assassination of a game designer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>or Really? But that's very creative.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLE</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But on second thought, I see what you mean. It makes me nervous. You think it must have come from one of our game players?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both reflexively begin to scan the gaming group, who are all innocently dealing with their question cards.</context>
      <utterance>It sure didn't come from me. The tone of it in the game was very, very passionate, fanatical. And the atmosphere of paranoia and betrayal was overwhelming. The whole thing felt unstable, dangerous, volatile. But worse than that, there was a kind of industrial espionage subplot. Stealing game-systems, jumping ship from one game company to another. That kind of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So which one of them did these elements come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pikul and'Geller, questionnaires in hand, wander over to the wary Nourish and Merle. Pikul is now leading the dog that the security guard was holding for him earlier on, the model for the game dog in the Chinese restaurant.</context>
      <utterance>Let's probe it when we do the focus group. I think we might have been infiltrated here, and if we have, we've got a big security problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. We were just wondering if we could ask Mr. Nourish a question, away from all the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>CHUCKLES</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long as you don't ask me to fill in your questionnaire.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode>NO CHUCKLES</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've played your game now, and so we can finally agree with the others that you are the world's greatest game artist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>NO SMILE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yevgeny, don't you think you should suffer for all the harm you've done, and intend to do, to the human race?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOURISH</speaker>
      <mode>STUNNED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Don't you think the world's greatest game artist ought to be punished for the most effective deforming of reality?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERLE</speaker>
      <mode>NERVOUSLY</mode>
      <context>(looks towards security</context>
      <utterance>I don't think this is very...</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>SCREAMS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death to the demon Yevgeny Nourish!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, wait, you don't have to shoot me. I just wanted to ask you a question. _</utterance>
   <speaker>GELLER</speaker>
      <mode>WARY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
