<movie id="203" title="Fantastic Four">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben glances at Reed, who looks a little nervous.</context>
      <utterance>High open space, exposed structural elements. Obviously aimed at first time visitors to create feelings of... smallness, inadequacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good thing it ain't workin... Reed, what are we doing here? This guy's fast-food, strip-mall science --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This wasn't our first stop, in case you forgot NASA. And Victor's not that bad. He's just a little...  Larger than life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's financed some of the biggest breakthroughs of this century.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to a high-tech ORB, showing FOOTAGE of VDI's accomplishments: a safe and clean nuclear facility, the first private Space Station. All images have VICTOR front and center, glad-handling George Bush, Tony Blair, shady International Leaders. The last image is Victor holding the AMERICA'S CUP.</context>
      <utterance>You'd never know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They reach three stern RECEPTIONISTS.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. That too?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A receptionist cuts him off, handing them each a pass.</context>
      <utterance>Reed Richards and Ben Grimm to see --</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Executive elevator, top floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head for the elevator. Reed carries a small, black box. As they enter the elevator, steel doors shut and we CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>What's the price for a smile round here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>REED stands among the holograms, speaking to a MYSTERIOUS FIGURE in shadow behind a desk. An ominous, PULSATING RED CLOUD covers the stars. It washes over a hologram of EARTH.</context>
      <utterance>My research suggests that exposure to a high-energy cosmic storm born on solar winds might have triggered the evolution of early planetary life.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The SHADOW clears his throat. Reed speeds up, emotional.</context>
      <utterance>In six weeks another cloud with the same elemental profile will pass Earth's orbit. A study in space could advance our knowledge about the structure of the human genome, and help cure countless diseases, extend human life --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give kids the chance to be stronger, healthier, less prone to --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOWED FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn it off. Please. The figure's DEEP VOICE pierces the darkness.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I haven't fully explained my --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOWED FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lights brighten, revealing the face behind the voice: VICTOR VON DOOM. 35, handsome, commanding. He looks almost... airbrushed. He drops a WIRED magazine to the desk. REED is on the cover over the words: RICHARDS BANKRUPT, GRANT</context>
      <utterance>Yes you have... Imagination. Creativity. Passion. Those were always your trademarks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But dreams don't pay the bills, do they?  Same old Reed, the hopeless optimist. Still reaching for the stars, with the world on your back.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed presses the remote. Another hologram appears: A SHUTTLE slowly approaching AN ORBITING SPACE STATION. Both bear the VON DOOM INDUSTRIES logo. Victor smiles, more intrigued.</context>
      <utterance>You remember in school we talked about working together. That's what I was about to explain...</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor is a step ahead. Reed pauses, thrown for a beat. Ben wakes up, suspicious. Victor notices. He notices everything.</context>
      <utterance>So it's not my money you want. It's my toys... Tell me: if NASA doesn't trust you, why should I?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ben gets close to Reed, turning toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>That's my job. To stay a step ahead. To know what other men don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't take this.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben. This is business. Just work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They turn to see...SUE STORM (demure, stunning) standing in a corner...possibly for the whole presentation. A little cold:</context>
      <utterance>He's right, Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just business.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you both know my Director of Genetic Research, Susan Storm.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue gracefully walks into the office, only taking her eyes off of Reed to give Ben a warm hug.</context>
      <utterance>Heya Susie.  One more thing he's got.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives Reed a polite handshake. Victor watches carefully. Reed looks uncomfortable in her gaze. A little tongue-tied.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, it's been too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're, you've, I mean, how have you bee--</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor sizes them up. He puts a hand on Sue's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Never better.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't going to be a problem, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor smiles, eyeing Sue.</context>
      <utterance>Ancient history.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben tightens. A hard beat. Reed sucks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Then you're just in time to hear the great Reed Richards ask me for help.  You know, you made a lot of folks at MIT feel like a junior high science fair. So you'll excuse me if I savor the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You back this mission, and I'll sign over a fair percentage of any applications or --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The number's seventy-five. And it's applications and patents.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about his first born?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue gives a thin smile -- a flicker of old feelings.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, the money's not important. We could save lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at Victor. How does he know all this...?</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-five percent of a billion is enough to keep the lights on, isn't it? Maybe even pay off your fourth mortgage on the Baxter Building.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reed looks at Ben, who shakes his head softly no. But Reed...drops a nod. Done. Victor smiles, offers a handshake.</context>
      <utterance>Deal...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Victor squeezes. Hard. His other hand on Sue's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Well then, to our future. Together.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny how things turn out, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Reed and Sue lock eyes, Ben watches Victor. Wary.</context>
      <utterance>Hilarious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Reed's right, then this little trip will double our stock offering.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if he's not...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reed's always right. Good thing he doesn't always know what he's got...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knew about NASA. What if he made the call to shut us down --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben, think about all the people we can help if this works --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should think about yourself for once. You always let this guy push you round --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got what we wanted. That's enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed follows Ben's eyes to...SUE. She joins them. Doors shut.</context>
      <utterance>I know, I know. I'm just worried about what he wants... Speaking of which...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, head down. He doesn't want eye contact.</context>
      <utterance>You sure about this, Reed?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those solar winds are flaring, but I factored them into my coordinates and --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue holds her eyes on Reed. He is clearly uncomfortable in her gaze. Did the elevator just get smaller?</context>
      <utterance>I was talking about us. Working together.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, based on our history...you can handle the biogenetics, and I'll focus on the molecular physics. Or, uhm, maybe I should take the biotech, you work the microscopes, since you have some background in electropho--</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Way to not overthink it.  So when do we leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She offers a business card. Reed doesn't take it.</context>
      <utterance>I'll schedule the launch. Call me in the morning to talk about resources and crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, uh, think I remember the number.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Ben grimaces. Reed takes the card, his eyes down.</context>
      <utterance>It's been changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As far as crew, I was hoping Ben could pilot the mission --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Ben's curdling smile, we DISSOLVE TO --</context>
      <utterance>Well, he's welcome to ride shotgun, but we already have a pilot on our payroll. You remember my brother Johnny...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't do it. I cannot do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>External SRBs, orbital system engines. Its just like the shuttles you flew in --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I cannot take orders from that underwear model. That wingnut washed out of NASA for sneaking two Victoria Secret wannabes into a flight simulator.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Youthful high spirits. They walk toward the base of the scaffolding.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They crashed it into a wall. A flight simulator.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on JOHNNY STORM, leaning over to kiss a hot redhead. PULL BACK TO REVEAL he's riding a MOTORCYCLE, and she's driving a red CORVETTE with license plate: FRANKIE. PICK UP Reed and Ben, watching through binoculars.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure he's matured since then.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When have I asked you to do something you absolutely said you could not do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five times.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had it at four.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This makes five.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ben goes to attention on reflex: Johnny snaps a picture with a digital camera. Then advances, as Ben realizes who it is...</context>
      <utterance>Captain on the bridge!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ben eyeballs Johnny, suddenly reaches up as if to grab him. Johnny flinches. But Ben just reaches for Johnny's zipper, adjusts his uniform.</context>
      <utterance>Digital camera: $254. Memory stick: $59. The look on your hard-ass former CO's grill when he finds out he's your junior officer: priceless.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can handle the ship. I can even handle Mr. Blonde Ambition. But I don't know if I should be flying or playing Vegas in these suits. Who the hell came up with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue enters, wearing her blue, wetsuit-like uniform, carrying a stack of flightsuits. She hands them out to the guys.</context>
      <utterance>Victor did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The synthetics act as a second skin, adapting to your individual needs to --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep the hot side hot, and the cool side cool!</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed stares at Sue in the skintight outfit. She wonders, maybe hopes -- is he actually checking her out?</context>
      <utterance>Wow. Fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Material made from self-regulating unstable molecules. I've been working on a formula for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great minds think alike.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Victor enters, wearing his custom-tailored flightsuit.</context>
      <utterance>Guess some think faster than others.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A DOOR OPENS. Leonard enters, in a sharp suit.</context>
      <utterance>I hired Armani to design the pattern. These colors will look great on camera.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're ready for you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Showtime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our numbers are through the roof. The IPO's tracking at fifty, sixty a share. The bank's five times oversubscribed --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not just the money. I could make money in my sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leonard pulls out a BOX. Opens it: a TEN KARAT DIAMOND RING.</context>
      <utterance>History, Leonard. History. Everything else is conversation...  How's the other matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hit a set of big doors. Victor stops and looks into the reflective, metallic surface on the wall. He fixes one last strand of hair. Perfect. Then he opens the door to... SNAP!SNAP!SNAP! WHIP-PAN a row of CAMERAS snapping shots of --</context>
      <utterance>Harry Winston sends his regards.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEHIND THE ACTION: Reed, Sue, Johnny and Ben walk past. News crews barely notice, passing without even taking a picture. Our "Fantastic Four" are not exactly big news. Not yet.</context>
      <utterance>Today we stand on the edge of a new frontier. In the furthest depths of outer space...we will find the secrets to inner space. The final key to unlocking our genetic code lies in a cosmic storm...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that your speech?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's made a few changes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is your dream, Reed. You should be the one up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just past the press area, they see...one woman standing, waiting. This is DEBBIE, Ben's fiance. And for the first time in the entire film...Ben SMILES. They hug, kissing. Johnny and Reed watch. Reed glances at Sue, who walks ahead. Debbie slips a photo into Ben's flightsuit. A tender beat.</context>
      <utterance>Victor's better at these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be watching over you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben looks at the little ENGAGEMENT RING on her finger.</context>
      <utterance>Just get back soon, or I start looking for a new groom.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon as I'm back, I'm gonna trade that in for a bigger rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed nods, smiles. Debbie gives Ben a last kiss. Ben turns to Johnny, who gives a cocky smile.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care about rocks, I care about you.  You bring him back in one piece, or you can forget being Best Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell you smiling at? Just keep your mouth shut, and your mind on those SMBs --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben just glares at Reed. This is going to be a long trip. As they follow after Sue, we CUT BACK TO --</context>
      <utterance>Actually, the engines are SMEs. Hydrogenbase, carbon propellant. Couple generations past your last ride.  I'm not as dumb as you look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben and Reed hear the speech. Ben bristles.</context>
      <utterance>Think of a world without genetic flaws -- no asthma, allergies, baldness, breast cancer...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor smiles at the crowd, commanding. A true leader.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with being bald...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The red cloud of cosmic rays wash over the Earth.</context>
      <utterance>Darwin discovered evolution. Now we -- I -- will define it. Only in America could...</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>On those words, the HOLOGRAM TRANSFORMS TO...Von Doom's SHUTTLE on the launch pad. BOOM! THRUSTERS FIRE WHITE HOT. Smoke billows across the pad. Ready for take off. Victor walks past the hologram and exits. His departure perfectly timed with the shuttle LIFTING OFF. We push in on the shuttle, and follow the ship as it leaves Earth's atmosphere. BOOM -- booster rockets fall away and the shuttle fires its thrusters. The hologram transitions to... A shot of the SPACE STATION high above the Earth. The shuttle enters from the top, lighting up the hologram with engines afire. As the shuttle approaches the station we CUT</context>
      <utterance>...a little country boy from Latveria build one of the biggest companies in the world, and truly reach the stars. Now if you'll excuse me, history awaits...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you behave, maybe next time daddy'll let you drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed is focused on THE EARTH.</context>
      <utterance>Keep talking, there won't be a next time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed turns towards her -- a little stunned that she would bring that up. It's the first time she's been nice to him so far. He smiles, gently, hesitantly, always hesitant with Sue.</context>
      <utterance>Long way from the projection booth at the Hayden Planetarium, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny and Ben exchange a look. Reed keeps looking at the stars, eyes wide, like a little kid.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leonard, how's the feed?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Victor glances at a camera mounted into the console.</context>
      <utterance>Recording, sir. We see you perfectly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can monitor the cloud's approach and observe the tests from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it safe?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The shields on the station should protect us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben turns to Victor. A little tension. Reed cuts it:</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong, Ben? Eighty-million dollars worth of equipment not enough for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor keeps his eyes on Ben.</context>
      <utterance>Let's start loading those samples. Get your suit ready, Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor gives a friendly smile, patting Reed.</context>
      <utterance>So you still do all the heavy lifting?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reed doesn't defend himself. Ben steps up.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should have stayed back in the lab. Field work never suited you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor holds tight to his smile. He nods, condescending.</context>
      <utterance>He does the talking. I do the walking. Got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it. So take a walk, Ben...I'm going to borrow Susan for a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Ben and Johnny read his eyes, as we CUT TO --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please tell me your dawg's not trying to rekindle things with my sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Course not. Strictly business.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, his eyes say different.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, two hearts got busted last time. Maybe she's not over it either.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see: you got Victor, stud of the year, more coin than God? Or Reed, the world's dumbest smart guy worth less than a postage stamp. Hmmm, it's a toss-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put your tiny little mind at ease.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny steps out of the air-lock and shuts the door. He looks through a small window to see Ben give the thumbs up. THE AIRLOCK DOOR opens, and Ben gracefully steps into space.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you wander off, boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surprised I agreed to Reed's proposal?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand the business reasons.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue's eyes narrow. What is this about...?</context>
      <utterance>Well, when you're looking at your future, it never hurts to find closure about the past.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He presses a button and the observation deck's outer windows open up, revealing a spectacular, romantic view of the EARTH.</context>
      <utterance>Susan, every man dreams that he'll meet some woman he can give the world to.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>While she stares out the window, Victor reaches into a pocket, revealing a RING BOX. Sue looks unsettled.</context>
      <utterance>In my case, it's not just a metaphor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue doesn't know where this is going. She treads lightly.</context>
      <utterance>You've been with me two years now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The company's accomplished so much.</context>
      <utterance>It's been a good two years, Victor...</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, of course, the company... But you see, I've come to realize all the accomplishments in the world mean nothing without someone to share them with --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Victor, I hope I haven't done something to make you think...</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is about to spring the ring on her. She looks like a deer in headlights. She opens her mouth, and...WHAM! Doors slam open. REED RUSHES INTO THE ROOM.</context>
      <utterance>Sue, I've lived my life unafraid of taking big steps. And this is the biggest step yet. If it helps, think of this as a promotion. A merger of sorts...  Four little words that can change our lives...</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor quickly puts the ring back in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>The cloud is accelerating!</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sue quickly moves to a nearby control panel to verify Reed's claim. Starts punching buttons. Confirms Reed's findings with a nod. Victor hardens, in control.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got minutes until it hits, not hours...Victor, that storm's deadly -- the radiation's lethal. We need to abort.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get a grip. Reed. We didn't come all this way to lose our nerve at the first little glitch. Just close the shields...</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben's still out there --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So reel him in. But we came here to do a job. So let's do it. Quickly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context>Ben turns to see Reed and Johnny staring from a window.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, we need you back inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>INTO RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't done arranging your flowers, egghead.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context>Ben sees Johnny motioning for Ben to look behind him. Ben turns and sees: THE COSMIC STORM, rumbling toward the station. Not close, but not far. That gets Ben's attention.</context>
      <utterance>Ben. This is serious. Turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>INTO RADIO</mode>
      <context>He turns back towards the ship. BEHIND HIM, the storm grows.</context>
      <utterance>Roger that, on my way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Ben, come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reed, we're running out of time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor, annoyed by the indecisiveness, marches right up to Sue. Practically shoves her aside as he hits the INTERCOM.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny... Reed...</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue glares at Victor. His lack of compassion shocks her.</context>
      <utterance>Reed, you need to get up here so we can close the shields! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not until Ben is back inside!</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor doesn't bother to wait for a response. He takes over the console, punching keys.</context>
      <utterance>It's too late for him, and soon it'll be too late for all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raising the shields.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue glares with as much contempt as her face can muster.</context>
      <utterance>You can't leave them out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. She takes a step toward the door. Not sure what to do.</context>
      <utterance>Watch me. Reed had his chance. You can't help them any more than I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With one final glare, she bolts from the room.</context>
      <utterance>I can try.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victor's right. Johnny, get to the command center. Close the shields.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One look from Reed tells Johnny, he won't leave without Ben. Johnny eyes Ben, steels his courage. He's not going either.</context>
      <utterance>What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on big guy, you can do it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not responsive --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben! Ben!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOHNNY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUBJECTIVE CAMERA, BEN'S POV: The blurry image of Johnny comes slowly into focus, standing beside a hospital bed.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, wake up! Wake up!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where...where am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back on Earth. Victor's medical facility... We're in quarantine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reed? ... Sue?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny looks away, as if he can't bear to lay eyes on him.</context>
      <utterance>They're fine. Everybody else...is fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear to you they've done everything humanly possible. The best plastic surgeons in the world, Ben. You had the best --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Johnny picks up a hand mirror on the bed table before Ben can reach it, reluctant to give it to him.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a mirror...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They said that's not such a good idea, the shock alone could --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ben grabs it from him. Then slowly raises it to look and see that...except for some serious stubble, Ben's totally normal.</context>
      <utterance>Give me the god damn mirror!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cackles as he heads for the door. Ben heaves the mirror at him, breaking it into hundreds of pieces. He turns to the side-table, and grabs that picture of DEBBIE. It calms him.</context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately, the doctors just couldn't do anything to fix your face!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed passes a mirror, slowing, seeing his gray hairs. He keeps going. He passes a partially open door. He stops when he catches a glimpse of Sue asleep in bed. He sees a vase of flowers. He grabs a couple lilies, and enters. But Reed sees...the room is already FILLED with expensive flowers. All from VICTOR. Reed is trumped once again. A DOCTOR writes on Sue's chart. A wall TV plays a press conference with Victor, outside the FACILITY. He looks worse for wear. A few hairs out of place, and a small BANDAGE on his face. We PUSH INTO the press conference --</context>
      <utterance>Nice 'do. Going for the "grandpa" look?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been accused in the past of moving science a little too fast --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Accused by who? My competitors?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But surely this accident gives you pause --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without risk, there's no reward.</context>
      <utterance>Danger is always part of discovery. What would have happened if Ben Franklin never went out in a storm?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor pauses. For the first time. Just a flicker.</context>
      <utterance>So where's the reward? You promised a cure-all.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you'll have it. I've never come up short. And I'm not going to start now.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're still taking VDI public --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course. I've never been more confident in the compan-- Reed mutes the television.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's she doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed takes the clipboard, looks for himself.</context>
      <utterance>Stable. Vitals are strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blood panels show no irradiation. Good. You'll step up this protocol, every --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor takes his clipboard, and walks out. Reed steps to Sue, with the drooping flowers in his hand. Quiet:</context>
      <utterance>Four hours. We know what we're doing... One more day of observation, then you're all cleared.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHOOSH. A NURSE rolls in with a tray bearing ten more extravagant bouquets. Reed looks resigned. He walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Sue...I want to tell you...I'm...</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reed exits, dropping his two wilted lilies into the trash. Sue opens one eye, as the big lilies land by the bed.</context>
      <utterance>She's allergic to orchids. Put that Amaryllis Apapathos by her bed. The African lilies? They're her favorites.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SEXY NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where do we think we're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if "we've" noticed, but the sickest runs this side of the Alps are right outside that window --</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've noticed... But doctor's orders, you're not allowed to leave until we --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finish the tests, I know -- could you give me a hand with this zipper?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know this is not a ski resort.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny opens the cardboard box, revealing a colorful fiberglass object the size of a briefcase. In the blink of an eye, he unfolds it into a LONG SNOWBOARD.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The nurse pops a thermometer in his mouth to shut him up.</context>
      <utterance>Luckily grandma still sends care packages.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both pay more attention to his zipper than the digital read-out: it runs right up past 98.6, then accelerates fast.</context>
      <utterance>Brubbles my Triddle Name.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEXY NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're hot!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEXY NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, you feel a little feverish.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never felt better in my life. When do you get off work?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEXY NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My shift ends at four, but I couldn't --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her the thermometer, a quick kiss and he's out the door. The machine beeps: Johnny's temperature is 209</context>
      <utterance>Meet me at 4:01, top of the run. That'll give you a minute to freshen up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long was I out?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three days. I was worried about you. How are you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben can see Reed doesn't look too solid.</context>
      <utterance>Solid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reed shakes his head, looking back at his screen.</context>
      <utterance>How you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I just keep going over and over the numbers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reed. Even you can't compute every little thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben gets closer, pushing down Reed's computer screen.</context>
      <utterance>I should have done more, run more tests --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed considers. But he can't let it go. He opens his computer back up, returning to work. Ben shakes his head, looks out at the view. His eyes catch on something, wheels turning.</context>
      <utterance>It was a freak of nature. Last I checked, you don't have a crystal ball. Let it go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go through something like this, makes you appreciate having the right woman in your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you and Debbie and perfect --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed follows Ben's eyes to a lower level patio: SUE.</context>
      <utterance>Reed, I'm not talking about Debbie.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Come on. She's got a good thing with Victor --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, did that cosmic-bath loosen your screws?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's smart, powerful, successful --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed looks at Ben, resigned.</context>
      <utterance>Well maybe you should date him.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed steps away. Ben stands alone, an idea sparking.</context>
      <utterance>Ben. He'll give her the life she deserves. She ended up with the right guy. Things worked out for the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have to do everything myself?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me like-y.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEXY NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay right. Left is trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I though we went over this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEXY NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls down her goggles, jumps out. Johnny drops out after her, hitting the snow. He smolders: literally. The snow bank behind him sizzles and starts to melt. He takes off after her and the chase is on:</context>
      <utterance>Last one down springs for room service.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SEXY NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're on fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not this again --</utterance>
   <speaker>SEXY NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny sees his gloves are burning, flicks them off in alarm. His body SHUDDERS: the back of his ski suit catches on fire. A burst of flame launches him down the slope like a rocket. Nurse loses concentration, falls. Johnny races away like a missile, screaming in exhilaration. He looks back -- no nurse. He tries to put out his flaming clothes, and accidentally VEERS to the LEFT. He fails to notice the giant CHASM in front of him. He faces forward and... SCREEAAMMS! LAUNCHING off the cliff, LEGS FLAILING, trying to catch ground. FLAMES begin to TRAIL his body as he FALLS towards the rocks below. He tries to will his body away. Instead, his body becomes engulfed in flame. He is a HUMAN TORCH! And for a moment he HOLDS THE AIR -- the fire giving him some kind of...LIFT. He maneuvers just over the rocks, almost making a 90 degree turn. He looks back at the rocks in disbelief. But the lift doesn't last long. He quickly CRASHES, landing HARD into a snowbank. He opens his eyes; tries to move but can't. He's trapped under snow and ice. With all his strength, he tries to move, NO DICE. Panic sets in. His eyes go wide as the snow around quickly begins to melt. Johnny is on fire, and within seconds he's sitting in a small POND, steam rising from the water. The nurse races toward the steam. Scared, panicked. She finds Johnny...smiling, sitting naked in an impromptu hot tub, staring at his hands. His body. Exhilarated.</context>
      <utterance>No: You're ON FIRE!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and unzips. The FLAMES DISSOLVE TO...CANDLES IN --</context>
      <utterance>Care to join me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the IPO?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stable. We're looking at low twenties. It's a good number, considering the fallout from --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reed's disaster. You know, I half- think he did this to me on purpose.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Victor is on to the next thought, always strategizing.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I'm sure he wouldn't put himself --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me on the AM shows, Larry King, cover of the Journal...  I've got to do something about this scar. Make sure they only shoot my right side.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, uh, people seem to think the scar "humanizes" you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor looks at the scar, enraged by this defect. It glistens in the silver tray. His eyes are bloodshot, sleepless.</context>
      <utterance>And that's a good thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, maybe you should get some rest --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leonard looks at the table, the lavish spread. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Later. First, I've got some unfinished business. A deal that needs closing...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I've always wondered... Why Sue? You could have any woman in the world but --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why. Because I could have any other woman... You know, when they asked Caesar "why England," he said, "because it's not mine."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can only stay for one drink, Ben. I've got to meet with Victor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn a corner and find Reed, entering by another door.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't want to keep Vic waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He quickly shepherds the two of them toward a quiet table. Ben's stomach GROWLS; so loud that they all can hear it.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Reed, what are you doing here?  Great, why don't you join us?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ben's stomach growls again, even louder this time.</context>
      <utterance>God, I'm starving. Gonna hit the buffet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue and Reed stare at him. Ben's stomach growls again.</context>
      <utterance>Pardon me...</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This was Ben's plan, but he really isn't feeling well, unsteady when he walks away. He looks down at his stomach.</context>
      <utterance>I think I need to lie down. Bad shrimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ANGLE: Fireplace. Sue looks gorgeous in the light. A beat. A long beat. Reed doesn't know where to start with this woman.</context>
      <utterance>Really bad shrimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feeling better?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good. That's uh...good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue gets up to leave. Exasperated, Reed tries to think of something, anything, to say.</context>
      <utterance>You always had a way with words.  I should be getting back.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slows down, looking at him. She was hoping for more.</context>
      <utterance>I'm really happy for you and Victor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're happy for me and Victor.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can tell you guys are enjoying what was the best part of our relationship --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which was?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see surprise on Sue's face, and...</context>
      <utterance>Passion.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For science.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks more disappointed than angry.</context>
      <utterance>What? What did I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lets that hang. A lot of history here. Quiet, hurt -- she wants Reed to fight for her, to show some emotion.</context>
      <utterance>It's never what you say. It's what you don't say. What you don't do...</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Sue's emotions swirl, she slowly...disappears.</context>
      <utterance>I...I...I just wanted to --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up...but all that's left of her is the blush on her cheek and her bewitching eyes. He drops his fork, shocked.</context>
      <utterance>It's been two years, and all you can say is you're happy for me and some other guy...  You know, Victor may be a lot of things, but at least he's not afraid to fight for what he wants...  And it's nice to be wanted sometimes. To be heard...seen... Reed, look at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Sue...? I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What do you mean you --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises her hands, but we don't see them. We only see a medical waistband...floating. Her watch...floating. Her clothes appear to be suspended in mid-air. Sue is invisible. She shrieks and gets up -- knocking a GLASS off the table... SLOW MOTION: The glass flies off the table, tumbling... Reed instinctively reaches for the bottle: his arm stretches two feet out of his sleeve -- grabs it just before it hits -- Then snaps back into place. Reed stares at his arm in disbelief. Sue's eyes widen as well. The rest of Sue reappears. They look at each other: mutual alarm.</context>
      <utterance>Sue...look at your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They look up to see JOHNNY in the doorway, NAKED except for the nurse's PINK PARKA wrapped around his midsection.</context>
      <utterance>You guys will not believe what just happened!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has to be the cloud. It's fundamentally altered our DNA.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed glances over his shoulder. He stares. Sue follows his gaze to see: Johnny's FINGERTIPS are on fire. He SNAPS his fingers. They GO OUT. He's totally unharmed.</context>
      <utterance>Let's not jump to conclusions, we need a massive amount of evidence before making that leap.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what is up with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cloud has fundamentally altered our DNA.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool. What'd it do to you guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apparently I can disappear.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only one thing on Reed's mind --</context>
      <utterance>Please tell me you go silent too.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to find Ben.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flame on, flame off. Flame on, flame off --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does it again. Flame on, flame off.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed's about to knock on Ben's door when he hears the banging, moaning and pleading inside. Johnny smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, "mom."</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you dawg you. Better not be my nurse!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A creepy rippling movement begins beneath the sheet and gradually intensifies, reflected in the fabric's surface: the contours of Ben's body are changing, inflating, growing rough and craggy. SOUND of grinding heavy rocks.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, are you there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>It all stops. A beat, then all four legs of the bed give way and it crashes to the floor. Under the covers, he groans in pain, and his voice is DEEPER, GRAVELY, but definitely CLEAR:</context>
      <utterance>Open up Ben, we need to talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes adjust; there's a huge hole where the window used to be. They rush to it. Looking out they see SOMETHING LARGE in the distance, running away.</context>
      <utterance>...Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed looks out, emotions roiling. Is that his best friend...? Suddenly, Victor comes around the corner (bandage bigger).</context>
      <utterance>I think that thing is Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He considers, but never shows weakness. He nods.</context>
      <utterance>Victor, are you feeling alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little banged up. A couple scrapes. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben did this.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben did this?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's had some kind of...reaction to exposure from the cloud. And he's not the only one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor redirects his attention to Sue.</context>
      <utterance>We need to find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victor, I'm sorry I --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor strides off, leaving the others.</context>
      <utterance>Just find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We PUSH IN on a picture of Debbie lying on the floor, Reed knows exactly where Ben is going.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody know where the big guy's going?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben looks up the street, into the 2nd story window of a modest, working-class home. His eyes go soft when he sees Debbie grab the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Operator?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deb... It's me. I need you to step out front.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He blinks hard. Sad, dark.</context>
      <utterance>Out front? You home, baby? I got a surprise for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a surprise for you too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't come any closer for a sec. This is gonna be kind of a shock... You remember when we said "together forever no matter what"?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hanging beat. And Ben...steps into the light, where we SEE HIM FOR THE FIRST TIME: he's HUGE, easily twice the size he once was, and AN ORANGY ROCKY SURFACE COVERS HIS ENTIRE BODY. Debbie sees him. Fear washes over her, not sure what to think. He reaches out, a little tentative. She flinches back.</context>
      <utterance>Baby, you're scaring me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my G-g-g. What did you...do to Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out. She recoils. It's too much for her. Tears swell in her eyes. Covering her mouth, she backs away. He takes a step closer. She backs away faster, tripping over her robe, falling into the street. A car screeches to a halt. Ben instinctively steps out to help, but she scurries back.</context>
      <utterance>Deb, it's me. It's still me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her shout wakes NEIGHBORS. Lights flicker on. Ben knows he has to go. He looks at Debbie, sensing this is the last time he'll see her. She trembles, terrified. His eyes go moist.</context>
      <utterance>Don't...don't...DON'T TOUCH ME!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, he turns away. The "WELCOME HOME" sign flutters, falls to the ground. A tragic tableau. As more lights go on around him, Ben picks up his pace, speeding into the dawn.</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Deb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make sure you find Ben, bring him back here. And keep it quiet. I don't need this to hit the press.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir. You've got the Mayor at eight, then a nine-thirty interview with the Journal --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Front page?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor turns to Leonard, disappointed with him.</context>
      <utterance>Top left, like you asked.  Today Wall Street. Tomorrow, who knows...maybe Washington.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leonard. Think bigger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A PIGEON flutters past him, and drops a white gooey gift on his shoulder. Ben just glares up at the heavens.</context>
      <utterance>A few days in space, it'll be great, what's the worst that could happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He hears the sound of someone SOBBING. He turns to see...a distraught BUSINESSMAN with a briefcase. The man drops his case, which PLUMMETS hundreds-of-feet into the RIVER. The Businessman looks out, ready to jump. He doesn't see Ben (or doesn't realize Ben is not a statue).</context>
      <utterance>Perfect. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Businessman looks at Ben, terrified. Ben steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>You think you got trouble? Take a good look, pal, how bad could it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Backpedaling, the man SLIPS, FALLING toward the ROADWAY! His arms flail, grabbing a narrow beam -- his fingers hold tight while his legs thrash over speeding traffic. Cars and trucks SKIM right underfoot. Ben shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, easy there, buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ben steps out to help, but...his WEIGHT BENDS the beam! The Businessman LOSES HIS GRIP! He FALLS TO THE ROAD, landing hard on the highway! A few PEDESTRIANS see Ben. They point. Ben looks up, deer in headlights. He sees a massive TRUCK bearing down on the Businessman.</context>
      <utterance>You had to choose my spot, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ben DROPS to the street. WHOOMPF! He lands in front of the Businessman, SWEEPS him out of the way with one arm, and turns to the oncoming 18 WHEELER CAB. The DRIVER slams his brakes, eyes wide. The truck SWERVES, but cannot stop! Time slows to syrup, as Ben looks a little scared. He shuts his eyes, and... SHOULDER-BLOCKS the INCOMING TRUCK! A football move. The truck BUCKLES, POPPING a WHEELIE, CRUMPLING all the way to the windshield! It looks like a metal car-compactor. The truck SWERVES hard, its tail SMASHING into steel girders.</context>
      <utterance>This is really not my day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BRIDGE COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed, Sue, and Johnny slow down, swap glances.</context>
      <utterance>Back! We're evac-ing the bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MOVE IN ON REED. A first test of leadership. But he is not a leader. Not yet. Sue gets closer to him.</context>
      <utterance>What now? Reed...? What do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben's out there. Let's go get him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGE COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you didn't hear me. Those cars are gonna blow sky high, any second.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, we've got a friend out there in trouble. We need to get to him before --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGE COP #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hard beat. Reed signals Sue with a look, a nod.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody gets past this point.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to her body. She understands. She concentrates, and starts to turn invisible.</context>
      <utterance>We need to get past them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGE COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But her clothes don't go invisible. Beat. Reed mutters:</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this? A magic show?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sue. Your clothes. Lose them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She unbuttons her blouse. Not thrilled with the idea. She wriggles out of her pants. Down to her skivvies. She reaches back to undo her bra...momentarily loses concentration and becomes visible. The sight of Sue in her undies grabs the COPS' attention. Everyone watches, stunned. The realization that she's visible hits her like a ton of bricks. Cops are transfixed. So is Reed.</context>
      <utterance>What...?  Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is wrong in so many ways.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been working out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue takes a deep breath. Closes her eyes. Focuses. Nothing happens. She's embarrassed and furious.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>...and she DISAPPEARS. Entirely. Undies float. Jaws drop.</context>
      <utterance>Any more ideas, Reed? Maybe you should strip down next, see how it feels to have fifty people staring --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops ranting. Realizes she's gone invisible.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, Sue?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>INVISIBLE</mode>
      <context>The undies drop. The cops stare open-mouthed. They turn to look at Reed, astonished. He sheepishly shrugs his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well then...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. She walks away. The cops watch her, gaping. By the time they turn back around, Reed and Johnny are gone, disappearing into the clouds of smoke.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna need serious therapy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the --!</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben. Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to Reed's neck. Then to his own body:</context>
      <utterance>Am I okay?! You wanna explain that?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reed opens his mouth, but he has no answer. Not yet.</context>
      <utterance>Or this?! What the hell am I? 'Cause I sure ain't Ben anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHIEF FIREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's some folks outside, want to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not going public with this. We're scientists, not celebrities.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF FIREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns on a little TV MONITOR in the corner. NEWS FOOTAGE plays on all stations, with the tagline: FANTASTIC FOUR.</context>
      <utterance>Too late, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF FIREMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what they're calling you. The Fantastic Four.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny heads for the exit.</context>
      <utterance>Nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny pauses. Rubs his chin once. And...</context>
      <utterance>Johnny, slow down. Let's think this through, a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs out. Sue, Ben, and Reed swap glances, knowing Johnny cannot be their spokesman. They take off after him, out to --</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Done thinking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>CHIEF FIREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny does not hesitate.</context>
      <utterance>So which one of you's the leader?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'd be me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF FIREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Sue and Ben turn to Reed. The Chief hands him a mic.</context>
      <utterance>No seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF FIREMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>All eyes go on Reed. He looks out, gulps hard. A long beat.</context>
      <utterance>You're on, son. They all want a statement.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody came for a science class. A crush of questions overwhelms Reed:</context>
      <utterance>Uh, during our recent mission to the Von Doom space station, we were exposed to as yet-unidentified radioactive energy, most likely some kind of nucleotide compoun--</utterance>
   <speaker>VARIOUS REPORTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened on the bridge? Does it hurt to stretch? Were you really on fire? Is it true that one of you can fly?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Working on it. And it's a lot harder --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't know much more than you do, at this point. Which is why we will be going directly to the lab, where we can diagnose our symptoms and --</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed looks at Ben's face, feeling the guilt. Ben is lost in thought, looking at Deb's ENGAGEMENT RING. Johnny leaps in.</context>
      <utterance>Symptoms? So it's like a disease?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Symptoms? Please. If having powers is a disease, then yeah we got it. And we are gonna blow your minds. There's a new day dawning. The day of the Fantastic Four.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Reporter nods toward Ben. Ben's fists tighten, the sound of rocks crushing together. Reed feels the pain.</context>
      <utterance>That thing doesn't look too fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben Grimm is a genuine American hero who's been through a terrible orde--</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reporters laugh. Ben turns his head away. Reed burns.</context>
      <utterance>What he's trying to say is: every team needs a mascot...</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed, Sue, and Ben get up to go. The press waits a beat, then surges. Ben spins, holding up one finger. A giant.</context>
      <utterance>Look, we went up to space to find a way to understand DNA, to cure disease, save lives. Well, now it's our DNA, our disease, our lives on the line...  Thank you. No more questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The press step back, intimidated. Flashbulbs POP, and Ben's FACE FREEZES. It goes BLACK-AND-WHITE on a NEW YORK POST in --</context>
      <utterance>Be nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NED CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Victor, the bank would like to congratulate you. On the fastest freefall since the Depression. We can't even give your stock away.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ned, you know I can turn this around. Ned motions to the paper, the picture of BEN.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor's grip tightens around the table, and...the LAPTOPS FLICKER, losing feeds. Victor looks down at his hands -- a private beat (did I do that?) He lets go of the table; screens go back to normal.</context>
      <utterance>You promised a cure-all, and came back with this. Who the hell's going to invest in a biotech company that turns its workers into circus freaks?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really appreciate all your support.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor looks at him, blood boiling, and we CUT HARD TO --</context>
      <utterance>You've got a week, Victor. One week to turn this around. Or we pull out...  This meeting is over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leonard is thinking all business.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn book-keeper doesn't know preferred stock from livestock.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor considers. His mind races, eyes narrow.</context>
      <utterance>Sir. Reed's comments at that press conference killed us. How are we going to turn this around?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leonard nods, impressed. Victor is a man in motion. As they step into sunlight, we cut to...CLICKCLICKCLICK in --</context>
      <utterance>Very simple. I cure them. If I can cure these freaks, then I can cure anyone. What better way to restore my reputation?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben turns to a group of LITTLE KIDS. Stiff, tentative:</context>
      <utterance>Smile, Ben. They want to like you. Give 'em your good side. Or your less bad side.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids FLINCH. Ben trudges on. Johnny smiles bright, doing hand-signs for F4. Sue pulls him toward --</context>
      <utterance>Uh...don't do drugs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>O'HOOLIHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to the flashing cameras outside.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome back to the Baxter, Dr. Richards. All that for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He searches for the name. Sue steps up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid so...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at Sue, then at Reed.</context>
      <utterance>Jimmy. Good to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HOOLIHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good to see you too... Don't worry, sir. I know how crowded that head of yours is.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any visitors while I was away?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HOOLIHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens a drawer full of LETTERS from the BANK. Reed looks sheepish. He shuts the drawer, looks to Johnny and Sue.</context>
      <utterance>Just the usual. Told 'em you were circling round outer space.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a tough year.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed looks at Ben. Thanks a lot. DING. Elevator doors open.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, nine years straight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty? From outside the place looks a lot taller.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doors close, but...the ELEVATOR does not move. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A digital readout on the panel: EXCEED MAXIMUM WEIGHT. A sign reads: MAXIMUM CAPACITY: 2000 pounds. They turn to Ben.</context>
      <utterance>Either we're moving really fast...or not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doors open. He lumbers out. As the doors close behind him, he looks back over his shoulder, locking eyes with Reed.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take the stairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come Ben can't turn it on and off like us?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we're here to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Happen to all of them. Reed nods softly.</context>
      <utterance>If it happened to him, then it could...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. You mean there's chance we could be full-on-24-7-fantastic?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grow up, Johnny. You want to run around on fire for the rest of your life?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed considers. But Sue cuts him short with a look. DING! The elevator stops.</context>
      <utterance>Is that a trick question? C'mon, I can't be the only one who thinks this is cool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should stay here until we can define the extent of our changes...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place is deluxe. You got cable?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and figure out how to reverse them. Let me show you to your rooms.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She notices the scar on his head.</context>
      <utterance>God, I've been so worried about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victor, your scar --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I'm fine. It's you I'm worried about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I didn't get a chance to --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes for her bag. But she stops him. A half beat.</context>
      <utterance>Please, no apologies. I've arranged for your things to be moved to one of my condos. You'll have round-the clock care.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor is not used to being rebuffed. He gives a thin smile.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, that's generous, but I think I should stay here. With my brother. Until we get a handle on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sue. I think you should let my doctors have a look at you. A tense beat. Standoff. Made more tense by --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They turn to see Reed approaching, with files in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Victor! What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm starting to wonder the same thing... How much do you know about what happened to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor pauses. He looks at Sue, knowing she's here to stay.</context>
      <utterance>Not much. We need to run tests to see the extent of the damage.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor shakes Reed's hand. His GRIP is so tight that Reed's fingers STRETCH. Victor lets go, and turns to Sue, who puts her hand out. He smiles, and shakes. He heads off. Reed looks at his hand. Shakes his wrist. He looks at Victor.</context>
      <utterance>Well, let me know if there is anything I can do. We're all in this together now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor suddenly WHEELS on Reed. Lights flicker.</context>
      <utterance>Victor wait... I just wanted to say, I'm sorry the mission didn't go as planned --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't go as planned? It was a catastrophe. You ruined the lives of four people --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ruined? With all due respect, I told you to abort --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abort? Reed, I put my company, my name, billions of dollars on the line, and I will not let you make me look like a fool --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victor, if we could understand what happened to us --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed sees Victor's SCAR maybe growing. Lights dim.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to understand it. This isn't one of your science projects. I just want to fix it. Fast!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They turn to see...BEN down the hall, leaning in a doorway. Victor tightens, looking at Ben's massive rock-hewn body.</context>
      <utterance>There a problem, Vic?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to Reed. Close, quiet. Lights flicker.</context>
      <utterance>No problem, Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Victor steps away, toward the elevator. He passes Ben, who just smiles and waves "goodbye." Before Victor's finger taps the down-button, the button lights up (as if the circuit responded to him). Reed exhales, shaken. Victor steps into --</context>
      <utterance>Just pay your goddamn electric bill, and get to work on a cure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a chisel round here?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben looks to Sue for translation.</context>
      <utterance>If we're going to identify the source of the mutation, we need to isolate your recombinant DNA so we can activate positional genomes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to give you a physical, so we know what got zapped.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed shakes his head. He approaches with an X-RAY MACHINE.</context>
      <utterance>Well why didn't you say so? You want me to lift some weights or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns on the X-ray machine. The graph shows SOLID ROCK. The rays don't penetrate. Sue and Reed look confused.</context>
      <utterance>No, just sit back. We have a good sense of your strength from the firetruck. We need to find the source of your strength.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed grabs a BLOOD PRESSURE MACHINE, but the strap is way too short to wrap around Ben's arm. Reed stands stumped. He looks at his tray full of instruments. He picks up the little rubber REFLEX-HAMMER. But it looks miniscule compared to Ben. Reed has an idea. He opens a drawer full of HARDWARE TOOLS. He pulls of a real HAMMER. He approaches Ben.</context>
      <utterance>How bad is it? You know I used to smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He taps Ben's knee lightly, and BEN'S LEG KICKS! SLAMMING UP! RIGHT BETWEEN REED'S LEGS! The ultimate kick in the crotch. Reed STRETCHES UP a few feet, then SNAPS BACK, wincing.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, this might smart a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll...continue this later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back it down, Johnny!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He won't stop. Reed pulls a switch on the wall. FOAM sprays out of nozzles, dousing Johnny's flames. He stands there, covered in thick FOAM. His body steams. So does his temper.</context>
      <utterance>I can go hotter!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really cramping my style here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were at 4000 Kelvin. Any hotter, you're approaching supernova --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the temperature of the sun.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not only could you kill yourself, but you could set fire to Earth's atmosphere and destroy all human life as we know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed looks at the control panels.</context>
      <utterance>Gotcha. Okay. Supernova bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frustrated, Reed looks at the smoking system. And we CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>He cooked the equipment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I've uh, got some questions, from Sue. That she thought might be better coming from me... Can you, you know, go to the bathroom...like normal...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.  You don't wanna know the details.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben, I'm afraid I've got to ask --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not unless you want that clipboard stretched up your --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O-kay. We'll skip that question.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there something about flames? About flaming, that you --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you trying to say? Just because I dress well and like to dance --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No. I'm trying to figure out why we each ended up with different symptoms.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed sighs. It's going to be a long process.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, well that's easy: I'm hot. You're...well, you're a little limp. Sue's easy to see through. And Ben's always been a hardass.  Why aren't you writing this down?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not "invisibility" per se. You're bending the light around you with some kind of malleable force field. That's what you projected on the Bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tightens, uncomfortable with being center of attention. She reaches for his arm, like a specimen. He pulls away, but she sees a glimpse of BRUISES on his ARMS. She slows down.</context>
      <utterance>What about you? You haven't eaten in days. How come you're never on this side of the microscope?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He nods, rolls down his sleeves.</context>
      <utterance>Bruises...from the bridge?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She considers. A little vulnerable.</context>
      <utterance>Have you had any side-effects, from your powers?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Reed drops his eyes, makes a note, back to work.</context>
      <utterance>I've had some headaches. Migraines.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should be able to bend light around other objects, even people, if you could control your emotional state better --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is annoyed. Reed is oblivious.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm saying, if you had a little more self control, you could locate the trigger. Can you remember the exact emotions when --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anger. Rage. Frustration.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Is there any way to duplicate that feeling? Some memory or...</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FORCE-FIELD shoots in all directions, knocking everything over in a fifteen foot radius. Reed is thrown from his chair.</context>
      <utterance>How's that coming -- whoa --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I didn't mean to do that... You must think that was some kind of latent hostility or --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An awkward beat.</context>
      <utterance>What in the world would give me that idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, you broke up with me, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She didn't want to get into this. She looks down, vulnerable.</context>
      <utterance>No, I distinctly remember: you walked out my door. Ergo...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reed. I was ready for the next step, you weren't, ergo, I walked.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it was a little more complicated than --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The question stumps him. A beat. He struggles.</context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to share an apartment. What was so complicated about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There were a lot of variables to consider --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her words penetrate. He knows she's right. He looks away.</context>
      <utterance>No. There weren't. There was you. And me. No variables, no math. It was actually the simplest thing in the world. But your head got in the way... like it always does.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He struggles for the words.</context>
      <utterance>Sue...I just...I thought...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens his mouth, but...WHAM! Doors open. Johnny enters, wearing a CHARRED SHIRT. He points to the burned scraps of his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Same old Reed. Too much thinking...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay guys, we have a serious problem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>REVEAL: Reed, Sue, and Johnny step out to look at themselves in a mirror wearing the uniforms. No boots, no gloves. Not yet. (The uniforms will develop, like our heroes).</context>
      <utterance>Our uniforms were exposed to the storm like us. So they can transform like us, becoming invisible, changing size on demand or remaining impervious to flame.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look like an eighties rock band.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The suit will stretch. You should try it --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't be caught dead in that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right. These costumes are... missing something. I can't put my finger on it --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not costumes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not taking them out. Johnny, we need to stay here till we've stabilized.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny shakes his head, frustrated.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He marches out. Sue turns to Reed, who says nothing. Sue heads out, leaving Ben and Reed. A beat. Ben looks at Reed.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting sick of being trapped here. NASA wasn't even this strict!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Reed's dark look, we hear:</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's missing a utility belt.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the prognosis?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your tissue, your organs, your entire biophysical structure is changing. Every system is still functioning, somehow --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they're changing into...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't really know. A compound organic-metallic alloy. Stronger than titanium or carbon steel. Harder than diamonds --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like the shields Reed said would protect us.  How long?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At this rate, the infection should be complete in two, maybe three weeks --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean "complete"?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I could tell you. I can't pretend to know what we're dealing with here. I'll notify the CDC and -- Victor hardens, razor sharp.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Center for Disease Control. If this thing is contagious -- WHHM! Victor GRABS the Doctor by the throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor's grip TIGHTENS around the man's throat.</context>
      <utterance>Look at me. I have a life. I'm the face of a billion-dollar-company... We need to keep this confidential, understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>degenerative...</context>
      <utterance>But...this disease...is progressive...</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With one cobra-swift move, Victor thrusts his metallic arm into the doctor, killing him instantly. Victor retracts his arm, and looks at it, shocked by his own strength.</context>
      <utterance>That's terrible news...</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...but I think I'll get a second opinion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hits the end of the slides. The wall fills with white light. Frustrated, Reed SLAMS his head into his desk, CRASH! Something FALLS off the end of the desk. Reed raises his head, revealing his flattened face. He steps over to see...a PLANT SAMPLE from space, glass box shattered. Red sparks swirl around the plant, like the cosmic storm --</context>
      <utterance>Nothing...nothing...nothing...</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>THE COSMIC STORM swirls, terrifying. We slowly PULL BACK TO --</context>
      <utterance>Of course...of course...the cloud...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plants, from space. Their particles are still charged. With the right amount of energy, those ions could create the elemental profile of the cosmic storm. He rifles through a desk drawer, then heads out. Sue stands there, looking at the storm. Concerned. Then we CUT TO --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we can build a machine to re-create the storm, we can reverse the polarity --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And reverse the mutations --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Curing countless diseases, not just ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we're the focus, right Reed? Reed...?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you sure you can control this thing? Last time didn't work out so well.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps his head down, making notes, entering --</context>
      <utterance>With the right energy, we can stabilize the storm. Maybe tie into the city grid...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at shelves upon shelves of overcrowded clutter.</context>
      <utterance>You really need to get a janitor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reed finds his electron microscope. He turns to Sue, defensive:</context>
      <utterance>This must be what it looks like inside your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to pull out a MODEL of the FANTASTICAR.</context>
      <utterance>There's a system to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The little car sets the whole shelf off balance. A WAVE OF INVENTIONS COME CLATTERING DOWN! Reed moves fast: He LUNGES toward Sue, STREETCHING his ARMS AROUND the SHELF, pushing Sue away, just as the INVENTIONS SMASH TO THE GROUND! Reed and Sue hit the floor. A close call. Now more closeness: Sue and Reed lay face-to-face, with Reed's wrapped around her. A heated beat. Their first real intimate moment.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Sue, don't touch tha--</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if suddenly made aware of their vulnerability, Sue and Reed stand, backing off. As they part, we see: BEN watching from the doorway. Melancholy. He disappears. We slowly MOVE TO...A SURVEILLANCE CAMERA in a VENT GRATE.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. My fault. I won't...touch anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor looks at that image of Reed and Sue on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Is Reed any closer to a cure?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Victor sees something between Reed and Sue on the wall. He leans closer, and the camera ZOOMS IN, as if responding to his will. He ZOOMS all the way to a CLOSE UP of: REED'S BLUEPRINTS FOR THE TRANSFORMATION CHAMBER. Victor's eyes narrow, mind ticking, a plan forming.</context>
      <utterance>The only thing he's closer to is Sue...</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Victor opens a drawer, pulls out an old VIDEOTAPE.</context>
      <utterance>Make me a reservation for two at Cipriani tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Victor leans forward, fixated on that machine. As he gets closer, his screens go STATICKY. He absentmindedly picks at his SCAR. In shadows, we see skin peeling off.</context>
      <utterance>And get this over to Ben Grimm.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close your eyes, baby. Keep 'em closed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Now we PULL BACK to reveal DEBBIE and BEN on a SCREEN. The Thing watches the old videotape. He smiles sadly at his old life. He mouths the words -- he knows this tape by heart.</context>
      <utterance>You surprised?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN: the handheld camera whips around, revealing...a SURPRISE PARTY. Full of people. Ben Grimm is a popular guy. On screen: Reed hugs Ben. They pose for pictures together.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah I'm surprised. Surprised the fire department didn't shut this down.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE THING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the party sing "HAPPY BIRTHDAY." Debbie kisses Ben. Thing's eyes start to mist. On screen: Ben blows out candles.</context>
      <utterance>God. I was good looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you wish for, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context>As they kiss, a tear runs down Thing's cheek. The tape ends, and he sits in darkness for a beat. A long, lonely beat.</context>
      <utterance>I already got it. Everything I want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Reed turns his head around, seeing JOHNNY come down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Damn, Stretch!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed keeps moving, slowly. His muscles and tendons laboring.</context>
      <utterance>How far's that rubber bend?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm trying to calculate. And it's not rubber. It's muscle, tendon. I seem to have the ability to manipulate the malleability of my molecular structure and redistribute my density to --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Johnny is GONE, ducking under Reed's arm into --</context>
      <utterance>Right, whatever, have fun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go silent. They drop bills onto tables, filing out, scared of this monster. ERNIE works the bar.</context>
      <utterance>That's not funny!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the patrons keep filing out. Ben looks down, weary.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, that's Ben Grimm there, the first mook from Brooklyn to go to outer space, so pay him some respect!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernie heads for the booze. Ben gives a sad shake of his head. Then he notices...one lone patron at the end of the bar. A beautiful young woman nursing a drink. Meet ALICIA</context>
      <utterance>Ernie. Sorry for killing your business. I'll take the usual, then I'm out... Better make it a double.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to him, unafraid. He notices her blank stare, lack of focus, and white cane. Alicia is blind.</context>
      <utterance>Who killed the party?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ben takes his drink, but SMASH! His grip shatters the glass, spilling all over himself. He smiles ruefully.</context>
      <utterance>Make it a triple. On the house, Benny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs a bar-rag to dry off.</context>
      <utterance>If there's a God, she hates me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think She's real big on hate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She knocks back her drink, grabs her cane, steps toward Ben.</context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't say that, if you could see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben doesn't say anything. A little unnerved by this woman.</context>
      <utterance>Can I...? See you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She puts a hand on his face -- something in her tone and gentle touch allows Ben to let her. She smiles softly.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, I won't bite...  ...not that I could.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such a sad face... You know, sometimes being different isn't a bad thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles softly, takes her cane, and starts to head out.</context>
      <utterance>Trust me, this ain't one of those times.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right as she hits the door, over her shoulder --</context>
      <utterance>See you round, Benny...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ben watches her disappear. He sees a few people staring. He lowers his head, turns back to the bar, and finds a new drink, in a steel MARTINI SHAKER. He knocks it back.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Alicia, by the way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, a little self-conscious.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for coming out to see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said it was urgent.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue senses where this is going, and she cuts it short.</context>
      <utterance>It is. There's something we need to talk about. Something I need to ask you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victor, wait, slow down a second. I want you to know I appreciate everything you've done for me, but I just don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is cold as ice. If he's hurt, he'll never show it.</context>
      <utterance>Susan. What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She pauses. Then:</context>
      <utterance>You think I brought you here to talk about us? Please. This is business.  I need to know: how close is Reed to finding to a cure?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's working round the clock. But the data needs to be tested, analyzed before --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds tight, keeping cool.</context>
      <utterance>Same old Reed. All analysis, no action. Wasn't that the problem with you two?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If these molecules aren't stable, they could make us worse, maybe even kill us.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words sting. She can't help but hear some truth in them.</context>
      <utterance>Then why is Reed dragging his feet? Maybe he likes having his prize specimen under glass...  It's ironic, isn't it? You're finally the perfect woman for him...because you're his science project.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't make this personal --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I think you already have.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor's fist CLENCHES -- metal SFX.</context>
      <utterance>Victor, we can't do anything until the research is ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor SCREECHES his chair back, PUSHING the table so hard that he SPILLS water. Heads turn, all eyes on Sue. Victor gets close to her, too close, a hand on her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>"We," huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He walks out. As he goes, he slips the engagement ring out of his pocket. He crushes the diamond to dust, leaves the dust in an ashtray, and disappears into the night. Sue sits embarrassed. She slowly...disappears. People gasp. She walks out, invisible, save for her clothes, which DRIFT through the air. At a TABLE FULL OF BUSINESSMEN --</context>
      <utterance>Don't forget who you work for, Susan. So get to work. And do your job.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other men laugh, but WHHM! The man's wine SPILLS into his LAP! Sue walks out. The restaurant is left buzzing. Lights twinkle. And we FADE OUT. A beat. Then we CRASH</context>
      <utterance>I wish my wife would disappear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>X GAMES ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>JOHNNY emerges, wearing his blue uniform, waving to the crowd. He steps up to the pit where RIDERS prep. He beelines to RONNIE RENNER.</context>
      <utterance>And now, ladies and gentlemen, we have a special guest for you... Johnny Storm of the Fantastic Four!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie gives a tight nod. He doesn't like being upstaged by this circus freak. The other bikers approach.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ronnie Renner! I'm a big fan.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY BARTRAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to his BIKE. Johnny eyes this mean machine.</context>
      <utterance>Heard you like to ride. Wanna take her for a spin?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE RENNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We PUSH IN on Johnny, his ego getting stoked, as we CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>Come on, bro. I'll teach you some tricks...if you can keep up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>X GAMES ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CROWD goes wild. Now it's Johnny's turn. He hits the hill and pulls the exact same move. With even more height!</context>
      <utterance>A rock-solid double-flip!</utterance>
   <speaker>X GAMES ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Johnny sticks the landing. The crowd swells. Ronnie tightens, pulls his throttle harder, taking the next jump, and...MAKING AN INSANE MOVE, CORKSCREWING IN THE AIR!</context>
      <utterance>Look at that lift, ladies and gentlemen!</utterance>
   <speaker>X GAMES ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He lands clean. The crowd is ready to explode. Johnny REVS his engine, his body starting to STEAM, adrenaline burning. He hits the hill, and pulls an even gnarlier SPIN!</context>
      <utterance>Frontside 360! He's totally flat and whipped!</utterance>
   <speaker>X GAMES ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa! That's a...what is that? A</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>X GAMES ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A beat. Time suspended. And...WHHM! He PLUMMETS back down! LANDS on his bike in mid-air! And sticks a perfect landing, maybe even kicking a little dirt up at Ronnie. Johnny swerves to a stop, with a "holy shit" look on his face. What the hell just happened??</context>
      <utterance>Is he......flying?</utterance>
   <speaker>X GAMES ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A new name is born. The crowd goes berserk. Standing ovation. Riders rush up to Johnny. Kenny sees his bike: THE SEAT MELTED, WHEELS BURNED OFF. Johnny smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Unbelievable, ladies and gentlemen! You've just seen the first...the first...TORCHFLIGHT! The McTORCH!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOT GIRLS swarm. As Johnny gets swallowed by fans, we see a scary thing flicker in his eyes: the birth of a star.</context>
      <utterance>My bad. Sorry about that.  Thanks for the lesson, bro.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed enters -- overworked, unshaved. He keeps his head down, preoccupied. Sue shifts focus.</context>
      <utterance>That's new...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She puts the letters down, steps closer to Reed.</context>
      <utterance>Have you read these...? From all over. People want us to fight crimes... save their kids...solve their problems...  ...when we can't even solve our own.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reed. How close are we to a cure?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She considers. Victor's words echo in her head.</context>
      <utterance>No way to know. Without more tests, experiments.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed looks up, a little surprised. He opens his mouth, but --</context>
      <utterance>We're not specimens, we're patients. This isn't just another science project to you, is it...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben points to the wall-sized TV: the ESPN MOTO X GAMES.</context>
      <utterance>BEN! What? What's going on!?</utterance>
   <speaker>X GAMES REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>REVEAL: JOHNNY standing next to an X GAMES REPORTER. He is peeling off the burned remains of his motocross outfit, revealing his FF UNIFORM, with a "4" STITCHED ONTO THE CHEST. Behind them, STEP UP RIDERS launch their MOTO-BIKES off huge 18' high mountains of dirt, thirty feet in the air.</context>
      <utterance>So what can you tell us about the outfit?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>Ben, Sue, and Reed stare at the wall-sized TV. Mouths agape.</context>
      <utterance>Not too much, but I will say that it's all weather and no leather. Kind of Armani meets Astronaut.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to Reed, who gives a sheepish shrug, and peels back his labcoat revealing a "4" stitched onto his chest too.</context>
      <utterance>What did he do to the uniform?!</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He talked me into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>X-GAMES REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are your superhero names?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I go by the Human Torch. The ladies call me Torch.</utterance>
   <speaker>X-GAMES REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>Johnny hadn't really thought about them. He spitballs:</context>
      <utterance>What about the rest of the team?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, we call my sister the invisible girl...the Invisible Girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girl...?!</utterance>
   <speaker>X-GAMES REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's easy to remember. And Reed Richards? He's the leader. So what's he? Mr. Fantastic?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed shrugs. He doesn't hate the name.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I wouldn't say he's the leader.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Case in point: a photo of Ben fills the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Could be worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>X-GAMES REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>Johnny smiles, looking right into camera.</context>
      <utterance>What about this one? What do you call this Thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A LAUGH from the studio audience.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. Just The Thing. We would have gone with The Rock, but it was taken. And "Thing" pretty much sums it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to go. Reed wraps an arm around Ben.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'm gonna go kill him now.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben! Slow down a second and -- He sees a photo of himself on screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>X-GAMES REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true what they say? That he can expand any part of his anatomy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, between us, I think he's got some problems staying rigid.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...wait for me...</utterance>
   <speaker>X-GAMES REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>They put up a shot of Susan.</context>
      <utterance>Which may explain why this woman's not smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm driving.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude. That's my sister.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Valet blows his whistle...and a 4 X 4 solid cube of RED JUNK METAL slides down the street and stops at the curb in front of Johnny. The Valet timidly holds out the keys...</context>
      <utterance>Where's my ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Before he can finish, Johnny gets PELTED IN THE HEAD with the license plate. It rattles to the ground, face up. Johnny rubs the sting out of his head. Looks up and sees Ben in the distance, dusting off his hands.</context>
      <utterance>What the?! Is that my --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna pay for that, Pebbles.  What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben marches up. Hands balled into fists.</context>
      <utterance>You gave us names? What are you, the "face" of the Fantastic Four now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about to be a broken face.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't permanent, Johnny. We need to be careful until we're normal again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben reels back a FIST the size of an anvil. Stops himself. Instead of attacking, he starts to walk off. Johnny hurls a FIREBALL that SMACKS Ben in the back of the head. Ben stops. Turns around more shocked than hurt.</context>
      <utterance>What if some of us don't want to be "normal" again? We didn't all turn into monsters like --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben gets hit with ANOTHER FIREBALL. This time in the face.</context>
      <utterance>Did you just --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ben charges like a bull, fist cocked back, and...Reed steps in the way! Too late! WHAMM! Ben's fist PUNCHES INTO REED'S CHEST, which INDENTS. Reed's BACK EXPANDS with Ben's fist, PUNCHING into Johnny, launching Johnny off his feet. BAM! Johnny SLAMS into a moving ADVERTISING TRUCK, with a BURGER KING flame-broiled WHOPPER on the side. WHOOSH! He leaves a flaming imprint on the all-beef patty. The crowd stands stunned. So do Reed and Sue. Cameras pop. Johnny slowly pulls himself up. The paint on the truck begins to bubble around his hand. Beaten, bruised, he stands. Heating up. Both his hands are now flaming fists of fury.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, that's it, tinkerbell! You want to fly? Fly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Ben lock eyes, with a block of sidewalk between them. High Noon. They start to RUN toward each other... When they are almost within range, Sue STEPS BETWEEN THEM, stops them both in their tracks with just a look. Like a mom:</context>
      <utterance>Let's see if we can get blood from a stone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two need a time-out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben just stalks off. The crowd clears, scared. A PAPARAZZI snaps a picture. Ben GRABS his camera, and flicks the lens.</context>
      <utterance>Blockhead started it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes after Ben, leaving Reed and Johnny on the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need to control yourself and think before you --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Act. Here we go again. Reed, what if we got these gifts for a reason? What if we have some, you know...like, calling?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny nods, totally missing the sarcasm.</context>
      <utterance>A higher calling like getting girls and making money?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed looks at him, disgusted. Johnny waves to the crowd, hand flaming. People SHRIEK, snap pictures. Johnny smiles at Reed.</context>
      <utterance>Is there any higher?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Johnny steps into the sea of fans. Reed stands alone.</context>
      <utterance>This is who we are Reed. Accept it. Or better yet: enjoy it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben glances sideways at her, doesn't stop. She catches up.</context>
      <utterance>Ben! Slow down...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't mean it. You know Johnny. He's always been a hothead --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not him. It's them.  I can't live like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just give Reed a little more time. You know how he works -- analyzing every little step before he takes one --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's easy for you to be patient.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slows down, gets closer, intense.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's not. I thought I was done waiting for Reed... We're all in this together now, Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens her mouth, but has no response. She doesn't know his depth of pain. As he disappears into the alley, we CUT</context>
      <utterance>Together? Look at me, Susie. You got no idea what I'd give...to be invisible. Your nightmare...is my dream.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NED CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor has a larger bandage on his face now.</context>
      <utterance>This is how you "turn things around"? These freaks are on the front page and your company's in the obituaries.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a plan to use their publicity for --</utterance>
   <speaker>NED CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cold, silent beat. Victor leans forward.</context>
      <utterance>Victor, stop. The bank's lost enough already. This isn't a negotiation. It's a notification. We're pulling out.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need to look long-term here. Without risk, there's no --</utterance>
   <speaker>NED CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to his men. They all stand. Victor is the lone man sitting. PUSH IN on Victor's face, his inner rage palpable. A few quick surges of electricity emanate from his body. This man is getting stronger, more electric.</context>
      <utterance>Reward. We all know the sales pitch, Vic. And frankly, we're done buying... Gentlemen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NED CECIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hanging beat. Victor steps out from shadows.</context>
      <utterance>Hello...?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Victor says nothing. Ned keeps going.</context>
      <utterance>Von Doom? Gave me a little shock. No hard feelings, right? Nothing personal.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He mispronounces Latveria, dripping condescension.</context>
      <utterance>You know, you could always move back to Latvura, start fresh.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED CECIL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>That does it. A surge of electricity courses through Victor. His eyes narrow, and the electricity crackles down his leg to THE GROUND. The electric spark hits the water and...</context>
      <utterance>Maybe that's where you belong, back in the "old country."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>An IMAGE of VICTOR on screen.</context>
      <utterance>...the Fantastic Four put on quite a show last night. They landed in every major headline in the northern hemisphere. In related news...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Victor turns away from the screen. The volume goes down. He focuses his eyes on REED. Leonard enters, stepping closer, seeing the faint flicker of VICTOR'S METALLIC SCAR. His eyes narrow, concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Reports have surfaced that Von Doom Industries may be filing for bankruptcy. You may remember that it was Victor Von Doom who...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor keeps his eyes on the screen, totally engrossed.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, is everything okay? What happened to your...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>His fist clenches. We hear METALLIC SFX.</context>
      <utterance>Now I'm going to take it back. Piece by bloody piece...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor turns away.</context>
      <utterance>Victor, are you...are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed looks around, seeing his lab turned inside out.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about me. Worry about yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed reaches out, grabbing a folder from a box.</context>
      <utterance>What I should have done a long time ago. Applications and patents, Reed. This all belongs to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm not done with the machine --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed shakes his head, defending himself.</context>
      <utterance>Which is precisely the point. Analysis is over. It's time for action. My men could have mass- produced this by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor pulls the folder from Reed's hand, and whips out the intricate DIAGRAM of the MACHINE. He points to parts:</context>
      <utterance>Mass-produced? This isn't a toaster. You have no idea how it works.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed is a little surprised that Victor is so familiar with his machine. He points to a SECURE CHAMBER on the blueprint.</context>
      <utterance>Re-create the storm, invert the polarity here, reverse the mutation there. Don't talk to me like I'm some schoolboy. I've got the same Phd you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor slows. Is Reed getting to him? Or giving him ideas?</context>
      <utterance>The storm needs to be handled exactly right, or it could make our mutations worse, much worse, maybe even kill us...</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Victor considers. He seems to enjoy watching Reed dangle.</context>
      <utterance>Victor, please. We need time to verify the data... We can't afford any mistakes -- there's only enough ions for two or three attempts.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor walks out. Reed looks unsure, as we CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>Reed. I'm not asking permission.  We'll build it, while you check the specs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let Victor push you into making a mistake --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was going to take away all my data, equipment --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better than your life. Victor's not the one who has to get into that thing. We are. Reed starts to snap, losing his studied cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is why I'm working twenty hours a day, checking every variable --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every variable but yourself. You don't eat, sleep. You can't live in your head like --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue stands there, shocked by his outburst. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not the only one in there. I got you, Vic, Ben, Johnny, all rattling around in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, knowing what she means. Where she means.</context>
      <utterance>So clear it out. Get out of your head. Get out of here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eyebrows are a little big... A beat. He stares at these images of himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He turns to see...ALICIA in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>I figured the only way to get you here was to stick that in the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you know it was me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps toward her. But he sees...a PARTY in the back part of the gallery. Ben pauses, a little insecure.</context>
      <utterance>I'm blind, not deaf. Wanna come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not really dressed for a party.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, it's casual.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, a thought forming, as we CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>No, I mean...I'm a little...dusty...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those yours too?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My step-dad's. I'm strictly into stone. I was wondering when you'd walk by.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE THING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you could'a run an ad in the personals.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Sensual blind chick seeks three-ton, rock-hard he-man for deep spiritual relationship."</utterance>
   <speaker>THE THING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets closer, running her hands across his arm.</context>
      <utterance>This ain't permanent. My friend Reed's working on a cure...I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben bristles. He doesn't want to stay this way.</context>
      <utterance>Bennie. You feel pretty good as is.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE THING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know what it's like out there. Walking around like some kind of circus freak. People staring, whispering --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't know anything about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE THING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he ponders that, we hear a CROWD SWELLING on the CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>Tell me. When you grew up in Brooklyn, how many astronauts did you know?  You went your own way then. You didn't listen to people. So why start now...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few fans. Hope you don't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, sitting down in the middle of them.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta take care of the fans, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny eyes the models, all lusting.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I built my business knowing what people want. And right now, the people want you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we don't want to let the people down now, do we?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we don't. Which is why we need to strike while the iron's hot. I'm talking action figures, videogames, sponsors --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor nods, knowing he has Johnny on the hook.</context>
      <utterance>Videogames? You serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talk to Reed and Sue about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor subtly nods to the models. They envelop Johnny.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny. Let's be honest here. Ben, Reed, Sue. Good people, all. But stars?  I don't want to break up the band, but you're the one they want. Don't you think it's time to go solo...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The car stops. Victor gets out. He stands on the pavement. As he shuts the door, we see the women climbing onto Johnny. The door shuts, and... WHHHMMMPF! The windows all suddenly STEAM UP!</context>
      <utterance>Take the car for a spin. Think about it. Is this the life you want? Or would you rather live in Reed's lab...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could get Ben to tap into the Baxter's main power to generate enough voltage --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slowly looks up. The stars seem to calm him.</context>
      <utterance>Reed. Shh. Just be quiet. And look up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember our first date here...? God, I was so nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed smiles softly, thinking back.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I was. I'd read all your papers on bioethics. Some of them two times just so I'd have something to say to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I bribed the projectionist ten bucks to keep it open late?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave him twenty. They laugh. Sue looks up to the stars. Quiet:</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reed looks at her. Wrestles with a decision. Then quietly:</context>
      <utterance>I didn't want that night to end.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She knows. He trails off. Sue looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Sue, you were right. It wasn't complicated. I just wasn't ready to be...to become...  You can be a little intimidating.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always talked about how you liked the kind of man who could approach you...speak his mind. One who wasn't afraid to tell you what he wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone SHUSHES them. They slump down further. Closer.</context>
      <utterance>I did. I did, Reed...but I wanted you to be that man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I walked out, I waited ten minutes outside your door. Ten. Waiting for you to come find me.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you say something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes lock. A heated beat. No more secrets. Their faces are close. A kiss is coming. Closer, closer. Sue disappears.</context>
      <utterance>That would have kinda defeated the purpose. And Reed...  I'm saying it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reed tentatively leans into the kiss, and...</context>
      <utterance>Come find me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reed's face is SQUEEZED on both sides by Sue's invisible hands. She pulls him into a KISS. Lips touch. Soft, tender. Stars twinkle. And we slowly DISSOLVE TO --</context>
      <utterance>That's my nose, genius... These are my lips.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben keeps his eyes on Alicia. He overhears two BOHEMIAN GIRLS, who assume he's a statue.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know about this one. It lacks a certain...realism.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOHEMIAN GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's always had a thing for runaways and strays, but this is ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOHEMIAN GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Did she really think these sculptures would sell?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOHEMIAN GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben just stands there, frozen. His eyes dart around the room, paranoid now. Aware of people staring, laughing. He glances at Alicia, who giggles at something else. Ten seconds ago, this would have been dreamy. Now it's damning. We stay with Alicia, who cuts through the crowd, emerging where she left Ben. She has a PITCHER of wine in hand for him. But Ben is gone. She looks disappointed, hearing his heavy FOOTSTEPS get softer and softer in the distance. THUNDER booms on the CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>Like anybody would want this thing in their house. That girl's a one-woman charity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ben turns to see...VICTOR.</context>
      <utterance>This seat taken?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm worried about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About me? How sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben considers. A man deeply alone. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Let me buy you something to eat. Looks like you could use the company.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THE THING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Scuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whispering behind your back...</context>
      <utterance>I know it can't be easy. Life hasn't changed that much for Reed, Sue and Johnny. At least they can go out in public. But for you? People staring.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE THING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're trying to cheer me up you're doing a helluva job --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Thing shoves a huge piece of pie in his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying, I know what it's like to lose something you love. To see it slip away, and know it's never coming back.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE THING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reed's gonna fix me up --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For your sake I hope you're right. I'm sorry if that sounds a little skeptical.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE THING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben doesn't trust him. But Victor is hitting pressure points.</context>
      <utterance>Skeptical...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off The Thing: a seed of doubt has been planted. He can't help but find truth in the words. And we CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>Look, he's a brilliant man, we should trust he's working as hard as he can. You're his best friend. So what possible reason could he have for taking his time?  I mean, other than getting close to Sue?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The construction of the TRANSFORMATION CHAMBER is complete. The Technicians are gone now.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I have that effect on people.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you remember my name do you? You happen to remember what you swore to do with every breath in your body?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're working as hard as we can --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to Reed and Sue together.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I can tell. Victor was right.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue looks a little hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, this is nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad "nothing" could take you away from your work.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He POKES his finger into Reed's chest, which INDENTS around it like the Pillsbury Doughboy. Ben pushes Reed back. Hard.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, I don't know if this thing'll change us back or make us worse. I need you to be patient for a little while longe--</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs Reed's face, his fingers INDENTING the skin. He THROWS Reed back. Reed slams down to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Look at me, Reed. Look at me!</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben shakes his head, looking down at Reed.</context>
      <utterance>I am looking. That's why I can't make a mistake! I've got to get it right, and it's not right yet! We need to test this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed tries to stand, but Ben KNOCKS him back. Reed slams into the wall, and stays down this time.</context>
      <utterance>I spent my whole life protecting you, from the schoolyard to the stars. For what? So you could play Twister with your girlfriend while I'm the freak of the week?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to raise her hands to throw force-fields.</context>
      <utterance>Ben! Stop it! Or I'll stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ben turns to her, Reed takes this opportunity to WRAP Ben up like a python. They struggle. Ben runs back into a wall to shake Reed. Their faces are close, heated.</context>
      <utterance>Stay out of this Susie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ben seems to relax and Reed lets go. Ben walks out. Sue comes to Reed's side. He's bleeding.</context>
      <utterance>Good thing you're flexible enough to watch your own back. 'Cause you're on your own now.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads out. Reed slowly stands. He looks at the transformation machine. It's not ready. But...Reed steps toward it. As he walks, his image goes grainy in --</context>
      <utterance>I'm OK. Just go, go after him. Stop him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! That's a prototype!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strides away.</context>
      <utterance>Go back to the drawing board.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny? Did you see Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, for the last time, I hope. I'm done with this freak show. I'm moving back to the real world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you call it? "Real"?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits home. Sue is quiet. Johnny turns to go.</context>
      <utterance>At least it beats living in a lab like somebody's science project.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny, slow down. Think. You know mom didn't raise us to --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look around, sis! She's not here. So you can stop talking to me like I'm your little boy --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls away from her, taking a step out the door.</context>
      <utterance>As soon as you stop acting like one. Come on, you're smarter than this. You think those people out there care about you? You're just a fad to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strides into the night, leaving Sue alone. A dark night. The Fantastic Four is no more. The family is split apart.</context>
      <utterance>Let's try something new: you live your life. And I'll live mine.  And just for the record: they LOVE me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can...make it work.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reed, stop, you need to rest your --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The power...I need...more power...to control...the storm --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed loses consciousness. Sue carries him out.</context>
      <utterance>You need a doctor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out for his phone, and...his SPEAKERPHONE AUTOMATICALLY TURNS ON. His powers growing.</context>
      <utterance>More power...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>TO PHONE - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leonard. Bring me our lab rat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses. And...a very LARGE MAN steps up.</context>
      <utterance>What do you say we get out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Boyfriend doesn't look too happy.</context>
      <utterance>This your boyfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYFRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny does one more trick...taps the guy's drink...igniting it into a burst of flame. The Boyfriend drops the glass, which SMASHES on the ground...catches the floor on fire. The boyfriend quickly moves in and stamps it out.</context>
      <utterance>Is that all you do? Bar tricks and stealing chicks...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLFRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boyfriend takes his girlfriend's hand, they start to walk off. She turns back for one last comment...</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?! You could have burned somebody!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLFRIEND</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Johnny looks a little embarrassed. The couple leaves. Johnny glances around. His FANS look down, away. He sees how quickly they can turn. The crowd parts slightly. He looks very alone.</context>
      <utterance>You know, if I had your power I'd be doing something with it, not wasting my time doing cheap bar tricks, hitting on some other guy's girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben, come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? Where's Reed?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben looks at the flickering lights. Suspicious. Victor turns to Leonard, who looks a little scared by this dark room.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you think? With Sue.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Leonard nods, all too eager to get the hell out of here.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it from here, Leonard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leonard disappears fast, as Victor turns back to Ben.</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want, Vic?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben shakes his head, wanting to believe, but...</context>
      <utterance>To help you. I've run every test known to man. And they all yield the same result: the machine is ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reed said it'd be weeks till --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben nods. Reed was wrong before. Ben gets closer to the machine, drawn to it. He wants to believe, so badly.</context>
      <utterance>He also said we'd avoid that storm in space. And we know how that turned out.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fantastic."</context>
      <utterance>He couldn't generate enough power for the machine to reach critical mass. Yet another mistake for "Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Victor stands in shadows, but we see the tiniest little SPARK around him. The lights...? Or his skin...?</context>
      <utterance>And you can? Power it up?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps his arm behind his back -- his fingertips course with ELECTRICITY. It starts to build, sparking up his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I've found a new energy source.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ben keeps his eyes on the machine. His dream is alive.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me...do you want to be Ben Grimm again?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vic... What the...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone thought I was safe behind those shields...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victor, the machine worked for me. It can work for you --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben starts to realize...</context>
      <utterance>It did, Ben. It worked perfectly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom smiles, reaches out his hand -- ELECTRICITY builds from his shoulders, coursing down his arms to his fingertips.</context>
      <utterance>You planned this...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always wanted power. Now I've got an unlimited supply...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DOOM smiles, nods, stronger than Ben now.</context>
      <utterance>And no Thing to stand in your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom clenches his fist and BLASTS Ben, sending him flying backwards across the room -- knocked unconscious.</context>
      <utterance>Take a good look, Ben. This is what a man looks like who embraces his destiny.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, WHOOSH! The lab door flies open. Reed enters. Doom steps back into the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>One down, three to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reed's eyes go wide. He sees Ben crumpled in the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Right on cue.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god Ben. Are you okay?  You did it, you really did it...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed slowly turns to see...DOOM. His body, his face.</context>
      <utterance>No, Reed. I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victor...? What, what happened to you? What did you do to your --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly what I said I would: I built a better, stronger being. And outsmarted the great Reed Richards --</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victor, this isn't the way to --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>O'HOOLIHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom casually SWIPES, sending him through revolving doors.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Von Doom? Are you oka--</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never better, Jimmy. And it's Doctor Doom now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She helps him out of the rubble. He is beaten, battered.</context>
      <utterance>Ben?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Johnny comes running in. He sees the wreckage.</context>
      <utterance>Sue!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sis, for leaving you guys --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. A beat between them. He looks around, sees Ben.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm sorry, for pushing you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to the wreckage.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Ben!  I go away, look what happens. You got a lot of explaining to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The machine works. And Vic's gone Mister Hyde on us --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue looks around. Only one question. Dead serious:</context>
      <utterance>Really? With a name like Von Doom? Never saw that one coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Reed?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victor must've taken him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We now see what he sees: Reed sits in a chair with TUBES INJECTED into his skin FREEZING HIM SOLID! Ultra-cold vapor coats him. Doom steps closer, a sadistic smile. Reed tries to move but can't even ball his hand into a fist.</context>
      <utterance>Chemistry 101, Part Two. What happens to rubber when it's super- cooled?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He PRESSES DOWN on one of Reed's fingers, which makes a horrific CRACKING SOUND. Reed's face twists with pain.</context>
      <utterance>Allow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Doom seems to enjoy every CRACK. He leans closer.</context>
      <utterance>Painful...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Doom lets up on Reed and reaches into a crate, and pulls out a military-issue ROCKET-LAUNCHER. He aims at the city skyline, locking onto his target: JOHNNY STORM.</context>
      <utterance>You don't know the meaning of the word.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Johnny's HEAT SIGNATURE glows. The screen flashes: TARGET ACQUIRED. Doom looks back at Reed, his launcher aimed casually over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>But you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>BOOOOM! He fires without looking! A MISSILE blasts into the sky. THE MISSILE LIGHTS UP THE DARK NIGHT beginning its wide turn towards its target.</context>
      <utterance>Flame off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His mind races. He makes a decision, and steps up onto the ledge, hundreds of feet above the street.</context>
      <utterance>Great. Heat-seeker.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sis. Let me take care of you for once.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny considers, a half-beat. He looks out. Under breath:</context>
      <utterance>But Johnny...you can't fly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue reaches out to stop him, but Johnny DIVES HEROICALLY OFF THE EDGE! He FLAMES ON! The missile follows his arc. As he drops, his clothes BURN OFF, revealing his UNIFORM.</context>
      <utterance>Well then this'll be one hell of a basejump.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He falls lower, lower. And...he...BANKS! SWOOPS UP!</context>
      <utterance>Come on...come on...come on...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLAME ON.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sue watches, with fear, and a hint of pride.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to help Reed -- Sue shakes her head, sympathetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads off. Ben watches her go, helpless.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, you got what we all wanted. You need to stay here. It's too dangerous.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed's eyes shift to see...Doom emerge from the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>What has he done to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How romantic.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victor, please --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps closer. Electrodes course over his metal skin.</context>
      <utterance>It's Doctor Doom to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know the machine works. It worked on Ben, it'll work on you. We can turn you back --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hardens, a little force field starts to emanate from her.</context>
      <utterance>Do you really think fate turned us into gods so we could refuse these gifts?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom has a hand behind his back, generating an energy blast.</context>
      <utterance>Victor. You always thought you were god.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sue please, let's not fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She HURLS a force-field at him. It CONNECTS, KNOCKING him back a half-step. But he simply shakes it off, and steps up. Too powerful. He smiles. His arms CRACKLE with electricity.</context>
      <utterance>No, Victor... Let's.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOOM! He FIRES an ELECTRIC SHOCKWAVE that LAUNCHES her back. She spirals through the air, crashing into the wall, THUDDING to the floor. As Doom stalks closer, Sue gathers her strength to...GO INVISIBLE.</context>
      <utterance>Susan...... You're fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A hanging beat. We see: a FAINT OUTLINE of Sue behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Marco...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He SPINS, GRABS her! Doom grips her neck, SLAMMING her to the ground beside Reed. She lays there, beaten, visible. In the distance behind Doom, city lights BLINK, fading in and out. Lights flutter softly here (like when Ben went through the machine). Reed looks up. Could it be...?</context>
      <utterance>Polo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue and Reed lock eyes. Reed tries to move his mouth. He has something to tell her, struggling just to move his lips and get the words out.</context>
      <utterance>One more down. Now it's just the scientist and his specimen.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to say "you," but his lips FREEZE, mid-word. Sue whispers to him:</context>
      <utterance>Sue. The only thing I ever knew without thinking was...  I...love...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom steps toward Sue, about to deliver the final blow.</context>
      <utterance>Me too, Reed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOOOOM! An elevator DOOR FLIES INTO THE ROOM! SMASH!</context>
      <utterance>And so four became none. It's my time now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Reed recognizes the voice. So do we. Doom turns to see... BEN GRIMM, AKA THE THING. Back in rocky, fighting form.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, Vic...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods and quickly gets out, shaking.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Maam. Can I borrow your car?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The clutch sticks a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben LIFTS the car and THROWS it at Doom. WHMM! It FLIES through the air, and WHAM! Hits hard, knocking Doom back twenty feet! As Doom FLIES back, a BUS enters frame, and --</context>
      <utterance>Not gonna be a problem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Simple, strong. Doom turns to see...REED. Alone. Bruised and battered. Slowly stepping toward him. Doom smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I can't let you do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to Ben, raises the pole, but...he CAN'T SWING DOWN! Something is HOLDING the pole in mid-air. Something invisible.</context>
      <utterance>And you can't stop me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She turns VISIBLE, holding back the pole with a FORCEFIELD. Using her power, she FLINGS the pole from Doom's grip. It skids along the street. Reed helps Ben to his feet. Doom turns to these three wounded soldiers.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Susan.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Doom steps toward them, but --</context>
      <utterance>What is this? The pitiful three?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>WHOOOSH! Johnny SWOOPS DOWN, hurling a FIREBALL like a flamethrower, KNOCKING Doom back. Johnny takes his place alongside the others. The four of them stand as one. Johnny turns to Thing.</context>
      <utterance>Four.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thing starts to retort, but Johnny gives a warm smile.</context>
      <utterance>Had a little relapse, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They turn to Doom, who stands with metal skin slightly singed and melted, making him look all the more menacing.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Electricity starts to course through his body. He stands at the foot of the crater Ben made. He THRUSTS down, grabbing a thick POWER CABLE, RIPPING it out of the street! He SNAPS the cable into two snaking, lashing strips. He holds tight, ABSORBING the power. Lights FLICKER and DIM in buildings around him. Windows BLOW! Doom GLOWS, amped up. He LETS GO of the cables! The two deadly wires SNAKE out of control! PEDESTRIANS scatter, panic. Reed sees the wires SLASHING through the air. He makes a move: Reed STREEETCHES HIS ARMS, reaching for the deadly cables. Doom FIRES superpowered ENERGY BOLTS. The electric charges surge through the air toward the Fantastic Four, but -- Sue TOSSES her FORCE-FIELDS, exploding Doom's blasts in mid- flight. She keeps her hands up, BLOCKING blows like a prize fighter. One of Doom's BOLTS glances off her force-field and -- SMASHES into a concrete stanchion of a BUILDING! The pillar starts to crumble, with PEOPLE huddled under the overhang! They're about to be CRUSHED by the falling concrete! But -- Suddenly, the concrete roof HOLDS STEADY...because...BEN is holding it up! He stands beside the stanchion, like Atlas holding the world. People run out, safe. ON THE STREET: Reed finally grabs both ends of the wire.</context>
      <utterance>This is going to be fun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom smiles. Reed sees her. She is about to drop her hands, vulnerable, but..............REED STRETCHES HIS WHOLE BODY! He EXPANDS himself across the street, and GRABS a TREE, so he forms a WALL between Sue and Doom. Doom keeps FIRING his bolts. They SLAM into Reed's body, RUBBERBAND his skin, and DISTEND OUT his back without breaking. He strains, agonizing.</context>
      <utterance>Can't...hold...on...</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny. SUPERNOVA.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But all these people...</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny charges toward Doom -- flames on his body starting build to a blinding white intensity, ENGULFING everything. Johnny GRABS DOOM.</context>
      <utterance>Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>THING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH! Johnny explodes in a PULSE of BRIGHT WHITE LIGHT, which starts to HEAT UP everything surrounding it. Reed doesn't miss a beat. He's in total command now.</context>
      <utterance>Flame on, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sue, I need some of that anger, rage, frustration --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed stays perfectly calm. He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Is that the best you can do...? A little heat...?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time for your lesson, Vic. Chem 101: what happens when you supercool hot metal...?  Ben...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He KICKS OPEN the FIRE HYDRANT. The water GEYSERS UP! Ben kicks down with his foot, deflecting the water so it sprays toward Reed, who...TWISTS HIS TORSO so... The water CURLS around his chest, RACES down his arms, and SHOOTS right off his wrists toward Doom!</context>
      <utterance>Got it, teach.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom RUSHES TOWARD Reed, but the WATER FLIES OUT, DOUSING DOOM. GIANT CLOUDS OF STEAM fill the air from the cooling metal. DOOM screams. His shrieks finally fade to SILENCE. The water stops, thick steam clouds roll, completely obscuring Doom from view. A beat. The steam clears to reveal: DOOM. A true statue now -- a hard, cold solid piece of METAL. Frozen forever. Reed, Sue, Ben, and Johnny -- The Fantastic Four -- exhale. They stand as one, in roiling smoke. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed and Sue slowly lock eyes, thinking the same thing.</context>
      <utterance>Damn, I love this job.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will they accept their mantle? Reed shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Job, huh...?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They give weary smiles. A team. Sue gets close to Reed.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we do have the suits...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THHM! He KISSES HER. His neck extending. Strong, powerful. He pulls back slightly, smiles at her. A new strength in him.</context>
      <utterance>You know, about what we said up there, I think maybe --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sue looks at Reed. A long way from that conference room.</context>
      <utterance>Funny how things turn out, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they kiss, people emerge, stepping out of hiding. The sun rises around them. The Fantastic Four step into the new dawn of a new day. And we slowly DISSOLVE TO --</context>
      <utterance>Hilarious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A PARTY IN PROGRESS. Drinks, food, music. We see in the crowd a familiar faces: O'HOOLIHAN (cast on his arm), bartender ERNIE, others. JOHNNY and BEN stand behind Reed and Sue. Reed and Sue pull apart. Reed turns to Ben, excited.</context>
      <utterance>Dude, that's still my sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben, I've been crunching the numbers on the machine. I think if we can rework the power settings...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, egghead. I'm good as is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She hands Ben a big METAL MUG. Ben takes the mug. He CLINKS, but SHATTERS her glass.</context>
      <utterance>That's my Benny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to have to work on your touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alicia gets close. A soft smile. Reed turns to Sue.</context>
      <utterance>I like the sound of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed leads her out. Ben and Johnny swap a glance.</context>
      <utterance>Sue, can I talk to you for a second?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found a broken gasket, from space --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens his hand, revealing a circular piece of metal, just about the size of......a RING. Sue slows down.</context>
      <utterance>A gasket? Reed, we're at a party.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees Johnny and Ben inside, watching -- in on a secret. Reed looks her square in the eye. Unflinching.</context>
      <utterance>If one of us were to wear it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reed drops to his knees. His head stays eye-level, while his body drops. Sue gapes, so emotional she starts to DISAPPEAR.</context>
      <utterance>Reed. What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dead silence. And then...</context>
      <utterance>No more thinking, no more variables... Sue Storm...will you...  Sue? Sue? You there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Reed goes to kiss her.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Reed's face is SQUEEZED on both sides by Sue's invisible hands. She pulls him into a KISS and reappears. INSIDE: the party applauds. Ben, Johnny, and Alicia move through the crowd to join Reed and Sue. As they go --</context>
      <utterance>That's my nose, genius... These are my lips.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more cracks about how I look.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben glares, fists clenched. Johnny smiles, mischievous, as they hit the balcony. And he FLAMES ON, taking off into the air, blazing the NUMBER "FOUR" enclosed in a circle of flame (their future callsign), over the city skyline. The crowd oohs and aahs. Ben watches, unimpressed.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm Mr. Sensitivity now.  Clear the way, wide load coming through.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People drink, laugh, dance. We slowly PULL BACK from the party, the boat, the city, and...CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>Showoff.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
