<movie id="206" title="Fatal Instinct">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She stops at the railing. We see an incredibly beautiful face and cool, alluring eyes. This is LOLA CAIN. The term "femme fatale" was coined for her. She's on display... and knows it.</context>
      <utterance>To some guys, women are like a cheap puzzle... with pieces that just don't fit. They think the soul of a woman is darker than a back alley... more tangled than a telephone cord... and colder than a Klondike Bar in Canada. But those guys don't even have a clue.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The CAMERA MOVES with her as she walks on, passing TWO MEN whose eyes are glued to her. We HOLD ON THEM. One is NED RAVINE, in his thirties, stalwart, handsome, hair trimmed neatly, but with a feel of loose ends about him... coat slung over his shoulder, sleeves rolled up, the sweat dampening his shirt. He's a cop. A plain clothes detective who's been around the block a few times and still gets lost. Next to him is ARCH, his partner. Older, if not in years, at least in mileage. Dependable, solid, with no great aspirations except to reach the end of a shift intact. He's eating Nachos from a cardboard container, licking the cheese off his fingers. The CAMERA PUSHES IN to NED. His eyes are fixed on Lola.</context>
      <utterance>When you know women the way I do, you understand exactly what what makes them tick... what makes them hum... what makes them jiggle up and down when they walk. And it's not the kind of thing you can learn from a correspondence course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="44">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One will take you for a fast ride on a bumpy road with no seat belt. But the other kind...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez... knock off the chatter, will ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just trying to keep you awake, Arch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm awake! Where do you come up with all that crap about women?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's true. Women are very complex, but if you know how to read 'em... they're an open book. You can always tell the rotten apples from the peaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kiddin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd stake my career on it. Anybody ever proves me wrong, I'll throw away my badge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aayyhh... women are trouble...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to believe that too. Until I married Lana. Now, she... is a peach.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well you're a lucky stiff, pal. Ya hold down two jobs. Got a beautiful wife waitin' for ya at home. Everything a guy could ever want, including NO kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd love to have kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! Rug-rats? Give me a break!  Jeez, I hate stakeouts. What makes you think Milo's gonna show up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Logic. He knocked off all those banks. He's got cash. He's gonna want to spend it. This is one of the few places that still takes cash. Sooner or later... he's gotta turn up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how we s'posed to recognize this scumbag?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the b.g., MILO CRUMLEY, the "Support Hose Bandit", ambles by casually, unnoticed, sucking on a cherry Snow-Cone through the panty-hose pulled down over his head.</context>
      <utterance>The "Support Hose Bandit"? When you see him... you'll know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pops the last chip in his mouth, licks his fingers and turns the container over.</context>
      <utterance>These are the best damn Nachos in North America. Maybe the world!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned shakes his head. Arch heads off to the Nacho stand. Ned steps over to the railing... gazes out at the ocean. A SAXOPHONE begins to wail a scorching, romantic melody... a recurrent tune that will come to be known as LOLA'S THEME. A beat later... Lola moves to Ned's side at the railing. He tries to ignore her presence, peering into the darkness. Lola digs in her purse for a pack of cigarettes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm empty. I'm gonna get a refill. You want some?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a light?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned pulls out a small flashlight, shines it in her purse. She pulls a cigarette out of the pack, puts it to her lips... her eyes on Ned, sizing him up.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about a match?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out a handful of matchbooks, shows her, then stuffs them back in his pocket. He turns and walks along the pier. She falls into step beside him, lighting her own cigarette. A saxophone player named DIZZY follows behind them, continuing to play. He's the actual source of the romantic THEME MUSIC we've been hearing.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks. I have plenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really are incredibly stupid, aren't you? I like that in a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be insulted, but I know you're serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sound so sure of yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not as dumb as I look.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me buy you a drink, Mr. uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ravine. Ned Ravine. And you are...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirsty. What about that drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brain surgeon?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooo... and I bet you have a big gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lola looks toward a nearby hot dog vendor.</context>
      <utterance>You lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I can't buy you a drink...  ...let me buy you one of those.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who can say no to a weiner?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lola turns to the hot dog VENDOR, raising two fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Not me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes them... hands one to Ned. He picks up the plastic mustard container to put mustard on her hot dog first.</context>
      <utterance>Two dogs. Hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come here often?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned REACTS to this, squeezing the container. A stream of mustard squirts out, hitting the front of Lola's dress.</context>
      <utterance>Only when I'm in heat.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flustered, he stuffs his hot dog into his inside jacket pocket, then tries to wipe the mustard off Lola's dress, smearing it all over her, making it worse. She watches him with a cool, detached gaze as he fumbles ingenuously. Suddenly, Ned stops, looking off. He sees... Milo Crumley going into the PUBLIC RESTROOM. Ned starts to leave. Lola grabs his hand, holding it tightly against her breast.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where ya going?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get something to wipe it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. You're doing just fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads for the men's room... signaling to Arch, who's waiting in line at the Nacho stand. Arch motions at the long line... all UNIFORMED COPS... shrugging helplessly.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get you a wet paper towel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Men turn, seeing Ned pointing the frankfurter.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it right there, Milo!</utterance>
   <speaker>RESTROOM PATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milo bolts, slamming into Ned, knocking him back through the door of a stall, into the lap of the MAN inside.</context>
      <utterance>Look out! He's got a weenie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take science in high school, Milo?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I skipped high school, cop!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you're probably not familiar with the theory of inverse proportionate explosive dynamics.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you fire a weapon with the barrel obstructed, the explosive force multiplies by twenty-three point five nine eight and reverses on itself with diametric polarity?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. So?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The gun will blow up in your hand... and it won't even scorch my pinkie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha! That's just theoretical hypothesis. Inverse proportionate explosive dynamics has never been demonstrated conclusively in a laboratory environment.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milo hesitates, unsure. Finally, he releases the gun. Ned raises it up on the end of his finger. Arch pulls it off with a loud POP! Ned cuffs Milo's hands behind him... spins him around.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Then pull the trigger, smart guy. Let's find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have the right to remain silent... next... if you waive that right, anything you say... next...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...may be used against you in a court of law... next... You have the right to an attorney... Do you have an attorney?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nahhhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flips out a business card, handing it to Milo.</context>
      <utterance>Then today's your lucky day...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - THE BUSINESS CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It reads... "Ned Ravine - Defense Attorney"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A beat. The LIGHT clicks ON. LANA; a sexy redhead with a cool, manipulative edge, and FRANK; a slick, smarmy Lothario, lay under the sheets, panting, glistening with sweat. Lana reaches for a pack of "Fatal 100's" on the bedside table.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, Frank! Adjust the stroke by ten percent! That's it.  Now tweak my points. Oh yes, oh yes!  You got it! Stabilize your ball joints and grind my rear differential!  Now accelerate! Floor it! Lay rubber, baby! VRRROOOOOOOOOOMMMMMMMMM!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad for an auto mechanic...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well you're not so bad yourself... for a lawyer's wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better watch your tongue, sweetie, or I'll have my husband arrest you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lights a cigarette... exhales a soft, gloomy cloud.</context>
      <utterance>Busy man. Cop and a lawyer. When does he ever find time for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't. That's why I need you to keep my engine tuned, Frank. Why drive a jalopy when you can have a hot rod?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should trade him in on a new model.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would... if I could make any money on the deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SOUND of an automobile engine outside. Lana stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Want to go for another test drive?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull over and park it, Frank. I'm still under warranty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned kisses her on the back of the neck as he passes through the kitchen on his way to the dining room. She reacts with bored, contemptuous disinterest, picking up the coffee pot.</context>
      <utterance>Morning sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned steps back into the kitchen with his briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>Uh huh. Want some coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned sees Frank sitting at the kitchen table, hair messed up, coveralls hastily pulled on inside-out. Frank is reading a copy of INSURANCE DIGEST magazine. A headline on the cover touts an article: "LIFE INSURANCE FOR YOUR CAT!... Cover All Nine Lives For The Price of One!" Ned's smile fades.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps over to the table... gives Frank a cool stare.</context>
      <utterance>Frank here was just grabbing a little before going back to work on my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long you been working on Lana's Mercedes, Frank?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... I don't know... six, seven weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And ya still haven't found the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned turns to Lana.</context>
      <utterance>Think I got my finger on it though.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lana tenses up at this. Frank freezes. He figures they've been busted. He sits there, holding the magazine, not moving a muscle... as Ned turns on him.</context>
      <utterance>I know what he's doing, Lana. I wasn't born yesterday. He's not fixing your car. He's SCREWING you!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lana braces herself against the sink, breathless... turned on by Ned's description. Ned goes to her, sympathetic.</context>
      <utterance>YOU are screwing my wife! I can see what your game is, Frank. You open up her hood, poke around in there... squirt some lubrication in... play around with all her parts... then take an old used piston and stick it in... then pull it out... in, out, in, out! Every day! There's no end to it. You just keep coming and COMING!... and the bill just gets bigger and BIGGER!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't see it, do you, Lana? You're too good... too pure. You can't see the evil in people like him.  Well, you're not getting away with it, pal. I'm pulling the plug! You're fired!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ned... don't you have to be somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up his briefcase, gives Frank a nasty look, then exits thru the back door. Lana and Frank stare at each other lustfully, really hot now! Frank sweeps the dishes off the table with his arm. Lana leaps into his arms, wrapping her legs around his waist. He lays her down on the kitchen table, standing over her. Suddenly, Ned opens the back door, glaring right at Frank... not even noticing Lana on the table.</context>
      <utterance>You are so naive.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams the door. A beat. Lana and Frank begin to devour each other with passionate kisses. Another beat. The front doorbell RINGS once... then again.</context>
      <utterance>Finish your coffee... then GET OUT!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just the postman. He always rings twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura... do you know where...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up a lawbook, flips it open to a dog-eared page.</context>
      <utterance>Right here. The judge decided to skip arraignment and take Milo direct to trial. You're six minutes late, but don't sweat it. You got Judge Allen. He's always eleven minutes late.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suggest you try Lemming versus Florida, 1956... where the guy jumped in the water and everybody followed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles gratefully... drops the file into his briefcase. Ned heads for the office washroom. Laura darts ahead of him into the washroom and turns the water on. Ned steps in... splashes some water on his face. Laura grabs a towel from the rack where three small towels hang neatly... hands it to Ned. He dries his face, looking at her with genuine fondness and gratitude.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances toward the toilet, notices it hasn't been flushed. She FLUSHES it, lowers the seat.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what I'd do without you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits down on the toilet seat, watching him adoringly as he shaves with an electric razor.</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura, how long have you worked for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two years, seven months, twenty-three days, nineteen hours...  ...six minutes and fifty-two seconds.  ...fifty-three... fifty-four... fifty- five... fifty-six...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura neatly folds the end of the toilet paper into a point.</context>
      <utterance>And when was the last time I gave you a raise?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He clicks off the razor, turns to look at her for a long moment, considering this, then...</context>
      <utterance>Never. But that's okay. I don't need a raise. In fact... I was thinking of giving you a rebate on my salary.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a manly pat on the shoulder then casually tosses the towel onto the rack, where it hangs sloppily askew... right next to her face. He exits. Laura stares at the towel with a tortured expression. The CAMERA PUSHES IN to her face as we see...</context>
      <utterance>Naw. That's okay. You keep it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAURA'S HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She meekly lines up all the towels.</context>
      <utterance>Did we forget something?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA'S HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She meekly lines up all the towels.</context>
      <utterance>Did we forget something?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura. Laura! What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay, I'm okay. I just get a bit... claustrophobic... in the bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her shoulder a consoling squeeze, then exits. She shakily straightens the towels and regains her composure. Ned opens a wardrobe closet in his office. He walks along, looking at thirty exactly identical blue suits, hanging neatly. Laura follows behind him. He stops and stares, indecisive.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should try some prune juice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wear the blue one.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen... I ask you... does this look like the face of a crook?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it does. But the question of my client's guilt or innocence is not the issue here today. I'm certain every member of the jury can clearly see that he's guilty!</utterance>
   <speaker>BLIND JUROR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the pantyhose over the LENS, obscuring our view.</context>
      <utterance>Put yourself in his shoes. Look through his eyes. See the world the way HE sees it!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things just don't look the same. It's fuzzy... and frightening!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milo unwraps a piece of bubble gum and pushes it into his panty-hose covered mouth, chewing the nylon and gum together.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen... Milo Crumley is not the perpetrator here. He is the VICTIM!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...MILO'S WIFE and TWO CHILDREN, all wearing panty hose over their faces. Ned motions toward Milo.</context>
      <utterance>Like ALL of us... this man is the unfortunate victim of these tragically difficult economic times. And what does that mean? He can't support his family! Ned motions toward the gallery, where we SEE...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For God's sake!... He can't even support his own FACE! JUDGE ALLEN notices that Milo is chewing gum.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE ALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milo holds up a big plastic bag filled with bubble gum. Judge Allen grabs it, takes a piece of gum and hands it to the Bailiff.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Crumley... you cannot chew gum in my courtroom... unless you have enough for everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE ALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bailiff takes the bag, offers one to Ned... who takes a piece, unwraps it and starts chewing. The Bailiff then proceeds to pass out gum to EVERYONE in the courtroom. The JURY FOREMAN raises his hand and clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>Bailiff. Pass these out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE ALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And don't forget the jury.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The courtroom erupts in CHEERS! Judge Allen raps the gavel.</context>
      <utterance>And so, desperate and broke, with no other options before him, Mr. Crumley went to eleven Savings &amp; Loans and did what any of you would have done. He stole back the money that the S&amp;Ls had stolen from him!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE ALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned turns... looking out over the courtroom.</context>
      <utterance>You're not running for congress here, so knock off the speeches and quit inciting these brainless morons! Now pick up the pace and wrap this son- of-a-bitch up! Call your first witness.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a surprised GASP from the crowd... and a loud MURMUR. The BAILIFF holds out a video box. It's titled HOLY BIBLE - THE VIDEO. Ned puts one hand on it, raises the other.</context>
      <utterance>I call... Detective Ned Ravine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you swear to tell the truth, the whole truth and nothing but the truth, so help you God?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned sits down... then gets up, his demeanor changing.</context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slips back into the witness box.</context>
      <utterance>Detective Ravine, at the time of the arrest, did you read the defendant his Miranda rights?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned steps over to Arch, who is sitting in the first row of the gallery. Arch hands him the Miranda "cue cards."</context>
      <utterance>Of course. That's standard procedure.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lays them on the corner of the stand... then slips into the chair. He picks the cards up and flips thru them. On the back we can see scribbled... "NED'S IDIOT CARDS"</context>
      <utterance>Are these the cards Officer Brooks used to prompt you while reading Mr. Crumley his rights?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned jumps to his feet, pacing dramatically, grabbing the cards.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. These are them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reading from the cards now... quote "You have the right to remain silent, if you waive that right, anything you say... may be used against you in a court of law." Is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned pivots into the witness stand, changing his attitude from aggressive attorney to defensive, angry witness as he hits the chair.</context>
      <utterance>WRONG! The official Miranda warning is... "anything you say CAN be used against you in a court of law." Not "may"... "CAN!"  Don't you know the difference between "can" and "may", Detective? Every school kid knows "can" is a verb that indicates ability to perform, while "may" is a verbal auxiliary indicating the permission to act.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The courtroom ERUPTS! The Judge bangs the gavel. Ned strides proudly toward the defense table.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't have time to worry about past participles or interrogative pronouns! I was trying to protect society from a deranged MADMAN!  But this ivy league fop...!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no more use for this witness.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE ALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned turns. The Judge motions with a finger for Ned to approach the bench. Ned does, resting his hand on it.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Ravine...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE ALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Judge smacks Ned's hand with a ruler!</context>
      <utterance>I'm dismissing this case on the grounds of improper grammar.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But your Honor...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE ALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Judge mistakenly picks up the microphone and whacks it on the bench like a gavel. BAM! BAM! BAM! It is DEAFENING! Everyone covers their ears in pain. The THX Sound System Logo appears at the bottom of the screen... along with "The Courtroom Is Listening"</context>
      <utterance>I know, I know. It's a technicality. But it's the kind of technicality that makes the American legal system what it is today! Court's adjourned!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned reaches in his pocket, pulls out a wet paper towel.</context>
      <utterance>I waited. You never came back.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got busy. Here's that paper towel I promised.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lola proudly holds up a tiny bobbie pin. She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>How'd you get in? The door was locked.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned looks at the door. The frame and lock have been brutally chewed away, as if someone used a jackhammer on them! She pulls out a pack of cigarettes... BLACK LUNG LITES.</context>
      <utterance>It's miraculous what a real woman can do... with a bobbie pin.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the water cooler. She lights up, exhaling a soft cloud of smoke through a sleepy smile, her voice purring.</context>
      <utterance>No... thanks. They're bad for ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned hesitates... about to drink from the paper cup.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know. I like things that are bad for me.  So... I hear you go both ways.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gulps the water down, crumbles the cup in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Only once. It was a fraternity prank. I never saw him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean... you're a cop and a lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned turns, tries to casually "dunk" the crumpled cup in the waste basket. He misses. Laura enters with a huge pile of lawbooks in her arms. She sees Ned miss the basket and darts over as he bends down to pick it up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Yeah. Well, there's a lot of scum out there on the streets... but they all deserve a fair and costly trial.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks it up and tosses it into the waste basket.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... Laura... this is, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura sets the heavy load of books on the desk and steps toward Lola, extending her hand. Lola takes her time removing the long white glove... finally reaching out and shaking Laura's hand with a condescending air.</context>
      <utterance>Lola Cain.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura suddenly whirls Lola around, putting her in an arm lock. But Lola elbows Laura in the stomach! Laura doubles over. Lola feigns sympathy, taking her hand... then spins, twisting Laura's arm, flipping her head over heels! Laura lands on the couch... upside down... gasping. Lola strikes a haughty pose, still holding her lit cigarette. She takes a drag. Laura checks her watch, then tumbles off the couch, landing on her feet. She straightens her skirt.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta keep these darn books in their right place or we'll never find the ones we need. Let's see, Q thru M... R thru B... W thru F...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's getting late. I'll give you a ride home, Ned. Finished with the books, Ned turns... smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tow you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lola looks at Laura... icy, haughty, triumphant. Laura moves reluctantly toward the door, sees the lock and door frame chewed to pieces... whirls around, heads back toward Ned.</context>
      <utterance>Not today. You don't need to wait. I'll see you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should call someone to fix this...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She instantly spins around, heads back toward the door...</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...and exits. Ned sits down on the corner of the desk. Lola sits in the chair across from him.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call from home.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses her legs suggestively... then slowly, enticingly, re-crosses them in the other direction. Unimpressed, Ned opens Laura's desk drawer... pulls a pair of sexy lace panties from a Kleenex-style dispenser box labeled "PANDORA'S POP-UP PANTIES"... which pulls another pair up into position. He tosses the panties to Lola.</context>
      <utterance>I think I should warn you, Mr. Ravine... I'm not wearing any underwear.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does... very, very slowly and seductively... as they talk.</context>
      <utterance>Try these on.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... what can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've run across some... papers... and I thought you might be able to tell me what they are. You see, I'm not very experienced when it comes to... papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll help you Miss Cain, if I'm able. Do you have the... papers... here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... they're at home. I thought you might stop by...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on duty tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't they ever give you a night off?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll let you know where.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around, exhaling another cloud of smoke.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with my office?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door. Behind her, in the hall, we see Dizzy, the saxophone player, wailing away on "Lola's Theme."</context>
      <utterance>Nothing a good interior decorator couldn't fix.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lana, now wearing the diaphanous gown, pulls him inside. She kisses him hungrily, slipping a frilly plastic shower cap with a gaudy floral design on his head.</context>
      <utterance>I came back for my shower cap.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks to the living room. Frank follows, still wearing the shower cap. Lana snaps her fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well you came to the right place.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits in a chair, looking around.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits on the couch, picks up a stack of papers.</context>
      <utterance>On duty all night. By the time he wraps up his reports, it'll be close to noon tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up at Frank. Sees the shower cap.</context>
      <utterance>I was just reading over...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slips the shower cap off as Lana continues.</context>
      <utterance>Take off the hat, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just reading over my husband's insurance policies. You wouldn't know anything about insurance, would you, Frankie?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, matter of fact, I sell policies part-time. I got half a brain... or didn't you notice?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flips through, scanning the pages, shrugging.</context>
      <utterance>I musta had my eye on something else.  How about a translation.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Standard accident policy... all the usual stuff... blah, blah, blah. The face value is... Wow. Not bad. Three million bucks!  And there's a triple indemnity rider.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, it's just something agents throw in so we can boost the premium. If the policy holder dies under very specific conditions, it pays off three times the face value of the policy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine million dollars...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... but it's a sure bet for the company. Nobody ever collects.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, like here... it only pays off if he's shot with a pistol, falls from a moving northbound train and drowns in a fresh water stream.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All three?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See what I mean, sweetheart? What are the odds of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could happen.  Suppose it did happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you'd be rich.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we'd be rich.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drops to her knees in front of him, her face close to his, speaking with a persuasive urgency.</context>
      <utterance>What're you sayin'...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna kill the son-of-a-bitch! And I know exactly how! He has a legal symposium in Santa Barbara this weekend... All we have to do is get him to take the train up instead of driving.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How we gonna do that? Didn't you tell me he hates trains?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up, walks to the adjoining room... snapping her fingers at her side. He follows. She steps to a table, pulls the cover off an elaborate scale- model of Dealey Plaza and a train station, complete with HO- Scale model trains chugging around the tracks. She uses a pointer to trace the route to the depot.</context>
      <utterance>That's where you come in, baby. You're gonna rig his car so it doesn't work. That should be no problem for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then... we give him a lift to the train station... through Dealey Plaza, past the Book Suppository and around the grassy knoll...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignoring this, she turns the LIGHTS OFF, walks over to a screen and picks up a remote control. She clicks the button. A SLIDE PROJECTOR comes on, throwing an IMAGE on Frank's back. We can read the words: THE PLAN.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that out of our way?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves over. "THE PLAN" appears on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Move, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she talks, IMAGES appear on the screen, accompanying her rapid spiel. We see: a shot of the depot, a map of the rail route, a gun, a river, a Bingo game, baseball action and a huge dollar sign!</context>
      <utterance>And pay attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights click ON.</context>
      <utterance>Ten minutes out of the station he'll be standing in the vestibule between cars... trying to avoid a panic attack. Fourteen minutes and ten seconds out, the train crosses the Santa Ynez River. So at thirteen minutes and fifty-four seconds, I shoot him, shove him out the door... he hits the river and drowns. Bingo! A triple play. We're rich!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been thinking about this a lot, haven't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace, kissing passionately, dropping out of frame. The model train CHUGS faster, the train whistle SHRIEKING a long "Woooooooo-woooooooooo!"... racing into a model tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>No. It just came to me.  I had this image of a big, powerful, throbbing train... plunging into a long, dark, wet tunnel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand over there and shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANG MEMBER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned goes ballistic and slams him into the wall again!</context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, we got rights! Don't you be layin' no deleterious malfeasance on us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arch grabs Ned by the shoulder, pulling him back, calming him.</context>
      <utterance>Watch your mouth, punk! I don't want to hear language like that!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned regains his composure. He's depressed.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, hold on, hoss! Take it easy. You seem a little tense tonight. What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gang Member 1 steps closer, listening.</context>
      <utterance>Aw... I don't know. I guess it's Lana. It's just... I know she wants to have a baby so bad...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gang Member 1 steps closer, listening.</context>
      <utterance>...but I never get to spend any time with her. And when I am home... it's like she's, you know... avoiding sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANG MEMBER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps between them, putting his arm around Ned's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>You should try to be more sensitive, man. More romantic. Bring her flowers.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANG MEMBER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps back, begins to SING "Try A Little Tenderness"...</context>
      <utterance>Try to understand how she feels. After all...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANG MEMBER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other Gang Members join in on the SECOND VERSE with a sweet, mellow street-corner harmony as back-up... and some smooth group choreography. The COPS on duty listen raptly, getting maudlin and dewey- eyed. Tears roll down the cheeks of the BOOKING SERGEANT. The lights dim. A big, gruff COP makes eyes at a HOOKER being booked... and they start to slow dance. Arch watches all this with a sentimental smile, munching on his Nachos. When the song ends, Arch puts a comforting hand, covered with Nacho cheese, on Ned's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>She may be weary... Women do get weary... Wearing that same old shabby dress... But when she's weary... Try a little ten-der-ness...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That can't be it. I'm the tenderest guy on the force. Nah... I think she's just afraid she won't be able to get pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's to be afraid! It's like making breakfast! You bring home the bacon... she's got the eggs. Ya scramble it up. Ba-da-boom ba-da-bing! She's got an omelette in the oven!  Why don't you knock off early... go home. It'd be nice for Lana to wake up in the morning and find you there for a change.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw... I can't. I got all this paperwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANG MEMBER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll do our own paperwork, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER GANG MEMBERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned nods, smiles and gratefully "high-fives" the Gang Members as he heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! We'll fill out all that shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, Ned... you look like you were hit by a bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was.  Who's in my office?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Max Shady's mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned goes straight to his office closet, pulls out an identical blue suit... and starts stripping off his tattered clothes.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mrs. Shady.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura reluctantly returns to the outer office.</context>
      <utterance>Laura... check on my insurance. Make sure it's paid up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea, Mr. Ravine. My son, Max, is getting out of prison tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, has it been seven years already?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven long, miserable years in the slammer. And he's a bit pissed off.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, being locked in a tiny room with no TV can make a guy feel pretty tense.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to her, putting a comforting hand on her shoulder, looking her right in the eye, attempting to provide solace.</context>
      <utterance>I'm very concerned about him, Mr. Ravine. He said you were a two-bit shyster... and he's going to rip your head off and use it for a bowling ball!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure the experience wasn't all negative. He probably made a lot of friends...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...learned a useful trade...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes... live autopsies...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She struggles to her feet feebly...</context>
      <utterance>...caught up on all those books he wanted to read...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hauls off and PUNCHES him like a pile driver! WHAM! He doubles over, gasping.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe so... but he said he's going to punch you in the testicles...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She KNEES him in the face, raising him up... then nails him with a devastating RIGHT CROSS, spinning him around. He collapses over the desk.</context>
      <utterance>...smash your face...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs the tail of his suit jacket and rips it up the back!</context>
      <utterance>...and decimate your wardrobe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and shuffles out, passing through the outer office.</context>
      <utterance>And I wouldn't want that to happen.  He's a naughty naughty boy. I just thought I should warn you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye for now.  Oh... may I have a cookie?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs a handful of cookies and casually flings them at Laura... as she heads out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura rushes into Ned's office with the file folder. He staggers unsteadily by the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Thank yooooooooou.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, Ned.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate when she comes to see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you realize, Ned?... you could be in real danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Extreme peril. You know, the risk of personal bodily harm.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I mean that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your insurance file. But the policy's missing. Did you take it home?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura looks puzzled... wondering where it might be. Then...</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes to her desk in the outer office, digs through a drawer. Suddenly, she GASPS! She is holding...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, wait a second...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She snaps out of it, sputtering.</context>
      <utterance>Laura! Are you alright? That was a very long flashback you had.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes to her desk, still upset. She picks up the message spike and turns to Ned.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... I know. It's okay. I'm just a little... pre-menstrual.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thrusts it toward Ned's face! There's a business card stuck on the end. He pulls it off.</context>
      <utterance>That Lola Cain... "person"... stopped by. She left this!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into his jacket pocket, pulls out a LIT CIGARETTE. It has a very long ash.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, before I forget... you asked me to take care of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes it... inhales a drag, then lets the smoke flow out through her smile. It flows out for a loooooooooong time! More smoke than she could ever have inhaled. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You smoke too much.  It's hot tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He notices the drink in her hand is BOILING. A saxophone begins to softly wail Lola's Theme. Ned looks over to see a QUARTET, featuring Dizzy on sax. The GUITARIST spontaneously bursts into FLAME! A FIREMAN, in full gear, jumps up from the bar and puts out the blaze with a fire extinguisher. None of the band members miss a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Is it? I never know. My body heat runs about twenty degrees above normal.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should look for a cooler place.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned glances at the MALE CUSTOMERS... sitting at the bar across from them. They're staring coldly at Ned.</context>
      <utterance>I doubt we'll find one. Even the wind chimes on my porch aren't moving much these days. They keep thudding softly, like dairy cows bumping butts in the night. I go out there expecting to find a cool breeze... but it's just a lot of hot air.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're they lookin' at?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of them have tried that seat. You're the first one's lasted this long.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel honored.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat of realization, then the stool collapses with a CRASH! Ned pulls himself back up and drags another stool over.</context>
      <utterance>Don't. It's broken.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you bring the... papers?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I thought you might come over...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. I'll drive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brought my own car.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll follow you then.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it sounds silly, but would you leave first... wait in your car? I come here a lot and I wouldn't want those men to think I'm "easy"... a slut who'll jump into bed with anyone at the drop of a hat. But if you leave first...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lola stares at Ned for a long moment... then SLAPS his face. He doesn't move, remaining staunchly macho. Then, suddenly, she SLUGS HIM so hard it knocks him over the top of the bar!</context>
      <utterance>...they'll think I'm a putz for passing up a sure thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses to give him a flicker of a COY SMILE... then picks up her drink and moves to a nearby table. Ned struggles to his feet and staggers to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Now leave me alone!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, here we are... in the dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have The Clapper.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lola CLAPS her hands twice and all the LIGHTS COME ON. She smiles at him... drops her car keys on the hall table, then goes up the stairs. Ned drops his car keys on the table too and follows her.</context>
      <utterance>You what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned steps over, running his hands along the boxes. They "thud" against each other.</context>
      <utterance>My wind chimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slips several boxes off, releasing clusters of the metal chimes. They "tinkle" and "clang" melodically in the breeze.</context>
      <utterance>You know, these would work a lot better if you took them out of the boxes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves close, coming on to him. Ned feels uneasy.</context>
      <utterance>Well well... I guess you have been around. I'm impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we take a look at those... papers?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papers. Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it? These are the... papers?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He checks them out... shrugs. It's obvious.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. They're so confusing to me. Can you tell me what they are?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands them back to her, but she gently pushes them away.</context>
      <utterance>This one's a laundry receipt... and the other one's an expired lottery ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slips them into his jacket pocket... then sensuously slides her hands around him, grabbing his buns, pulling him closer.</context>
      <utterance>No. You keep them... as a memento of our time together.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so grateful. How can I ever repay you for all you've done?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cash would be nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't there some other way?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose you could wash my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seductively starts to slide the jacket off his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>No, I mean, isn't there something else you want? Something I could give you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... slow down... there's a speed limit in this state. Sixty-five miles an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How fast was I going, officer?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, about a hundred and twenty-three.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suppose you pull me over and frisk me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suppose I let you off with a warning?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suppose I find a cop with a bigger nightstick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suppose I put you under arrest for being a bad girl with bad thoughts?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suppose you handcuff me to the bed?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and leaves. She is stunned, confused, breathless.</context>
      <utterance>Suppose I do and then we lose the key and while I'm gone to get a duplicate made the house catches on fire and I can't get back to save you because the bridge is washed out and so you die a horrible death toasted like a Polish sausage on a flaming spit!  Nah... I better be going.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves her lips close to his, about to kiss him. Then...</context>
      <utterance>You're not so tough. Last chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks. I got a cold shower and a wife who trusts me waiting at home.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps out, pauses... turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? Don't you want me? It's the way I look, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned pulls the door shut. The lock CLICKS. He pauses by his car, realizing something, heaves a sigh, goes back to the door. He tries the knob, but the door is locked. He looks through the small window. He sees Lola standing inside... breathing heavily, bracing herself against the staircase bannister, hand to her heaving chest as if to calm a pounding heart. He pushes against the door. It won't budge. He goes to the large window, gazing inside. She slides one hand enticingly across her breast and thigh, striking a seductive pose. He points toward the door, motioning for her to unlock it. She looks away. Frustrated, Ned tries the window. It's locked. He picks up a wrought iron chair, SLAMS it into the window! The heavy chair falls apart. The glass doesn't even vibrate! He sees a riding power mower in the driveway... jumps into the seat, starts the engine... barreling toward the front of the house! THUNDER CRASHES and LIGHTNING FLASHES in the sky! He PLOWS into the side of the house, SMASHING a huge hole thru the wall!... MOWING a swath in the carpet! Lola GASPS. Ned climbs off the mower, moving toward her. She opens her arms, breathless. The MUSIC SWELLS dramatically! She intercepts him, embracing him passionately.</context>
      <utterance>Don't forget to lock up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd come back...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He struggles free, grabbing his car keys from the hall table. She follows, embracing him again, even more tenaciously.</context>
      <utterance>I forgot my car keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what you came back for.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Impatient, she crushes her mouth against his, kissing him hard, desperately clawing at his clothes. She's relentless... devouring him with her lips and tongue. Overwhelmed, he succumbs to her passion. His car keys drop from his hand. She pushes him down toward the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Yes it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Shady! What's the first thing you're gonna do now that you're out?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find Ned Ravine... rip his head off and use it for a bowling ball!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a good bowler?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever bowled a three-hundred game?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would you handle a seven-ten split?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, aren't you wearing one of Ravine's "trademark" blue suits?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shady sees someone o.s., waves like a gleeful little kid.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. The bastard gave it to me as a gift... to make up for losing my case. Now I'm going to wear it to his friggin' funeral!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Madam Butterfly, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Iron Butterfly. In-A-Gadda-Da-Vida.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, sure... now I can hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It tells the sad story of a woman who is rejected by her lover after a brief, but torrid, affair... so she stalks him with an ice pick and stabs him with it more than a thousand times.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts his feet out of the water, dangles them over each side of the tub. He's still wearing one blue sock. Lola raises her feet out of the water. She's still wearing her high heel shoes. They are dripping.</context>
      <utterance>Really? I never could understand the lyrics.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, what happened last night was very, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... it was. I should check on my homeowners insurance.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we can't ever let it happen again. Ever!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned pulls his feet in, sits up... suddenly feeling vulnerable. He measures his words very, very carefully.</context>
      <utterance>What are you saying, Ned? That you're rejecting me, your lover, after a brief, but torrid, affair?!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice begins to ECHO and FADE as the CAMERA MOVES IN to a CU of Lola's enraged EYES!</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't put it exactly like that. It's just that... well, I'm married to a wonderful woman... who is very, very attractive...  ...not that you aren't very attractive!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch anything. You bond with it... you buy it. Whatdya want?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She eyes him suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to buy a pet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. For what purpose?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a gift... for my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. They all say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She spends a lot of time alone. I thought it might be nice if she had something to keep her company.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sure. I bet. How do I know you're not the kind of guy who punches out parakeets? Or takes some poor defenseless animal, throws it in a sack and runs over it with your car five or six times.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would never hurt an animal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I would. They're driving me</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They do. She turns back to Ned.</context>
      <utterance>Shuddup!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... tell me more about this broad you're married to. I like to match people with the pets they deserve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gang Member drops the chip. Arch pops it in his mouth, continues singing. The Gang Members join in with harmony. Ned enters in the background, carrying a box with airholes in it. He steps over to his desk, looking at the singing Gang Members, then motions like a choir leader, cutting them off neatly.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-uh.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all hand over their completed paperwork. Ned stares at them for a beat... surprised.</context>
      <utterance>You do all my paperwork?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They do. He opens the files... checks out the papers. Arch notices something O.S. and gets up.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arch turns the sound up on a wall-mounted TV monitor.</context>
      <utterance>And a damn good job, too. One of 'em even did it in Spanish.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the screen... it's Max Shady speaking to the press.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Ned! Catch this! Friend of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'd like to reach down Ned Ravine's throat and pull out his guts with my bare hands!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus... you hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just working through his anger, trying to find a constructive outlet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kiddin'! He'll do it! The guy's a friggin' looney!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, I spent a lot of time with him when I was preparing his case. He's really a very sweet, sensitive human being.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to mash his head like a ripe melon...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gets a little melon-dramatic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...then cut off all his fingers and rip out his liver with my teeth!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arch slumps in his chair, really stunned.</context>
      <utterance>See. Loves to exaggerate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned laughs it off. He starts checking through the messages and paperwork on his desk. The PHONE RINGS. He picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Christ, Ned... you're in deep shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned's face darkens. He turns away.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant Ravine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to see you, Ned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He SLAMS the receiver down, shattering the phone! Everyone stares at Ned in stunned silence.</context>
      <utterance>I told you not to call me! It's finished between us. No. No, I'm not sucking anything of yours anymore!  It's done! OVER!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong number.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come we gotta meet here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a hat.</context>
      <utterance>We have to be careful now. We can't risk being seen together at the house or someone might connect us to the murder later on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes her sunglasses off, looks at him. He hesitates, staring at the hat. A dignified looking OLDER GENTLEMAN approaches. Frank quickly slips the hat on his head. The Older Gentleman sits on the bench across from them. He opens a paper sack and begins neatly laying his lunch out next to him. An apple, sandwich, napkin, Mountain Dew.</context>
      <utterance>Here... put this on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speak Yiddish.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the SUB-TITLE "Speak Yiddish." From this point on, all their dialog is in YIDDISH... but it appears in ENGLISH SUB-TITLES across the bottom of the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Red Yiddish.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ich hobe getracht, efsher iz der nisht geshtoigen un nisht gefloygen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zein nisht azoy meshige! Der plan iz kosher vi yosher.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo! Ober mir darfen imvarfen in tsug. Un schissen un schtippen in vasser arein. Oy a broch! Mir zenen git bakackt.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vus iz mit idr? Die host a vaichen schmoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ven hob ich gehat a vaichen schmoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Last Yom Kippur.)</context>
      <utterance>Lest'n Yomkippur.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nu shoin, ein mul. Es paseert tsie yeyden man.  He looks around nervously.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oy! Mir vellen zein oif groise tsures. Me'vet unz chap'n.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER GENTLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both look at him... stunned. A long beat.</context>
      <utterance>There's very little risk involved. Statistics reveal that less than thirty-two percent of all murderers are ever apprehended.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You speak Yiddish?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER GENTLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank and Lana are speechless. But across the bottom of the screen we see a SUB-TITLE reflecting their thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>No. But I can read sub-titles.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUB-TITLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oy vay!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh gee, you shouldn't have...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes into his office, starts to change out of his tattered suit. Laura talks to him from the outer office.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't. It's for my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps into the doorway of his office.</context>
      <utterance>She called. Wondered why you never came home last night. I told her you were working with a client, undercover.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She returns to her desk. Disturbed, Ned quickly pulls the shirt collar out, checks it.</context>
      <utterance>There's lipstick on your collar.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No there isn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... there isn't. But you answered my question. She's a real looker, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lola Cain.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the blinds behind her and looks at Ned through the window between their offices.</context>
      <utterance>I hadn't noticed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up a stack of papers from the FAX machine. Ned steps into the doorway, wearing a clean shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I noticed how you hadn't noticed.  That's alright. She noticed enough for both of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I worry about you, Ned. I worry a lot.  Max Shady's been faxing death threats to you all morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...stick a knife in your...  ...rip the eyeballs out of your...  ...drive razor-sharp spikes under your...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get to the one...?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...cut it off... shove it in a blender.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a KNOCK at the door. They look up to see an ominous SILHOUETTE of a MAN on the milkglass. Ned starts toward the door. Laura grabs his arm, stopping him.</context>
      <utterance>He's just getting it out of his system. Once they say it... they never do it. You know... like the President.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens her purse, pulls out a big COLT .45, holding it out to him. Ned stares at it, taken aback.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. It might be him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you get that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From my purse.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Handing it to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, Laura, what do you use a gun for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shoot it. A bullet comes out. Gosh, Ned, after all your years as a cop, I'd think you'd know these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the gun back to her... goes to the door... opens it. There's a young DELIVERY MAN holding a bouquet of flowers.</context>
      <utterance>Laura... put the gun away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELIVERY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned grabs the flowers, slams the door. Laura takes the envelope from the flowers... opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Flowers for Ned Rav...  Hey... aren't you that lawyer guy? Man, you are dead meat!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at the card... her expression turning cold.</context>
      <utterance>Is this another sick joke from Max Shady?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs the flowers... takes them into the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Lola Cain.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned opens the envelope. An audio cassette drops into his hand. Written on the label: PLAY ME. From the bathroom, we hear the LOUD SOUND of a TOILET</context>
      <utterance>I'll put these in water for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOLA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned swerves to avoid a collision, HONKING his horn.</context>
      <utterance>Ned, darling... I know this seems like a strange way to talk with you... but since you won't take my calls, I have no other choice.  Watch it! That red car's turning left!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned guns it!... accelerating through a yellow light.</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Ned. We're meant to be together... forever.  The light's changing! Floor it! Go! Go! Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see HEADLIGHTS behind Ned's car.</context>
      <utterance>Nice move!  Nothing can keep us apart, Ned. Not even your wife. I'd hate to have to tell her about us, but if necessary... I will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to you last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What have you heard?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could have called. But then, I suppose you were tied up.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only part of the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the b.g., through the window, WE SEE Frank drop from the second floor, right onto the seat of a waiting motorcycle. He ZOOMS OFF into the night. Ned steps up behind Lana, slips his arms around her.</context>
      <utterance>I never know when you're coming home, Ned. How can I ever make any plans?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rolls her eyes at this... changes the subject.</context>
      <utterance>I promise I'll spend more time with you. I know it's been rough, being alone so much. But I'll make it up to you. Maybe we should try again, you know... to have a baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's in the box?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands it to her. She opens it, looks in. She looks up, struggling unsuccessfully to hide a look of displeasure.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... I brought you a present!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned pulls out a PET SKUNK and puts it in Lana's lap. She forces a weak smile.</context>
      <utterance>It's... sorta like a cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not enough like a cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a little skunk. I got it at Birds-and-Skunks-R-Us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... what're you going to name him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about... Ned?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Got a nice ring to it. I've always liked the name Ned.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his arms around them both.</context>
      <utterance>No kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So whatdya think? You love Ned Junior as much as you love me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone RINGS. Lana stands up, unceremoniously dropping the Skunk into Ned's arms. She goes into...</context>
      <utterance>At least.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ADJOINING ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...to answer the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?... Hello?... Hello?  Frank? Is that you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Frank?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to move off, but she stops him, impassioned.</context>
      <utterance>Frank? The only Frank I know is an auto mechanic... but I sure as hell wouldn't recommend the guy. He's really slow.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lola's voice ECHOES. BYSTANDERS gather, listening. Ned looks around self-consciously, embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>I had to see you, Ned. I need to feel your arms around me! I wanna suck your toes til the nails pop off!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CROWD presses closer... not missing a thing. A WOMAN snaps a FLASH PICTURE! A MAN turns on his video camera.</context>
      <utterance>I told you, what happened was a big mistake. A one night stand. It's over. I have a wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mortified, Ned spins on his heels and makes a bee-line for the safety of the Men's Room. Lola holds up two tickets.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter. She'll know all about us soon anyway. I want YOU! In my bed... in my arms... in MEEEEEEE!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got us tickets to see Iron Butterfly!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate opera!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you running from me? Didn't it mean ANYTHING to you?... buffing my buns with carnuba wax?  Come on, Neddy-poo. Doesn't Mr. Pokey want to go exploring?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arugula glances sideways at Ned, curious and uneasy.</context>
      <utterance>He's busy right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I told you... Mr. Pokey made a big mistake! One lousy mistake in his whole stinkin' life! So why don't you give him a BREAK! Besides... he belongs to my wife!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your BIRTHDAY! Today? Why didn't you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not important. I just had one last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the b.g. the Slimy Defendant pulls a gun and forces CITIZENS... including Judge Arugula... up against the wall, robbing them!</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm taking you out to celebrate!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no no! It's no big thing. I'll have another one sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I insist. And I want to get you a nice present.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're so sweet. You don't have to. You gave me a present last year. Those lovely Ginzu knives.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they walk off, we HOLD ON a CLOSE SHOT of a newspaper. The headline reads: EX-CON STALKS COP/LAWYER NED RAVINE! Below it is a picture of Max Shady, eyes wide with psychotic rage... a huge cigar in his mouth, wearing a garish Hawaiian shirt. Hands lower the newspaper... revealing Max himself, with the same cigar, shirt and crazed look on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... aren't they great! They last forever. And you can cut right through a shoe with 'em!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned motions casually toward the world "out there"... sticking his thumb into the eye of a WAITER who is bending over to pick up a spoon, setting off a chaotic CHAIN REACTION of small disasters that finally culminates with someone near the dance floor bumping into the Torch Juggler, throwing his rhythm off. Distracted, he starts catching the FLAMING ENDS of the torches! OW! OH! YI! OUCH! YIPES! He drops them all. The Waiter who bumped into him, politely picks up one of the flaming torches and hands it back to the Torch Juggler. He grabs the flaming end of the torch... and lets out a SCREAM! He lunges toward a voluptuous HULA GIRL ICE SCULPTURE, grabbing the frozen breasts. His burned hands SIZZLE! Ned and Laura don't even notice... gazing only at each other.</context>
      <utterance>It's nice to be off the streets... away from all the pain and misery out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he thinking when he looks at me with that goofy smile...?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, does she look stupid in that hat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I told him how I really feel, he'd probably fire me. What am I saying? He probably doesn't even know I exist.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura's incredible. And so smart. Smart enough to recognize that Ginzu knives are the gift of a lifetime.  But she never goes out with guys. I wonder why?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I'll just have to wait. But he's married. I could wait forever. Than again... maybe Lana will get hit by a runaway truck. There's always a chance that...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But who cares if she... Oh, sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's alright. I was just rambling.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, really... you first...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I insist... please...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, uh... I just wanted to remind you about...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the Legal Symposium...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...in Santa Barbara...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED &amp; LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..."How To Sue Your Loved Ones."</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm driving up in the morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Ned? You can tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a man, Laura. And all men feel passion at one time or another. Even me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would you think of a married man who gave in to those wild, sensual, raging desires?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gulps, eyes wide. The DRUMS pound faster as the Dancers in the b.g. pick up the frenetic tempo!</context>
      <utterance>Oh... wow... golly...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if, for just one crazy moment, he couldn't resist...? He got knocked for a loop and lost control?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Breathless, she breaks a sweat, gasping for air. The DRUMS beat LOUDER, FASTER. The b.g. Dancers whip into a frenzy!</context>
      <utterance>Gosh... that might be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both of Laura's ballcap beer cans EXPLODE! Beer SPRAYS out in a huge gush, drenching her! Ned is so preoccupied with his own dilemma, he doesn't even notice. He heaves a sigh... pats her hand... smiles philosophically.</context>
      <utterance>What if a tidal wave of lust crashed over him and he was sucked into a vortex of wild, thrashing urges?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... it's not your problem. I'll work it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drops the ice Mermaid head. It shatters Laura's glass to bits! Lola turns to Ned with a cold glare.</context>
      <utterance>Like some ice for your drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lights her cigarette with the ice pick lighter, then flips it like a jackknife. It STICKS into Ned's chair, right between his legs. Lola flashes a coldly arrogant smile at Laura... then exits.</context>
      <utterance>Does your wife know you're... "working" late? I certainly hope so, Mr. Ravine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank slips in, wearing his greasy overalls. He wipes his hands on a rag... giving Lana a sly wink.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry up, darling. You'll be late!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all taken care of. When do I knock on the door?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps over to the blinds and demonstrates. He knocks.</context>
      <utterance>Wait until I signal you. When I raise the blinds... you knock.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, patronizing. Frank exits. Lana picks up the Skunk, cuddling him. Ned comes down wearing his trademark gray suit. Lana kisses him passionately... a final farewell.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, later... right... okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive carefully, sweetheart. Say bye- bye to Little Ned. He loves his daddy... don't you Stink Pot?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As soon as Ned closes the door, Lana's smile vanishes and she casually tosses the Skunk aside with a LOUD CRASH O.C.</context>
      <utterance>See you tonight, Junior.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This neighborhood is getting worse all the time! Damn kids stole my engine!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you catch the train to Santa Barbara? It leaves in twenty minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll just fly up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned looks at her strangely. She catches herself.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean... you can't. Armed terrorists seized the airport this morning. A plane crashed into the tower... and all the runways are on fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. So?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's fogged in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dammit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lana goes to the window, starts to raise the blinds.</context>
      <utterance>For my peace of mind... take the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops... letting the blinds drop down.</context>
      <utterance>I can't do it. You know how I feel about riding trains.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darling... it's only a short trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to raise the blinds again. He picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... right. A short trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just because both your parents died in a train wreck...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And my brother, Jeff...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your brother, Morty...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My two sisters...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My best friend, Al... my dog, Woof... Grandma Rose... and Uncle Lionel. All killed by trains!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coincidence, Ned. Beside... that's the past. They're gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I guess I can't bring them back by not riding on a train.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to raise the blinds again...</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She abandons the blinds, leaving them raised part way...</context>
      <utterance>But I just can't get over this stupid nagging fear that...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a KNOCK at the door. Lana tugs on the cord and the blinds drop with a CRASH. The KNOCKING stops. She pretends it didn't even happen, racing on.</context>
      <utterance>Fear! What about our baby, Ned? I don't want to raise a child in a home filled with fear!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if you can conquer your fear... maybe I can conquer my fear of having a baby with a father who's fearful.  Ned... don't let a train kill our child before it's even conceived!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs the cord, then hesitates...</context>
      <utterance>I guess you're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. He nods. She quickly pulls the blinds up.</context>
      <utterance>You're sure now...?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A LOUD KNOCK at the front door. Lana opens it. It's Frank.</context>
      <utterance>But we'll never make it to the station. By the time a cab gets here...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was in the neighborhood. Thought I'd stop by and pick up my tools.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank will drive you. Won't you Frank?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all freeze. Lana glares at Frank, who is completely unaware of his faux pas... while Ned tries to figure out why that response didn't sound right.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, I'll take you to the train station.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not going to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shifts gears, guns the engine. They rocket ahead, BOUNCING WILDLY, their heads THUMPING the car roof! The van SPLASHES through deep water, a huge fantail spraying out on both sides.</context>
      <utterance>We'll make it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... now what're you going to do if you feel queasy going through the tunnel?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll stand in the vestibule between the cars.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses his cheek. He reluctantly boards the train. Her smile vanishes. She hurries back to the next car, nods at Frank, boards the train. Frank peels off his coveralls, follows her on.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. When you get queasy... go stand in the vestibule between the cars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WOMAN PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max swivels around to look at her... turning his bare behind toward an IRRITABLE MAN across the aisle.</context>
      <utterance>OH! My dear gracious!</utterance>
   <speaker>IRRITABLE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SIR! Would you PLEASE extinguish that foul smelling cigar?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to put out my CIGAR? YOU want me to put out my cigar? You want ME to put out my CIGAR?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRRITABLE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without turning, Max holds the ticket up over his shoulder. The Conductor takes it, punches it, notices the gun barrel.</context>
      <utterance>Ticket?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max turns, raising the gun with a nasty GROWL. The Conductor casually snaps a baggage tag to the barrel, taking the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry pal... automatic weapons are only allowed in the club car after nine p.m.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Conductor drops the weapon into a big mesh bag... along with a dozen other guns he's collected. He exits. Max whirls around facing the window, eyes filled with rage. Now what?</context>
      <utterance>I'll check it with baggage. You can claim it at the depot in Santa Barbara.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lana turns to Frank... inspired. She leans toward Jeff.</context>
      <utterance>Hi! I'm Jeff and I'm eight years old. Didja know if ya put a penny on the track it'll make the train crash? No kiddin'! You ever been in a wreck? My uncle has. Lotsa times. It's really neat. Everybody gets creamed! All bloody guts... heads ripped off and stuff... Hey... wanna hear my song "Great Green Gobs of Greasy Grimy Gopher Guts"?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to earn a couple bucks, kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi! I'm Jeff and I'm eight years old. Didja know if ya put a penny on the track it'll make the train crash?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank gets up, moves down the aisle slowly, eyes on Ned. He can't squeeze past the Old Woman, who is still struggling to pull her huge trunk down aisle. So... he climbs right over the top of it... oblivious to her. Frank stares at Ned warily as he gets closer. Suddenly, Jeff squirts a stream of water in Ned's eyes. Frank sees his chance, rushing past Ned toward the vestibule.</context>
      <utterance>He's losing it. You better get up to the next car. Remember, give me the high sign as soon as you see the river. It'll be two minutes and nine seconds past the tunnel. I'll take care of the rest. Anything goes wrong... just make sure you back me up.  And don't let him see you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This... is not a toy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Ned realizes he's right. Acting tough, he pulls the plug and drains the water out of the gun, then tosses it back to Jeff. Without missing a beat, Jeff drops the empty water magazine from the grip and jams a full one in... just like loading a cartridge clip. He smirks, ready for action. In the aisle next to them, the Old Woman now pulls her trunk back toward the vestibule. Jeff points the squirt gun at her. Suddenly, she whips around and SQUIRTS HIM in the face with her own squirt gun! He sputters!</context>
      <utterance>Yes it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes the trunk into the first coach car, then very politely holds the door open for her. She smiles sweetly at him as she shuffles through.</context>
      <utterance>Here... let me help you with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a nice young man. You are so polite.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I try to be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>French fried eyeballs and ugly scabs you wanna pick... stuff to make your mother sick... dog poop on a stick... puke and snot all mixed together in a pot... Ned is looking very pale and queasy. Suddenly, Jeff jumps up... presses his face against the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned can't take it anymore. He gets up, pale and sweating.</context>
      <utterance>Oh boy! Here comes the tunnel!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shocked to see it's Max, Lana empties the rest of the bullets into him... BLAM! BLAM! BLAM! BLAM! Max is SLAMMED back into the vestibule door by the impact!</context>
      <utterance>You shootin' at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fires one last shot... BLAM!!!</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... you're definitely shootin' at me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her hand gently and kisses it...</context>
      <utterance>In this crazy world, there's not a whole lot a guy can count on. But when the chips are down, I can always count on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... then, CLICK! He snaps a handcuff on her wrist!</context>
      <utterance>You risked your life to save mine. A guy can't ask any more from a woman than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I saw you shoot him, Lana. In cold blood. I gotta arrest you for murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ned... you wouldn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I'm a cop. I have a job to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... you said it yourself. I saved your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, baby. I know a good lawyer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of gun did she use?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a question for the arresting officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you the arresting officer?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have to ask her attorney.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But aren't you her attorney?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only her husband can answer that.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned stops at the top of the stairs, turning to the Reporters.</context>
      <utterance>What will Mrs. Ravine be wearing at the trial?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lovely powder blue dress with a cinch waist, full bodice and a delicately pleated skirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it have a matching jacket?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No comment.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it cotton or rayon?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned and Laura turn and enter the building.</context>
      <utterance>I said... NO COMMENT!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she eat any of the victim's body parts?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez... they're really throwing some tough questions out there today.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're just doing their job.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... well I call it a "high-tech lynching of an uppity white housewife."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arch hands him a hardbound book.</context>
      <utterance>Only cell available. They had that serial killer locked up here... you know, the one who talks his victims to death then eats them... Hannibal the Lecturer. But they let him out for a three week tour to publicize his new book.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"To Serve Man."</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned flips it over.</context>
      <utterance>It's a cookbook.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arch pulls the front cover of the book open, pointing.</context>
      <utterance>And look, look... he autographed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arch points toward the cage.</context>
      <utterance>To Arch... Love to have you for dinner sometime... Hannibal.  Very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're waiting for ya. They didn't want to start without her attorney being present.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three POLICE INVESTIGATORS sit opposite Lana at a long table. Moths flutter everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>PFFFTT! Damn moths! This place could use a good exterminator.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVESTIGATOR # 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned, Laura and Arch enter the cage as the Guard exits.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get the SWAT Team in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you get me out of this cage, Ned? I'm goin' buggy in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to the Investigators.</context>
      <utterance>Judge said no bail. Don't worry. Just tell the truth, you'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's gonna handle the interrogation?</utterance>
   <speaker>INVESTIGATOR 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your collar... your bust... your call... your show... your play... your move... your wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura sits at the far end of the table and opens her notebook. Lana pulls out her mirrored compact, starts to apply lipstick.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay!... I'll handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVESTIGATOR 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods toward a warning sign: a circle around a LIPSTICK with a diagonal line thru it. She responds, cool, confident.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry Mrs. Ravine... there's no makeup allowed in this building.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the b.g., members of the SWAT Team desperately swat at the fluttering moths. Ned spins his chair around, plants one foot on it, leans on his knee, looking hard at Lana.</context>
      <utterance>What're you gonna do... arrest me for primping?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give us a tough time. Just spill it! What were you doing on that train?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned raises his hand, sits down, leans close, changing his tone.</context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, quit playing games with us!  Who put ya up to it? Where'd you get the gun? What's your link with the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams his briefcase shut and turns to Lana, sincere.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa whoa whoa whoa! That's it! I will not tolerate this unwarranted badgering of my client. She'll have her day in court, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to thank you, Mrs. Ravine, for being so cooperative with these gentlemen.  Did you get all that down, Laura. Every word she said?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. Both of 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whips the cover off the bubbling pot.</context>
      <utterance>NOOOOOOOooooooo!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YES! Cappelini pomodoro!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts up pasta with a spaghetti spoon... tossing a sprig of basil into the pot from the basil-leaf crown she wears.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pasta with tomato sauce. Whatsa matta? You don't like Italian?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Ned Junior? WHERE IS HE?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs Lola's arm and drags her toward the front door.</context>
      <utterance>I thought he might like to get out, so I took him to the amusement park.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't just break into my house, cook my food... borrow my skunk!  Leave me alone. Stay out of my face! Out of my neighborhood! Out of my</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He SLAMS the door in her face... hesitates a beat, curious... then pulls the door open. Lola's still there.</context>
      <utterance>You haven't seen the last of me, Ned.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned SLAMS the door again.</context>
      <utterance>I told you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHEERLEADERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BBC COMMENTATOR speaks to a TV camera.</context>
      <utterance>Lana, Lana, she's the one Shot a bad guy with a gun Blew that sucker off a train Some guys are a friggin' pain YaaaaaAAAAAAAAY LANA!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENTATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned and Laura push their way through the crush of REPORTERS.</context>
      <utterance>Once again, Americans are making a mockery of their courts, turning a murder trial into a media circus! How can justice ever prevail when it is ridiculed and reviled in such a heinously revolting manner? This is Clement Von Franckenstein returning you to our BBC studios in London for the latest photographs of Lady Di naked in the bath.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the prosecution will prove that this repulsive and degenerate woman coldly murdered a decent, law-abiding citizen...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Objection! Move to strike. Hearsay, irrelevant, stupid, idiotic, caca- doody poo-poo...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sustained.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And can you tell us what this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned snatches it back, pacing, folding it into a paper airplane.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's a death threat that Max Shady FAXED to you on the day he was released from prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A FAX in which he threatened to puree certain parts of my anatomy in a blender! I'd like to submit this into evidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Objection! Who cares about the FAX in this case?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned sails the paper plane toward the COURT CLERK, who is at an evidence table already piled high with tagged guns, appliances, knickknacks, auto parts and other junk. The plane sails toward an open window. The Clerk grabs it... going OUT the window with the plane!</context>
      <utterance>I'll allow it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And is this the blender you found in the lavatory of the train?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bailiff reaches out, Ned waves him off... instead, tossing the blender over several heads to the Court Clerk... who runs to catch it, CRASHING into the wall. The blender falls,</context>
      <utterance>I'd like this marked as evidence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SPORTSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the RE-PLAY SCREEN we see the action repeated in SLOW MOTION as the Sportscaster draws lines, circles, x's and squiggles.</context>
      <utterance>Awwwww... a bad call by Ravine. Let's check out the re-play.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORTSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at THAT! The Bailiff is wide open! But instead of handing it off, Ravine goes for the long bomb. Ohhhh! The pass is wide! A real wobbler! There's no way! He scrambles, but he just can't get his hands on it... And RIGHT THERE!...  ...WHAM! That blender is gone!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ned... did you ever consider that maybe you don't know women as well as you think you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They both look toward the witness stand. Ned is shaken.</context>
      <utterance>Now would you tell the court, in your own words, what you said to Mr. Ravine?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really worried about this guy. He could blow our whole case right out of the water.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great green gobs of greasy grimy gopher guts... mutilated monkey meat... itsy-bitsy birdie feet... Great green gobs of greasy grimy gopher guts... and me without a spoon! The JURORS turn pale and reach for the air sickness bags in front of them. The Courtroom erupts. The Judge pounds his gavel LOUDLY.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recess! Ten minutes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotcha, dork face! Gotcha, gotcha!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you didn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BAILIFF steps into CLOSE UP, blowing a whistle loudly!</context>
      <utterance>No way! Uh-uh! Missed by a mile!</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recess is over! Let's go... move it, move it, move it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORTSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There they go... the UCLA Marching Band! And now... Holy Toledo!... it looks like the victim's mother... Helen Shady... is gonna take the stand! This will be the first defensive play of the afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Shady... would you tell us about your son, Max. Was he a... a good boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was the best. And that's not just a mother talking. You can ask anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he got into trouble once in awhile... like all kids do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches down into her huge purse, pulling out a photo album. She opens it, showing Ned.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, pranks. Little jokes and things. But he was so cute. I have pictures!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. This is when he set the cat on fire...  Oh... but the cat deserved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what, uh... what are these...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marshmallows. He just loved to toast marshmallows over a roaring cat. Burned on the outside... all soft in the middle.  And right here... this was taken on the day he left the priesthood to join the Green Berets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes! That was during his Ku Klux Klan phase. He would take the sheets right off my bed... cut those little holes in them. What a stitch he was!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She snatches the photo out of the album.</context>
      <utterance>And is this Max... with all the tools... fixing his bike?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why that shouldn't even be in there! It's his rotten little half-brother.  Stinkin' little pecker... he never was any good...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Court Clerk, Bailiff and Court Recorder have all moved around behind the witness stand, peering over Mrs. Shady's shoulder at the photos.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! I didn't like these neo-Nazi boys. They were all so fussy and persnickety about everything. Heil this and heil that.  Oh look... here's Max with his chainsaw. He loved to go to the national park and cut down those giant old trees. It made him feel so patriotic. You know, if he hadn't been such a successful criminal... I think he would have been a lumberjack.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But now he'll never be anything! Not since...  ...that woman, your wife, pulled the trigger and put my little Max in his grave!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Shady! Do not POINT your finger in my courtroom. It's discourteous, impolite and disrespectful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you tell me what to do with my finger! It's been more places than you've ever dreamed of!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit down!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SHADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Shady goes berserk... leaping from the witness stand, pointing several different fingers at Judge Skanky. The Bailiff attempts to restrain her, but she breaks free... scurrying around the courtroom, pointing fingers at everyone! CHAOS prevails!</context>
      <utterance>I'll point my finger wherever I want!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you encounter the victim... Max Shady... on board the train?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRRITABLE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And I told him... "this is the NO SMOKING car! Would you please put out your damn cigar!"</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man strains to see the cigar out of the corner of his eye. Impatient, Ned finally holds up a small pocket mirror.</context>
      <utterance>And is that the cigar in your ear?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRRITABLE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bailiff picks up the Irritable Man and dumps him on the evidence table, where he is tagged by the Court Clerk.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like the cigar and the head of this witness entered into evidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The defense calls... Lana Ravine!</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you swear to tell the truth, the whole truth and nothing but the truth so help you God?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have to answer that, Harlan?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned approaches.</context>
      <utterance>No, no dear. I'll vouch for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Mrs. Ravine... may I call you Lana?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Call me Angel Tits.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I object!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sustained. Counselor... you will address Angel Tits as Mrs. Ravine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Ravine... would you please tell the court... what were you doing on that train?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned and EVERY MALE in the courtroom winces at this, doubling over in imagined agony. Lana pauses, then continues...</context>
      <utterance>I saw Max Shady at the station... saw him get on board. I knew he'd made threats to kill you and mutilate your reproductive organs...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...so I got on the train too... so I could warn you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to have children?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someday. With the right man.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you couldn't have children if my...  ...were...  ...and, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would be difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you followed him, knowing you had to protect me... your husband... your best friend... the man you love... the future father of your children.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when you saw that maniac standing in the vestibule, waiting to pulverize my pee-pee... you pulled the gun and fired and fired and FIRED!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses to count off on her fingers, then...</context>
      <utterance>And fired and fired and fired and fired and fired and fired and fired...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and fired and fired and fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The defense rests, your Honor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned shoves the BANANA and two PLUMS into a demonstration blender on the defense table. He hits the puree button and the blender WHIRRS loudly!</context>
      <utterance>How can you convict a courageous woman who risked everything to save the life of her beloved husband? A woman who acted boldly to stop a demented maniac from doing THIS!...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lana Ravine is a loving wife and the potential mother of my potential child. I challenge YOU to strike a blow for motherhood and the American justice system! Put the "con" back in the Constitution. Put the "ju" back in jurisprudence. Put the "can" back in American. And put the "dom" back in freedom. Find this woman INNOCENT!... so we can all go to bed happy tonight!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... has the jury reached a verdict?</utterance>
   <speaker>JURY FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes we have, your Honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you find the defendant... on the count of manslaughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>JURY FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not guilty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the count of murder in the first degree?</utterance>
   <speaker>JURY FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not guilty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the Count of Monte Cristo?</utterance>
   <speaker>JURY FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BOISTEROUS CLAMOR in the court. The electronic signs FLASH</context>
      <utterance>Not guilty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Jury and Spectators start to rise. The Judge hesitates, gavel poised, shooting them a warning look.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Then on the count of three, let's all get the hell out of here! One... two...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone FREEZES halfway out of their seats... waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Wait... for... it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE SKANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smacks his gavel. Everyone scatters for the doors, but Judge Skanky beats them out of the room. Lana turns cool, dropping her courtroom facade. She plucks off her earrings, unbuttons the neck of her dress, reaches in and magically pulls out her bra, tossing it away.</context>
      <utterance>Two and a half... THREE!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO LEGAL AIDES sneak up behind Ned and dump a big plastic barrel of Gatorade cans over his head!</context>
      <utterance>Well, counselor, looks like you won another case. Lucky for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRRITABLE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls him away as Lana steps up, with a cigarette dangling from her lips. Lana picks up her gun and spins the cylinder. It's loaded. The battered Court Clerk limps over, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>I told you, Bernard... smoking cigars is bad for your hearing!</utterance>
   <speaker>COURT CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Ravine! What can I do for ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura sees this... turns to Ned with a look of shock.</context>
      <utterance>How much for my gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned looks off toward Lana with admiration.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it! She just bought her gun back! The gun she used to kill a man!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Lana wades into the crowd of REPORTERS, some still without pants, the CAMERA MOVES TO Lola, who is watching Lana from the back of the courtroom. Lola pulls a small cord hanging from the side of her hat... opening her veil like window drapes. She's not happy.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... the same gun that saved my life. I'm sure it has sentimental value.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... you did it. Ya beat the rap.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets to his feet, cocky.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks toward him, her voice cold, accusing. He backs up.</context>
      <utterance>Hey... I knew he'd spring ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't lift a finger, Frank. You let me take all the heat.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lana pulls the gun from her purse, pointing it at him.</context>
      <utterance>Heeeee-eeey... what could I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were gonna let me rot in the slammer... never say a thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look... you're out... free. Now we're together. That's what counts. We can try again! Forget triple indemnity. We'll whack him and split three mil.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not splitting anything, Frank.  And you know too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs arrogantly... starts to unbutton his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>You're right.  Maybe I'll just screw you to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're talkin' baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FORENSIC MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Throughout this scene, in the b.g., the milling COPS and INVESTIGATORS slip on all the blood, as if on slick ice, and fall out of frame, their arms and legs flailing helplessly! One of the Coroner's INVESTIGATORS approaches Arch and Ned.</context>
      <utterance>Watch your step, guys. There's a lot of blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVESTIGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up a rolled piece of paper with a pair of tweezers. Ned takes it, trying to unroll it.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like a suicide. We found a note.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVESTIGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned hands it off to Arch, who casually unrolls it. The Investigator slips, arms waving, and falls out of frame.</context>
      <utterance>It was stuck up his nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I can't take it anymore. I'm a mediocre mechanic... and a lousy lover."</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arch gives Ned a very strange look. Ned feels his stare.</context>
      <utterance>He's sure got that right.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the b.g., various COPS pair up to have their pictures taken by the Police Crime Scene Photographer... posing, grinning.</context>
      <utterance>The "mechanic" part, I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why, Arch, but I just can't shake this crazy hunch it wasn't suicide.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... uh, Ned... This is Lola, um...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Lola.</context>
      <utterance>Um? She told you her name was Um? And what other lies did she tell you? I've never seen this woman in my life! Never followed her home! Never had sex with her in the refrigerator! It's all a sick fantasy... and I deny everything!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When will women like you learn, you can't tear apart a perfectly good marriage with your vicious lies... Miss UMMMM!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to Lana with a cold and contemptuous glare.</context>
      <utterance>Actually... it's Smith. Lola Smith. I sell vacuum cleaners, Mr. Ravine. The big powerful kind that suck up everything in sight. I was just telling your wife, if she wants to get rid of all her dirt, she has to be willing to pay the price.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lola exits. As soon as the door closes, Lana whirls around in a fury!... SMASHING a lamp! She SHRIEKS furiously!</context>
      <utterance>Let me know what you decide, Mrs. Ravine. I'm sure we can work out a convenient "payment" plan. A pleasure meeting you... Ned.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his arms around her, comforting.</context>
      <utterance>I... hate... SALESMEN!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it's been a tough ordeal... with the trial and everything. Tell you what... let's take a trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A trip?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Just the two of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like that. Just you and me... all alone. I'll start packing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her and exits. Lana turns to look up toward the landing, a vengefully insane smile clouding her face.</context>
      <utterance>Great. Listen... I got something to take care of. I'll be back in awhile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door CRASHES OPEN! Ned is silhouetted in the doorway. He looks really pissed! Lola turns and runs. Ned sprints after her, leaping through the air... bringing her down with a tackle!</context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her foot shoots out, smashing him right in the face... WHAM! She jumps up and scrambles away. Ned pursues her. She grabs a bottle of scotch from the counter, spins around.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you say so?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws the bottle! He ducks and it shatters on the wall!</context>
      <utterance>Would you like a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whirls on one foot, nailing him in the head with a FLYING SPIN KICK! He stumbles back, dazed. She grabs an ice pick.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks. I'm driving.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lola charges! Ned rolls onto his back, jamming both feet into her stomach, heaving her up over him... thru the air! She SLAMS into the wall!... then slowly turns... still cool and collected. She raises a cigarette... lights it with the ice pick "lighter."</context>
      <utterance>Then let's get to the point!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's your problem, tough guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves her against the wall... the cigarette flying away.</context>
      <utterance>Stay away from my life, my wife, my home and my pets! I'm taking Lana on a vacation and when I come back, I don't ever want to see your face again!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her by the shoulders, shaking her.</context>
      <utterance>A VACATION! She doesn't deserve a VACATION! She's a brat! A bad girl! She always was and always will be!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? You don't know anything about Lana?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know EVERYTHING!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She clams up. He slaps her.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know her? Who is she to you? TELL ME!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is she!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's your wife!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is she!?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's my sister!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liar! Who is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his hand to slap her hard.</context>
      <utterance>She's your wife!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues to slap him... back and forth... repeating her answers... "She's your wife"... "She's my sister!"... "Your wife!"... "My sister!"... "Wife!"... "Sister!" He reaches a boiling point, raising two fingers, preparing to give her the Three Stooges "two-fingered eye poke." She blocks it with her hand and shoves him away. Then, she executes a perfect Three Stooges "wiggly-hand head slap", telling him...</context>
      <utterance>She's my sister!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned is stunned. MUSIC THUNDERS dramatically! Lana clicks the stereo off. The MUSIC STOPS.</context>
      <utterance>She's your wife... AND my sister!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was spoiled rotten! She stole everything I ever had. Everything! Including him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Him? Who, him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dwayne. The boy's gym teacher. He was older. So mature... so strong. He smelled like dirty sweat socks and old basketballs. And he was all mine. For awhile.  But Lana wasn't satisfied with her own things. She had to have mine too. She took it all... my makeup, my sweaters, my shoes, my underwear...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wore the same clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were identical twins.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you talking about? You two don't look anything alike.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore. One day I caught her stealing my lavender eye shadow and she smashed my face in with a shovel. I had fifty-three operations. When the doctors were finished with me... I looked like THIS! I'm ugly. UGLY!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't lie to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They did a terrific job!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look in the mirror. I can SEE!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... you're gorgeous!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes toward him... feeling in control once more.</context>
      <utterance>Tell that to Dwayne. When he saw my face, he left me for HER... because she looked more like me than I did! First she stole my looks... then she stole the only man who ever loved me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I found a way to get even. The best revenge possible. Destroy her marriage!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why you did all this? Seduced me... harrassed me... the tape... the flowers... the phone calls...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been hangin' out with Dick Tracy, haven't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't work. Lana loves me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter. I'm blackmailing her for everything she's worth. She murdered that greasy auto mechanic. I saw her do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lana killed Frank Kelbo?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelbo! His name was Kelbo?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Why? Did he burn you on car repairs too?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dwayne's name was Kelbo. He had a son. Frankie Kelbo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ned rubs his temples, shuts his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>The pieces of the puzzle were falling into place and I didn't like the picture they were making. If Lana really killed Frank Kelbo, then I had misjudged her by a mile. Sure... he was a lousy mechanic. But murder?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was all starting to give me a headache bigger than the national deficit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ned! I'm glad you're here. I have so much to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on in. I'll make some tea. Grab a chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drags a chair in behind her, sits at the kitchen table. Ned puts a kettle on the burner, turns it on. He starts searching through the cupboard for teabags.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks... I brought my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... what have you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned freezes, staring out the window, unable to face her.</context>
      <utterance>A lottery ticket and a laundry receipt.  I found them in the pocket of that suit you wore the night you were working under cover with a client.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned turns to her when he hears Lola's name... looking baffled by this convoluted piece of logic.</context>
      <utterance>You remember that night, don't ya Ned? Then it hit me. Lottery starts with L-O. Laundry starts with L-A. L- O... L-A. Lola.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to the cupboard, picking up a container.</context>
      <utterance>Don't sweat it. It's the way a woman's mind works.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about Ovaltine?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Then I remembered you told me some guy named Frank had been working on your wife's car for two months. You with me so far?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brings the Ovaltine container to the table.</context>
      <utterance>I'm way ahead of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A huge ceramic cookie jar sits on the table in front of them. Laura SMASHES it with her fist, breaking it open! Cookies spill out... and the insurance policy.</context>
      <utterance>Well back it up. You probably took a wrong turn. Remember your insurance policy... the one we couldn't find? I started thinking, who else had access to it beside you and me? The answer came up... Lana. And since she's a woman, it's probably hidden right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits down... starts eating Oreos... twisting them apart.</context>
      <utterance>So that's where she hid the Oreos.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ned, Lana wasn't trying to save your life when she shot Max Shady. She and Frank were plotting to kill you and collect on your insurance policy. But she shot the wrong guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the craziest thing I ever heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you see... Frank was going to let her take the fall. So she murdered him and tried to make it look like suicide.  That's when I realized there was a connection between Lola and Lana...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... they're sisters. Twin sisters.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She unrolls a complex genealogical chart... walks him thru it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, hang on to your jock strap, Ned. There's more.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura pauses dramatically, then announces.</context>
      <utterance>Not only is Frank's father Dwayne Kelbo, notoriously amorous gym teacher and Lola Cain's former lover... Frank's mother is Helen Shady. Max and Frank are half-brothers who never met.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your lovely wife, Lana, murdered both of Helen Shady's sons.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is so unbelievable.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you haven't even heard my story.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tea kettle WHISTLES! Laura pulls it off the burner. The whistling subsides... replaced by the distant SOUND of water running upstairs. Ned cocks his head, listening.</context>
      <utterance>He turned into a monster. And that's when I left him. I just couldn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That damn faucet keeps turning on all by itself. I'll go check it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned exits. Laura opens the Ovaltine container. It's empty. A DARK SHADOW moves past the window behind Laura. Suspense MUSIC. Laura opens the cupboard. PIGEONS explode out, wings beating furiously! She catches her breath, looks in the cupboard. The cans and boxes are covered with pigeon shit. She shoves them aside, looking for the Ovaltine.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'll make the Ovaltine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>ECHOING V.O.</mode>
      <context>The repetitive ECHO gets to him. He smacks his head with the palm of his hand. The skipping stops... followed by...</context>
      <utterance>Women are an open book. You can always tell the rotten apples from the peaches. I'd stake my career on it... stake my career on it... stake my career on it...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>ECHOING V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...If anyone ever proves me wrong, I'll throw away my badge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Ned!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out his police badge, looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>You were right... there's a million things I don't know about women. Maybe you can teach me a few hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses it away, over the railing.</context>
      <utterance>Hell... I had too many careers anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hears THIS... smiles at her.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. But I want to have kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace.</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... maybe I was wrong. Maybe women really are like a big jigsaw puzzle... with pieces that never seem to fit where you want 'em to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...understand women... give birth... and program a VCR. And giving birth is the easy one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ned...</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Laura?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at her. They kiss. Romantic SAXAPHONE MUSIC begins to play... only this time, it's "Laura's Theme." The CAMERA PULLS BACK SLOWLY... revealing Dizzy laying on the bed beside them... playing the sax. After a beat, Laura turns to Dizzy.</context>
      <utterance>Knock off the chatter, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned casually slips him a twenty dollar bill. Dizzy slips off the bed and out the door. Laura turns to Ned.</context>
      <utterance>We won't need you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand reaches slowly over the edge of the bed, toward the floor. Suddenly... she comes up with a CONCERTINA, a small accordian... and begins to play it! Ned lays there listening for a few moments, a stunned look frozen on his face. Then... he reaches under the pillow and pulls out a HARMONICA and joins in. The CAMERA BOOMS UP to a HIGH ANGLE SHOT... as they play MEDLEY of all the MUSIC heard in the film.</context>
      <utterance>We can make our own music.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROLL END CREDITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After the final credit, WE HEAR:</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ned, do you know... I want you to make love to me all night long?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But if you hum a few bars... I'll fake it.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
