<movie id="210" title="Fight Club">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One minute.  This is the beginning. We're at ground zero. Maybe you should say a few words, to mark the occasion.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... i... ann....iinn.. ff....nnyin...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack tongues the barrel to the side of his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>With a gun barrel between your teeth, you only speak in vowels.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't think of anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tyler checks his watch.</context>
      <utterance>With my tongue, I can feel the rifling in the barrel. For a second, I totally forgot about Tyler's whole controlled demolition thing and I wondered how clean this gun is.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's getting exciting now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack turns so that he can see down -- 31 STORIES.</context>
      <utterance>That old saying, how you always hurt the one you love, well, it works both way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have front row seats for this Theater of Mass Destruction. The Demolitions Committee of Project Mayhem wrapped the foundation columns of ten buildings with blasting gelatin. In two minutes, primary charges will blow base charges, and those buildings will be reduced to smoldering rubble. I know this because Tyler knows this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look what we've accomplised.  Thirty seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PULL BACK from Jack's face. It's pressed against TWO LARGE BREASTS that belong to...BOB, 45, a moose of a man. Jack is engulfed by Bob in an intense embrace. Bob weeps openly.</context>
      <utterance>Somehow, I realize all of this -- the gun, the bombs, the revolution -- is really about Marla Singer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to wide on...</context>
      <utterance>Bob had bitch tits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was a support group for men with testicular cancer. The big moosie slobbering all over me was Bob.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're still men.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. We're men. Men is what we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six months ago, Bob's testicles were removed. Then hormone therapy. He developed bitch tits because his testosterone was too high and his body upped the estrogen. That was where my head fit -- into his huge, sweating tits that hung enormous, the way we think of God's as big.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob hugs tighter; then looks with empathy into Jack's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>They're gonna have to open my pec's again to drain the fluid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. You cry now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. Back up. Let me start earlier.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For six months. I could not sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack looks up as a pudgy man, Jack's BOSS, enters, Starbucks cup in hand, and slides a stack of reports on Jack's desk.</context>
      <utterance>When deep space exploration ramps up, it will be corporations that name everything. The IBM Stellar Sphere. The Philip Morris Galaxy. Planet Starbucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to need you out-of-town a little more this week. We've got some "red-flags" to cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must've been Tuesday. he was wearing his "cornflower-blue" tie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to de-prioritize my current reports until you advise of a status upgrade?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need to make these your primary "action items."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was full of pep. Must've had his grande latte enema.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack hides a yawn, pretends to listen.</context>
      <utterance>Here are your flight coupons. Call me from the road if there are any snags. Your itinerary...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like everyone else, I had become a slave to the IKEA nesting instinct.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MOVE IN ON CATALOG -- ON PHOTO of COFFEETABLE SET...</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I'd like to order the Erika Pekkari slip covers. Jack drops the open catalog on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PAN TO PHOTO of ARMCHAIR...</context>
      <utterance>If I saw something like clever coffee table sin the shape of a yin and yang, I had to have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like the Johanneshov armchair in the Strinne green stripe pattern...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The lamps APPEAR. PAN OVER to wall...</context>
      <utterance>Or the Rislampa wire lamps of environmentally-friendly unbleached paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The clock APPEARS as the shelving unit APPEARS on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Even the Vild hall clock of galvanized steel, resting on the Klipsk shelving unit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A dining room set APPEARS. Jack, the cordless phone still glued to his ear, walks INTO FRAME and continues.</context>
      <utterance>I would flip through catalogs and wonder, "What kind of dining set defines me as a person?" We used to read pornography. Now it was the Horchow Collection.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack opens a cabinet, takes out a plate.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't want Cobalt. Oh, that sounds nice. Apricot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He rummages through the refrigerator. It's practically empty. Jack takes out a jar of mustard, opens it and uses a butter knife to eat it.</context>
      <utterance>I had it all. Even the glass dishes with tiny bubbles and imperfections, proof they were crafted by the honest, simple, hard-working indigenous peoples of wherever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>INTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you can't die of insomnia.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I died already. Look at my face.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need to lighten up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you give me something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red-and-blue Tuinal, lipstick-red Seconals.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Intern ushes Jack to the door. They step into the...</context>
      <utterance>You need healthy, natural sleep. Chew valerian root and get some more exercise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Intern moves into the other room. Jack stares after him.</context>
      <utterance>You want to see pain? Swing by First Methodist Tuesday nights. See the guys with testicular cancer. That's pain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Speaker cracks a sad smile. Some men chuckle, happy to lighten the mood.</context>
      <utterance>I... wanted three kids. Two boys and a girl. Mindy wanted two girls and one boy. We never could agree on anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack watches. A couple of the men go up to the speaker, comforting him, leading him away. A LEADER takes the stand.</context>
      <utterance>Well, she had her first child a month ago, a girl, with her new husband... And, Thank God. I'm glad for her, because she deserves... The speaker breaks down, WEEPS UNCONTROLLABLY.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack, uncomfortable, joins EVERYONE ELSE:</context>
      <utterance>Everyone, let's thank Thomas for sharing himself with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVERYONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks around. Many of the men are sniffling, sobbing. Jack squirms in his seat.</context>
      <utterance>I look around this room and I see a lot of courage. And it gives me strength. We give each other strength.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone gets out of their chairs and begins pairing-off. Jack stands, uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>It's time for the one-on-one. Let's follow Thomas's example and open ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob, his chin down on his chest, starts toward Jack, shuffling his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Can everyone find a partner?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bob takes Jack into an embrace.</context>
      <utterance>The big moosie, his eyes already shrink-wrapped in tears. Knees together, invisible steps.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob was a champion bodybuilder. You know that chest expansion program you see on TV? That was his idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...using steroids. I was a juicer. Diabonol, then, Wisterol -- it's for racehorses, for Christsake. Now I'm bankrupt, divorced, my two grown kids won't return my calls...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bob breaks into sobbing, putting his head on Jack's shoulder and completely covering Jack's face. After a long beat of crying, Bob raises up his head, looks at Jack's NAMETAG.</context>
      <utterance>Strangers with this kind of honesty make me go a big rubbery one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other. Slowly, Jack's eyes grow wet.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, Cornelius. You can cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bob pulls Jack's head back into his chest. Jack tightens his arms around Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Then... something happened. I was lost in oblivion -- dark and silent and complete.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack pulls away from Bob. On Bob's chest, there's a WET MASK of Jack's face from how he looks weeping.</context>
      <utterance>I found freedom. Losing all hope was freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Babies don't sleep this well.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I became addicted.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight, we're going to open the green door -- the heart chakra...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't really dying, I wasn't host to cancer or parasites; I was the warm little center that the life of this world crowded around.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack, eyes closed, is silent...</context>
      <utterance>...And you open the door and you step inside. We're inside our hearts. Now, imaging your pain as a white ball of healing light. That's right, the pain itself is a ball of healing light.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Step forward into your cave.</context>
      <utterance>It moves over your body, healing you. Keep this going and step forward, through the back door of the room. Where does it lead? To your cave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEADER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack comes upon a PENGUIN. The penguin looks at him, cocks his head to signal Jack forward.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. You're going deeper into your cave. And you're going to find your power animal...</utterance>
   <speaker>PENGUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The penguin jumps onto a patch of ICE and slides away.</context>
      <utterance>Slide.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>MARLA SINGER enters. She has short matte black hair and big, dark eyes like a character from japanese animation.</context>
      <utterance>Bob loved me because he thought my testicles were removed too. Being there, my face against his tits, ready to cry -- this was my vacation.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Marla looks around, raises a cigarette to her lips.</context>
      <utterance>And, she ruined everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob and Jack stare, dumbfounded.</context>
      <utterance>This is cancer, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack leans out further than the others, scornful.</context>
      <utterance>... and at "Free and Clear," my blood parasites group Thursdays.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- And, again, at "Seize The Day," my tuberculosis Friday night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- But, in here, in everyone, there's the squint of a five-day headache. Yet they forced themselves to be positive. They never said "parasite;" they said "agent." They always talked about getting better.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone sits in chairs. Jack catches sight of Marla.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking the lectern is CHLOE, a pale, sickly girl whose skin stretches yellowish and tight over her bones. She wears a head bondage. She clears her throat.</context>
      <utterance>To open tonight's communion, Chloe would like to say a few words.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh, Chloe. Chloe looked the way Joni Mitchell's skeleton would look if you made it smile and walk around a party being extra nice to everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>APPLAUSE from around the room.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm still here -- but I don't know for how long. That's as much certainty as anyone can give me. but I've got some good news -- I no longer have any fear of death.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LEADER gingerly takes control of the microphone.</context>
      <utterance>But... I am in a pretty lonely place. No one will have sex with me. I'm so close to the end and all I want is to get laid for the last time. I have pornographic movies in my apartment, and lubricants and amyl nitrate ...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Chloe. Everyone, let's thank Chloe.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVERYONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Chloe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack's face, eyes closed, is motionless.</context>
      <utterance>Now, you're standing at the entrance to your cave. You step inside your cave and you walk. Keep walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I did have a tumor, I'd name it Marla. Marla...the little scratch on the roof of your mouth that would heal if only you could stop tonguing it, but you can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, find your power animal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack sees the ghastly spectre of Chloe ambling towards him. He tries to smile. She smiles with a twisted, dying mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Pick someone special to you tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Tayler.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never gave my real name at support groups.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Chloe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chloe's eyes are eerily bright with desperation. Jack, in a sincere attempt at levity, chokes out:</context>
      <utterance>We've never actually talked.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chloe laughs, a little too much. Jack squeezes out a laugh. Then he sees Marla, off by herself. Someone heads for her.</context>
      <utterance>You look good. You ... look ... like a pirate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack gives a quick nod to Chloe and darts towards Marla. Chloe watches him go. STAY ON JACK AND MARLA as Jack CLAMPS his arms around her. He whispers into her ear.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, I have to...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on to you. You're a faker. You aren't dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, in the Sylvia Plath philosophy way, we're all dying. But you're not dying the way Chloe is dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell the other person how you feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a tourist. I saw you at melanoma, tuberculosis and testicular cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I saw you practicing this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Practicing what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Telling me off. Is it going as well as you hoped... ?  "... Mr. Taylor."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll expose you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. I'll expose you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla puts her head down on Jack's shoulder as if she were crying. Jack pulls her head back up. She deadpans at him.</context>
      <utterance>Share yourself completely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cheaper than a movie, and there's free coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are my groups. I was here first. I've been coming for a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A year? How'd you manage that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone who might've noticed either died or recovered and never came back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let yourself cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't know. I guess... when people think you're dying, they really listen, instead...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Instead of just waiting for their turn to speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brief recognition between them, broken as the Leader passes.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack waits till the Leader's out of earshot.</context>
      <utterance>Quietly, now. Share with each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It becomes an addiction.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack sighs, then pulls back.</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I can't cry with a faker present.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Candy-stripe a cancer ward. It's not my problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla starts out of the room. Jack follows her.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Can't we do something... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, the closing prayer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll split up the week. You can have lymphoma, tuberculosis and --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take tuberculosis. My smoking doesn't go over at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think testicular cancer should be no contest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, technically, I have more of a right to be there than you. You still have your balls.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack follow Marla into...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know -- am I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take the parasites.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't have both parasites. You can take blood parasites --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want brain parasites.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'll take blood parasites and organic brain dementia --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't have the whole brain!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So far, you have four and I only have two!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla gathers the chosen garments and heads out past Jack...</context>
      <utterance>Then, take blood parasites. It's yours. Now we each have three.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HONK! Jack starts. Marla's led him into the street with traffic barreling down. Marla walks on, oblivious as CARS screech to a halt, HORNS BLARING. Jack dashes, following...</context>
      <utterance>You... left half your clothes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla steps down hard on Jack's foot. He winces in pain.</context>
      <utterance>You're selling those?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Clerk starts to ring up the assessed amounts.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm selling some chothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, we each have three -- that's six. What about the seventh day? I want ascending bowel cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girl had done her homework.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Clerk gives a strange look as he hands money to Marla.</context>
      <utterance>I want ascending bowel cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's your favorite, too? Tried to slip it by me, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll split it. You get it the first and third Sunday of the month.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake. Jack tries to withdraw his hand; Marla holds it.</context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like this is goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks to the door, pocketing money, not looking back.</context>
      <utterance>Let's not make a big thing out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack watches her go. A moment, then he follows after...</context>
      <utterance>How's this for not making a big thing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... Marla, should we maybe exchange numbers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In case we want to switch nights.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack takes out a business card, writes his number on the back, hands it to her. She takes the pen, grabs his hand and writes her number on his palm. She walks into the street, causing more SCREECHING and HONKING. She turns, holds up the card.</context>
      <utterance>I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack starts to answer, but the traffic noise is too loud. Marla just shakes her head, turns, and keeps moving. A BUS moves into view, obscuring her.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't have your name. Who are you? Cornelius? Mr. Taylor? Dr. Zaius? Any of the stupid names you give each night?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is how I met Marla Singer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks with blearing eyes at his watch, steps away and looks at an overhanging CLOCK.</context>
      <utterance>Check-in for that flight doesn't begin for another two hours, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pacific, Mountain, Central. Lose an hour, gain an hour. This is your life, and it's ending one minute at a time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wake up at Air Harbor International.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everywhere I travel -- tiny life. Single-serving sugar, single-serving cream, single pat of butter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Microwave Cordon Bleu hobby kit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack picks up an individual, wrapped Q-TIP, looks at it. He moves out of the bathroom into...</context>
      <utterance>Shampoo/conditioner combo. Single- serving mouthwash, tiny bar of soap.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people I meet on each flight -- they're single-serving friends. Between take-off and landing, we have our time together, but that's all we get.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wake up at Logan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Two TECHNICIANS lead Jack to the BURNT-OUT SHELL of a WRECKED AUTOMOBILE. Jack sets down his briefcase, opens it and starts to make notes on a CLIPBOARDED FORM.</context>
      <utterance>On a long enough time line, the survival rate for everyone drops to zero.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a recall coordinator. My job is to apply the formula. It's a story problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's where the infant went through the windshield. Three points.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A new car built by my company leaves somewhere traveling at 60 miles per hour. The rear differential locks up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The teenager's braces around the backseat ashtray would make a good "anti-smoking" ad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The car crashes and burns with everyone trapped inside. Now: do we initiate a recall?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The father must've been huge. See how the fat burnt into the driver's seat with his polyester shirt? Very "modern art."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the number of vehicles in the field, , and multiply it by the probable rate of failure, , then multiply the result by the average out-of-court settlement, . A times B times C equals X...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If X is less than the cost of a recall, we don't do one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSISNESS WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are there a lot of these kinds of accidents?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you wouldn't believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESS WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Which... car company do you work for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Turgid silence. Jack turns to the window. He sees a PELICAN get SUCKED into the TURBINE.</context>
      <utterance>A major one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack's face remains bland during the following: the plane BUCKLES -- the cabin wobbles. People panic. Masks drop.</context>
      <utterance>Every time the plane banked too sharply on take-off or landing, I prayed for a crash, or a mid-air collision -- anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The side of the plane SHEARS OFF! Screaming PASSENGERS are sucked out into the night air, flying past the quivering wind. Magazines and other objects fly everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>No more haircuts. Nothing matters, not even bad breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack remains in his same position, same bland expression. DING! -- the seatbelt light goes OUT. Jack SNAPS AWAKE. EVERYTHING IS NORMAL. Some passengers get out of their seats. From next to Jack, a VOICE we've heard before...</context>
      <utterance>Life insurance pays off triple if you die on a business trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns to see TYLER. Without turned to Jack, Tyler continues:</context>
      <utterance>There are three ways to make napalm. One, mix equal parts of gasoline and frozen orange juice...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two, equal parts gasoline and diet cola. Three, dissolve kitty-litter in gasoline until the mixture is thick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler turns to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Pardon me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is how I met --</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler offers his hand. Jack takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Tyler Durden.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know why they have oxygen masks on planes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, supply oxygen?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler grabs a safety instruction CARD from the seatback, hands it to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Oxygen gets you high. In a catastrophic emergency, we're taking giant, panicked breaths...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler points to passive faces on the drawn figures.</context>
      <utterance>Suddenly, we become euphoic and docile. We accept our fate.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Emergency water landing, 600 miles per hour. Blank faces -- calm as Hindu cows.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you do, Tyler?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean -- for a living.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack laughs. Tyler reaches under the seat in front of him and lifts a BRIEFCASE.</context>
      <utterance>Why? So you can say, "Oh, that's what you do." -- And be a smug little shit about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack points to his own briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>You have a kind of sick desperation in your laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler turns the top of his briefcase toward Jack.</context>
      <utterance>We have the same briefcase.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at Tyler, then pops the latches and raises the lid to reveal quaintly-wrapped bars of SOAP.</context>
      <utterance>Open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler hands Jack his card. "THE PAPER STREET SOAP COMPANY."</context>
      <utterance>Soap -- the yardstick of civilization.  I make and sell soap...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler SNAPS the briefcase shut. Jack stares.</context>
      <utterance>If you were to add nitric acid to the soap-making process, one would get nitroglycerin. With enough soap, one could blow up the world, if one were so inclined.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler stares back. Jack, enjoying his own chance to be witty, leans closer to Tyler.</context>
      <utterance>Tyler, you are by far the most interesting "single-serving" friend I've ever met.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, when you travel, everything is small, self-contained--</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The spork. I get it. You're very clever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that working out for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Being clever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh... great.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler stands, looks towards the aisle.</context>
      <utterance>Keep it up, then. Keep it right up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler moves to the aisle, his ass toward jack, walks away...</context>
      <utterance>... As I squeeze past, do I give you the ass or the crotch?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler goes to the curtain dividing First Class, slaps the curtain aside and sits in an empty seat. Jack watches.</context>
      <utterance>We are defined by the choices we make.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How I came to live with Tyler is: airlines have this policy about vibrating luggage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SECURITY TFM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Modern bombs don't tick.</context>
      <utterance>Throwers don't worry about ticking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me? "Throwers?"</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY TFM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baggage handlers. But when a suitcase vibrates, the throwers have to call the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My suitcase was vibrating?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY TFM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack sees, through the window, Tyler, at the curb, throwing his briefcase into the back of a shiny, red CONVERTIBLE. Tyler leaps over the door into the driver's seat and PEELS OUT. jack turns away, looks at the Security TFM. In the background, a HARRIED MAN dashes after Tyler and the convertible, SCREAMING.</context>
      <utterance>Nine time out of ten, it's an electric razor. But, every once in a while ...  ...it's a dildo. It's airline policy not to imply ownership in the event of a dildo. We use the indefinite aricle: "A dildo." Never "Your dildo."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had everything in that bag. My C.K. shirts... my D.K.N.Y. shoes...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY TFM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, uh huh... yeah?  Oh...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SECURITY TFM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Security TFM hands Jack a claim form. Jack snatches it, disgusted, takes out a pen, starts filling out the form.</context>
      <utterance>I'm terribly sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY TFM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the industry slang for "Flight Attendant?" "Air Mattress."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The taxi turns a corner and Jack sees the front of the building. A diffuse CLOUD of SMOKE wafts away from a BLOWN- OUT SECTION of the fifteenth floor. FIRETRUCKS, POLICE CARS and a MOB are all crowded around the lobby area.</context>
      <utterance>Home was a condo on the fifteenth floor of a filing cabinet for widows and young professionals. The walls were solid concrete. A foot of concrete is important when your next- door neighbor lets her hearing aid go and has to watch game shows at full volume...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Or when a volcanic blast of debris that used to be your furniture and personal effects blows out your floor- to-ceiling windows and sails flaming into the night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack presses the button. The Doorman moves next to him.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator doors open. Jack hesitates. The doors close. Jack heads out the lobby doors. The Doorman follows...</context>
      <utterance>You can't go into the unit. Police orders.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How embarrassing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack comes to his REFRIGERATOR lying on its side. He reaches down and takes a note: "MARLA --" and a phone number, from under a BANANA MAGNET.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have somebody you can call?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE SHOT - JACK'S STOVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hissing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The police would later tell me that the pilot light might have gone out... letting out just a little bit of gas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack picks up the receiver, puts in a quarter. He looks at Marla's number a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>Lots of young people try to impress the world and buy too many things.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The gas could have slowly filled the condo. Seventeen-hundred square feet with high ceilings, for days and days.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doorman walks away. Jack stares at Tyler's card.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't know what you want, you end up with a lot you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack re-deposits the quarter, dials Tyler's number. It RINGS... and RINGS and RINGS. Jack sighs and hangs up the phone. A moment, then the phone RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>If you asked me now, I couldn't tell you why I called him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyler?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm... you know, the clever guy.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... I'm sorry. We met on the plane. We had the same briefcase.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just called a second ago. There was no answer. I'm at a payphone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I star-sixty-nined you. I never pick up my phone. What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... let me see... here's the thing...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="47">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You buy furniture. You tell yourself: this is the last sofa I'll ever need. No matter what else happens, I've got the sofa issue handled. Then, the right set of dishes. The right dinette.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler lights a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>This is how we fill up our lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess so.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, now it's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler offers cigarettes. Jack declines.</context>
      <utterance>All gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be worse. A woman could cut off your penis while you're asleep and toss it out the window of a moving car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's always that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, maybe I'm wrong. Maybe it's a terrible tragedy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...no ...no ...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack laughs, nods. He shakes his head, drinks.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, you did lose a lot of nice, neat little shit. The trendy paper lamps, the Euro-trash shelving unit, am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But maybe, just maybe, you've been delivered.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delivered from Swedish furniture.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delivered from armchairs in obscure green stripe patterns.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delivered from Martha Stewart.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh together. Then, silence. They drink.</context>
      <utterance>Delivered from bullshit colors like "Cobalt," "Ebony," and "Fuchsia."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Insurance'll cover it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, you gotta start making the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What list?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The "now I get to go out and buy the exact same stuff all over again" list. That list.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't... think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You'll be occupied for weeks.</context>
      <utterance>This time maybe get a widescreen TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I have to file a claim...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The things you own, they end up owning you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, it's late. I should find a hotel...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hotel?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you called me up, because you just wanted to have a drink before you... go find a hotel?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't follow...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just ask me.</context>
      <utterance>We're on our third pitcher of beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You called me so you could have a place to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you cut the shit and ask if you can stay at my place?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would that be a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it a problem for you to ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I stay at your place?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome. But, I want you to do me one favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to hit me as hard as you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freeze picture.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to hit me as hard as you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you a little bit about Tyler Durden.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXTREME CLOSE-UP - FILM FRAME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- And we see it's PORNOGRAPHY.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler points to the side of OUR FRAME and the TWO DOTS briefly APPEAR ONSCREEN.</context>
      <utterance>Tyler was a night person. He sometimes worked as a projectionist. A movie doesn't come in one big reel, it's on a few. In old theaters, two projectors are used, so someone has to change projectors at the exact second when one reel ends and another reel begins. Sometimes you can see two dots on screen in the upper right hand corner...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're called "cigarette burns."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called a "changeover." The movie goes on, and nobody in the audience has any idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would anyone want this shitty job?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It affords him other interesting opportunities.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Like splicing single frames from adult movies into family films.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the AUDIENCE, CHILDREN suddenly start squirming, confused, looking at each other. A WOMAN abruptly stops sucking her soda straw, feeling vaguely terrible. Her uncomfortable HUSBAND slowly leans back in his seat. Jack and Tyler watch from the projection booth window.</context>
      <utterance>In reel three, right after the courageous dog and the snooty cag -- who have celebrity voices -- eat out of a garbage can, there's the flash of Tyler's contribution...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One-forty-eighth of a second. That's how long it's up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one really knows that they've seen it. But they did.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A nice, big cock.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only a hummingbird could have caught Tyler at work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was the guerrilla terrorist of the food service industry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack waits. The SOUND of a STREAM of LIQUID is HEARD.</context>
      <utterance>Don't watch. I can't if you watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He farted on meringue; he sneezed on braised endive; and, with creme of mushroom soup, well...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get the idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, either. I want to find out. I've never been hit, have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That's a good thing, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to die without any scars. How much can you really know about yourself if you've never been in a fight? Come on... you're the only person I've ever asked.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not you? I'm letting you go first. Do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, go crazy. Let 'er rip.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you want it? In the face?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack swings a wide, clumsy roundhouse -- hits Tyler's neck -- makes a dull, flat sound.</context>
      <utterance>Surprise me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. Sorry. That didn't count.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler shoots out a straight punch to Jack's chest. Jack falls back against a car. His eyes tear up.</context>
      <utterance>Like hell. That counted.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But a good strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've crossed the threshold. You want to call it off?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call what off?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack swings another roundhouse that slams right under Tyler's ear. Tyler punches Jack in the stomach. Tyler and Jack move clumsily, throwing punches. They breathe heavier, drooling saliva and blood, growing dizzier from every impact.</context>
      <utterance>This fight, pussy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you could fight anyone... one on one, whoever you wanted, who would you fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack thinks.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My boss, probably.  Who would you fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pause as Jack studies Tyler's face.</context>
      <utterance>My dad. No question.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah.  I didn't know my dad. Well, I knew him, till I was six. He went and married another woman, had more kids. Every six years or so he'd do it again -- new city, new family.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was setting up franchises. My father never went to college, so it was really important that I go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get married."</context>
      <utterance>After I graduated, I called him long distance and asked, "Now what?" He said, "Get a job." When I turned twenty-five, I called him and asked, "Now what?" He said, "I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another pause. Jack feels his bleeding lip, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>A generation of men raised by women. I'm wondering if another woman is the answer we really need.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler cracks a smile, give a sidelong glance to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>We should do this again sometime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your car?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What car?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how Tyler found the house, but he'd been there for half a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looked like it was waiting to be torn down. Most of the windows were boarded up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The previous occupant had been a bit of a shut-in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hum.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler begins RIPPING the ARTICLE from his magazine.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, a new riot control grenade...  "...the successful combination of concussive, 3000 foot-candle flash- blasts and simultaneous high-velocity disbursement of...blah, blah, blah..."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I am Joe's Lungs." It's written in first person. "Without me, Joe could not take in oxygen to feed his red blood cells." There's a whole series -- "I am Joe's Prostate."</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler tosses his article in a pile of other articles, chooses another magazine.</context>
      <utterance>"I get cancer, and I kill Joe."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you reading?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>New Republic.</context>
      <utterance>Soldier of Fortune. Business Week.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show-off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack's face shows no reaction. He continues to walk.</context>
      <utterance>.... I should have been upset about my nice, neat, flaming little shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I wasn't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack picks up his briefcase and walks out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Most of the week, we were Ozzie and Harriet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Wednesday night, ever Wednesday night...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The basic premise of cyber-netting your office is -- make things more efficient.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I get the icon in cornflower blue?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walter continues, his sales pitch drowned out by Jack's V.O.:</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Walter moves to Jack and slaps him in the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Walter, the Microsoft account exec. Walter, with his smooth, soft hands. Maybe he was thinking about the free- range potluck he'd been to last weekend, or his church-group car-wash fund-raiser. Or, probably not.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack smiles. His teeth are RED with BLOOD. They GLOW eerily in the dim light.</context>
      <utterance>I showed this already to my man here. You liked it, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can swallow a pint of blood before you get sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack keeps the smile frozen on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, I'd hate to see what happened to the other guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screw Walter. His candy-ass wouldn't last a second Wednesday night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>IRVINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irvine flicks on the LIGHTS. Drunken customers squint and get the message. They plop down money, leaving.</context>
      <utterance>Drink up people. We're closing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Irvine hits a button and the JUKEBOX loses power. Members of the waiting army begins to share secret looks. Finally, one buy locks the door. Two other guys close the blinds.</context>
      <utterance>It was right in everyone's face. Tyler and I just made it visible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was on the tip of everyone's tongue. Tyler and I just gave it a name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guys mill around, finding partners. Everyone brims with eagerness, but tries to act cool. CHATTER gets LOUDER. Everyone spreads out, forming a circle, Tyler at center.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to fight club.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PEAKING CHATTER, till Tyler raises his arms and the CHATTER DIES. A couple of COUGHS, FEET SHUFFLING, then, SILENCE.</context>
      <utterance>Every week, Tyler gave the rules that he and I decided.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler steps back. A short guy, RICKY, and a GOATEED MAN take off shirts and shoes and step to the center.</context>
      <utterance>The first rule of fight club is -- you don't talk about fight club. The second rule of fight club is -- you don't talk about fight club. The third rule of fight club is -- when someone says "stop" or goes limp, the fight is over. Fourth rule is -- only two guys to a fight. Fifth rule -- one fight at a time. Sixth rule -- no shirts, no shoes. Seventh rule -- fights go on as long as they have to. And the eighth and final rule -- if this is your first night at fight club, you have to fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The two fighters circle, then begin throwing PUNCHES...</context>
      <utterance>This kid, Ricky -- supply clerk -- couldn't remember whether you ordered pens with blue ink or black ink ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Harder, faster PUNCHES between the two. SWEAT flies. SHOUTS become DEAFENING. Ricky's getting the best of Goateed Man, POUNDING him...</context>
      <utterance>But Ricky was a god for ten minutes last week when he trounced an actuary twice his size.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes all you could hear were flat, hard packing sounds over the yelling, or the wet choke when someone caught their breath and sprayed...</utterance>
   <speaker>GOATEED MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ssssstop... !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Goateed Waiter approaches Jack and sets a refill soda down on the table. The two of them briefly make eye contact.</context>
      <utterance>Even if I could tell someone they had a good fight, I wouldn't be talking to the same man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who you were in fight club is not who you were in the rest of the world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack keeps playing Solitaire. Boss enters, folds his arms.</context>
      <utterance>What are you getting yourself into every week?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After fight club, everything else in your life gets the volume turned down. You can deal with anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you finished those reports?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack looks at Boss. Reflexively, Jack's tongue plays with his teeth.</context>
      <utterance>The people who had power over you have less and less.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By this point, I could wiggle most of the teeth in my jaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A guy came to fight club for the first time, his ass was a wad of cookie dough. After a few weeks, he was carved out of wood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you could fight any celebrity?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alive or dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hemingway. You?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach a BUS STOP as a BUS arrives, tossing their cigarettes, getting on board...</context>
      <utterance>Shatner. William Shatner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>They hold hand grips. Jack looks up at an ADVERTISEMENT; a CALVIN KLEIN ad featuring a tan, bare-chested MUSCLE STUD.</context>
      <utterance>We all started seeing things differently. Wherever we went.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tyler looks at Jack, looks at the C.K. advertisement.</context>
      <utterance>I felt sorry for all the guys packing into gyms, trying to look like what Calvin Klein and Tommy Hilfiger said they should.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MAN in a suit KNOCKS Tyler's shoulder as he passes. The Man takes a handle, close by. Jack's pissed, staring at the man, who stares back.</context>
      <utterance>Self-improvement is masturbation. Self-destruction is the answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler looks to Jack, glances over his shoulder at the Man. Tyler casually picks a small scab off Jack's nostril.</context>
      <utterance>You could take him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler stares forward.</context>
      <utterance>The trick is not to care.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Opponent recovers, throws a headlock on Jack. Jack snakes his arm into a counter headlock. They wrestle like wild animals. The crowd CHEERS maniacally.</context>
      <utterance>Fight club wasn't about winning or losing. It wasn't about words.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Onlookers kneel to stay with the fight, cheering LOUDER. The Opponent SMASHES Jack's head to the floor, over and over.</context>
      <utterance>They hysterical shouting was in tongues, like at a Pentecostal church.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... stop...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Everyone moves in as the Opponent steps away. Tyler pushes through the crowd. Others lift Jack up. They turn their attention to the floor, to a BLOOD MASK of Jack's face -- similar to the TEAR MASK on BOB'S SHIRT.</context>
      <utterance>When the fight was over, nothing was solved, but nothing mattered.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack limply shakes his Opponent's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>OPPONENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about next week?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone helps Jack walk. He's sweating, bleeding, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Look at me. How about next month?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Afterwards, we all felt saved.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Nurse doesn't look at Tyler, just keeps tending to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>He fell down some stairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fell down some stairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes Tyler spoke for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fight club became the reason to cut your hair short and trim your fingernails.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any historical figure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... Ghandi.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack reaches in his mouth, exploring, pulls -- yanks a TOOTH. Jack looks at it. Tyler puts scissors down, done.</context>
      <utterance>Abe Lincoln. Big reach. Skinny guys fight till they're burger.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack drops the tooth in the sink with Tyler's hair.</context>
      <utterance>Remember, even the Mona Lisa's falling apart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have you been the last few weeks?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks through the archway and sees Tyler, in his gummy flannel bathrobe, doing sit-ups. Jack leans, cups the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Marla?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you find me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The forwarding number. I haven't seen you at any support groups.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the idea -- we split them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't been going to yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found a new one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's for men.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like testicular cancer?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, this is a bad time...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been going to debtor's anonymous. You want to see some truly fucked up people?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just on my way out...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks exasperated, turns TO LOOK INTO THE CAMERA.</context>
      <utterance>Me too. I got a stomach full of Xanax. I took what was left of a bottle. Might've been too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Picture yourself watching Marla Singer throw herself around her crummy apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't a for-real suicide thing. This is probably one of those cry-for- help things.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This could go on for hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're staying in tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack puts the handset on top of the phone, still off the hook, walks out the back door.</context>
      <utterance>Do you want to wait to hear me describe death?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thru the archway: Tyler leans to look in, curious.</context>
      <utterance>Do you want to listen and see if my spirit can use the telephone?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla walks in, straightening her dress, looks like she's been raped by a hurricane. Jack's jaw drops.</context>
      <utterance>You're not going to believe what I dreamt last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla goes to pour coffee. She takes a swig, GARGLES and SPITS it in the sink. She gives Jack a lascivious smile.</context>
      <utterance>I can hardly believe anything about last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla stares at him a beat, then drops the cup in the sink.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla shoves open the door to the backyard and walks out. Jack gets up, watches her stomp away. Jack turns and -- Tyler is at his shoulder, staring after Marla. He's in his usual sweatpants. He grins at Jack, then moves away, pours himself coffee. Jack, smoldering, slumps at the table and picks up Reader's Digest. Tyler puts his foot on a countertop, does stretching exercises.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack pretends to read, quickly glances at Tyler. TYLER'S</context>
      <utterance>She's a piece of work. Get this -- I come in here last night, the phone's off the hook...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARLA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you when I'm floating out of my body.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could Tyler, off all people, think it was a bad thing that Marla Singer was about to die?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She staggers and sits on the bed. She slides off, along with the blanket and sheets, to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You got here fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to focus her eyes on Tyler.</context>
      <utterance>The mattresses are all sealed in slippery plastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler studies her with cynical curiosity, looks at a DILDO lying atop a dresser. Marla follows his gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Did I call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SIRENS and vehicles SCREECHING outside can be HEARD; doors opening and SLAMMING; running FOOTFALLS.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. It's not a threat to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets to her feet, grabs Tyler, pulls him out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no! Somebody called the cops...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>8-G! Where's 8-G?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rescuers keep running.</context>
      <utterance>End of the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girl who lives there used to be a charming, lovely girl, but she's lost faith in herself...</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla yanks Tyler's arm, heading down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Singer, let us help you! You have every reason to live!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a monster! Infectious human waste! Good luck trying to save her!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I fall asleep, I'm done for. You're gonna have to keep me up all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unbelievable, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tyler stands across from Jack, gets a cigarette from a pack.</context>
      <utterance>He was obviously able to handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, this girl... uh, you're not into her or anything... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tyler lights his cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>I am Jack's Raging Bile Duct.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. This chick was up on the table with her legs in the stirrups before the doctor even walked in the room. The things that she said... I've never heard a woman talk like that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could Tyler not go for that? Night before last, he was splicing sex organs into "Little Mermaid." Tyler sits, studies Jack's face.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're okay with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tyler smokes.</context>
      <utterance>Put a gun to my head and paint the wall with my brains.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is a wild, twisted bitch. Stay away from that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, and my pace is more librarians.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... don't knock librarians.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marla doesn't need a lover. She needs a case worker.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She needs an exorcist. This isn't love. This is sport-fucking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'd invaded my support groups, now she's invading my home.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler pulls out a closer chair, motions to it. Jack puts down his Reader's Digest and moves to that chair.</context>
      <utterance>Listen... do me a favor... sit here a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler fixes Jack with a friendly, but firm stare.</context>
      <utterance>You've gotta understand something about me. I have a little rule, okay? Don't ever talk to her about me. Ever. I can't stand that kind of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you ever say anything about me or about what happens here in this house, to her or anyone -- I will find out. And you'll never see me again. Promise me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise you won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said I promise!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler smiles, gets up and leaves. Jack sits smoldering.</context>
      <utterance>That was three times you promised.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If only I had wasted a couple of minutes and gone to watch Marla die, none of this would have happened.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARLA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miserable fucking discharge!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could've moved to another room, one on the third floor -- so I wouldn't have heard them. But I didn't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack steps back.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler scratches his head, wears a RUBBER GLOVE.</context>
      <utterance>I... uh... just going to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to finish her off?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack continues toward his room.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... nah...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I became the calm, little center of the world. I was the Zen master.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He hits "SEND," gets the "ERROR CHIME" SOUND. He presses this key over and over. Boss enters.</context>
      <utterance>I faxed them around to everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boss stares at Jack like he's from Mars.</context>
      <utterance>Some of it, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get yourself together.</context>
      <utterance>Take the rest of the day off. Come back tomorrow with clean clothes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got right in everyone's hostile little face. Yes, these are bruises from fighting. I'm comfortable with them. I am enlightened.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You give up the condo life, give up all your flaming worldly possessions, go live in a dilapidated house in the toxic waste part of town...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and you come home to this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fucking slut!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack rolls his eyes, takes off his pants. He runs water in the sink, finds a tiny bit of SOAP and scrubs at the blood stains. The PHONE RINGS. He answers it.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir, may I have another! Thank you sir, may I have another... !</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Speaking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="46">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Detective Stern with the arson unit. We have some new information about the "incident" at your condo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if you're aware... your front door -- it seems someone sprayed freon into the lock, then tapped it with a chisel to shatter the cylinder.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I wasn't aware...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Jack's Cold Sweat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does this sound strange to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack starts to sweat, scrubs his pants obsessively.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sire, strange. Very strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dynamite...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dynamite?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you know what that means?</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It left a residue of ammonium oxalate and potassium perchloride.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means it was homemade.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is... really a shock...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever set this homemade dynamite could've blown out the pilot light days before the explosion. The gas, it seems, was just a detonator.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think could've done this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll ask the questions, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack almost leaps out his skin, startled; looks to see Tyler standing right next to him.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The liberator who destroyed my property has re-aligned my paradigm of perception."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhhhhh!  I don't know what to make of this, sir, I really don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know anyone who'd have the expertise or motive to do something like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I reject the basic assumptions of civilization, including material possession." Jack pushes Tyler away, cups the receiving.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, sir. I loved that condo. I loved every stick of furniture. The lamps, the chairs, the rugs, were me. The dishes were me. The plants were...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to thank the academy...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if any ideas come to you, give me a call. In the meantime, don't leave town. I may need to bring you in for questioning.</utterance>
   <speaker>END INTERCUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack hangs up. Tyler shrugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns away, continues to scrub his pants. Marla's FOOTSTEPS can be HEARD coming downstairs... Jack really grinds the soap against the pants, splashing water. He turns, sees Marla enter. Tyler is GONE. Marla lights a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Could be worse. You could be cursed with the three terrible Karmas. You could be beautiful, rich and famous.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except for their humping, Tyler and Marla were never in the same room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got this dress at a thrift store for one dollar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worth every penny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Marla begins a slow, exotic dance, moving very close to Jack. She lifts her dress dangerously high, dancing close to Jack's body, almost touhcing.</context>
      <utterance>My parents pulled this exact act for years -- one came in, the other disappeared.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a bridesmaid's dress. Someone loved it intensely for one day, then tossed it. Like a Christmas tree -- so special, then, bam -- it's abandoned on the side of the road, tinsel still clinging to it... Jack becomes very aware of having no pants on, presses against the counter. Marla pulls her hemline further up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like sex crime victims, underwear inside-out, bound with electrical tape.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans in very close to Jack's ear, whispers hoarsely:</context>
      <utterance>It suits you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack takes a step away, keeps scrubbing. Marla blows smoke in his face. Jack takes her cigarette and throws it in the sink. Marla backs away, fed up, storms out, going UPSTAIRS.</context>
      <utterance>You can borrow it sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jack turns to see Tyler in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Get rid of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get rid of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla's FOOTSTEPS are coming DOWNSTAIRS. Jack looks to the archway, then back at -- Tyler's GONE. Marla enters, shoes and balled up clothing under one arm, looking for something on the junk strewn table.</context>
      <utterance>Don't mention me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm six years old again, passing messages between my parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla ignores, still searching the table, tossing things, pushing other things off to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>I, uh... think you should go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's time for you to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla finds what she wanted, a pack of cigarettes. She moves up into Jack's face.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I'm leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're such a nutcase, I can't even begin to keep up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs, spins on her heels. As she exits the back door, she sings "This Merry-Go-Round" from "Valley of the Dolls." Jack watches her through the kitchen window.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jack turns. Tyler's right behind him. Through the window, Marla can be seen walking away. Tyler picks up the remnant of SOAP Jack's been using, holds it up to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Nice work.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at Tyler.</context>
      <utterance>To make soap, first we have to render fat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler lifts the lid -- it CREAKS.</context>
      <utterance>The best fat for making soap -- because the salt balance is just right -- comes form human bodies...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the dumpster, Tyler pulls out an industrial-sized, thick plastic bag full of PINK GOO.</context>
      <utterance>A liposuction clinic.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIME CUT: Tyler and Jack climb back over the fence, carrying BAGS of fat. One of Jack's bags RIPS, spilling the goo down the chain-link fench. Jack slips and slides. Tyler laughs. Tyler tries to scoop the running fat back into the bag.</context>
      <utterance>Paydirt. From society's richest asses and thighs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As the fat renders, the tallow floats to the surface. Remember the crap they taught you in Boy Scouts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard to imagine you in Boy Scouts.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler sticks a spoon into a pot, lifts up a scoop of the glycerin layer. Then, he crabs a can, opens it.</context>
      <utterance>This clear layer in glycerin. We'll mix it back in when we make the soap.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler licks his lips until they're gleaming wet. He takes Jack's hands and KISSES the back of it.</context>
      <utterance>Lye -- the crucial ingredient.  Ancient peoples found their clothes got cleaner if they washed them at a certain spot in the river. Why? Because, human sacrifices were once made on the hills above this river. Year after year, bodies burnt. Rain feel. Water seeped through the wood ashes to become lye. The lye combined with the melted fat of the bodies, till a thick white soapy discharge crept into the river.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The saliva shines in the shape of the kiss. Tyler pours a bit of the flaked lye onto Jack's hand.</context>
      <utterance>The first soap was made from the ashes of heroes. Like the first monkeys shot into space.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack's whole body JERKS. Tyler holds tight to Jack's hand and arm. Tears well in Jack's eyes; his face tightens.</context>
      <utterance>Without sacrifice, without death, we would have nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks -- the burn is swollen, glossy, in the shape of Tyler's kiss. Jack's face spasms.</context>
      <utterance>This is a chemical burn. It will hurt more than you've ever been burned and you will have a scar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyler's kiss was a bonfire on the back of my hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at your hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guided meditation worked for cancer, it could work for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack, snapping back, tries to jerk his hand away. Tyler keeps hold of it and their arms KNOCK UTENSILS off the table.</context>
      <utterance>Come back to the pain. Don't shut this out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried not to think of the words "searing" or "flesh." I imagined my pain as a ball of healing white light.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it. This is your pain -- your burning hand. It's right here. Look at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was going to my cave to find my power animal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I think I understand. I think I get it...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, what you're feeling is premature enlightenment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the greatest moment of your life and you're off somewhere, missing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up. Our fathers were our models for God. And, if our fathers bailed, what does that tell us about God?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me. You have to consider the possibility that God doesn't like you, he never wanted you. In all probability, He hates you. This is not the worst thing that can happen...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't need him...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't... ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Marla ... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at Tyler -- they lock eyes. Jack does his best to stifle his spasms of pain, his body a quivering, coiled knot. He bolts toward the sink, but Tyler holds on.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck damnation. Fuck redemption. We are God's unwanted children, with no special place and no special attention, and so be it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack spasms with a shiver of pain...</context>
      <utterance>You can go to the sink and run water over your hand. Look at me. Or you can use vinegar to neutralize the burn, but first you have to give up. First, you have to know that someday, you are going to die. Until you know that, you will be useless.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler shows Jack a LYE-BURNED KISS SCAR on his own hand. Tears begin to drip from Jack's eyes. Tyler grabs a bottle of VINEGAR -- pours it over Jack's wound. Jack closes his eyes, holds his hand... slumps to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You ... you don't know what this feels like, Tyler.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations. You're a step closer to hitting bottom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Boss slaps a piece of PAPER down on Jack's desk.</context>
      <utterance>He was wearing a yellow tie. It must be Thursday. I didn't even wear a tie to work anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack snuffs his cigarette in an ashtray, stares up stoically.</context>
      <utterance>"The first rule of fight club is you don't talk about fight club."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must've left the original in the copy machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is this yours?</context>
      <utterance>"The second rule of fight club...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't get paid to abuse the copy machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Abuse" the copy machine. There's an image.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack rises slowly, walks to his door, shuts it.</context>
      <utterance>Pretend you're me. You find this. What would you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack moves very close to Boss, picks up the PAPER and starts tearing it into pieces.</context>
      <utterance>Me? I'd be very careful who I talked to about this. It sounds like someone dangerous wrote it... someone who might snap at any moment, stalking from office to office with an Armalite AR-10 Carbine-gas semiautomatic, bitterly pumping round after round into colleagues and co- workers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack puts the PAPER in his trash. Bass stares with a tinge of outrage, a tinge of fear. PHONE RINGS. Jack answers it.</context>
      <utterance>Might be someone you've known for years... somebody very close to you. Or, maybe you shouldn't be bringing me every little piece of trash you pick up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Compliance and Liability.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My tit's going to rot off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boss goes to the door, stares at Jack a beat, then leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Just a second.  Could you excuse me? I need to take this call.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you do something for me? I need you to check and see if there's a lump in my breast. I can't afford to throw money away on a doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't call Tyler. I'm neutral in her book.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a sweet side of you. Picking these up for ...  "Mrs. Haniver" and... "Mrs. Raines." Where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tragically, they're dead. I'm alive and I'm in poverty. You want any?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her while she eats.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack awkwardly puts his bandaged hand behind his back.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to your hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where? Here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack's head is behind Marla's. They speak softer, slower.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay, I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feel nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla turns around and faces him, begins to button her shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's a relief. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... no problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack touches his own chest, shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I could return the favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think everything's okay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could check your prostate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh ... nah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla leans to kiss him -- lingers for a bit longer than just friendly. Jack pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>Well... thanks, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla sighs.</context>
      <utterance>So.... are we done?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we're done. See you around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cornelius! How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob. I'm okay. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better than I've ever been in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An intense look of born-again fervor comes over Bob's face.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Great. Still "Remaining Men Together?"</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I found something new.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, what's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first rule is... you aren't supposed to talk about it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the third rule...</context>
      <utterance>And the second rule about it is... you're not supposed to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob, Bob... I'm a member.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob roughly slaps Jack's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Look at my face.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a fucking great, man! Fucking great! Congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, both of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know about the guy who invented it? I hear all kinds of things. Supposedly, he was born in a mental institution. They say he only sleeps one hour a night. You know about this guy? Tyler Durden?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob relaxes the hug and Jack drops to the ground like a sack, completely enervated from the beating he took.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fight club -- this was mine and Tyler's gift... our gift to the world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks, I quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You quit?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Where you headed?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler scratches his chin absently.</context>
      <utterance>Work. Going to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler walks out the way he came.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Do what you like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Where to begin? With your constant absenteeism? With your unpresentable appearance? You're up for review...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boss sits up in his seat, becoming enraged.</context>
      <utterance>I Am Jack's Complete Lack of Surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's pretend. You're the Department of Transportation, and you discover that our company intentionally did nothing about leather seats cured in third world countries with chemicals we know cause birth defects? Brake linings that fail after a thousand miles. Fuel injectors that burn people alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just who the fuck do you think you are?! Get out! You're fired!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boss stands, moves around his desk, glaring with rage.</context>
      <utterance>What about this? Keep me on payroll as an outside consultant. In exchange for my salary, I'll keep my mouth shut. I won't need to come to the office. I can do this job from home.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack PUNCHES HIMSELF in the nose. Blood starts to trickle. He punches himself in the jaw, throws himself back as if by the force of the punch, SLAMS against a framed picture and SHATTERS the glass. He falls to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You little fucker! I oughta...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack gets back to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>I Am Jack's Smirking Revenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He PUNCHES himself in the stomach, then in the jaw again. He reels backwards, pulls down a hanging shelf, its contents flying. He hits the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Please... don't hit me again, please. I'm your responsibility...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack crawls toward Boss, dripping blood, grabs Boss's leg.</context>
      <utterance>For some reason, I thought of my first fight -- with Tyler.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack climbs up Boss's leg while Boss tries to shake him off. Boss stumbles back into his desk, knocking off belongings.</context>
      <utterance>Please... give me the paychecks like I asked for. I won't be any trouble. You won't see me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>everything this man took for granted, something horrible had been growing. Jack crawls high enough to grab Boss's belt, hoisting himself up. He dribbles blood an Boss's clothing, SMUDGES blood from his face onto the knuckles of Boss's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Under and behind and inside</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please... please...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Two SECURITY GUARDS enter and gape at the sight. Behind them stand CURIOUS WORKERS, looking in.</context>
      <utterance>And right then, at our most excellent moment together...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't hit me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six months advance pay. Six months!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucking sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack digs in his pocket, takes out a thick bundle of CARDS.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, and... and...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack holds up a finger, going to open the front door. He drags an unwieldy SHOPPING CART in behind him; filled with his COMPUTER, PHONE, FAX and other office equipment.</context>
      <utterance>Forty-eight airline flight coupons. Plus... hold on... just a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at the cart, then back at Tyler, proud.</context>
      <utterance>I am now officially self-employed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An enthusiastic RUMBLE from the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>I look around... I look around and see a lot of new faces.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A glum silence falls. Guys look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Which means a lot of you have been breaking the first two rules of fight club.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd erupts into a DEAFENING CHORUS of agreement. Jack looks at the blazing excitement in the eyes of the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>I see in fight club the strongest and smartest men who have ever lived -- an entire generation pumping gas and waiting tables; or they're slaves with white collars.  TYLER  Advertisements have them chasing cars and clothes, working jobs they hate so they can buy shit they don't need. We are the middle children of history, with no purpose or place. We have no great war, or great depression. The great war is a spiritual war. The great depression is our lives. We were raised by television to believe that we'd be millionaires and movie gods and rock stars -- but we won't. And we're learning that fact. And we're very, very pissed-off.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A fat, MIDDLE-AGED MAN stomps down the stairs, pushing into the crowd, followed by a TALL, HEFTY THUG who holds a GUM.</context>
      <utterance>We are the quiet young men who listen until it's time to decide.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode>LOU</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who am I?! There's a sign on the front that says "Lou's Tavern." I'm fucking Lou. Who the fuck are you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler extends his hand for a shake, but Lou SLAPS it away.</context>
      <utterance>Tyler Durden.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you motherfuckers you could use my place?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a deal worked out with Irvine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone glances guiltily at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Irvine? Irvine's at home with a broken collarbone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't own this place, I do. How much money's he getting for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no money.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's free to all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't that something?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, stupid fuck, I want everyone outta here now!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome to join our club.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear what I just said?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lou SLUGS Tyler in the stomach, doubles him over.</context>
      <utterance>You and your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler gains his breath, determined. He looks up, turns his head, looking to Jack. Jack watches, wide-eyed. Tyler straightens, facing Lou.</context>
      <utterance>You hear me now?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lou PUNCHES Tyler in the face. Some of the guys move forward, but the Thug points his gun. Jack-runs forward anyway -- Lou PUNCHES him in the face. More guys move forward, but Tyler waves them off, facing Lou.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm sorry, I didn't hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lou proceeds to beat the shit out of Tyler, PUNCHING his face, his stomach. Tyler collapses to the floor. Lou starts KICKING his. Tyler bleeds from the mouth and face.</context>
      <utterance>We really need to use this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lou flushes red with exasperation, KICKS more. Finally, sweating, bewildered, Lou stops. He looks to the Thug, who is just as bewildered. Suddenly, Tyler SPRINGS UP, grabs onto Lou...</context>
      <utterance>That's it.... that's good. Get it all out. You'll feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler's blood spatters on Lou. Lou tries to shake Tyler off, but Tyler BITES Lou's NECKTIE. The Thug grabs Tyler and pulls, the necktie tightening and strangling Lou. Lou slaps at Tyler's face, but recoils from the blood. Tyler spits and shouts through clenched teeth...</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am shit and crazy, to you and this whole fucking world...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler bear hugs Lou, pulls him to the floor. Tyler rubs his bloody face into Lou's face. The Thug lifts Tyler. Tyler clings to Lou's belt, dragging Lou as he is dragged...</context>
      <utterance>You don't know where I've been.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blood dribbles out of Tyler's mouth, spattering Lou.</context>
      <utterance>We need this place. We need it. Please let us keep it, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleeeeeease!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay! Okay, fuck it! Use the basement! Get off me!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need some towels, Lou. We need replacement light bulbs.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, Christ! Fucking let me go!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Thank you, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler lets go of Lou's belt. Lou scrambles away. The Thug drops Tyler, trying to keep clear of the blood. Lou gets to his feet, looks at Tyler, then at the rest of the guys. He and the Thug back away... slamming the door behind. Fight club surrounds Tyler. They help him up, move him to a crate. Tyler sits slumped for a long moment, his breathing labored... then, he sits back, crossing his legs and looking to the group, his demeanor businesslike.</context>
      <utterance>Let go of me!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack beams in appreciation.</context>
      <utterance>This week, each of you has a homework assignment. You're going to go out and start a fight with a total stranger...  You're going to start a fight... and you're going to lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Yuppies gets up, angry, and Ricky PUNCHES him...</context>
      <utterance>Not as easy as it sounds. People'll do just about anything to avoid a fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Yuppie backs away. Ricky follows...</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Wha... What the hell... what are you doing?! Who are you?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get away from me! Keep away!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FIRST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mechanic sprays a third man, a SEMINARY STUDENT, who looks down, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out, jackass! These men continue on their way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEMINARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mechanic DOUSES the Seminarian. The Seminarian grabs the hose, wrestling the Mechanic for it. The Mechanic shoves the Seminarian, who responds with a half-assed PUNCH. The Mechanic purposely takes it. The Seminarian starts to run away. The Mechanic sprints after him, PUNCHING the Seminarian in the back of the neck. They fight.</context>
      <utterance>You... you did that on purpose!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tyler hands ENVELOPES out to the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Now nobody was the center of fight club except the two men fighting. The leader walked around in the crowd, out in the darkness.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone took a homework assignment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's fight club in Delaware City.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they pass PARKED CARS, they SWING the planks against front bumpers -- activating ALARMS and INFLATING AIR BAGS...</context>
      <utterance>I heard. Local 15, Monday nights.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Local 8 just started in Penns Grove. And, Bob said he was at fight club in Newcastle last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Newcastle? Did you start that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the background, a CAR quickly EXITS the parking lot -- front tires EXPLODING, wheel rims throwing sparks.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler takes the BACKPACK, unzips it, searching the contents.</context>
      <utterance>Let me have that a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Homework assignment.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler takes out a HANDGUN, hands the backpack back.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns white, staring at the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Human Sacrifice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On a long enough time line, the survival rate for everyone drops to zero.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please... don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Clerk fumbles his wallet out of his pocket and Tyler snatches it. Tyler pulls out the DRIVER'S LICENCE.</context>
      <utterance>Give me your wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raymond K. Hessel. 1320 SE Benning, apartment A. A small, cramped basement apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler rummages through the wallet.</context>
      <utterance>They give basement apartments letters instead of numbers. Raymond, you're going to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this a picture of Mom and Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesssss...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mom and dad will have to call kindly doctor so-and-so to dig up your dental records, because there won't be much left of your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond begins to weep, shoulders heaving.</context>
      <utterance>Please, God, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyler...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An expired community college student ID card. What did you used to study, Raymond K. Hessel?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>S-S-Stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler rams the gun barrel against Raymond's temple.</context>
      <utterance>"Stuff." Were the mid-terms hard?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked you what you studied.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Biology, mostly.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond weeps and says nothing. Tyler COCKS the gun. Raymond GASPS.</context>
      <utterance>What did you want to be, Raymond K. Hessel?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The question, Raymond, was "what did you want to be?" A beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer him!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A veterinarian!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah ... animals and s-s-s ---</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stuff. That means you have to get more schooling.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler shoves Raymond's wallet back into Raymond's pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Too much school.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you rather be dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler moves the gun right between Raymond's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No, please, no, God, no!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond staggers to his feet, heads down an alleyway. Jack and Tyler watch Raymond flee, then Tyler looks at Jack.</context>
      <utterance>I'm keeping your license. I know where you live. I'm going to check on you. If you aren't back in school and on your way to being a veterinarian in six weeks, you will be dead. Get the hell out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler brings the gun to his own head, pulls the trigger -- CLICK. Empty.</context>
      <utterance>Imagine how he feels.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler walks away.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care, that was horrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack watches Tyler go.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow will be the most beautiful day of Raymond K. Hessell's life.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns to look the direction Raymond ran. He finally turns back, following after Tyler.</context>
      <utterance>His breakfast will taste better than any meal he has ever eaten.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler's marking a large SQUARE in the weeds and rubble of the backyard, kicking rocks away, dragging the rake...</context>
      <utterance>... You are not how much money you have in the bank. You are not the shoes you wear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not the contents of your wallet...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack notices ROPE and RAPPELLING TOOLS on the table. Tyler comes to hand Jack a bunch of beers, nod to the living room.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on in. We're celebrating.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not your job.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHERS TOGETHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not your job.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not how much money you have in the bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob goes to turn up the TV. One guy, sixteen years old with an angelic face, ANGEL FACE, gets up to take beer from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Shhhh, wait... they're back to it...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angel face starts distributing beer amongst his cohorts.</context>
      <utterance>Great, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks to the TV -- it shows a LIVE shot of the "PARKER MORRIS BUILDING." The building has a GIANT, GRINNING FACE PAINTED on it -- two BROKEN WINDOWS for EYES, with flames pouring out... FIRETRUCKS spray water.</context>
      <utterance>Shhhhh! Watch!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>COMMISSIONER JACOBS, a wrinkled official, turns to camera.</context>
      <utterance>Police Commissioner Jacobs has just arrived... just a second... excuse me, Commissioner, could you tell us what you think has happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISSIONER JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack turns, sees Tyler in the archway, watching him. Tyler tips his beer to toast, pulls back, out of sight.</context>
      <utterance>We believe this is related to the recent acts of vandalism around the city. It's some kind of organized group, and we are coordinating a rigorous investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all BURST INTO LAUGHTER. They look at Jack and shake their heads. Jack doesn't get it. Suddenly, the guys' faces turn to stone. Bob sits rigid.</context>
      <utterance>What did you guys do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stares at them.</context>
      <utterance>The first rule of Project Mayhem is... you do not ask questions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrap it around the top of his hackie- sack.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky produces a KNIFE, moves it down to Jacob's testicles. Jacobs is bug-eyed. Jack, red-faced, keeps his distance.</context>
      <utterance>Man, his balls are ice cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to continue your "rigorous investigation." You will publicly state that there is no underground group. Or -- imagine, the rest of your life with your scrotum flapping empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... no... please, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky makes a dramatic cut with the knife, causing Jacobs to JUMP -- Ricky holds up the severed RUBBER BAND.</context>
      <utterance>We'll send one to the New York Times and one to the Los Angeles Times. Press release style. Your nuts will be bicoastal. Understood? The people you're after are everyone you depend on.  TYLER  We do your laundry, cook your food and serve you dinner. We guard you while you sleep. We drive your ambulances. Do not fuck with us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The crowd shouts maniacally, save Tyler, who watches with an inscrutable stone face. Angel Face tries to speak, but Jack POUNDS too hard. Blood flies. The crowd begins to grow QUIETER.</context>
      <utterance>I felt like putting a bullet between the eyes of every Panda that wouldn't screw to save its species.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Finally, Angel Face lies still, unconscious. Jack stops, stares down, numb. Jack walks away -- the crowd parts to let him pass. Jack scans faces... finds Tyler.</context>
      <utterance>I wanted to open the dump valves on oil tankers and smother all the French beaches I'd never see.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you go, Psycho-Boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I felt like destroying something beautiful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you are, Mr. Durden. Airport parking, long term.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After you, Mr. Durden...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... after you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something on your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler shrugs; turns on the RADIO, ignores Jack.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wasn't I told about "Project Mayhem?"</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I have told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wasn't I involved from the beginning? You and I started fight club together.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fight club was the beginning. Now it's out of the basements and there's a name for it -- Project Mayhem.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY AND MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first rule of Project Mayhem is you do not ask questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is as much mine as yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this a needlepoint club? Is it about you and me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want? A statement of purpose... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I E-mail you? Should I put this on your "action item list?"</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to know --</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to know about Project Mayhem?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY AND MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first rule of Project Mayhem --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler steers the car into the opposite lane, accelerates... Opposing HEADLIGHTS get closer fast...</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!!  I want to know what's going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This does not belong to us. We are not the leaders. We are not special.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are the all-singing, all-dancing crap of the world. We are all part of the same compost heap...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler steers back into the proper lane. The other CAR flies past, HORN SOUNDING...</context>
      <utterance>Tyler...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell ... ?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I won't make decisions for you.</context>
      <utterance>You choose your level of involvement.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not asking you to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're asking questions that don't have answers. You know just as much about Project Mayhem as anybody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler again steers into the oncoming lane, speeding up. Through the windshield: oncoming headlights -- a TRUCK.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think that's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack fights to turn the wheel, but Tyler uses both hands.</context>
      <utterance>Tyler... what is this... !</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What will you wish you'd done before you died?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paint a self-portrait.</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Build a house.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know! Nothing!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you died right now, how would you feel about your life?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The oncoming truck HONKS and FLASHES its LIGHTS. It moves to the other side of the road. Tyler steers there, too.</context>
      <utterance>I would feel nothing about my life? Is that what you want to hear?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to hear the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck my life. Fuck fight club. Fuck you and fuck Marla. I'm sick of this. How's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you think I blew up your condo?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nearing impact with the oncoming truck, Tyler takes his hands off the wheel -- Jack keeps his grip, turns the wheel... the car swerves... The truck ROARS past, spraying water, HORN BLASTING. Tyler looks at Jack, his hands in the air. Jack looks at Tyler with dead eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Hitting bottom isn't a weekend retreat! It's not a seminar! You have to forget everything you know, everything you think you know -- about life, about friendship, about you and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack takes his hands off the wheel, holds them in the air. Tyler studies Jack face, impressed. Tyler makes no move to take the wheel. THROUGH THR WINDSHIELD: a STALLED CAR ahead on the side of the road, surrounded by flares. Jack and Tyler's eyes stay locked as the car drifts onto the shoulder... heading for the stalled car. Their faces are illuminated by the light of the flares. Tyler smiles. They SMASH into the stalled car -- AIRBAGS INFLATE! The back of their car whips around and carries it into a ass- over-tea-kettle ROLL down a hill...</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay... fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The car finally hits the bottom, lying on its roof.</context>
      <utterance>I'd never been in a car accident. This must've been what all those statistics felt like before I filed them into my reports.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler stands, gives Jack's head a pat.</context>
      <utterance>In the world I see -- you're stalking elk through the damp canyon forests around the ruins of Rockefeller Center. You will wear leather clothes that last you the rest of your life. You will climb the wrist- thick kudzu vines that wrap the Sears Tower. You will see tiny figures pounding corn and laying-strips of venison on the empty car pool lane of the ruins of a superhighway.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel better, champ.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seems to be as weak as Jack.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be out of your way in a sec.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... don't have to... leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really... I mean it.  Have you been going to your groups?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chloe's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you care?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla turns to face Jack, a grim expression on her face. There's a BRUISE on her ARM. Jack gets up, moves closer.</context>
      <utterance>It was the smart move on her part.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are we both... caught up like this... with... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Marla looks a him, waiting.</context>
      <utterance>I came so close to saying Tyler's name, I could feel it vibrate inside my mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. Why does a weak person have to go out and find a strong person... to hang onto?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Faint SOUND of SAWING and HAMMERING. Jack can't quite figure where it's coming from.</context>
      <utterance>What do you get out of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hear what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That... sawing and hammering.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns -- through the crack of the open basement door, Tyler's staring at Jack from the bottom of the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Have we been talking too long? Must we change the subject?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack reacts, turns back to Marla.</context>
      <utterance>You're not talking about me, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That day you came over to my place to play doctor... what was going on there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing? I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This conversation...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This conversation...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla comes to touch Jack's hair. Jack closes the basement door. Marla sees the kiss-scar on Jack's hand, grabs his hand. Jack tries to pull it back, but Marla keeps a grip.</context>
      <utterance>... is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? Who did this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... A person.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guy or girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you ask if it's a guy or a girl?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you get bent if I asked?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go of me...  Leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla backs away, closes her eyes, struggling with frustration. She leaves out the back door, not looking back. Jack leans against the wall. After a moment, he opens the basement door, heads downstairs...</context>
      <utterance>You're afraid to say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... what can I do for you, Ricky? Tyler steps up beside Jack, looks Ricky over.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're too young. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler comes back inside, shuts the door.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Too young?"</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fat, too fat.</context>
      <utterance>If the applicant is young, we tell him he's too young. Old, too old.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Applicant?"</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the applicant waits at the door for three days without food, shelter or encouragement, then he can enter and begin training.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Training?" Tyler...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You will never get inside this house!</context>
      <utterance>Are you deaf?! I told you to leave!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, friend, I'm sorry for the misunderstanding. It's not the end of the world. Just go away. You're trespassing and I will call the police. Nothing personal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He WHACKS Ricky in the shoulder with the broom.</context>
      <utterance>You're never getting through this door, you stupid little weasel! Look at me when I talk to you... !</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your major malfunction!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky goes in. Tyler turns to Bob.</context>
      <utterance>You have two black shirts? Two pair black trousers? One pair black boots? Two pair black socks? One black coat? Three hundred dollars personal burial money? Go inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob looks genuinely hurt. He picks up his mattress and starts away. Tyler looks at Jack and rolls his eyes. Jack follows Bob...</context>
      <utterance>You're too old. Sorry. And, you're too fat. Nice seeing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob... Bob, wait...  Let me explain this to you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky HITS them with the broom, then goes in, SLAMS THE DOOR.</context>
      <utterance>You're too fucking old, fatty! We don't want your kind here!  You're too short. Go away, stumpy! Go back to the circus!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it went...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>IN THE KITCHEN WINDOW, Jack watches...</context>
      <utterance>Tyler built his army.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack turns to look around the kitchen. THREE SPACE MONKEYS work -- one SCRUBBING the FLOOR, one WASHING DISHES, one SCRUBBING the walls. Jack walks out.</context>
      <utterance>To what purpose, might one ask? Well, one might ask, if not for the first rule of Project Mayhem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Tyler We Trust.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room is empty. Jack stares.</context>
      <utterance>Tyler...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRECKLED SPACE MONKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"You are not a beautiful and unique snowflake. You are the same decaying organic matter as everything else. We are all part of the same compost heap."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack dips a spoon into the rice, chomps on it irritatingly.</context>
      <utterance>Planet Tyler.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRECKLED SPACE MONKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"We are the all-singing, all-dancing crap of the world." Jack picks up a BOTTLE of VODKA.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to hug the walls, trapped inside this clockwork of Space Monkeys, cooking and working and sleeping in teams.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANGEL FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wouldn't interest you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Tyler?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first rule of Project --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Angel Face replaces the file, Jack notices -- a LYE- BURNED KISS-SCAR on the back of Angel Face's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Right, right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack drops his cigarette in the gravel, steps on it. A Space Monkey immediately comes to clean it up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm all alone. I Am Jack's Broken Heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get away from me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Paper Street Soap Company.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla stares at Jack, miserable. A tear runs down her cheek. She turns and walks away. Jack watches her go. There's a LOUD COMMOTION from the house, VOICES SHOUTING. Jack heads to the back door...</context>
      <utterance>He's not here! Tyler's not here anymore! He's gone away!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Space Monkeys stare at the body. The Mechanic, sweating, gets to his knees and pulls the ski mask off the corpse -- it's BOB, with a gunshot wound to the HEAD.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack pushes past a Space Monkey, stares down, stricken...</context>
      <utterance>Bob... oh, Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... what happened... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were on assignment...</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A SERIES of EXPLOSIONS blasts the GLOBE free. It ROLLS...</context>
      <utterance>We were supposed to kill two birds with one stone:</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The GLOBE ROLLS downhill, to the street -- rolling over one parked LUXURY CAR after another, crunching car roofs and causing windows to explode...</context>
      <utterance>A piece of corporate art...</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Then, the GLOBE arrives at the lobby of a HOTEL... BROADSIDES a limo, RICOCHETS... ROLLS directly into the front of a closed ARROSTO coffee bar, SMASHING windows... DECIMATING coffee push-pats...</context>
      <utterance>... and trash a trendy coffee bar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had it all worked out, man. It went smooth... until...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARSH VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O.S. SOUNDS of GUNSHOTS and FLASHES of MUZZLE FIRE.</context>
      <utterance>Police! Freeze!</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack walks away from Bob's corpse, distraught, holds his head, turns to look back, his eyes filling with tears.</context>
      <utterance>They shot Bob... they shot him in the head. Those fuckers...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER SPACE MONKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We have to get rid of this body.</context>
      <utterance>We got to get rid of the evidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks around in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Bury him...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several Space Monkeys gather around Bob's body.</context>
      <utterance>The garden. Take him there. Move, people. Let's do this!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Space Monkeys stop. Jack gets between them and Bob, SHOVES a few Space Monkeys back...</context>
      <utterance>No... !</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your hands off him! Get off...! What the hell do you think you're doing... ? Evidence?! This is a man... ! You killed him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was killed in action.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Look at you! You're... you're running around in ski masks, exploding things...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was killed serving Project Mayhem.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what he would have wanted, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What he wanted? Look... look at him. Look at him! What does he want?  This is a person. This is not a cog in your machine...</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, this is Project Mayhem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. This is a man -- this man has a name...</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, in Project Mayhem, we have no names.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Wrong! This man's name is Robert Paulson.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robert Paulson?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robert Paulson is dead. He's dead, because of you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone just stares at Jack.</context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In death, a member of Project Mayhem has a name.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Robert Paulson.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Robert Paulson!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL SPACE MONKEYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Robert Paulson!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop that -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL SPACE MONKEYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack backs away, surrounded, PUSHES his way out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>His name is Robert Paulson! His name is Robert Paulson...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyler?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE STERN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack, in a panic, HANGS UP.</context>
      <utterance>This is Detective Stern of the arson unit. I'd like to see you in my office tomorrow morning...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know how or why, but I could look at fifty different bars, and somehow I just knew...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. Let me out, right here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for Tyler Durden.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never heard of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is an emergency. It's important I find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bartender WINKS at Jack.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I could help you... sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to know where Tyler is. Can't you help me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDAGED PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, you're disturbing the other patrons with your laudish behavior.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no one else here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDAGED PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I haven't the faintest idea what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at my face. I'm a member. I just need to know if you've seen Tyler Durden.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDAGED PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks around, incredibly frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not disclosed to bespeak any such information to you, nor would I, even if I had said information you want, at this juncture be able.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are a moron.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDAGED PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack gives up, shoves his way out the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I have to insist you leave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRUISED PATRON #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's ever seen him. No one knows what he looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUISED PATRON #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has facial reconstructive surgery every three years.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the stupidest thing I've ever heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUISED PATRON #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true about fight club in Miami?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUISED PATRON 12</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Mr. Durden building an army?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I asleep... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have I slept? I'm not sure if Tyler is my bad dream or if I'm Tyler's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KITCHEN WORKERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Robert Paulson. His name is Robert Paulson...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jack whirls, startled -- facing the wounded BARTENDER, who wears a NECK BRACE, his nose a smashed eggplant.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome back, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOUNDED BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... You know me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOUNDED BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this a test, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... it's a test.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOUNDED BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were in here last Thursday night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOUNDED BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's tight as a drum.</context>
      <utterance>You were standing right where you are now, asking how good our security is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOUNDED BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods slowly. The Bartender holds up his hand, shows the KISS SCAR on the back of his hand...</context>
      <utterance>Is this part of the test?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOUNDED BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're Mr. Durden, sir. Tyler Durden.</context>
      <utterance>You're the one who did this to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please return your seatbacks to their full upright and locked position.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marla, it's me. Have we... have we ever had sex?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of stupid question is that?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because the answer's "yes" or because the answer's "no?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this a trick?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you just answer me, for Christsake?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean, you want to know if I think we were just having sex or making love?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did make love?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you're calling it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer the question!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fuck me, then snub me. You love me, you hate me. You show me your sensitive side, then you turn into a total asshole! Is that a pretty accurate description of our relationship, Tyler?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've just lost cabin pressure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is wrong with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say my name! What's my name!?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyler Durden! Tyler Durden, you fucking freak. What's going on? I'm coming over there...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Marla HANGS UP. Jack stares at the receiver, dazed...</context>
      <utterance>Marla, no, wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack spins, dropping the phone -- TYLER sits beside him.</context>
      <utterance>We've got six fight clubs in Chicago now...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four in Milwaukee.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this all about, Tyler?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, we're definitely filling a void in the rural South.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do people think I'm you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You broke your promise. You talked to her about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do people think I'm Tyler Durden?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer me, Tyler.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do people think anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler shakes his head in disgust, extremely irritated.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know! Tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People think that you're me, because you and I happen to share the same body.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this really news to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I control it, and you imagine yourself watching me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack listens, looks at the empty space beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone?  My boss, probably.  Who would you fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah.  I didn't really know my Dad...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I go places without you. Get things done...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASHBACK - BUILDING - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK, Bob, Ricky, Angel Face and another GUY rappel down the side, SPRAYING PAINT. JACK is "TYLER" in demeanor, mannerisms, speech...</context>
      <utterance>The Parker Morris Building.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO WINDOWS SHATTER OUTWARD -- TWO MEN look out and yell:</context>
      <utterance>You are not your job. You are not how much money you have in the bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUISED MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not my job!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUISED MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not how much money I have in the bank!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There! Happy? I asked for one thing from you... one simple promise. Now look what you've done!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't possible...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to have to do something about Marla...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... what are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack shakes his head in disbelief, in denial...</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. We okay... a little codependent, sure, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! This isn't true. We... we were around other people, together, both of us...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never talked to me in front of anyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong, wrong -- what about the car crash... the two guys in the backseat?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about them? They're lunatics.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You took me to the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The house is rented in your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have jobs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Night jobs -- while you were sleeping.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Marla?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Marla?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's... you... you're fucking her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stands, trying to absorb, feeling ill, trying to find words, then -- he suddenly FAINTS to the floor, OUT COLD.</context>
      <utterance>Um, well... technically, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called a "changeover." The movie goes on, and nobody in the audience has any idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir... sir? Are you checking out?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clerk follows the length of the counter, waves a PAPER.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please initial this list of phone calls.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack goes out the door, freezes. He rushes back in, going to the desk -- snatches the bill, studies it: many NUMBERS.</context>
      <utterance>Bill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait...when were these made?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at the clerk, at the bill, at the clerk.</context>
      <utterance>It says right there, sir... between two and three-thirty this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a copy of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had I been going to bed earlier every night? Have I been sleeping later? Has Tyler been in charge longer and longer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jack finger stops on a NUMBER. He dials, phone to his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Deja vu, all over again...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack sees a file on the wall: "1888 CENTURY PARK EAST."</context>
      <utterance>Eighteen-eighty-eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maintenance.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, something is going to happen, something terrible...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about us, sir. We're solid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everything's changed...</context>
      <utterance>Now wait, there's been a mix-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me you'd say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abort the plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me you'd say that, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I tell you I'd call you a fascist dickhead?!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack HANGS UP, desperately dials the next number on the bill.</context>
      <utterance>Well, sir, you said you might.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla makes a sharp turn, walking away. Jack follows, hugging the files to his chest, catching up.</context>
      <utterance>Marla!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marla...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your whacked-out, bald freaks hit me with a fucking broom. I thought they were going to break my arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The were burning their fingertips with lye. The stink was unbelievable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marla... I need to talk to you. It's going to take a tremendous act of faith on your part for you to hear me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla heads into a DINER. Jack follows...</context>
      <utterance>Here comes an avalanche of bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- A little more faith than that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to hear anything you've got to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>just sixty seconds.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a minute, Marla, alright...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty seconds, then I'm out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely, you have every right. I need you to do me a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WAITER with a BLACK EYE appears at the table.</context>
      <utterance>I've done you enough favors.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir! Anything you order is free of charge, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is it free of charge?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because... I'm Tyler Durden.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack look to the pass-through WINDOW into the kitchen where THREE COOKS look out with STITCHES in their faces.</context>
      <utterance>Then, I'll have the clam chowder... fried chicken and a baked potato with everything and a chocolate chiffon pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clean food, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In that case, sir, may I advise against the lady eating the clam chowder?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter snaps to attention and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, no clam chowder. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got about thirty seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that I've been... unwell. I know it's been like there's two sides to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackass.</context>
      <utterance>Two sides? You're Dr. Jeckle and Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I deserve that. Anyway, I've... I've only just realized</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, the depth and breadth of our relationship has only recently been illuminated for me. I know this... I know us hasn't been such a great thing for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla's getting up to go, but Jack rises, fed up, takes her by the arm, putting her back in her seat.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever.  I'll take my food to go...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla crosses her arms. Jack collects himself.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down! Sit down and give me my last fifteen seconds without opening your mouth!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to tell you -- and this is where you have to trust me -- but, I think your life might be in real danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to get out of here. Leave as soon as possible. Go to any rural town, away from any major city...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are an insane person.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marla...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla's getting upset, tears coming to her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, shut up! I've had enough. I tried, Tyler... I have tried...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a part of you I really like, but I can't do this anymore. I just can't. This is killing me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla gets up. Jack grabs for her, but she's gone, heading for the door. Jack gathers his files, runs to follow...</context>
      <utterance>What?! You're sorry? I don't believe that for a minute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack grabs her arm, tries to hail a TAXI, but the taxi races past. Marla pulls free, screaming at him...,</context>
      <utterance>I can't explain. You wouldn't believe me anyway. I'm trying to protect you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go of me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack spots a BUS idling further up the street.</context>
      <utterance>Do this for me, Marla. Do this for me, if you never do anything else...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone! I don't ever want to see you again!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls MONEY from his pocket, holding it out.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, if that's what it takes, you'll never have to see me again.  Here... here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla looks at Jack, numb.</context>
      <utterance>Take this money, get on this bus...  Get on, and I promise you, I'll never bother you again, if that's what you want. Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyler...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla takes the money from Tyler, walks towards the bus. As they approach it, Jack shields his eyes, afraid to look...</context>
      <utterance>I'm begging you. Get on the bus. Get on the bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla stands at the doors of the bus, heartbroken, gives one last look at Jack.</context>
      <utterance>I can't let myself see where you're going. Go wherever it takes you, remember... keep away from major cities...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not paying this back. I consider it "asshole tax."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack's still covering his eyes. Marla gets on the bus.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, fine. Just, get on. Stay away a couple of weeks, at least.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack finally looks to her.</context>
      <utterance>Tyler...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DOORS HISS SHUT. The BUS LEAVES, heading away. Jack seems relieved. Then, a SCREAM is HEARD from MARLA... Jack turns, looks... THROUGH THE BUS WINDOWS: the bus is filled with BALD MEN IN BLACK: Space Monkeys. Jack SPRINTS after the bus... The bus speeds away. Onboard, Space Monkeys subdue Marla. Jack falls to the asphalt, rolls, files-flying.</context>
      <utterance>You are the worst thing that ever happened to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are probably several hundred members in the metropolitan area. Chapters are sprouting in at least five other major cities. They're tightly-regimented, with many cells capable of operating without a central leader. Check this address: 1537 Paper Street. You'll find the body of Robert Paulson buried in the garden. You'll also find numerous tubs used to make gallons of nitroglycerin. The plan, I believe, is to blow up these credit card headquarters and the TRW building.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why these buildings?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not your job. You are not how much money you have in the bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern leaves. A beat, then, the remaining Detectives smile at Jack with REVERENCE.</context>
      <utterance>Keep him talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAT-TOP DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're a brave man to order this.</context>
      <utterance>I really admire what you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>REDHEAD DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They grab Jack and force him on his back on the table. Flat-Top has a rubber band; the Bald Detective has a knife.</context>
      <utterance>You're a genius, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALD DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flat-Top PULLS Jack's pants completely off, tosses them aside. Jack SCREAMS. Flat-Top holds his legs.</context>
      <utterance>You know the drill. You said if anyone ever tries to interfere with Project Mayhem, even you, we got to get his balls.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAT-TOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's useless to fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>REDHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is really a powerful gesture, Mr. Durden. It'll set quite an example.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... you're making a mistake!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAT-TOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told us you'd say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not Tyler Durden!</utterance>
   <speaker>BALDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told us you'd say that, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I am Tyler Durden and I'm ordering you to abort the mission!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAT-TOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you would definitely say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's our best time for a "cut and run?"</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAT-TOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is somebody timing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baldy glances back at the other Detectives, leaves, closing the door. The two remaining Detectives continue. Jack kicks and screams and writhes. The Detectives wrangle him, but with more difficulty, now that Baldy's gone.</context>
      <utterance>Some of this info checks out. Let's go to the place on Paper Street.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="48">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks -- Tyler's seated, his back against one post.</context>
      <utterance>Could be worse...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could be standing under 37 stories of steel and concrete with a 150 gallons of nitroglycerin strapped to the support... oh, maybe it couldn't be...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... you can't be serious about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a ridiculous thing to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't let you...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What are you going to do?</context>
      <utterance>...go through with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...stop me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...to let this happen!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop finishing...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler gets up walks to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>...your sentences! They're our sentences. Get your mind around that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing running through the streets in your underpants? We both use that body.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when is Project Mayhem about murder?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The buildings were evacuated thirty minutes ago. Everything's proceeding exactly as planned.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know that. There could still be people inside. Tyler keeps walking around, crosses his arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks back to the BOMB, goes to it, wipes sweat off his face. He starts finger the MANY WIRES, sorting them.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Maybe a couple of guys with shaved heads couldn't synchronize their watches. Good riddance.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't be doing that. Unless you know which wires, in what order...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack holds his gun under one armpit, uses both hands to go through the tangle of colored wires.</context>
      <utterance>If you know, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack chooses one wire, GREEN, holds it in his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Or... maybe I knew you'd know, so I spent the whole day thinking about the wrong ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm wrong, we're both dead..</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not about martyrdom. Jack twists the GREEN WIRE around his finger.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pulling the green wire.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler comes a little closer, leaning to try to get a look, seems genuinely concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Green? Did you say green?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't pull the green wire. Pull anything but the green wire.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack's unsure, swallowing, pulling the wire taunt, fingers trembling. The SOUND of a VEHICLE is HEARD from below...</context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. That's the wrong one.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks to Tyler. Tyler points towards the SOUND...</context>
      <utterance>Hear that? Marla's here. Just in the nick of time, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack releases the wire, walks to a RAILING, gun in hand, keeps an eye on Tyler. Jack looks over the railing... BELOW, a BUS idles. The doors open and MARLA'S dragged out, kicking and screaming, carried by SIX SPACE MONKEYS...</context>
      <utterance>See for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They carry Marla into the BUILDING'S ENTRANCE. Jack leans against the railing, exhausted.</context>
      <utterance>You motherfuckers...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got everything. The bombs. The army. I've got Marla.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler thinks, shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Bob is dead, Tyler. The police blew a hole in his head. Was that part of your plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob was a grown man. In any great struggle, there will be casualties. Wouldn't that be implicit in the name? Project "Mayhem."</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck your struggle. I want out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want out?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler's walks away. Jack looks at the gun in his hand. He points the gun at Tyler...</context>
      <utterance>Not an option, for the most obvious of reasons. You need to get with the program.  Seven minutes. Let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyler...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler stops walking.</context>
      <utterance>Defuse the bomb.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask me nicely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Defuse the bomb, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Defuse the bomb?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler strides towards the BOMB. Jack trains the gun...</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler looks at the BOMB, reaches over to it. He grips the GREEN WIRE, yanks it out -- the CLOCK STOPS. Jack lowers his gun.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack's stunned. Tyler walks across the parking garage, past Jack, heading for the STAIRS. Jack aims the gun at Tyler's back, FIRES! Tyler ducks to one side, impossibly quick, avoiding... Tyler spins to face Jack.</context>
      <utterance>I did that for you. As a gesture. Now, how fast can you run? There are ten other bombs, in ten other buildings in the immediate area. If you're going to get them all, you better get cracking.  Six minutes. Green wires, remember. I'll be upstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler DODGES behind a post as the BULLET THROWS CONCRETE. Jack edges forward, gun held in both hands, moves around the post... Tyler is NOT THERE. Jack turns, takes slow steps, moving the gun from side to side... Suddenly, a FIST ENTERS FRAME -- SLUGS Jack's face. Jack falls. The gun goes CLATTERING across the floor... Jack turns, looking... Tyler's GONE. Jack looks to the gun, scrambles to his feet, running to pick up the gun... Tyler KICKS Jack in the chest, sends Jack sprawling. Jack rolls, holding his chest. He looks up, sees Tyler run into the STAIRWELL. Jack grabs the gun and follows...</context>
      <utterance>Whoa! What was that all about? Jack aims... FIRES!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack clenches his teeth, FIRING -- nothing happens to Tyler. Jack FIRES TWICE -- no effect. Tyler raises his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Fire at will.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack charges. Tyler dodges, PUNCHES, knocks the gun out of Jack's hand. They FIGHT, trading PUNCHES, grappling, taking each other to the floor...</context>
      <utterance>What did you expect?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think this is about where we came in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the beginning. We're at ground zero. Maybe you should say a few words, to mark the occasion.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack tongues the barrel to the side of his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>i... ann....iinn.. ff....nnyin...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler checks his watch.</context>
      <utterance>I still can't think of anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's getting exciting now. Jack turns, so he can see down -- 31 STORIES.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler watches the skyline, WHISTLES at tune, waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Look what we've accomplished.  Thirty seconds.  Out these windows, we will view the economic collapse. One step closer to global equilibrium. I'm glad you're here with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you call it off... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's out of our hands.  This is it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler looks out the windows, at SURROUNDING BUILDINGS, excited. Jack closes his eyes, despairing.</context>
      <utterance>Fifteen seconds now. Can you see alright? 10... 9... 8....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paraffin.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paraffin. Your merry band mixed the nitro with paraffin. I saw it floating in the bomb.  JACK  They must've run out of cotton and Epsom salt. Paraffin is iffy at best. Tyler rises, taking the gun from Jack's mouth, starts pacing. Jack rubs his sore jowls, allows himself a smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it! God-damn it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly according to plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler stops walking, lets out a sigh of disgust. He reaches into his pocket, taking out a WALKIE TALKIE.</context>
      <utterance>Do we have to do everything ourselves?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack's eyes go wide.</context>
      <utterance>... Codename Rooster. Passcode First Strike...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="51">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack SHOOTS TWICE. Bullets pass right thorough Tyler. Tyler just rolls his eyes, drops the walkie-talkie to the floor and STOMPS on it, CRUSHING it.</context>
      <utterance>Haven't we already done this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you do that?! You're a fucking figment of my imagination... you're psychogenic fugue state...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack falters, pointing at Tyler's feet. There's no walkie- talkie there. Jack looks down, sees the WALKIE-TALKIE CRUSHED under his own foot.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck that, maybe you're my hallucination.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack holds his head, walks around, at his wit's end.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why... why... why... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't I get rid of you? Why can't I just wish you away?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, I don't.  I thank you, I really do. Thank you, but I don't need you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I can be selfish, I know that.  I'm not blind to my own failings...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack backs up against a window, numb and weary.</context>
      <utterance>Noooo, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From now on, we'll share Marla. We've been spending too much time apart...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... no, no, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From here on out, we do it together.</context>
      <utterance>No more running off without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm doing this for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please understand... I've gotten all I can from this, Tyler.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I leave, you will be right back where I found you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear on my life, I won't...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stares at Tyler, tears welling up, hangs his head. He looks at the gun in his hand...</context>
      <utterance>You will. You know you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stares at the gun a long time... then... Jack brings the gun up, PUTS THE GUN IN HIS MOUTH. Tyler cocks his head.</context>
      <utterance>Can you live with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you left for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you want to do that? Why do you want to put that gun in your mouth?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler is calm.</context>
      <utterance>Not my mouth. Our mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler smiles in appreciation, slowly walks forward, stands very close to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>This is interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you going with this, Ikea- boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack COCKS the hammer on the gun.</context>
      <utterance>It's the only way to get rid of you...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes are locked, unblinking. Long silence.</context>
      <utterance>I can see you feel very strongly. I feel strongly too.  Hey, you and me.  Friends again?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do something for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Appreciate something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at me...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My eyes are open.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack slumps to the floor... Tyler falls... Tyler hits the ground. The back of TYLER'S HEAD is BLOWN OPEN, revealing blood, skull and brain. Suddenly, a GROUP of SPACE MONKEYS burst into the room, moving forward to Jack. TYLER'S BODY IS GONE.</context>
      <utterance>What's that smell... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TALL SPACE MONKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack quakes, holding the side of his head; a ragged hole blown in his CHEEK. He's bleeding hard, but he's alive.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right, sir... ?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks to the Space Monkeys, trying to get his eyes to see. TWO SPACE MONKEYS enter with Marla. One holds a gun to Marla as she struggles.</context>
      <utterance>I'm okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHORT SPACE MONKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure? You look terrible, sir! What's happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER SPACE MONKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack sees Marla, tries to get to his feet, falls...</context>
      <utterance>Sir, you look really awful! Do you need medical assistance?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Monkeys bring Marla, releasing her, saluting.</context>
      <utterance>Bring the girl to me. The rest of you get out. Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla crouches, takes out wadded TISSUES and tries to apply. them to Jack's wound. Space Monkeys are leaving, hesitantly.</context>
      <utterance>Don't ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack and Marla are left alone.</context>
      <utterance>Get to the rendezvous point. Move it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, you're shot...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack tries to got up. Marla helps him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did this to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MASSIVE EXPLOSION... the glass walls rattle... Jack and Marla look -- OUT THE WINDOWS: a BUILDING EXPLODES; collapsing upon itself. Then, ANOTHER BUILDING IMPLODES into a massive cloud of dust. Jack and Marla are silhouetted against the SKYLINE. Jack looks to Marla, reaches to take her hand.</context>
      <utterance>I did, I think. But, I'm okay... I'm fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla looks at him. ANOTHER BUILDING IMPLODES and COLLAPSES inward... and ANOTHER BUILDING... and ANOTHER... The FILM SLOWS, then ADVANCES ONE FRAME at a TIME -- SHOWING SPROCKET HOLES on the SIDES. EACH FRAME is an IMPLODING BUILDING -- then, ONE FRAME IS A PENIS. Then, the IMPLODING BUILDING again. SPEED UP the frames, LOSE the sprocket holes, RESUME NORMAL SPEED...</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... you met me at a very strange time in my life.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
