<movie id="214" title="Four Rooms">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>VOICE-OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another voice of a young man interrupts.</context>
      <utterance>There used to be a staff of fifty in this place. I'm the only one left from those days. It all comes down to one sap: the night-shift bellhop, that's me. What the hell is a bellhop? You know where the name comes from?  Of course not... It's so simple it's stupid. They ring a bell and you hop. You hop to front and center. No heroes in this line, kid. Just men doing a job. No questions asked, none answered. I try to keep it simple, kid, not too personal...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You met any of those old stars?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stars! Are you kidding me? I took Rin Tin Tin out for a shit, for Christ's sakes. I taught Shirley Temple how to roller-skate. I saw Fatty Arbuckle regurgitate three cheese sandwiches right on the spot you're sitting, kid. What did you say your name was?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted, right. I remember Marilyn used to come down at night and doze off in the kitchen. She liked the sound of the fans out back spinning around. Sure, these were stars, kid. Errol Flynn used to call me "Alibi." You'll pick up a few stories yourself, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so, not like yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think a star does when he goes to the bathroom, kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beats me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wisp of smoke passes over a napkin pinned to the wall with a lip print on it signed "Marilyn." The camera pulls back to reveal Ted and the Old Guy sitting on a foldout cot in a small back room of the Hotel Mon Signor. The old man is dressed in a striped T-shirt with a bellhop's cap on. He looks like an old pirate. Next to him on the bed sits Ted, a young guy with a bellhop jacket draped over his knees. The old bellhop takes a long drag off a big cigar.</context>
      <utterance>He pulls his pants down and takes a crap just like you and me. Take my word for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Camacho!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old bellhop takes a hit off his cigar and stares down at his cap, lost in thought.</context>
      <utterance>The cigar. Cuban. A good cigar, wrapped in Miami. I get a box of them every Christmas from the chairman of the board. I think he sends them to me to keep my mouth shut. It's tough not to get a little personal in this business.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old guy passes the cap over to Ted.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted puts the cap on.</context>
      <utterance>Put it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Guy gets up from the bed and throws a jacket on. Pulls a few postcards off the wall, throws them in an old straw suitcase, and slams the lid down. He heads for the door. Ted follows.</context>
      <utterance>Frankly, you look stupid... like the Philip Morris guy. I can't believe I wore that thing for fifty years. You keep it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Guy pauses for a second and looks Ted dead in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Stay away from night clerks, kids, hookers, and marital disputes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never have sex with the clientele.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way, not me. You got any other advice.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door slams shut on the back room.</context>
      <utterance>Always get a tip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Guy stops in his tracks and turns around.</context>
      <utterance>Sam! Hey, Sam, wait a minute!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty comes from behind the desk.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to say good-bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Guy squints his eyes at the young gal.</context>
      <utterance>Uhhh, Betty. The concierge. Your boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Gotta light, sister? Goddam cigar went out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She speaks to the Old Guy as she lights his cigar and he puffs away.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want you to know, from the owner and all the staff, your fifty years of service have been an inspiration to us all. You're a legend in your own time, and the Mon Signor will never be the --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty is left standing in the lobby. Ted appears behind her in his bellbody uniform, sans cap.</context>
      <utterance>Just forward my cigars, Red.  Aufwiedersehen!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam the bellboy. Now there was a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Oh, hi, Teddy. Ready to start the night shift?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let me buy you a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna buy me a drink? I'm starting my shift.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not an alcoholic, are you; one drink won't kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure. They walk out of frame. In the empty frame we</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="55">
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After fifty years, Sam retires, and you're taking over the night shift.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're filling some mighty big shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam was a legend in the hotel business.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bellhop's bellhop.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An inspiration to us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ran the night desk for fifty years, all by himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An amazing man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No desk clerk. No night man. No help. Just fuckin' Sam, and his wits.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're gonna do the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted spews his drink.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I can't. I never worked the night shift before.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh night shift -- smight shift.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were supposed to work it together.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm having a New Year's Eve party.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I'm not having it. My roommate is. And there's this guy. German guy. He's gonna be there. And so am I.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't run this place by myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure ya can.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam ran this place by himself for fifty years.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and he had fifty years of fuckin' practice, too. I haven't had a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Teddy, calm down --</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Don't call me Teddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted, the night's cake. It's easy. The day's when it's busy. During the night there's nothing to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's New Year's Eve.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which'll make it less busy than normal. Ever worked on Christmas? Unless you sell turkeys, business is dead. You just got butterflies, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty slows the scene down.</context>
      <utterance>What I have ain't butterflies. I can't handle this hotel all by myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's calm down a minute. Slow it down, cool it off. Let's just talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can say any goddamn thing you want --</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Ted? I thought we were calming down? I thought we were cooling off? No hostility. Say good-bye to hostility. We're just talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... okay... okay... I'm calm, I'm cool, let's talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted, in a nutshell, all you have to do is hold the fort. It's New Year's Eve. Most of the guests are going out. You'll just be giving them a little nod as they come staggering in at three... four... five... in the morning. Nobody's having any parties, a few get-togethers, but no parties. You got about three people checking in tonight, that's it. The only variable is Chester Rush in the penthouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chester Rush? The guy from The Wacky Detective?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty takes a piece of paper and writes her number down.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, him and his entourage checked in last night. They're in the penthouse. The only reason I refer to it as a variable is that he's a movie star. Ya never know about movie stars. I'm tellin' ya, Ted, it's cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted thinks about it for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>And look, if you have any problems, call me at the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great --</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- For fifty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty bucks!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're shirking your duties for this Nazi. For that you pay a price, and the price is fifty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One, Horst is not a Nazi. Two, that's not a fair price. You're taking advantage of the situation. Twenty bucks. Now, twenty bucks is a fair price.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty begrudgingly digs in her purse.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but what you're doin' to me ain't fair. And, you are completely and totally taking advantage of me and your position. So fifty bucks is the perfect price.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him the money.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, but don't be a pussy. You don't bother me unless it's an emergency. In fact, for fifty bucks, you better not call me unless the fuckin' building's burning down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted sits in the chair, takes another drink, and prepares himself for the night.</context>
      <utterance>Get ready to take the desk. Betty leaves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted strains as he uses all his cojones to lift the insanely heavy bag onto the cart. Athena tips the cab driver, stingily. The driver winces and gets in the cab. Ted has now managed with grunts and groans and strained blood vessels to put this thing on the cart. The cab skids away. Athena looks at Ted, who is out of breath.</context>
      <utterance>Pleeze be careful -- my God. You have no idea...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted wheezes and pounds on his chest.</context>
      <utterance>I'm usually a good tipper, but this one -- this cab driver -- he had green all around him. I don't like that in a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Green? Is that bad? Like you read auras or something like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well what color are you seein' around me... how's the tip lookin?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if she can't help herself, Athena's eyes are strangely drawn to his crotch. She frowns, confused by this impulse. Ted appears to be charmingly oblivious. Athena looks back into his face.</context>
      <utterance>I see purple... in your face, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted touches his face -- as if searching for the "purple" in it -- and moves the cart inside, discreetly checking out his crotch and giving her a confused side glance.</context>
      <utterance>...you're okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Athena Z.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're booked in the Honeymoon Suite -- just one night? With all this luggage?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will only need to stay till sunrise.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... and how will you be paying?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at this wacky Gypsy chick numbly -- she pulls out her Gold Card and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>With gold.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- the other bag -- I need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to lift it, again straining and turning purple. He laughs sickly.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She relieves him of the task and effortlessly picks up the bag.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell you got in here, lady? Nuclear weapons?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted nods, confused by "the others," and walks off with the cart. Then he turns from outside the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>The others will be coming soon. Send them, pleeze.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Athena is ahead of him -- she flips a switch and water begins to flow from the baby cupids' urns into the hot tub.</context>
      <utterance>Oh -- I forgot to show you how to turn on the Jacuzzi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she says this, the door closes with a strange force, shutting Ted out. Athena takes the bag to the bedroom of the suite.</context>
      <utterance>I been in dis' place many New Year's. So... you send the others to me, huh. Go now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On this night, oh great goddess Diana, we restore your virgin flesh and bring you back to real life. CLOSE ON the rock slab. We hold the artifact.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon -- I take you to the pond for a cleansing. Well, it's a swimming pool, but it will be under the setting sun, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she snaps, irritated, behind her.</context>
      <utterance>I... we... have a reservation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON a young punk rocker chick with long orange hair, a long leather coat, wearing a tight T-shirt with studs spelling "PUSSY" across her breasts. This is Kiva. Kiva is kicking the tar and nicotine outta the cigarette machine. Just as Ted's eyes grow wide with anxiety, several packs of smokes drop into the juvenile delinquent's hands.</context>
      <utterance>Kiva!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait up, gawd! I had to get supplies for this boring ass night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a reservation in the Honeymoon Suite.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him without humor. He fumbles for the key. He walks around the desk to help her with her black crocodile luggage. Jars clang inside. He is ready to go, but Elspeth turns to lecture Kiva on the hazards of smoking, as Kiva lights up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah... you must be one of "the others." And what're you carrying -- the Rock of Gibraltar?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I tell you about smoking?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right -- I smoke, and I'm addicted to it, and I don't want the same thing to happen to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Kiva goes off on her impression of a game-show host, Elspeth is growing increasingly rageful, like a mother with an unruly child. Ted waits, luggage in hand.</context>
      <utterance>"Hello -- welcome to this week's edition of the Hypocrite of the Year Award --"</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cuts Kiva's ramble off. Kiva blows smoke defiantly.</context>
      <utterance>Kiva! That's enough --</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not my mother!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted looks on uneasily at the relationship that is beginning to unfold here. Elspeth checks his reaction and becomes self-conscious at his scrutiny.</context>
      <utterance>Then why're we sleeping together?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But her wild child looks off, bored. Elspeth turns to Ted, flustered.</context>
      <utterance>Well... I didn't mean it... literally. I... I happen to be the only one who... cares about you --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted smiles uneasily and reaches to relieve her of her sword, but Elspeth quickly slams her palm on the sword and shoots him a piercing glare. He jumps back with a light nervous laugh. He leads the way to the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>Please -- take us to our room!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted starts away again, perplexed. He turns for one last look to see Elspeth kneeling before Kiva, who sprawls on the floor. He shakes his head and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Flea powder. One of the others is bringing her cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna have to wait in the other room.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I said so.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll watch TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kiva looks around the room and spies the TV in the hallway. She turns to Elspeth with sarcastic concession.</context>
      <utterance>You can't watch TV because the noise will interfere with our ritual.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth bristles as the brat saunters off to the bedroom. Elspeth enters the sacred circle, stands before the altar, whips out her sword, and makes a ceremonial gesture pointing the sword upward, perfectly centered between her breasts. Kiva, behind Elspeth's back, exits from the bedroom doorway into the hall and comes back in, lugging the TV into the honeymoon bedroom. Elspeth kneels before the altar. Athena enters the room with the "cleansed" artifact and lays the slab in the center of the altar upon the heart-shaped pillows as Elspeth lays her sword next to the rock. The women look upon the union with tender affection.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... Mommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athena stands up but her reverie is dispelled as she shrieks! Loud TV suddenly blasts from the bedroom and Kiva the brat is trying on the pink negligee over her clothes. Athena takes the negligee off the irrepressible youth.</context>
      <utterance>Soon -- our goddess will come. I will go get her negligee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing! Have you no respect -- who -- who is dis girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiva. My friend. Kiva, turn off the TV! I can't leave her at home -- she's on probation and I gotta keep an eye on her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Elspeth, your friend cannot stay here during the ritual. She may be one of your kind, but she is not one of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women have a stare-down. Then Athena calls out --</context>
      <utterance>She stays!! Or I go -- along with my offering!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth becomes anxious with jealousy. Athena is exasperated as she firmly demands from Elspeth --</context>
      <utterance>Make me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth defers to Athena with remembered reverence and respect. She bows apologetic and scurries to the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Let's not forget -- I am the High Fucking Priestess. Deal with dis girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me -- did we have these problems in Salem? I don't think so...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kiva smirks... yeah, she knows.</context>
      <utterance>Kiva... you know what I love about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your sweet side.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do I get if I'm sweet?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get whatever you want. And you know what else I love about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And saying this, she kisses Kiva's nose and leaves the room. Kiva is quieted now. As Elspeth closes the bedroom door, she has the last word.</context>
      <utterance>Your nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kiva slinks back on the bed, put in her place -- for now.</context>
      <utterance>And I saw you checking her out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh you little stinker... oh you sweet little muffin. Yes... Mama loves the baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted carries all her bags inside awkwardly. Again, the place has become all the more transformed with wild canopies of exotic cloths and fixings. Elspeth and Athena are hard at work on a strange nature sculpture as Jezebel enters. She stands inside the powdered circle and before the hot tub, which now has dark blue water swirling inside. She presents her cat -- upward toward heaven -- frees the cat, bares her breasts and sucks in the vibes: "Ahhhh." Ted settles the bags down, hoping for a peek at her charms, but her back is to him. The kitty rubs on her leg. She picks it up and presses it against her bare breasts, petting it sweetly. She winks and hands him a tip.</context>
      <utterance>Well, this is just darlin'! Just darlin' Hi-dee, girls...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And saying this, she shoos him away. Through the glass doors to the bedroom, she sees Kiva sprawled on the bed, writing on herself.</context>
      <utterance>Toodle-loo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- I see Elspeth has herself a new lil' fool -- what the hell is she doin' here on our night of annual ritual?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have sanctioned her presence, as long as she behaves. Come on -- there is more work to be done to welcome our great Diana.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I always attract girls who are looking for a babysitter?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth seethes at her. Jezebel acts blithely innocent.</context>
      <utterance>Well now, honey, maybe Juvenile Hall ain't the best place to find serious relationship material.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for the room for making love.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might be referring to the Honeymoon Suite. Straight thata way... you can't miss it -- see all that furniture in the hallway --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh I know the way. I just wanted you to know that I knew where I was going and that you needn't bother yourself with me. The others are here -- great!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah -- it's so great -- it's fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohhh... I know it all seems very strange but you're coping with us much better than the bellboys of past New Year's.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Past New Year's?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes -- we've been coming here every New Year... for a long time. Thanks for your patience.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh hey -- no problem -- wreck the place. Bring in cats. Ruin the carpet with flea powder, pour paint in the Jacuzzi. Throw the furniture out the... where're your bags?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted looks down at the broom at her side, her bare feets, her thick dark hair. It keeps getting weirder. She wanders off.</context>
      <utterance>I travel very light.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, Honeymoon Suite.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lowers her eyes, worried.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... yes... I'm late.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right -- lemme give ya a hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is so sweet and sincere that he feels like a heel to have been irritated with her. He picks up her bags.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... no, that's all right. I can carry them by myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eva smiles, beautifully.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a man doin' a job -- no hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well gosh -- thank you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, how long have the others been here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eva's heart sinks. They arrive at the door. He carries her bags in.</context>
      <utterance>About an hour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are very late, Eva.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted is slightly queasy. She hands him a tip and smiles, then takes it back.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Athena. I was attending a birth and the placenta was late in coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted's no fool, he waits while Eva looks through her change purse.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, wait, lemme give you a little more than that...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which birth is more important to you, that of a mortal or that of a goddess?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All life is precious... but I do apologize for being late, Elspeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back home, they jist yank on the umbilical cord, do a Karate chop on the mama's belly, and them things come right out.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They do that here, too, Jezebel, in the hospitals, but it causes hemorrhages. I fed the mother a bowl of comfrey tea and it brought the afterbirth down perfectly. The couple are going to use it for fertilizer to plant a lovely tree for their baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON Ted's face as he gets thoroughly grossed out.</context>
      <utterance>Oh wow -- if they were really back- to-nature, they'd eat it, like other mammals do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In some Native American cultures, they dry the umbilical cord, grind it to a fine powder, and put it in a leather pouch that the baby wears to ward off evil. But burying the placenta is also a very sound ecological practice -- 'cause of the oxygen it carries.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- because you see when the placenta detaches from the uterine wall...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, thank you, ladies -- I'll be going now. If you need anything -- Eva places a nice tip in his palm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted sighs as Eva enters the circle with her black pot. She kneels softly, holds her hands in piety before the altar, and softly incants as she offers her pot and places it on the altar. The stone and sword and flowers now rest here on pillows covered in chiffon scarves. The negligee hangs from the mantel, the slippers underneath as if expecting someone to materialize into the garments.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. We do need a few things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted is watching Eva, enchanted.</context>
      <utterance>We need fresh rosemary from the kitchen. Mostly what we need is from the kitchen. Hey, are you listening?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, rosemary.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And a little bit of sea salt or Kosher salt if you don't got no sea salt. A bottle of spring water -- Italian please, not French shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And some french fries!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiva, shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And some ginger, two of the eyes of a trout fish, and a piece of raw meat, liver if you have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want fries -- you dumb jerks with your stupid fucking ritual!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, you little shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted has scribbled down the items as she speaks. He looks at this list and these girls and shudders as he walks away. He turns, points at Eva. Ted smiles at this angel of a girl. She smiles back. But, as she looks him in the eyes, he feels a strange buzzing connection happening. He holds his head, almost swooning with dizziness. Athena smirks.</context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to her that way!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted comes out of his daze, looks at the list again and huffs off. After he goes, the girls begin to bring forth their most treasured offerings in ornate ancient bottles, vases or vials. Jezebel folds her arms and clears her throat in the direction of Kiva, sitting idly on the edge of the blue water Jacuzzi, with her feet dipping irreverently in the water.</context>
      <utterance>Get to work, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiva...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to go in the next room now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, wow, like I'm bummed out that I can't watch.  I'm bored!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't put me in there by myself. I'll miss you way too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kiva sees a bit of weakening here; she takes her feet out of the Jacuzzi. She begins to speak softly.</context>
      <utterance>Kiva, don't do this to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth begins to weaken. But continues to pull the brat up. Kiva pours on softer seduction.</context>
      <utterance>Please... if you just lemme... I'll play dress-up with you, the way you like it... you know what I mean... remember...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth is now fully seduced. Kiva takes Elspeth's hand and presses it lightly on her face.</context>
      <utterance>We can pretend and I'll do it exactly... the way you want it... with the egg whites and the kilt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kiva nods. Elspeth is enthralled, but from a disgusted "ick" sound from Jezebel, Elspeth realizes she's revealing this side of her life -- in front of her coven. She nervously looks around and see all the coven looking at her: a disgusted Jezebel, an understanding Raven, a preoccupied Eva and an impatient and stern Athena. Elspeth comes to her senses, straightens her posture.</context>
      <utterance>You mean... like last week?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll talk about this later, Kiva.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns on Elspeth and bites her hand. Elspeth pulls her arm away and grabs Kiva by the hair.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, really now -- child abuse?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stay outta this!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth lets go of Kiva's hair. Kiva jerks away from her.</context>
      <utterance>I demand this stop now, Elspeth!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm running away from you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kiva stomps off into the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Go ahead. And I'll call your parole officer and she'll find you and send you back to Eastlake!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth enters the powered circle. Each girl takes off her shoes. They anoint themselves with oils.</context>
      <utterance>Now that the fucking melodrama is over, can we start the goddamn ritual -- pleeze?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls moan in sleepy, eerie agreement as they begin to sway within the circle.</context>
      <utterance>We are communing here on New Year's Eve to bring to life the great goddess Diana, who was turned to stone in this very room forty years ago today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And saying this, the girls all form a "rock" with their bodies gracefully draped one upon the other. Music begins, and slowly they start to unfold from the rock. The girls each find their place in a semicircle around the Jacuzzi. Some bare their breasts, other strip off a layer of clothes. They anoint their arms with water from the Jacuzzi. They begin a lovely dance, snaking their way around the semicircle. The first one to go from one end to the other is Athena. She then proceeds up the stairs and positions herself between the altar and the Jacuzzi. She steps forth with a bottle to the altar and pours it into the Jacuzzi.</context>
      <utterance>Diana, great beautiful one, we make these offerings to you, that we may undo the wicked spell which deprived you of the seed of your lover, your virginal blood, of your very life. We now form the symbolic rock with our bodies.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Each of the girls moans eerily. Athena places the bottle on the altar and bows away. She joins the circle as Elspeth now steps forward with her offering in a vial.</context>
      <utterance>On this night, in this hour, we Call upon the Ancient Power O Goddess bride, I offer thee Milk from a mother's sweet titty!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To reverse the evil which has been done I make this offering to the Divine One A whore not, an innocent was, For whom I seized a virgin's blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls moan loudly as they sway. Jezebel places her offering in the hot tub and bows out, returning to the circle. Now Raven comes forth with a small leather canteen. She unscrews the lid as she offers in her opiate stupor.</context>
      <utterance>Goddess of Light, Goddess of Lust, To undo this awful spell is a real must. To bring you life and get you high I offer the sweat of five men's thighs.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pours liquid into the mix, as the witches moan. Now it's Eva's turn. Eva continues to sway, not moving forth to the altar. The girls keep their eyes closed as they sway, waiting for Eva's offering. Athena finally gives her a push and she goes. Eva kneels before the altar. She produces a silver bottle with a chain on its cap and neck. She timidly begins to incant.</context>
      <utterance>Diana, oh great one, we live without sun Until this wicked curse is undone. In hope that you live, and to us appear, I have collected a year's worth of tears.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moans turn to wails as the girls GASP and SHRIEK! Athena opens her eyes, wildly.</context>
      <utterance>Great Goddess Diana, fail you I will, I was to bring fresh sperm from my Bill. I had him erect, and his semen would follow But alas I was hot, so hot that I swallowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth opens her eyes and folds her arms, smirking bitterly.</context>
      <utterance>You stupid little witch! You swallowed the sperm! Aye-yi--yi!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just shows what an amazing lack of control you have over yourself, Eva!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, why didn't you just use your hands? Didn't your mama teach you not to put them things in your mouth?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eva bursts into tears. Athena is firm.</context>
      <utterance>I understand though...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then: a knock at the door.</context>
      <utterance>There is no time to cry over swallowed sperms. You're gonna have to get some, baby. You have one hour to prove what kind of witch you really are.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athena smiles and turns to Eva.</context>
      <utterance>Ted... the bellboy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted opens the door. His eyes bulge out as he looks upon the fleshly feast. He steps back. They giggle seductively, all except Eva, who sniffles, red-eyed. Amazingly, Ted's attention is captivated by Eva's sorrow, not by the naked charms of the other witches. She shyly covers her breasts. Sensitive to her shame and sorrow, he looks away and steps from the door to fetch the room-service cart. Athena directs the others to put on their shirts. Ted wheels in the cart.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bellboy, come right in!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the trout. Elspeth picks it up, flings the eyes into the Jacuzzi, and tosses the trout out of the window. She smirks at him comtemptuously.</context>
      <utterance>Here's the things you asked for. Oh, and uhh, sorry, but I'm not gonna pick the eyes outta this dead fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she doesn't get his goop in ten minutes, I'm going to take him myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha! That'll be a first for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs back in for her bratty girlfriend, who is already sneaking out the bedroom door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit -- Kiva!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And just where do you think you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, gawd -- I need a candy bar or something -- you haven't fed me all day. I'm getting all shaky. My blood sugar's really low.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elspeth -- honestly now -- some babysitter you're turnin' out ta be!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elspeth, you go feed your terrible girlfriend. We meet back here in one hour and let's all have faith that Eva can get this guy off. The witches disperse.</context>
      <utterance>Enough, girls. I will collect fresh earth. Jezebel, I want you to gather damp moss. Raven, you bring me a birch branch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="45">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help me out, lady. I gotta earn this fifty bucks!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted waits; she sighs and rest her chin in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh look, they don't care if I smile or not! All they want is...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins to cry tearfully again.</context>
      <utterance>You won't understand, believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He postures proudly, all puffed out. Eva looks at him helplessly. And he paternally encourages her to explain.</context>
      <utterance>Try me. I've been around, y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... okay. The five of us -- Elspeth, Jezebel, Athena, Raven and me -- are a coven.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha, like a coven of witches?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around the room: QUICK CUTS of candles, iconography, jars of lurid substances, unknown body parts of animals woven into the nature sculpture... and are those tongues in that can? Ted's getting the creeps, but again puffs himself up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew that!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you see, our coven has spent forty years trying to perfect a ritual to undo a wicked curse put on our goddess Diana.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, you don't look a day over twenty!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... ha ha... I mean the witches before us tried and failed. But Athena, our High Priestess, discovered a great potion to reverse the evil spell which turned our beautiful goddess into an old rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eva nods, looking lovingly at the stone.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Is... is that her?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was a beautiful virgin. An entertainer by trade, but a great sorceress by design. It was here in this very room, on her wedding night, a jealous rival placed the curse on Diana.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She turned to -- that -- here?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted frowns as he ponders all this. Eva takes a photo from the altar and hands it to Ted.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... and her young husband turned into a pink fish! They found him swimming in the pool in circles. While our dear goddess: a stone in her honeymoon bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON photo: a Blond Bombshell in full-on Betty Page attire, a bare-tittied pinup girl, playfully spanking a girl in bondage with a spiked high heel.</context>
      <utterance>This was Diana.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The photograph slowly comes alive. Diana stops spanking the girl and unties her. She pulls the girl (in the black satin mask) up off her lap and makes the girl stand. The women face each other and break into a cheek-to-cheek tango. CLOSE ON Ted as he shakes his head. Are his eyes playing tricks on him?</context>
      <utterance>This girl here? This is the goddess Diana?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate to tell you this, but I kinda doubt she was a virgin.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins to sob again. Ted comforts her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, but she was! She had lovers, but she saved that for marriage. Which is the example I've tried to follow: to do everything but that till I marry...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, don't cry... a virgin is a rare and beautiful thing. If you say she was a virgin, I'll believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it doesn't matter now... and she won't be resurrected tonight 'cause I failed her. I let my whole coven down!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the photo. Eva nods.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a sec -- that rock was gonna turn back into this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, that would be something worth seeing!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only, not now -- we were each supposed to bring something -- a life fluid.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If this is gonna be like one of those afterbirth conversations, I don't think I wanna hear this.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only... I swallowed it...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eva looks off. Ted searches his brains, thoroughly sickened now.</context>
      <utterance>You swallowed what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods; he winces, queasy. Eva looks at him, helpless.</context>
      <utterance>You mean, you were supposed to bring... like... like a guy's... and you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now, you're my last chance!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whoa, what? You want my -- for the -- witchy poo -- ahh no -- no way -- nope. Besides, it's against hotel policy. I was warned: "No sex with the clientele"! Eva sobs, pleading. She throws off her shawl, baring her lovely breasts, and reaches her arms around his neck. He keeps backing off. Unbeknownst to him, he is already doing a ritualistic shuffle.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha, c'mon now, joke's over.  Hey, we're gonna step in the flea powder.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not flea powder, that's sacred dust ground from the horns of Albino goats.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is backing away, into the circle, as she comes for him, soft and sweet. Her eyes are again putting the magic hex on him, as he tries to resist her gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Right! I knew that!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a nice girl like you doing in a coven, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, see, what I really want to do is be a midwife. I've attended four births already! I can prevent vaginal tears and everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the while she is stepping toward him into the circle.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's a good thing! A guy doesn't like surprises down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I joined the coven to attain greater understanding of my feminine power so I could become a truly great midwife!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eva sweetly takes his hand and places it on her breast.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, well, I see you've been gaining a lot of insight into your... girl powers...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah, I'd say that seems to be the case...  Ohhh, God! Betty's gonna kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Betty -- your girlfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. My boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh good!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They fall into a kiss, as she begins to remove his cap. She moves him toward the Jacuzzi, closer and closer.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My phone number in Topanga. Call me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that used for?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a birch branch, symbolizing eternal life. You can also use the bark for a tea which assists in astral travel.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other girls roll their eyes as Elspeth smiles proudly. Ted blows smoke at them and pushes his cart off down the hall. The witches run inside the room.</context>
      <utterance>Hey -- I wanna be a witch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a woman now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But where is his "stuff"?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did it right there, in the big cauldron!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooohhh honey, you're gonna be sore tomorra! Didn't your mama teach you that water strips a girl's lubrication?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sex in water is great in the movies, not in real life... but you will learn. As we all did.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, when she can't walk...  I guess you wouldn't have those kinds of problems -- without penetration.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. And virtually no cervical cancer, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athena regally leads the ritual as they all bare their breasts again. Kiva throws off her shirt to join in. As she does, we see black bondage tape on her nipples. Elspeth darts a quick look at the tape, looks at the other witches -- not sure she likes this -- but she goes with it. The witches sway in a circle, eyes closed, as Eva makes her offering.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, girls, enough Sex Education 101, let's get going with our ritual, goddammit.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The witches all incant.</context>
      <utterance>Goddess Diana, I offer you The jism of one I wooed for you That you may live and know such bliss Of getting laid by a guy like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL OF THE WITCHES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They march half-naked as they moan and revel in eerie cries. The Jacuzzi begins to bubble and boil. Their cries heighten; the potion bubbles over.</context>
      <utterance>So must it be. Three times three times three.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand what went wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say Eva pulled one over on us.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey -- Eva was wearing the face of someone just fucked good... and the best actress in this world, or any other, can't fake a thing like that!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSPETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly -- if she was fucked so good, how could she save his come?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could be done...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girls, knock it off.  Maybe... maybe it needed to be the sperm of a virgin male.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The witches sadly collect their things. Athena, deep in thought, strokes the slab.</context>
      <utterance>He was no virgin!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all agree. They pick up their bags and head out.</context>
      <utterance>Let's leave her here, with the sword, until dawn. I will come back for her before checkout time. I just... feel too sad to carry her away before the sun comes up to warm her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEZEBEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe we have to carry our own bags out! My mama would have a hissy fit!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll carry your bags.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes the door on the Honeymoon Suite (till next New Year's Eve!).</context>
      <utterance>Next year, we try again -- with virgin sperm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus, what did I tell you? Do you want milk and cookies, or do you not?  I can't turn on an adult station without permission from your parents.  That's not what the machine tells me.  You be good and you'll get milk and cookies, but for now leave me alone, please. I'll be up later to put you both to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings again.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn kids. SUPER: 1:00 a.m.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Room Service.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Yuppie turns away from the phone and speaks to Real Theodore.</context>
      <utterance>This is the front desk, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE SCUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What room are we in?</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL THEODORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How should I know? I just got here.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE SCUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, don't you have one of those light things?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you care to go to the door and look on the other side, you'll find the room number.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE SCUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call my assistant and ask her what floor we're on.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL THEODORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's your assistant?</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE SCUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girl you party with every night.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL THEODORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here alone, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL THEODORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's room 404, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE SCUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could have sworn we were on the fifth floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL THEODORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. 404.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE SCUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. 404.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you need, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE SCUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we need?</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL THEODORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE SCUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ice?</utterance>
   <speaker>REAL THEODORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE SCUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUPPIE SCUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, sir. Ice. 404. I'll be with you momentarily.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="58">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A DEMONIC CACKLE cuts through the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody home?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one here but us chickens.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, it's pretty dark in here, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you expect, Theodore, a fuckin' floor show?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a flash the lights switch on and Ted finds himself staring down the barrel of a pretty intense-looking .357 Magnum, cocked and ready to fire. At the other end of the gun stands a 50-year-old man, Sigfried, who sports a Cheshire Cat smile and a "just try fuckin' with me" look on his face. Sigfried isn't the only person in the room. Directly behind him sits a beautiful young woman, Angela, gagged and bound to a chair. Ted drops the bucket to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brought your ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's cute. In fact, the whole getup's kind of cute. The monkey suit's a nice touch, honey puss.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has to be a mistake. Is this room 404?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Theodore? What do you take me for, Theodore?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried reaches in his pocket and throws a handful of assorted stimulants into his mouth, chewing on them like they were breath mints. Sigfried thrusts his hand forward, gripping Ted by the throat, and leads him to Angela.</context>
      <utterance>A very upset man?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am an upset man, Theodore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know my name, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm psychic, Theodore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look my name is Ted, actually, and I have no idea what's going on here, but I've obviously come at a bad time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried turns to Angela.</context>
      <utterance>Let's not belabor the fact that you have no sense of timing, Theodore. The fact is you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I couldn't think of a better time for you to introduce me to your beau than on New Year's Eve.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, with great force, Sigfried slams the butt of his pistol smack into Ted's temple, sending him to the floor. Ted looks up at Sigfried in shock.</context>
      <utterance>Oh fuck, there's a mistake. You're fucking wrong here. My name is Theodore, yes! My mother named me that and I hate the name. But I'm a fucking bellhop. People call me Ted. I work here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'd love to sit here all night with you talking about things like when you broke in your first mitt --  That was insensitive of me, wasn't it, T H E O D O R E? But let's cut to the chase, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tense silence fills the room. All eyes are on Ted, who can't figure out what the fuck this guy wants.</context>
      <utterance>So apologize!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried looks hard with disbelief at Ted, who winces back.</context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried throws another handful of pills into his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>You are really beginning to annoy me, Theodore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, obviously you two are working something out and if I could help you with your problem I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying? Are you saying I got a problem? Are you trying to say I don't give her what she needs? That I'm FUCKING INSENSITIVE!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted has struck a raw nerve. Sigfried's mood swings drastically; he bends down next to Ted.</context>
      <utterance>Look, is this about another man? Or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get our ABC's right, here, Theodore. Theodore, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted's better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted, okay... Are you saying my wife cheats on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say that... I...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, for Christ's sake, Theodore, this is about as intimate a situation as you can get, you, me, and Angela here. It's pretty cozy. To say nothing of how stupid an idea it is to lie to a man with a loaded gun without considering the possible response. I demand an apology!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried glances at it. Then to Angela. He picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move. I've got to take this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He listens to the other line, says good-bye, and hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>What?  We ain't got any needles here, kid. Just a big fucking gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried, hands clasped together, signals for Ted to do the same. The gun lies at his side. Ted considers a bold move, but thinks better of it. Sigfried's eyes pop open. He cuts a look to Ted, signaling him to assume the pose.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to pray for forgiveness, Theodore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now say after me, "I apologize..."</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I apologize...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted looks to Angela for help. She can only stare back with intense, wide-open eyes.</context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For fucking what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That I said you might have been unfaithful?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted repeats what Sigfried has told him. This appears to have a calming effect on Sigfried, who gets up off the floor, turning his face to Angela.</context>
      <utterance>"That I said you might have been unfaithful?" Listen, Theodore, you're in church here... you're kneeling in front of an altar. Truth... truth is all it hears. Say the following, "I, Theodore, must humbly and sincerely apologize for saying that you fucked another man!"</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela nods.</context>
      <utterance>Satisfied?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Naturally, Angela says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Do you accept the fucking apology?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried turns to Ted.</context>
      <utterance>You always gotta get the last word, don't you? It's one way with you, Angela, isn't it? I give and I give and I get nothing back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted beckons Sigfried.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid me, for a second I thought you were going to say something... something like, "I'm sorry." HA! "I'm sorry." You're absolutely right, love cakes, I wouldn't want it that way. That's one thing you can say about Angela. She'll never do anything she doesn't want to do. If the feeling ain't there, she just isn't going to do it. There is nothing in this world as fucked as a woman who gives when she doesn't want to. Never let that happen to you, Theodore. It makes you feel very little indeed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mind if I...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Spit it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean to upset you further, sir, but I think she was trying to say yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you condescending to me, Theodore?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not, I would never do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just say it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That you think I'm an idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would never say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you're superior to me, don't ya, Theodore? You don't think I notice there is a gag in the woman's mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naturally "of course." And do you know how I know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried empties the last of the pills into his mouth, heaving the empty bottle over his shoulder. He takes off, disappearing into the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Because I PUT THE GAG IN HER MOUTH! I'm gonna let you in on a little secret about communication, Theodore. It's all in the eyes...  Him?  Or me? Him or me? No one? Okay. Let's drag it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have time to play charades here, asshole! Untie me quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, lady, I don't know what in the hell is going on here, but I'd appreciate it if you would explain to that nutcase that he's making a big mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, whether you like it or not, you're in the middle of a situation here you can't just wish your way out of.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I've never seen you people before, we're complete strangers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted wrestles with the idea of whether to untie Angela or not.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone starts out strangers, Ted, it's where we end up that counts. Hurry up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I can do this. It's too hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On nervous impulse, Ted begins the calculations.</context>
      <utterance>Life is hard, Ted. You ever stopped to consider how many times you change your underwear in a lifetime?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean literally, you ignoramus.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, listen to me. There's a gun in my suitcase behind the bed, it's loaded...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to shoot anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Get the gun and I'll shoot "anybody."</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted collapses to his knees in front of Angela.</context>
      <utterance>And make me an accessory in the murder of your husband?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not fair. It just isn't fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted collects himself.</context>
      <utterance>Get a fucking grip on yourself. First off, who says he's my husband? And second, we are a long way from fair here, fair is back in jolly old England eatin' crumpets and sipping on tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tut. Tut. Tut. Not so fast. Well, maybe there are two sides to this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are two sides to a plate, still you only eat off of one. Now GET THE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why's he got you tied up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted is at a loss as to what to do. Angela turns on the charm.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a werewolf, Ted! Get the gun!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted creeps towards her.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Ted. Come over here just for a minute. You can do it. Come on, Ted. You look like a good guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried suddenly comes to life... He's heard from the bathroom belting out "Life is but a dream... she-boom, she- boom."</context>
      <utterance>That's it, Teddy. You look so much more attractive when you're self- assured.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted hurries to replace the sock in her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Quick, he's coming back. Put the gag back in, and remember the gun!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine thousand, three hundred and twenty-two times, to the best of my estimation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted's fingers are frozen over Angela's lips.</context>
      <utterance>I was just beginning to think I could trust you, Theodore. Silly me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just trying to help her breathe a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let me stop you, Teddy. You don't mind me calling you Teddy, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted starts to back toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>I used to have a little bunny rabbit named Teddy, it looked real cute nibbling on Angela's ear. Only problem here is you're no bunny rabbit, Theodore, and it really fuckin' razzes me to picture you doin' it. But don't let me stop you, Teddy... no need to play sneaky-poo.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, man, if this is some kind of Voodoo thing and you want me to have sex with your wife, there is absolutely no way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The directness of Sigfried's command, coupled with the SOUND of a trigger being cocked, forces Ted to approach Angela. Angela is a stunning beauty, and Ted being kind of a shy guy makes for an awkward situation. Ted leans forward. As he closes in, Angela's eyes close.</context>
      <utterance>I said, nibble, asshole! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted pulls up short of actually nibbling on Angela.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, no whiz left in the cheese? I'm not cramping your style, am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried yanks Ted backwards. He wraps his arms around him.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm not playing this game anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted struggles to free himself from Sigfried's powerful bear hug and blasts out the following monologue.</context>
      <utterance>It's almost all over, Theodore, and soon you can go home to Mommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is not Theodore, it's TED,</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sigfried.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Sigfried.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried cuts a "Something wrong with that?" look at Ted.</context>
      <utterance>Sigfried?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah, Sigfried.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted cautiously takes Sigfried's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you, Sigfried.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very impressive, Ted. "Theo the Thumper?"... Ouch. It's a deal, kid. Ted it will be.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried holds onto Ted's hand. The soft sound of distant fireworks pops in the background. Car horns and a muffled countdown signal that it's New Year's. Sigfried moves uncomfortably close to Ted and from out of nowhere bolts forward, planting a wet kiss right on Ted's mouth. Something snaps in Sigfried. He is either really getting off on this or he is caught in the grips of a seizure. He doubles back on the floors. Ted and Angela watch as he flops around like a flounder with the cocked gun waving all over the place. Ted wipes his mouth with his jacket sleeve while trying to dodge the barrel of the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried manages to steady the gun and point it directly at Ted. He signals for Ted to go to the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>You okay, mister? I'll get help!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted rushes into the bathroom, leaving Sigfried a babbling mess behind.</context>
      <utterance>Get me the nitro... it's in the bathroom cabinet. Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Something's wrong with the guy, all the blood is drained from his face and he is mumbling something.</context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I'm stuck here in a situation that I can't even begin to explain, but would you be so kind as to get help? Could you call the police, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young man manages to belt out the word "ice" just before hurling a mouthful of vomit toward Ted. It takes all Ted's strength to dodge the puke and pull himself back into the bathroom. He falls back on the floor. He props himself up and checks for damage. He notices something odd... the room is silent. No Sigfried. He walks into the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="64">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads toward the door and, from out of the corner of his eye, he spots Sigfried's hairy leg. Sigfried has passed out on the floor. Angela's chair has been knocked on its side. Ted races over to help lift her back up. He pulls the gag from her mouth. Angela jumps all over him.</context>
      <utterance>Sigfried?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the fucking nitro?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't find it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted struggles to untie Angela.</context>
      <utterance>You took long enough. Untie me, for Christ's sake, you fucking upset him and he's dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you wanted to kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The knots are all over the place and a real bitch to untie.</context>
      <utterance>You'd make a great cop, Theodore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted turns on a dime and runs smack into Sigfried, who's been taking in the whole conversation.</context>
      <utterance>I can't handle this alone, I'd better get help.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tie a pretty good knot, don't I, Ted?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God you're okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela hears Sigfried's voice from behind her back.</context>
      <utterance>Never felt better.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, honey, don't get mad. It was just a little test, and I'm glad I did it because now I'll know forever that you really do love me. Truly and deeply.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the simple fact that I didn't want your bloated, dead body lying out on the floor is love, then no wonder we find ourselves as we are at this very fucking moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no. I heard you and there was genuine care in that voice. Can't be denied. Can it, Ted?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted edges his way toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>I think you're right and, if you just keep this kind of open dialogue going, you'll go a long way to resolving this misunderstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be surprised what happens when people just listen to each other without succumbing to all that pain and anger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried turns an icy eye on Ted, who has given up all hope of ever getting out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>You heard shit, monkey boy. Easy for you to say after you fuck another man's wife. You should at least have the guts to stand by your convictions.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela continues her tirade.</context>
      <utterance>That's a lie, Sigfried. I swear to God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried slowly raises his gun, pointing it directly at Ted's chest.</context>
      <utterance>When I think of all the times you were inside me promising me a better life, it makes me want to puke.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this? What have I ever done to you people?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words hit Sigfried like bullets to the chest... his legs weaken.</context>
      <utterance>What didn't you do, stick man? Unfortunately, you don't have the balls to back up the actions of your huge cock.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got a huge cock?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's lying again, mister. It's not that big.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, man, she's lying. Can't you see she's fucking with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put it this way, God made up for what he did to Gumby with Ted here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried runs over to Angela and kneels in front of her.</context>
      <utterance>Show him your cock, Theodore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop talking about his cock, will you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela is on a roll. She fires the words at Sigfried, hitting him pointblank. He staggers. He pleads with her to stop, covering his ears. Ted watches the man crumble.</context>
      <utterance>It's hard to stop talking about something so huge. I could go on and on about his cock, bone, nob, bishop, wang, thang, hotrod. Hump mobile, Oscar, dong, dagger, banana, cucumber, salami. Sausage, kielbasa, schlong, dink, tool, Big Ben, Mister Happy, prick, disk, pecker, peter, pee-pee, wee-wee, weiner, pisser, pistol, joint, hose, horn, middle-leg, third- leg, meat, stick, joystick, dipstick.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, don't leave me. I'll call you Ted from now on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not me, mister, I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried heaves the gun over his shoulder, grabs a half-empty bottle of Jack Daniel's, and passes it to Ted, who takes a hit.</context>
      <utterance>Personally, I don't give a fuck, Ted, it's just I don't want to be alone right now. I'm feeling a little vulnerable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No guns, okay? Just you and me, Ted. You know my father used to say that forgiveness is the only thing that evil can't sink its teeth into.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kind of nice down here on the floor, isn't it, Ted?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things take on a whole new perspective... You'd like my trust, wouldn't you, Ted?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just got one thing to ask you and I'll let you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me straight now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it like?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was what like?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you and her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, for fuck sake, Sigfried, what do you want me to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either way you're fucked, right? You ever gonna see her again, Theodore?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I ever saw her again, I'd run the other way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried releases Ted and stands up.</context>
      <utterance>I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried throws his hand out to help Ted up.</context>
      <utterance>You're lying, but I can respect that, Ted. If you told me, it would no longer be a secret, and secrets have a power, kid. You open that box and they disappear forever. A bad secret will rip you apart, but the good one are all you got. In the end, when all the people you knew are dead and gone, all you'll have left are you secrets. And when you die, the box is open and it all blows away -- dust to dust -- all the anger, jealousy, desire and love just blow away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a man of love, Theodore. Love is all I live for.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe to a fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't beat yourself up over it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice of you to say, Ted, but I probably should make a clean break of it, cut her loose and get my own place. I just can't imagine living without her. Do you think I should seek professional help?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not for everyone, but maybe in your case it could help.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>You ever been out on the ocean at night?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sigfried is bent over, silently weeping on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You'd better go check to see if I killed anybody downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela sits next to Sigfried and gently strokes his back.</context>
      <utterance>You people gonna be okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted points to a tray with half-eaten food on it.</context>
      <utterance>We're fine, Ted.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like me to...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted slowly walks toward the door and takes one last look at the strange couple at rest in the corner of the room before closing the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Another time, Ted.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>YOUNG GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy New Year, buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy New Year.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just in room 404, what a party! You know where room 409 is at?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy takes off in the direction Ted's walking from. Ted suddenly realizes who this guy is and whips around, shouting to the Young Guy.</context>
      <utterance>Beats me. It's somewhere around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door SLAMS on room 409.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's your name?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE FRONT DESK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted is relaxing at the front desk. He breathes slowly. He finally has one moment's peace after an already long night. He even has a chance to straighten his tie. The phone RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>SUPER: 10:30 p.m.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Front desk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man hangs up the phone and stubs out his cigarette into an already overstuffed ashtray by the bed. Man turns around to face the camera. He is a dark and handsome Latin male in his mid-30s. Dangerous. Impatient. He walks toward the camera as he continues straightening his tie. He stops at the door of the bathroom and watches his Wife and two kids get ready for the party. Wife seems to be a beautiful woman in her mid-30s. The children are Sarah, nine, and Juancho, six. Man strikes up another cigarette and finishes his tie. He watches his Wife comb Juancho's hair down and to the side like an idiot. Not being able to stand it anymore, Man tears Juancho away from his Wife and snatches the comb.</context>
      <utterance>Bottle of Moet et Chandon. Fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man begins to slick Juancho's hair back.</context>
      <utterance>Give me that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juancho is smiling now. He's happy he's going to look like his dad.</context>
      <utterance>There... see? You look cool with your hair up like this. Like me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juancho looks over at Sarah, who is going through the tortuous ritual of having her mother brush the tangles out of her long, unmanageable hair. Wife seems to be taking out her aggressions on the tangled mess. Man is starting to have problems of his own with Juancho's hair. Juancho's hair is thinner than Man's, so it won't stay up. Man puts down his cigarette in order to get a better handle on it. We see the frustration growing in his face. Juancho picks up the cigarette and pretends he's smoking too, just like his dad. Man tears the cigarette away from Juancho and smokes it down to the filter. He looks at his own cool hair, and then down at Juancho's, which won't stay up. Man flicks the cigarette butt into the toilet in frustration.</context>
      <utterance>Not down and to the side, all stupid like your mom likes to comb it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In anger, Man starts messing up Juancho's hair.</context>
      <utterance>You've got your mother's hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious, Man simply swipes Juancho's hair back down and to the side, the way Wife had it before. Juancho looks like an idiot again.</context>
      <utterance>I can't do anything with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juancho slouches past everyone as he exits the bathroom. Sarah watches him leave as her own hair is finished.</context>
      <utterance>There. Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wife then finishes her own gorgeous hair. Man lights up a new cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>There. Go. Sarah exits.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah has joined Juancho in watching television. Man watches the children watch TV. We can see the wheels turning in Man's head. He turns back to the bathroom. He watches Wife now. Wheels turning. Practically burning rubber.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wife puts the lipstick down and turns to her husband. She is beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wife glances out at the children, eyes glued to the tube.</context>
      <utterance>Let's just leave the kids here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here in the room? By themselves?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wife thinks about it for a second. She shrugs a "sure."</context>
      <utterance>No... with the television.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to have fun tonight, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses Wife's face and exits the bathroom. She covers the wet spot with more cake makeup.</context>
      <utterance>They'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children turn to face him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>You guys are going to stay here and watch TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wife goes straight for the door.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to be in bed asleep before twelve. Your mother and I will be back later on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He blows one kiss. One for both of them. As Man and his Wife walk out the door, Man turns back to the children...</context>
      <utterance>Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah stands in the middle of the room. She's looking at the door Man and Wife just disappeared through. Stunned. Her dress looks frilly and beautifully uncomfortable. She touches the edges of the fabric.</context>
      <utterance>Don't misbehave. He closes the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did we have to get all dressed up if we weren't going with them?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man bursts through the door of the hotel room and stands in the doorway, glaring at the mischievous Juancho. Juancho bangs his head on the window trying to get back inside. He leaps to the floor and tries to turn on the TV with the remote.</context>
      <utterance>Escaping. Stinks in here, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juancho turns to Man as if he'd been sitting there watching television the whole time.</context>
      <utterance>What did I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behave.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Papa. Ted appears at the door with Man's champagne.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The champagne you ordered, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted proceeds to place the champagne in the room.</context>
      <utterance>No time for this. Leave it on ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted is torn. Man pushes him into the room.</context>
      <utterance>But I want some now...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There'll be plenty for you and the party, baby, you can bomb yourself all you want at the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted places the bucket near the bed. After setting up the bottle, he turns to leave, but now Man closes the door, trapping Ted inside with them.</context>
      <utterance>What a waste.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man is reaching into his coat pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Ted looks around, bewildered. Now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want five hundred bucks?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man hesitates a moment, then pulls out his wallet. That was too easy.</context>
      <utterance>Sure!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about three?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three hundred?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My children are staying here tonight watching TV. I want you to check up on them every thirty minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check up on 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make sure they're all right, make sure they're fed, make sure they go to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can call out and hire a babysitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't trust babysitters. My children are safer alone than with some fucked- up pedophile babysitter I don't know from the man in the fucking moon.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man grabs Ted's face and tilts it torward Wife.</context>
      <utterance>What about him? What makes you think you can trust him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man lets go of Ted's face. He feels his jaw. It's still there.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me that's not a face you can trust.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man whips out his wallet and counts out money in Ted's face.</context>
      <utterance>Look, sir, I'd like to help you out, but I really can't. I'm all alone here tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One hundred... two hundred... three hundred...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man glares at Ted.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you said five hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted doesn't back down.</context>
      <utterance>I said three hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The angrier Man gets, the quieter he talks.</context>
      <utterance>No, you distinctly said five hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted, while not backing down, massages the situation.</context>
      <utterance>You calling me a liar?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man has never been challenged like this by a fuckin' bellboy.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not saying you're lying. I'm saying you accidentally forgot that what you first said was five hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted not only doesn't back down, but psychologically pokes his finger in the scary Man's chest.</context>
      <utterance>I don't do anything accidentally, jerk. I might've first said five hundred, but what I last said was three hundred, and what you say last is what counts.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man's eyes narrow. He physically pokes his finger in Ted's chest.</context>
      <utterance>Well then, if you say five hundred one last time, we got a deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Ted takes a step backwards.</context>
      <utterance>You fuckin' with me, Pendejo?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not at all. It's New Year's Eve and I'm here alone. If there was somebody else here, no problem, but I'm by myself. And looking after your kids is a pain in the ass I don't need --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You callin' my kids a pain in the ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man drops the tenseness.</context>
      <utterance>-- No, they're not a pain in the ass, it's the situation that's a pain in the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man respects Ted for not backing down, but not insulting him either. A skill Man never learned. Wife shoots a look at the children.</context>
      <utterance>No, you were right the first time. You win, tough guy, five hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah stares down Wife.</context>
      <utterance>You kids are getting expensive. Juancho turns back to the TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE-UP of name tag.</context>
      <utterance>What's your name? Ted?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man tears off Ted's name tag and throws it to children.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's Ted.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If something happens to my children, I wouldn't want to be you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make sure they're in bed before midnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wife looks disgusted.</context>
      <utterance>Before midnight? Then should I wake them up for the countdown to the New Year?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Man and Wife exit, he turns to the kids and says:</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>Don't misbehave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. These are the rules. Don't break the rules and I won't break your necks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah laughs at his joke.</context>
      <utterance>I always wanted to say that. Someone said that to me when I was a kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted goes to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Except they were joking. I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rules are simple. Don't do anything you wouldn't do if your parents were here. If there's an emergency, call me on the phone, like your dad said.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted's surprised by a challenge this early in the game.</context>
      <utterance>That's not what he said.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said to call if we need anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I've got a lot of work to do and I can't have you calling me every time you want a drink of water, so please limit your calls to emergencies only.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We paid you five hundred dollars. We'll call you if we need anything. You don't want to upset my dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Please. Try to call only when necessary. Watch TV, and if you're good, I'll bring up some milk and cookies. Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juancho smells his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Your feet stink.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah throws his shoes and socks behind her. They land on the bed. Juancho is flipping channels and finds an interesting show.</context>
      <utterance>They don't stink.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah realizes he found a Nudie station.</context>
      <utterance>Check it out. T &amp; A.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Change it. You're not supposed to watch this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're supposed to watch TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juancho rolls up in a ball, the remote tucked in some recess of his stomach. Sarah hits him, then goes to the phone. She punches 0, sits on the bed, and checks the name on the name tag pinned to her shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Not this kind of TV. Change it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Front desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted? Hi. It's me, Sarah. You're our sitter for tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus, what did I tell you? I said if you don't bother me, you'll get milk and cookies. Now, do you want them or do you not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted checks the computer.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to turn off the Nudie station in our room.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't turn on an adult station without permission from your parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  Not turn it on, turn it off. It's already on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what the machine tells me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, stop listening to the machine and listen to me. There's naked ladies dancing on my TV and I want 'em off.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>If you're good, you'll get milk and cookies, so leave me alone, please. I'll be up later to put you both to sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juancho turns around. He has a face like someone just laid a fart in his nose.</context>
      <utterance>Change the channel, now!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah smells her feet. Twice.</context>
      <utterance>Man, you're the one with the stinky feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't stink.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sticks her foot out for Juancho to smell. He's reluctant. Fearful.</context>
      <utterance>Here, smell for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slowly, very slowly... climbs onto the bed and lowers his head to her foot. Very slowly. Sarah waits until he's close enough to her foot before she kicks him in the face, sending him somersaulting off the bed and crashing to the floor. She grabs the remote control he left behind and changes the channel to a cartoon. Juancho gets up and realizes his defeat. He decides to wander about. Looking for something to do... Sarah tries to ignore him as he stalks the room. It's only a matter of time before he finds mischief. Juancho sees the champagne bucket and Bingo!, he goes for the bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah opens her mouth, as if about to tell him to leave the champagne alone. She stops herself when she realizes she wants some champagne too. She quickly scrambles about for a bottle opener while Juancho unwraps the bottle top. Sarah opens the dresser drawer with such force that a few hidden contents long forgotten in the back of the drawer slide forward. Some coins, a paperclip, and a hypodermic needle. She looks down at the needle that lays beside the Gideon Bible and casually picks the phone back up and punches 0. The phone rings.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, get a bottle opener!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't shake it!  Ted? Hi. It's me. Sarah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Who died? No one? Then don't call me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah picks up the needle and rolls it over in her hand several times.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I'd tell you that your cleaning ladies are doing a bum job. There's all kinds of leftover stuff around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The champagne bottle explodes all over Juancho. He looks surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Needles and things. We're not supposed to have needles here, are we? I mean, they don't come with the room, do they? Send someone up here to clean this place up right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm calling another room, give me three numbers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHACK! The needle lands an inch from her face in the 20-point slot.</context>
      <utterance>The center is the bull's eye, 100 points, this one's 10 points, this one's 20 points.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah, a little tipsy now, grabs the needle and staggers to the bed. She hears the key in the doorway and throws the needle into the curtain to hide it. Ted enters the room, somewhat disheveled from his encounter with Sigfried. He has a tray and a new bottle of champagne. He puts the champagne bottle into the empty bucket. He spots the original bottle lying on the floor half empty and dripping into the carpet.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, wait a minute. Let me get out of the way!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brought you some milk and cookies. If you want some you have to eat them now, because you're going to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to sleep now?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your parents said put you to bed before midnight. Well, it's before midnight. Maybe that way you'll leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those aren't milk and cookies.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juancho bites into a Saltine. Sarah simply examines one.</context>
      <utterance>We were out of cookies, so I brought you milk and Saltines. Don't complain! Now hurry up and eat. You're going to bed right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are old.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're stale.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go to the bathroom. Ted sits on the bed. Waits. He sees the painting on the wall but can't figure out what's different about it. The red lipstick blends right into the aesthetic value of the painting. Ted smells something funny. He looks down and sees the socks on the bed. He grabs a fork from the tray and uses it to throw the socks across the room. The kids come back out.</context>
      <utterance>No crackers? Okay, fine. Sleepy time. Now, I don't want you guys wandering around, so if you need to go to the restroom, go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about our pajamas?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children nod.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna look nice in case there's an earthquake, don'tcha?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah notices a jar of Mentholatum ointment on the dinner tray.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Then stay in those clothes. The kids lie on the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children close their eyes. Ted opens the jar of the ointment and sniffs it. Strong stuff by the look on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is just some Mentholatum ointment. Come on, under the covers. Close your eyes and I'll tell you a story.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children lie in the bed, eyes closed, listening intently. Ted dips his fingers in the jar of vaporous ointment.</context>
      <utterance>Your dad says he doesn't trust babysitters. I don't blame him. You know what my babysitter did to me once?  I never told my parents, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes closed, the kids inhale. They smell the ointment and nod yes.</context>
      <utterance>I hated going to sleep. You know, it's nighttime and you wanna run around and act crazy. So what my babysitter did to make sure I'd go to sleep and not be tempted to get up, was, she'd take some of this vapor rub stuff... Can you smell this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted is spreading the ointment over their eyelids as he says this.</context>
      <utterance>Well, she'd just dab a little of this over each eyelid, so that I would be sure and keep my eyes closed all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There. Now you've got some, too! Don't open your eyes or it'll burrrn, burn, burn. The smell helps clear your sinuses too, so it's doing double duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens when it's morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you keep your eyes closed all night, it will wear off by morning. But DON'T OPEN YOUR EYES BEFORE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Extreme CLOSE-UP on Ted's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Did you ever open your eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children are quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now look at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Good. You'll do just fine. Sleep well and I won't tell your parents about the champagne.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The champagne bottle explodes. She pours herself a glass.</context>
      <utterance>Are you watching TV?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juancho gets up smiling and tries to run to the bathroom. He slams into the wall, hard.</context>
      <utterance>Yep. If you wanna watch too, you have to go wash your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juancho walks into the bathroom a little slower, more cautious. Sarah pours herself another glass. She downs the glass and shudders. She smells the bad smell again. Only now she really smells it. She smells her feet. Nothing. She smells the champagne. Nothing. Juancho enters the room and sits on the bed. Sarah grabs his foot and smells it. She drops his foot. Juancho stares blankly at her. Sarah looks down at the mattress. She smells the mattress. Juancho looks at her as if she's drunk. Sarah leaps off the bed and turns on the room lights. She takes a huge swig from the champagne bottle, then stalks toward the mattress. Juancho leaps off the bed as well and stands back. Sarah pulls the mattress off of the bedsprings enough to see what is underneath it. Juancho screams. Sarah is too stunned to scream. Stuffed into the bedsprings is a woman's dead and beaten corpse.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want now, for Christ's sake! Who died?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but she's in my bed!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a dead body in my bed!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just your brother. Sound asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, there's a woman's dead body inside the bed, in the mattress.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saw the body?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted answers.</context>
      <utterance>Impossible. You've got ointment on your eyes! You can't see shit! Now go to sleep! Ted hangs up the phone. Sarah redials.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Godammit, go to sleep!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I washed it off...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You washed off the ointment?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never tried it, did you? Then you agree I'm smarter than you...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Now you listen to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drinks from her champagne bottle. She's pulling the mattress back over the corpse again.</context>
      <utterance>Get your ass up here and call the police, because there's a dead body in my bed and it smells like shit and it looks even worse, and if you don't help us, my dad is gonna lay you down right next to her, I swear to fucking God!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's drunk all right.</context>
      <utterance>Go, sis.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm coming up and if there isn't a dead body by the time I get there, I'll make one myself. You!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRONT DESK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he walks away from the counter, he spots the children's parents driving up to the valet out front.</context>
      <utterance>Ted slams down the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted breaks into a sprint and dives into a closing elevator.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ROOM 716</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted pushes the champagne out of Sarah's hand, spilling it onto the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Ted bursts into the room. He sees the disarray.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees Juancho with the cigarette hanging out of his mouth and rips it away from him. The butt goes flying onto the carpet near the spreading champagne spill.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is going on??!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your parents are on their way up and I'm not taking responsibility for this mess!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check under the mattress!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the body, can't you smell it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah grabs the mattress and pulls it off herself. Ted sees the rotting corpse. Vomit spews out of Ted's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>It's your feet!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tears at the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus fucking Christ! What the fuck is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears well in Sarah's eyes as she looks at the body.</context>
      <utterance>Police, it's an emergency!  Hello, Police, this is the Mon Signor Hotel, get someone up here right fucking now, there's a DEAD WHORE stuffed under the mattress!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't call her that...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm dead fucking serious, there's a dead fucking Whore stuffed in the bedsprings of the fucking bed!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah grabs the hypodermic needle from under the curtain and stabs it into Ted's leg.</context>
      <utterance>Stop calling her that!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="74">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me speak to Betty.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUINNESS GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Party's over, she probably went home.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She lives there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUINNESS GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well, I haven't seen 'em in a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you even know who I'm talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUINNESS GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... yeah... yeah... I know 'em, I know Eddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betty, not Eddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUINNESS GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... yeah... I know Betty too... Tall...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not particularly. She's got curly red hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUINNESS GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no, no, no, I know, I know. Japanese girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not Japanese! I just said she had red hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUINNESS GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... yeah... yeah... I know her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then get her on the phone, it's an emergency.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUINNESS GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who -- who should I say's calling?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell 'em Teddy from work's on the phone, and it's a major fuckin' emergency.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUINNESS GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotcha, Betty from work.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not Betty from work, I'm calling Betty! I'm Teddy. Just say Ted.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUINNESS GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Ted, I'm Margaret. You sound down. Has this not been the happiest of New Year's?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Margaret, this hasn't been my best New Year. This year's starting off pretty badly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awww, how come?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Betty -- the chick whose house you're at, even though you don't know her -- leaves me here all by myself on New Year's Eve. And first thing right off the bat, I'm fucked by a coven of witches.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An oven full of witches fucked you? Is that like at the circus when they stick all those clowns in an itty- bitty car?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A coven. A coven of witches. Well, one witch in particular.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was she an old hag with a mole, with hair growing out of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margaret thinks for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>No-no-no, she was... quite beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, admittedly, that was the best part of the night. It was pretty fuckin' cool, actually. But it was still an unnerving way to start off the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds to me like a pretty great way to start off the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's just skip over the witches.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Skipping over the witches.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, later, in another room, some crazy sucking maniac sticks a gun in my face and forces me to play out some psychosexual drama with his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He made you have psycho sex with his wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he didn't make me fuck his wife, he thought I'd fucked his wife! He held me at gunpoint with a loaded gun!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kinda gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I'm not a gun guy. It was big.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like Dirty Harry's gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did it have a real long barrel or a short barrel?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What difference does it make?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, for one thing it's the difference between a .44 Magnum and a Magnum .357.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margaret takes this in.</context>
      <utterance>Who cares if it was a .44 or a .392, it was a fuckin' loaded gun, pointed at my fuckin' head!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna skip over this part, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to get Betty on the phone!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on.  Anybody live here named...  What's her name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sleepy room stirs. Betty wakes up from the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Betty!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, whatcha screamin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Betty?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm Betty, it's my fuckin' place, who the fuck are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty takes the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Margaret  And this is Ted.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted, what's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem? I don't got a problem, I got fuckin' problems! Wanna hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A RINGING SOUND happens that we haven't heard before. Ted's head turns toward it. It's the guest board. And the top light, the penthouse, is ringing. It rings where all the others buzzed. Betty can hear it distinctly on her side of the line. The sound fully wakes her up. They start talking Howard Hawks style again.</context>
      <utterance>Well, most recently, there's room 716. There's a scary Mexican gangster dude pokin' his finger in my chest. There's his hooligan kids snapping their fingers at me. There's the putrid rotting corpse of a dead whore stuffed in the springs of a bed. There're rooms blazing afire... There's a needle from God knows where stuck in my leg, infecting me with God knows what, and finally, there's me walking out the fuckin' door right now! Buenas noches.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the penthouse?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the Chester Rush party, they want something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, tough titty. They're just gonna have to wait, 'cause I'm out the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Ted, wait a minute. I know you're freaked, I know you're stressed. You've had a real bad night --</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Betty, I've had-a-real-bad-night --</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- You say there's a dead body in a room?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem, this is a hotel, we've had dead bodies before, it's just the price of doing business. You said the hotel was on fire. Is it still on fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, sprinkler system worked like a charm. Now, you wanna leave, you've had enough. Perfectly understandable. I'll take care of everything else. The only thing I ask is that you take care of Chester Rush. Then you can leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, look --</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted, he's a very important guest of this hotel. In fact, he is the most important guest at the hotel. The Mon Signor used to be a haven for movie stars. Through the thirties and forties, and the first half of the fifties, more movie stars -- if you break it down on a night-by-night basis -- stayed at the Mon Signor than any other hotel in Hollywood. Now, we had some hard time in the eighties, even though we were the official hotel of Cannon Pictures, but we're coming back strong in the nineties. And a movie star clientele is important to that comeback. If we can keep stars of his magnitude happy, we're on our way. So, Ted, just take care of him, then you can leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't feel like --</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted crumbles.</context>
      <utterance>He probably just wants some champagne! You can do that, can't you? Please just take care of him, the entire staff of the Mon Signor is begging you!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. But get your ass here pronto.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted hangs up the phone. And picks up the board phone.</context>
      <utterance>You're a good man, Ted. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Rush. Sorry for the delay. How can I help you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Theodore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up the drink she has in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Having a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that crazy husband of yours in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From behind her we hear:</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding, he'll be asleep till Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Angela steps aside and Ted wheels in the tray.</context>
      <utterance>Entrez, entrez.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="150">
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Entrez, entrez, come in, come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, sorry I took so long, but I got everything you asked for --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Not a problem, my friend Mr. Bellboy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name's Theodore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester rises from the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, it's not Theodore,  It's Ted.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Ted the Bellboy, as I was saying -- would you care for some champagne? That's not what I was saying, but would you care for some champagne?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya sure? Cristal. It's the best. I never liked champagne before I had Cristal, now I love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Chester goes and pours Ted a glass:</context>
      <utterance>Okay, yeah, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On "thoroughness," he hands Ted the glass.</context>
      <utterance>-- As I was saying, Ted, don't worry about being late. For our purposes, promptness is far behind thoroughness.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They clink glasses and drink.</context>
      <utterance>Chin-chin.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whadya say, Ted?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not thank you. Whadya say about the tasty beverage?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' good, Ted. It's fuckin' good. Let's try it again, shall we? So, Ted, whadya think about the beverage.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fuckin' good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norman in the chair starts yelling at Ted.</context>
      <utterance>You bet your sweet bippy, Ted. It's fuckin' Cristal, everything else is piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bellboy! Bellboy! Bellboy! Ted knows he's being laughed at, but not why.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knock it off, you're making my friend Ted here uneasy.  Pay no attention to Norman here, Ted, he's just fuckin' wit' ya, that's all. That's from Quadrophenia. Now me, myself, when I think of bellboys I think of -- "bellboy" isn't an insult, is it? Is there another name for what you do that I'm ignorant of? Bellman, bellperson --</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bellboy's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But me, when I think of bellboys, I think of The Bellboy, with Jerry Lewis. Didja ever see The Bellboy?</context>
      <utterance>Good. I'm glad they haven't changed that. There's a friendliness to "bellboy." As I was saying, Ted, when Norman thinks of bellboys, he thinks of Quadrophenia.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should, it's one of Jerry's better movies. He never says a word through the entire film. A completely silent performance. How many actors can pull that off? And he has to go to France to get respect. That says it all about America right there. The minute Jerry Lewis dies, every paper in this fuckin' country gonna write articles calling the man a genius. It's not right. It's not right and it's not fair. But why should that surprise anybody? When has America ever been fair? We might be right every once in a while, but we're very rarely fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you want this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You in a hurry, Ted?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not particularly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his arm around Ted and leads him around the room. Angela crosses frame, drink in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Good, then stop playing "Beat the Clock." Now let me introduce you to everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she snuggles up in a big comfy chair:</context>
      <utterance>Our friend from downstairs you already seem to be acquainted with.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, me and Theodore go way back. Don't we, Theodore?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name's Ted, Angela. I only let people with loaded guns at my head call me Theodore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angela's like you, Ted, a newfound friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We met at the pool.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever seen Angela in a one- piece?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's somethin' to see.  The Man sitting in the chair, with the bottle of Jim Bean in his hand and the sense of humor, is Norman. Norman, say hello to Ted.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norman shakes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo breaks away from his phone conversation for two seconds.</context>
      <utterance>The sociable son of a bitch on the telephone is Leo. And the person on the other end of the phone is his lovely wife Ellen.  Leo, say hello to Ted.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Ted, glad you could make it.  What?  What does punctuality have to do with love?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester shakes Ted's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Which brings me to me, Chester Rush, Ted. Pleased to meetcha.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester walks over to the table and pours himself some more champagne. When he talks now it's slower and somewhat distracted. The tone of the scene starts changing.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I'm sorry I haven't seen your movie. Chester stops. Ted wonders if he should have said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester takes a drink of champagne, a disgusted look crosses his face, and he slowly puts it down. His manner gives the room a chill. When he talks, he addresses the room.</context>
      <utterance>It's quite all right, Ted, nothing to feel sorry about. That's why God invented video. But you know, Ted, a lot of people did see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester walks over to Ted and fills his glass.</context>
      <utterance>Who drank out of this bottle last? No answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who drank out of this bottle -- not the other bottles -- this bottle last?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spills the champagne from his glass onto the floor.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong, Chester?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester improvises a temper tantrum about the flat Cristal. Everyone looks at him, not knowing what to say. Even Leo walks over to witness. The whole room is uneasy and a little frightened. When Chester finishes his tantrum, he turns his attention back to Ted. As he talks to him, he opens up another bottle. But it's not the rapid-pace delivery Chester has done so far. It's more troubled and distracted.</context>
      <utterance>It's fuckin' flat, Norman, that's what's wrong. The champagne -- the fuckin' Cristal's fuckin' flat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo is still in the doorway making sure his boy's cool.</context>
      <utterance>I was saying, Ted, a lot of people did see it. And not just on video, either. Leo, what was the final take on domestic?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>72.1 million.  You okay, champ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo turns his attention back to the phone and goes inside the room.</context>
      <utterance>I'm cool, so talk to your wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester walks over to Ted and fills his glass.</context>
      <utterance>72.1 million dollars. That's before video and before foreign, and before pay-TV and before free TV. We're talking fuckin' asses in fuckin' seats.  Before all that other shit, The Wacky Detective made 72.1 million dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And my new one, The Dog Catcher, it's projected to break a hundred.  The Dog Catcher.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tantrum's over, and Chester's back to his fast-talking, good-natured self.</context>
      <utterance>The Dog Catcher. They both drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now let's stroll over here and see what goodies you brought us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mind me asking what's all this stuff for?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One thing at a time, Ted. I'm not a frog and you're not a bunny, so let's not jump ahead. C'mon, Norman, you should be interested in this.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted produces the things they called for.</context>
      <utterance>Damn Skippy!  Tell it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester knocks on it.</context>
      <utterance>A block of wood.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three nails.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why three nails?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted is completely bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>That's how many Peter Lorre asked for. Continue, Ted.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A roll of twine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's definitely a roll of twine. Continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bucket of ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You into it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester takes it and eats it.</context>
      <utterance>A donut.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's for me. Continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And a hatchet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hatchet as sharp as the devil himself is what I asked for.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted holds the hatchet out for Chester to take. Norman snatches it instead.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you be the judge.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norman touches the end of the blade with his thumb.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be the judge.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whadya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a sharp motherfucker. Bring all this bullshit over to the bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted is completely confused and starting to get a little scared, but he does what he's told. Leo slams down the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You heard him, Ted.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still married?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe, maybe not, but I don't give a flyin' fuck either way. I've had it with that Machiavellian bitch! I'm too drunk to drive home. I'm sorry about that, I'm real sorry about that. I got drunk on New Year's Eve, cut my fuckin' head off...  What's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We now return you to The Man from Rio, already in progress.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noooo, you're gonna do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela is still curled up.</context>
      <utterance>You guys ain't bullshittin', you're gonna really go for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After talkin' about it all night, they better. I wanna see a show.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo walks up to Norman and throws his arm around him.</context>
      <utterance>When we do it, you'll have something to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted doesn't know what anybody's talking about, which is just fine with him. He finishes laying out everything on the bar and says:</context>
      <utterance>You are one radical dude.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's everything, so if you don't need me for anything else, I'll go back downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so fast, Ted. We ain't quite done yet. Why don't you take a seat at the bar, get comfortable, and have an open mind when we explain the festivities of the evening to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, guys, you paid for the room. As long as you don't break up the furniture, you can do whatever the fuck you want. And me personally, I don't care if you break up the furniture. You don't have to explain anything to me. Whatever constitutes a good time as far as you guys are concerned is your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's your business, Ted. 'Cause we want you to take part.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take part in what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chester, your way of breaking the news to him gently is scarin' the shit outta him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little by little everybody has gathered around Ted.</context>
      <utterance>Look at the poor guy. Just spit it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First off, let me say that there's nothing homosexual about what we're going to ask you to do. There's nothing sexual at all about what we want. But I was thinkin' you might be thinkin' we want you to do some sex thing. Pee on us, suck us off, shit like that. Let me assure you nothing could be farther from what we want -- Angela interrupts:</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I jump in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you can't jump in here, this is my story.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Theodore's been here fifteen minutes and you've talked about everything but.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo taps his champagne glass with a tiny spoon, shutting everybody up.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, if you don't like it, you can get the fuck out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it'll please the court, let me explain to Ted our intentions.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I second the nomination!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo, the floor is yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.  Ted, did you ever watch the old "Alfred Hitchcock Show"?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever see the episode The Man from Rio, with Peter Lorre and Steve McQueen?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted looks at all of them, taking in the information, before saying:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you'd remember it all right. In the show, Peter Lorre makes a bet that Steve McQueen can't light his cigarette lighter ten times in a row. Now if Steve McQueen can light his cigarette lighter ten times in a row, he wins Peter Lorre's new car. If he can't he loses his little finger.  Norman and Chester just made the same bet.  Norman's putting up his pinky against Chester's mint convertible, 1964 red convertible Chevy Corvelle that he can light his Zippo ten times in a row. Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that goes without saying, but that doesn't mean we don't know what we're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norman lays an issue of Hot Classic Cars in front of Ted on the bar. On the cover is a picture of Chester smiling, standing next to a beautiful 1964 red convertible Chevy Corvelle. The headline reads: "Hollywood's Hottest New Star Next to America's Hottest Old Car."</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell ya what I'm doin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I drive a motherfuckin' Honda my sister sold me. You hear what I'm sayin'? A little white motherfuckin' Honda Civic.  You see this shit?!  "Hollywood's hottest new star, next to America's hottest old car."  Now you take a good look at that machine that this motherfucker over here is standing next to. That's a 1964 nigger-red, rag-top Chevy Corvelle. And I love that car more'n I love hips, lips, and fingertips. Cut to we sittin' here celebrating, gettin' high, drinkin' champagne --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Cristal. When you're drinkin' anything else, you're drinking champagne. When you're drinkin' Cristal, you say you're drinkin' Cristal.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- drinkin' Cristal. Watchin' TV. "Rockin' New Year's Eve." When all of a sudden we flip on Steve McQueen and Peter Lorre bein' fuckin' badass. And I look at this funny motherfucker over here, and I say, "I'd do that for the Chevelle."</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Chester replies...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"...Oh, really?"</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody breaks into a "here, here" murmur.</context>
      <utterance>You guys wouldn't be doin' something this stupid unless you were drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that pretty much goes without sayin'. We'd probably chicken out. But when you're fucked-up, you don't lie. You tell the fuckin' truth. And the fuckin' truth is, my lucky Zippo's gonna win me Chester's car.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thrill of the bet. I'm the one with something to lose here. 'Cause I can pretty near guarantee that I love my car more'n Norman loves his pinky.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout you guys, you're just gonna sit back and let your friends mutilate each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? Life don't get much more exciting than this. I mean if Norman was puttin' his dick on the choppin' block, I'd step in, 'cause, ya know in the morning, we'd really regret that. But his pinky? Who gives a fuck? I mean theoretically, he could lose that choppin' onions tomorrow. Life still goes on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which brings us to your part in this little wager.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a part.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Ted, my old granddaddy used ta say: "The less a man makes declarative statements, the less he's apt to look foolish in retrospect." Now there're some inherent obstacles in this undertaking. First of all, I'm not some sick fuck like Peter Lorre on that show, travelin' the countryside collecting fingers. We're all buddies, here. Nobody wants Norman to lose his finger. We just wanna chop it off. So if fate doesn't smile on ol' Norman, we'll put his finger on ice and rush 'im to a hospital, where in all likelihood be able to sew it back on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hopefully.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighty percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our side.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause as they all look at him. Angela breaks it.</context>
      <utterance>So Norman's protected. His interests have been looked after. My interests, on the other hand, have not. I am as emotionally attached to my car as Norman is physically to his finger. I'm putting up a very expensive piece of machinery on this wager. Now, if I lose, I lose, I have no problem with that. I'm a big boy, I knew what I was doing. However, if I win, I wanna win. If Norman lights his lighter ten times in a row, he's gonna have no emotional problems about taking my car keys whatsoever. But if I win, it's not inconceivable that Leo or myself, at the last minute, might not be able to wield the ax. Which brings us full circle to you, Ted. Sober Ted. Clear-eyed Ted. We want you to be the diceman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helluva night, huh, Ted?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted abruptly gets up and makes a beeline for the door. Chester whips out a hundred-dollar bill and quickly calls to Ted from his position at the bar.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted spins in his direction.</context>
      <utterance>Ted, I got a hundred-dollar bill here with your name on it, whether you do what we ask or not, just to sit back down in the chair for one minute more.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna cut off his finger!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted just stands across the room, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you will and maybe you won't, but that has nothing to do with this hundred-dollar bill in my hand. You can tell us all to go fuck off and walk right out that door. But if you sit back down and wait sixty seconds before you do it, you'll be a hundred dollars richer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted. Take the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted thinks.</context>
      <utterance>Ted, you're gonna do whatever you want to do. We're just askin' you to indulge us for another minute more. And Chester's willin' to pay for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take your money, and I'll sit back down. But a minute from now, I'm gonna walk out the door, and when I do, there'll be no hard feelings?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester positions himself in front of Ted at the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I want you to have a bit more of an open mind than that, but, yeah, we'll either convince you or we won't. No hard feelings. Right, guys? Everybody agrees. Ted wearily sits back down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Leo, you be the timekeeper. Let us know when one minute begins and when it ends.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester jumps up and down, loosening up.</context>
      <utterance>You got it.  Gentlemen, start your engines.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester, who talks fast anyway, starts his pitch. It's Chester who now plays "Beat the Clock."</context>
      <utterance>Begin!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, pay attention here, Ted, I ain't got much time. Now I'm gonna make two piles here on the bar.  One pile,  which is yours. And another pile,  which could be yours.  Now, what you have to be aware of is we're gonna do this bet, one way,  or the other.  Whether it's you who holds the ax,  or the desk clerk downstairs,  or some bum we yank off the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can buy a lot of soup with that pile.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhhh, I'm the closer.  How much is on the bar already? I lost count.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six hundred. Ted, do you know how long it takes the average American to count to six hundred?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One minute less than it takes to count to seven hundred. You know, Ted, a person's life is made up of a zillion little experiences.  Some, which have no meaning, are insignificant and you forget them. And some that stick with you for the rest of your natural life --  -- barring Alzheimer's of course. Now, what we're proposing is so unusual, so outside the norm, that I think it would be a pretty good guess that this will be one of those experiences that sticks. So, since you're gonna be stuck remembering this moment for the rest of your life, you gotta decide what that memory will be.  So, are you gonna remember for the next forty years, give or take a decade, how you refused a thousand dollars for one second's worth of work, or how you made a thousand dollars for one second's worth of work?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted looks at the pile, then looks up. We dolly into his face.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Ted, what's it gonna be?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group cheers.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But when it's over, no matter what happens, I get the money?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as you do your part, you can take the pile, walk out the door, and not say another word.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do it right now, before I change my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody gets in their position by the bar. Norman lays his left hand on the block of wood with his pinky sticking out. In his right hand is his Zippo lighter, poised and ready to strike. Chester hands Ted the meat cleaver. Ted takes it, raises it up above Norman's finger, in position.</context>
      <utterance>Here, here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody is crowded around the scene, on pins and needles.</context>
      <utterance>Perfect, perfect, perfect, perfect! This is great! This is a moment in time none of us will ever forget.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norman, you ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted, you ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norman looks hard at the Zippo in his hand. Ted, holding the cleaver, stares focused on Norman's pinky. Norman readies himself. Places his thumb on the wheel in the Zippo. Takes a breath. And strikes. It sparks, but doesn't light. Without missing a beat, Ted brings down the cleaver, slicing off Norman's pinky. Norman lets out a scream. Ted, in one move, lays down the cleaver, scoops up the money and walks out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Okeydoke. Norman, begin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chester has the bucket of ice with the finger in it. Leo's trying to direct everything. Everybody's in frantic activity, except for Angela, who stands back, drinks her drink, and watches the show. They all run down the hall, toward the elevator. Somebody trips and they all hit the ground. The bucket of ice with the finger goes spilling. They run around like crazy, looking for the finger and picking up ice cubes. Norman lies on the floor and screams. They pick it all up, get to the elevator, and push the button. When it arrives, they all dive in except for Angela.</context>
      <utterance>My finger, my fucking finger!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angela walks through a door marked "Stairway."</context>
      <utterance>You know, I'm gonna call it a night and go back to my room. It's been fun. The doors close on the screaming maniacs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bombshell looks up at her dizzily.</context>
      <utterance>You okay, lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said -- you looking for someone?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Diana quietly says, "Ohhh," as she drifts on down the hall in a daze. Angela puts her hand to her temples before opening her hotel door. She does a double-take on the hallway -- empty. She pauses a beat, then walks into her room. After the door closes, we hear Sigfried on the other side.</context>
      <utterance>Lady, I haven't seen anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGFRIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell have you been?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
