<movie id="216" title="Frances">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PROLOGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BLACK. We HEAR the soft voice of Frances Farmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one ever came up to me and said, 'You're a fool. There isn't such a thing as God. Somebody's been stuffing you.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The girl, FRANCES, is 16, blond, very pretty: she seems like the most persuasive proof imaginable of God's existence. She swims toward the shore with long graceful strokes... then climbs the steps of the old wood jetty on West Point Beach.</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't a murder. I think God just died of old age. And when I realized He wasn't any more, it didn't shock me. It seemed natural and right.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And yet I began to wonder what the minister meant when he said, 'God, the Father, sees even the smallest sparrow fall. He watches over all his children.' That jumbled it all up for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ERNEST FARMER appears in the doorway and hesitates, listening to his daughter read.</context>
      <utterance>It usually worked. God became a superfather that couldn't spank me. But if I wanted a thing badly enough, He arranged it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernest goes to Frances and kisses her softly on the top of her head. She looks at him briefly, smiling slightly.</context>
      <utterance>But if God loved all of His children equally, why did He bother about my red hat and let other people lose their fathers and mothers for always?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the door and picks up his suitcase, glances at Lillian. She doesn't look up. He leaves.</context>
      <utterance>See you next weekend, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I began to see that He didn't have much to do about hats or people dying or anything. They happened whether He wanted them to or not, and He stayed in Heaven and pretended not to notice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The AUDIENCE consists of parents, students, and local dignitaries. We SEE several shocked faces. Lillian is there also, smiling. Seated next to her is a distinguished-looking woman, ALMA STYLES. Ernest sits on the other side of the auditorium, looking a little worried.</context>
      <utterance>I wondered a little why God was such a useless thing. It seemed a waste of time to have Him. After that He became less and less, until He was... nothingness.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances closes her notebook and looks up, waiting for some response. There is a deep shocked silence, then a smattering of applause. Lillian claps enthusiastically, then rises to her feet. In the back a WOMAN also stands.</context>
      <utterance>I felt rather proud that I had found the truth myself, without help from anyone. It puzzled me that other people hadn't found out, too. God was gone. We had reached past Him. Why couldn't they see it? It still puzzles me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stately man sitting next to her, her husband JUDGE BENJAMIN HILLIER, puts a restraining hand on her arm. The woman continues to glare at Frances. Frances stares back, dumbfounded.</context>
      <utterance>You're going straight to hell, Frances Farmer!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KAMINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do you think it's radical for a man to have a job and feed a family?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORK &amp; CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAMINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it radical for you to have a hand in shaping your future, and the future of your children?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORK &amp; CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAMINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it radical for the wealth of this country to be turned back to the people who built the country?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORK &amp; CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAMINSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd cheers. Harry York gives Kaminski the thumbs-up sign as a banner unfurls: "Today Seattle -- Tomorrow the World."</context>
      <utterance>Good! Because, Brothers, that's you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>City Hall steps. Judge Hillier and other BIGWIGS speaking heatedly to reporters.</context>
      <utterance>Seattle is in the news again as a high school junior wins a national competition and a hundred dollar prize with an essay denying God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lillian stands in front of her wood frame house addressing a small CROWD of reporters, photographers, and curious neighbors.</context>
      <utterance>This prompts civic officials to charge that left-wing politicians are encouraging atheism in the city's schools. Miss Frances Farmer was unavailable for comment, but her mother Lillian --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Farmer, a well-known local dietician, stepped to her daughter's defense.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances has not turned her back on the Lord, they're just having a momentary difference of opinion. What child hasn't questioned the Lord's mysteries in order to better understand them? To paraphrase Mr. Voltaire, I may not agree with what she says, but I'll defend to the death her right to say it. Freedom of speech, unlike in the dark countries to the east, still lives in America! And in my home. Among the AUDIENCE in the cinema, we SEE Frances and her father. Frances slinks down in her seat until she's hidden from sight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Emma. Emma looks away quickly, returns to her play.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances shakes her head as she walks on.</context>
      <utterance>Bye Emma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances hesitates, then turns to look: A man in his twenties whom we recognize as Harry York, Kaminski's compatriot, leaves a group of men in front of the union hall and walks toward her.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances keeps walking. Harry hurries after her.</context>
      <utterance>C'mere. I wanna talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Momma told ya not to speak to strangers, huh?  Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him. He's got a newspaper wedged under one arm.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna hurt you. I just wanna talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay then...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... you're causin' trouble, you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm causing trouble?! You're a pain in the butt! You newshounds've been after me and my folks ever since I won that dumb contest. I'm just sixteen, you know? Who the hell cares what I think?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me. But other people seem to.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Well if you didn't put it in the papers -- nobody'd even know about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now wait a minute, sweetie. Do I look like a newshound to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry laughs.</context>
      <utterance>No... Actually, you look more like a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances hesitates, leans toward him as though about to frisk him. Their eyes meet, and she pulls away, suddenly embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>That's rich. Hey, if I was a cop, I'd be packing, right?  You see a gun? Go on, search me. Pat me down.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll... take your word for it. So who are you, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry York. I work for Martoni Kaminski, he's running for Congress here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah! I saw you in the newsreel!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, my Dad's done some work for Kaminski...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're catchin' on. Don't wanna get your Daddy in hot water, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whattaya mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... see the papers've got us pegged as pinkos, then you come along, the friendly neighborhood atheist --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm not. The newspapers're --</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right again. You're no more an atheist than my man's a Red, but what they're doin', see, they're addin' up their version of your ideas with their version of ours. Could look bad for your Daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Could look bad for you and Kaminski too, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure don't talk like you're sixteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well aren't you the smoothie. Now you're going to ask for my number, I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose not. Gotta ask you this, though: for all our sakes, you better keep your trap shut.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I'll give it a try, Mr. York.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They half-smile, awkwardly, as if neither really wants this encounter to end. Then Harry doffs his hat.</context>
      <utterance>Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods shyly and starts up the path toward the house.</context>
      <utterance>Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure don't walk like sixteen, neither.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HILLIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are perilous times. With the economic collapse comes hopelessness and desperation; and people turn to dangerous ideas --</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA PULLS SLOWLY BACK. We SEE that the courtroom is empty.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HILLIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now we SEE who he's talking to: Alma Styles, the woman who sat with Lillian at the school auditorium.</context>
      <utterance>Those of us who represent law and order must be vigilant. Who's behind this, her mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>STYLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impossible. As her attorney, I've known her for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>HILLIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the father, he's a little pink. Maybe he wants to show our schools in a bad light, shift some support to Kaminski and those jackals.</utterance>
   <speaker>STYLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's no influence; he doesn't even live at home. No, I think Frances wrote that essay with no mischief intended. It was her teacher who entered it in the competition.</utterance>
   <speaker>HILLIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the publicity must stop. It's no good for Seattle and no good for the country.  Keep an eye on this, will you, Alma?</utterance>
   <speaker>STYLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods with satisfaction. Two right-thinking people fighting for what they believe in.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, your honor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It always amazes me, Lil, how you can whip up a hot, hearty meal out of thin air.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves the bread so Ernest again faces the check. As Lillian slices the bread, father and daughter eat grimly.</context>
      <utterance>I can thank you for that. It was a hard-earned talent.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bread?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's the last time you saw a hundred dollars, Ernest Farmer?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not hungry. You two just enjoy yourselves. After all, this is a celebration. She leaves. A long silence. They both glance slightly awkwardly at the check. Frances takes it, folds it, and puts it in her pocket, out of sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm... I'm really proud of you, Frances.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An essay contest... a national contest. That's pretty impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't have much to do with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wrote it, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I suppose... Dad, who's Harry York?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Harry York is a guy who... well, he does a lot of things. Why do you ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He talked to me today. Told me to keep my mouth shut or I'd get everybody in trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... well... it's possible. Harry York and I both work for Mr. Kaminski right now, and... well... There are lots of folks in this country who never got a square break. That's the way of things, but Mr. Kaminski wants to change it, and when it comes to new ideas, the people in power get nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Kaminski a Communist?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no. All he wants to do is see the common man get a little representation.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a socialist, then?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lillian's face becomes set. She looks down at the book. An article titled "Girl Denies God" is there, freshly pasted. She lays a hand on the blank page opposite.</context>
      <utterance>The label's not important, Francie. What's important is: this country's got nine million unemployed and something's gotta be done about it. Besides: left-wing, right-wing, up- wing, down-wing... they don't mean much. All a label is usually is a way to call somebody a dirty name.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's already started, Dad... with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I can't understand how it can hurt to be honest, but the more I tried to explain --  Lillian appears in the doorway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't listen to him, little sister. When you're proud of what you are, you don't refuse the label, understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stomps out. Frances and Ernest push back their plates.</context>
      <utterance>And you... should be proud. You won that contest and made a name for yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're poisoning that child's mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a right to talk to her. She's my daughter, and she's beginning to understand why I've sacrificed so much in order to achieve...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've sacrificed?! If you'd practice law for decent folk instead of Communists and indigents --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They need help, Lil. They pay me back in other ways.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How? What do they do for you, Kaminski and his friends? They're all anarchists! Traitors!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Lil. It's just you can't understand their brand of patriotism.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. I can't understand a man who puts strangers over his family, a man who gives up a good career to become a shiftless inkhorn failure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going back to the hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you next weekend?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernest starts back toward the house. He sees Frances watching them and slows down, turns...</context>
      <utterance>As usual. Everything as usual, Mr. Farmer. Just give me my due.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lillian... I'm more than willing to meet you halfway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make me sick. I'd sooner drown myself in Puget Sound.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WOMAN'S VOICE comes from behind the fence.</context>
      <utterance>That's a thought, Lil. That sure is a thought. He trudges back toward the house under Frances' eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you all right, dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine, perfectly fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, please, don't leave early. Just because of Mama --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances watches him, shaking her head. That is not a lesson she wants to learn.</context>
      <utterance>Francie, you'll learn that sometimes it's best to stay low and just walk away. He trudges out and down the walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances is acting with a nervous young man, CHET. As her speech progresses, the camera moves in nearer and nearer, ending with a close-up. It is as if we are being drawn in by her emotion.</context>
      <utterance>What can we do, we must live! We shall live, Uncle Vanya...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the curtain opens and the players take their bows, we SEE in the audience: Lillian and Ernest, Lillian clapping madly, crying, nudging Ernest to clap harder. And in the back stands Harry York.</context>
      <utterance>And then we shall rest, we shall rest. We shall hear the angels, we shall see the whole sky all diamonds, we shall see how all earthly evil, all our sufferings, are drowned in the mercy that will fill the whole world. And our life will grow peaceful, tender, sweet as a caress...  Poor, dear Uncle Vanya, you are crying...  In your life you haven't known what joy was; but wait, Uncle Vanya, wait... We shall rest...  We shall rest! Curtains close. AUDIENCE bursts into applause.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad, Farmer. Not half bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DRAMA TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Art is a constant struggle. Some of you have the will but not the ability. For others, the opposite. I don't wish to be harsh, but only one of you on stage tonight combined the two... The front door opens. Frances and Chet enter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAMA TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young men rush over to congratulate her. Frances takes a mock bow. She laughs as people cheer. TWO GIRLS observe from the back.</context>
      <utterance>On cue.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could really learn to hate her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand in line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DRAMA TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the answer: a subscription drive to "Voice of Action!" First prize is a trip to Moscow! You could visit the art theatre, maybe even meet Stanislavski!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'll never win that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAMA TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, it's all arranged. Everyone's collecting subscriptions in your name. And the best part is: the trip returns you to New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAMA TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New York, Frances! Broadway! This is your chance! You belong on the stage!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A door opens quietly and Harry slips in. He smiles at Frances, who disentangles herself from her teacher and rushes over.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Harry. Did you see the play?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'd miss it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well? What'd you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to see how you looked.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be a rat, Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates, looks around and sees Chet passed out, snoring in a chair. She takes Harry's arm.</context>
      <utterance>You looked okay.  Joint's pretty dead. How 'bout I take you home?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honest. When you were up there, you were really... there, know what I mean? Everyone else looked stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I did... feel different... Alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's a gift. You gotta do something with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but if I win this trip, Mama'll kill me. She hates Russians. I do want to go, though... to New York, especially... but I wanted to do it...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quietly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are silent for a while.</context>
      <utterance>You're not the quiet type, Frances.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, my old man was an inventor. Spent his whole life down in the basement trying to design transcontinental underground railroads, stuff like that. Well, I was supposed to be his partner. When I told him the smell of his workshop made me sick, I thought he was going to die right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins ironically and Frances laughs.</context>
      <utterance>He retired to Florida... made a killing in vending machines.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kick myself sometimes, but the thing is, I would have been miserable living his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...So you think I should go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Try this acting thing. You can make good money at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Harry. I... I want so many...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know what you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, smiles wistfully.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to unbutton her blouse. Harry is pleasantly surprised, but unnerved.</context>
      <utterance>Not in the long run, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... don't you think it's up to me to...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry can't believe his good fortune.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Harry. This is America, land of the free.  I thought we might go skinny dipping.  For starters.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lillian is in her apron, canning peaches.</context>
      <utterance>Communists?! No daughter of mine is going to Communist Russia!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves. Lillian follows her down the narrow -- almost institutional -- hallway.</context>
      <utterance>You act like I'm a bomb-thrower, Mama. It's just a trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they're using you!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've reached Frances' room. She puts on her coat.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Ma, they're not using me. It's just a chance to travel, see things. Besides, it's the only way I can get to New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll pay your way to New York. I'll work, I'll slave. I'll sell my vegetables to the truck farmers, or --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares out the window. We see Ernest mowing the lawn.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mama, don't you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances turns and heads back down the hall. Lillian follows.</context>
      <utterance>I have to do this on my own. You see, I've learned your lesson very well. To do what I think is right and everyone else be damned.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances keeps walking.</context>
      <utterance>I never taught you that!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've reached the kitchen. Ernest is there, sweating, drinking water.</context>
      <utterance>Little sister, if you don't wise up soon, it's going to be out of my hands!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't in your hands, Mama. It's my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but important people are concerned about this. Judge Hillier spoke to Alma Styles --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She storms outside. Frances sighs, looks at her father.</context>
      <utterance>...You will.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really want to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you think it's worth all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I didn't, I wouldn't put you through it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Then go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has your earlier denial of God led you to Communism?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a Communist.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Frances, you said --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said all countries are of cultural interest. Besides, Russia has the greatest theatre company in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better than any American company?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think of Stalin?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much. Ask me about Stanislavski.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A TALL SPECTRAL MAN dressed in black adds:</context>
      <utterance>Help me save my daughter! Save the children of America.</utterance>
   <speaker>TALL SPECTRAL MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Repent, Frances, Repent!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their cries seem weird, almost deranged, and Lillian is taken aback.</context>
      <utterance>Repent! Repent!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TALL SPECTRAL MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances accepts the gifts, bewildered. The Tall Spectral Man stares at her through hollow eyes. She staggers on toward the bus, looking like a bedraggled Statue of Liberty. The Tall Spectral Man sings an ethereal hymn. Lillian blocks Frances' path. Frances looks at her tearfully.</context>
      <utterance>Bless you, sister, bless you.  Here is a Bible for solace... and this plant to remind you of the eternal seed in all of us... and finally, a flashlight to illuminate your path through darkest Russia.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Mama.  I love you, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Frances climbs on board.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful, Francie.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside the bus, Frances stares out the window and shakes her head sadly. The bus starts. Everyone looks at Lillian. She is motionless... Furious. Frances sighs, and the bus moves off unimpeded. There is a homicidal rage in Lillian's eyes as she stares after the vehicle. Then the Reporters rush toward her.</context>
      <utterance>Frances, I'm warning you. I'm gonna throw myself beneath the wheels. I'll do it, Frances. Frances!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks down, her lip quivering. Humiliated, crumbling... As the reporters shout unanswered questions, Ernest puts his arm around his wife and leads her away.</context>
      <utterance>What do you say now, Mrs. Farmer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>PHOTOGRAPHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Frances stares dramatically off into space.</context>
      <utterance>One more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLICIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera clicks.</context>
      <utterance>Hobbies?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I swim some... play the piano badly... and I read like a fiend: I like history.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLICIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, people don't want that. Now listen: you spend lots of time at the beach. You're crazy about dancing. And you're the kind of girl who's just a little in love with love. Get it? Now try again? Hobbies?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLICIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beach... dancing... in love with love.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera clicks again. MR. BEBE -- a tall, brooding, well- dressed man -- ENTERS.</context>
      <utterance>That's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Mr. Bebe!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances Farmer, contract player, six- month option.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Good tits. Can't we show them off a little more?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess so, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Claire stares after him with profound contempt.</context>
      <utterance>Very fine bone structure.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLICIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much to work with. How's this:  'The most interesting thing about Frances Farmer is that her road to Hollywood was 12,000 miles long. After winning a beauty contest, the first prize of which was a trip to Europe...' She made some deal with the Commies and went to Moscow, but I'm not going to say that, am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heavens no. Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLICIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... 'Miss Farmer returned to New York City and had a brief fling with the Broadway stage before coming west to seek stardom.'</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Brief fling?'</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLICIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Camera clicks again. Frances is frozen in time.</context>
      <utterance>Well, actually she couldn't get hired, but lucky for her, some guy in our New York office saw her. She says soon as she gets a stake, she's going back. Claire rolls her eyes. She's heard this before.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Water lands on her face. She grimaces playfully.</context>
      <utterance>Did you get the check?... Oh my God, it opened?!, what'd you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The last line is garbled as water streams in her mouth. She fumbles for something on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope I get bigger parts, they don't come much smaller.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finds a water pistol on the floor, picks up the phone, and starts searching for her assailant.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm fine. I just have water in my mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flings open the bathroom door and finds him: Dick from drama class. A furious water battle ensues.</context>
      <utterance>No, Mama, I'm not changing my name. They can't actually make you, you know? Most people don't realize that.  Oh Dick...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up, lowers her gun as Dick squirts her. She's getting wet. Her shirt clinging to her breasts. She likes it.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, nothing's going on.  I love you too, Mama. Give my love to Dad. Bye!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, handsome. You win.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kurt!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Angela! Go with these trappers! They'll lead you safely down the mountain...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Kurt, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, No arguments. Be my good girl and go. There's a forest, a burning forest, and you know what I have to do!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Kurt!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN the corners of Frances' mouth begin to tremble, but her eyes remain wide and innocent. The Fire Chief slowly inclines his head toward hers. The brim of his hat hits her forehead. Frances covers her face with her hands and bursts out laughing. The Fire Chief looks stunned. She tries to control herself.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Angela, my own... Angela!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter inside the screening room. A small light flicks on, and from behind we dimly SEE TWO MEN.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry...  I'm sorry, let's go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that? What's she doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUGHING MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's talent, Andy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances throws her arms around him. They hug warmly.</context>
      <utterance>Harry! Harry-god-damn-York! A real person!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin', Farmer?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Look at you! What're you doing in Hollywood?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They compare forearms.</context>
      <utterance>Came to get a tan.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad. But come on, Harry; what's the real reason?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kaminski.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I read about that. Terrible business, suicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when do you believe the papers? They killed him, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They killed him. They threw him out that window.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares down two stories to the ground, imagining:</context>
      <utterance>Eight stories.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup. Poor bastard lay there on the sidewalk and he couldn't die. Too god damn much heart. He just didn't want to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... but why, Harry...? Why'd they do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wouldn't play ball. What can I tell ya... it's done.  Anyway, I didn't want to be next, so I skipped town; came down here to work for some big-wig. Tail and nail job.  I'm sort of a non-gentleman's non- gentleman.  How d'ya like the camouflage?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You jackass!  C'mon, let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad. It was slow at first, but I'm doing bits now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always told ya, Frances. You got real ability.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what ability you're interested in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm a man, aren't I? Whattaya say we have dinner, then maybe head out to the beach, rub some of this tan off each other.  For old time's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry... I met someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? What is he -- muscleman? Lifeguard?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods.</context>
      <utterance>Actor?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's joking, but she doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Then it's temporary.  All actors are phonies.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Serious, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles wistfully, seeing him cover up his disappointment. She squeezes his arm and they continue walking.</context>
      <utterance>Hey that's great, Farmer, just great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These creases... I look like I just came from the laundry! I'm supposed to be hiding out in boxcars, sleeping on floors.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDROBE MISTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the suit we fitted on you, Miss Farmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I know that. But it could look more realistic, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDROBE MISTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll do. No one will notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We HEAR a man conspicuously clearing his throat. Both women turn as Mr. Bebe steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>I'll notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDROBE MISTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods imperceptibly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mr. Bebe, good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates, then goes.</context>
      <utterance>Come along with me, Fanny.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Frances. I'm not the cookbook.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see: We've got to change that name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like your looks. You have the classical bone structure of the very great beauties... Garbo, Dietrich --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances is taken aback. This is all rather blunt.</context>
      <utterance>I intend to make a great deal of money off you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since we have you on a seven year contract, I'm planning long-range. I'm going to loan you out to Sam Goldwyn to make a picture called "Come and Get It."</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? That's a very good book. It'd make a terrific --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hear a ruckus in the distance and turn and look: PICKETERS are fighting with POLICE. It is raucous, brutal. Bebe turns back to her with a stern look:</context>
      <utterance>Never mind that. I'm concerned about you. Your attitude.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Society is falling apart, Miss Farmer, and people have to buckle down, do their jobs. You see, I view myself as the Henry Ford of motion picture industry, and I can't have the fellow who puts on the wheels arguing with the man who installs head-lights, now can I?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm concerned with everything, Mr. Bebe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm concerned with everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm the one up there on the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's about to reply, but he quickly takes her hand and raises it to his lips. Kisses it very formally, like a suitor. Then turns and walks into the sumptuous executive office building. She watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. You're an actress, Miss Farmer and your job is to act.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it's no secret that I'm proud. Only twenty-one years old, and look at all she's done.  As for her looks, I flatter myself that she gets them from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He winks at the reporters.</context>
      <utterance>Obviously.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And not only has Frances come home a star; she's also brought me this big handsome lug of a son-in-law!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Farmer, what was your reaction when Frances told you she had married...</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dwayne. Dwayne Steele.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dick smiles and hugs them both.</context>
      <utterance>What...? Oh. Well, I was pleased, of course. Richard... uh, Dwayne, is a real gentleman.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, all I can say is: I feel like I've known these two for years!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're stopped at a light. Outside their window we SEE DERELICTS, casualties of the depression, huddled in the night.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Dwayne!  This is like a fairy tale!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rolls down her window. The Studio Executive beside her looks at her like she's crazy.</context>
      <utterance>What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDIO EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The limousine lurches forward. Frances settles back in her seat, letting the night air sweep over her face.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go. We'll be late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There she is!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does it feel to be back in Seattle, Frances?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMEN'S VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't she gorgeous?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDIO EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the movie, Frances?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Frances sees her mother smiling nervously. They have entered the:</context>
      <utterance>Smile, little sister, smile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you make some statement about Seattle, how the city helped you, or the schools --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the truth is the city had nothing to do with it. I was lucky. And what wasn't luck was hard work.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Judge Hillier's Wife, whom we recognize as the Woman who shouted at Frances in the auditorium, steps forward in a garish gown. She's holding a large key.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE HILLIER'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She embraces and kisses Frances, who's more than a little put off. After the kiss, she takes firm hold of Frances' hand and won't let go. Judge Hillier steps to his wife's side. Lillian also approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Farmer, I can't tell you how proud I am to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE HILLIER'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On behalf of the Seattle Ladies Club, as a token of our vast admiration --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE HILLIER'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE HILLIER'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe so.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. You shouted at me in the auditorium when I read my essay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE HILLIER'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, my dear. You must be mistaken.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE HILLIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cracks up. Harry laughs at his mistake.</context>
      <utterance>...It's one thing to marry the guy, but did you have to sleep with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. I meant the other way around.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the studio told me not to.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why you did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who ever thought they'd be right for once? Jesus, Harry... it's a zoo back there --</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dick... and my mother! She acts like she's on Mars or something --</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she's back to earth now. They're all pretty huffed up about your leaving. I think you better go back, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her thoughtfully, then sits.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, the funny thing is: it's not a great movie. I mean it could've been, but they screwed it up, gave it a happy ending. And all my friends, I know they're going to smile and say they loved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they say they love it, they'll probably love it. Not everybody lies, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>No, they don't, do they?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances, you're a movie star now. If you give them what they want, you can get anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have what they want, Harry.  Harry, will you tell me something? How can I keep making movies when people in the streets are starving?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some people starve, kid. Until we can do something about it, they might as well see a movie. Makes 'em feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(important)</context>
      <utterance>But I don't want to be like that. I want to do something...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you gonna do, waste your talent? Why not use it to make something worthwhile. You can do that, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what. Let's ditch the limo. Let me drive you up to that red carpet in my beat up Chevy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you will, Harry York.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head mischievously... moves backward unbuttoning her coat.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Cinderella, your pumpkin awaits.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The coat falls.</context>
      <utterance>Bong... bong... bong...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't start, Farmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's midnight, Harry. My glittering raiments are dissolving.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The chauffeur. He's watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He deserves a show. He missed the movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious, Frances. This is important.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kicks off another shoe, sailing it into the water. Frances is zipping off her dress. Harry bends to pick up the first shoe.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry watches her, mesmerized. The dress is off.</context>
      <utterance>A single glass slipper left glittering on the pearly sands. Who was that girl, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She skips off down the beach, her dress strewn on the sands. After a moment, from the darkness, we SEE her underclothes fly into view. Harry can restrain himself no longer.</context>
      <utterance>'Come and get it,' Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops the shoe and runs after her, tearing off his clothes. After a moment, from the darkness, we hear her squeals of laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Hot damn!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Frances, got a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk toward the dressing room.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, Claire. If you don't mind walking my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I suppose I should just say it. It's your clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I mean slacks... and work clothes... and that awful car --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a perfectly good car. It runs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but... Really, I hate to sound... it's just that the public expects something different from its stars. People won't take you seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care if my clothes are taken seriously. Or my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire is laughing. They go inside.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. You mean what if the public finds out I perspire? And wear slacks. And drive an old jalopy? What if they find out I'm a real person. Oh no! Say it ain't so! Not a real person!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Frances sits at the table and Eddie goes to work:</context>
      <utterance>Morning, Eddie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not all, Frances. Mr. Bebe is very concerned about your politics. He hears you've been donating money, speaking at rallies.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup. Claire... please, please tell Mr. Bebe that if he worried half as much about his scripts as he does about my private life, we'd make a lot better movies.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Frances. It's my job, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.  'This is a factory and we each have our jobs. The writer writes, the director directs, and the actress...'</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...acts. I'll relay your message.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up. Immediately the phone rings again. He stares at it wearily, then answers:</context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course she'll make a statement on women's rights. Call back tomorrow, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the half-open door to the bedroom we see Frances dozing, an open script laid out beside her.</context>
      <utterance>Dwayne Steele's residence.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up. Stares off. Slowly enters the bedroom. Frances looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.  What...?  Yes. Yes, I'll tell her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You learn your lines?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort of.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There've been some calls.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... about half an hour ago that woman from the talent department called, what's her name?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claire?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Claire. She said she was fired. Too bad, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fired?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dick presses on.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. She said she delivered your message and that you'd understand. Frances looks stricken.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was another call too. From your agent. He says your summer stock deal is all set. So you're going back east, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Showdown.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't going to tell me, were you? Just pack up and leave, is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dick, we need some time apart --</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm not a complete fool, you know. I can see you're going sour on me, and when I try to do something about it, you turn your back and say it's nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dick, I can't even breathe here...</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dwayne! I'm Dwayne now! And you damn well better get used to it!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dick...</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't suppose it occurred to you that I might want to leave too, that I might want to do theatre? No, 'cause you don't want me along, do you? And the reason has nothing to do with summer stock.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's all about that night, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What night?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The premiere. I never pressed you about it but god damn it, you're gonna tell me right here and right now what happened and where the hell you were!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dick is crumbling inside.</context>
      <utterance>You want his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We watch it sink in. Confusion... self-pity... building gradually to resentment and rage. He starts to throw a tantrum. Hurling things around the room. Frances just sits there.</context>
      <utterance>What...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurls a pillow against the wall and rushes out. Frances looks after him, then turns. She's now facing the bureau.</context>
      <utterance>My God... I think you're overplaying this a bit...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A mirror sits on top of the bureau. She looks into it. Doesn't like her expression. Turns the mirror away.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Dick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Group is more than a theatre company. It's the embodiment of an ideal. Our approach allows the actor to be an artist in the fullest sense, a creative individual and an instrument of change. You see --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, Mr. Clurman, you don't have to sell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive my indulgence. Seems we always lecture those who are on time for those who are tardy. The point is, Mr. Odets here has written a wonderful play. Most of the roles are cast, but we haven't found our female lead...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a tramp from Newark.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odets is pacing furiously, seizing their attention. He stops, looks at her, then resumes.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, but I think you'd be perfect for the part.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops. Tentatively, almost boyishly, he smiles. She returns it. She's charmed.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Farmer, for me this is not a play: it's an assault... a seduction... a plea for understanding. I think we live in a time when new art works should shoot bullets... and you make very attractive ammunition.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what's the title of this seduc... assault?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Golden Boy.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another nod. He's silent. He peers up the street. A GIRL, 16, selling pencils catches his eye.</context>
      <utterance>You wanted to talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks like a waif: tough, vulnerable, pleading with a WEALTHY COUPLE, following them down the street. A drama being played out in the distance, out of earshot.</context>
      <utterance>You see that girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances watches the girl.</context>
      <utterance>That's who my play is about.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's me, Clifford.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but I'm not seeing it. It's there, Frances, the fire is there, but it's not coming through. You're lazy --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you win them, you bring them into your heart, touch them, but you don't set them on fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I want to. I'm trying!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need an incendiary! An arsonist!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then show me! That's what I'm here for, to learn, to grow!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Then it's very simple. You have to stop being afraid, Frances. It's in you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We now HEAR Clurman's speech. The initial words below were background to the above. What we HEAR now is underlined:</context>
      <utterance>I can see it. You just have to let it out. Trust it. No one will quash you here, but it's still a fight, a struggle! Being true to your art, being honest, is always a struggle!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(presenting check to</context>
      <utterance>...Not only an artist, but an instrument of change. We must look to the world around us, not content to observe, but to take an active hand in redressing its wrongs. We will not stand idly by as Fascist bombs obliterate democracy. We contribute our profits, for if fascism is not stopped in Spain, it will spread across Europe, jeopardizing the struggle of civilized man to survive.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANISH CONSUL)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The artist, to be vital, must be a soldier too.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not afraid of struggle, Clifford.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you are. We all are. The first step is to acknowledge our fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Face it! Confess it! You're weak!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're afraid!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to show your whole soul -- ugly, mis-shapen, and pitiful -- you don't want to show it --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, watching her.</context>
      <utterance>God damn it, Clifford, will you shut up! I tell you, I want to give these things! I want to give them to the audience, and I can give them, I will give them, so shut up! She is seething. Gorgeous. Alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, good. Give them that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she feels the anger coursing through her body she realizes what he's talking about. She looks at him, still breathing heavily. Gradually her face turns toward a smile. He reaches out and, with exquisite tenderness, kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLIFFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's looking at the apartment. He sees her. A dark thought flickers across his face, and he breaks into an exaggerated act:</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! Frances, I'm such a cad. I can't go through with this. My wife is in Europe, but this is her house...  her bedroom. I can't ask you to...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to put on her coat. He watches her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh well. I guess I better leave then.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, but come here first.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the bedroom door.</context>
      <utterance>Come here. I want to show you something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And on top of her political activities, now she's got a lawyer. She wants out of her contract, Mr. Bebe. She says she's through with motion pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure it wasn't me, it wasn't me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tora is massaging the back of Bebe's neck. He's oblivious.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know who she fucked to get where she is, but I don't think it was me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... you could always dump her, Mr. Bebe. Teach her a lesson. There are a million beautiful girls out there who don't give a damn about politics.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not the point. Frances Farmer has the world by the tit because of this studio, and now she thinks she can waltz off without a thank you. No. No, that young lady has a contract, and she's going to honor it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. I mean, good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this conversation, Bebe has been drawing on the Variety. We now see his work. Beneath the headline was a photo of Frances, on whom Bebe has drawn a mustache.</context>
      <utterance>I think it's time to take the gloves off.  Get me some reporters.  Particularly Louella Parsons!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shyly hands her the flower.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Farmer... I've never done this before... but... I had to tell ya' you're great!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and begins to walk away. The Young Man follows her.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much. I'm glad you liked the play.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really sad it's closing. Now what am I gonna do on Tuesday nights?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can always come see it in London.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only if you were in it. Are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't miss it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I'd love to... but I'm going to Hollywood.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you an actor?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell yes!... well, okay, I'm still in school. But as soon as I graduate... California, here I come!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you really serious? About acting?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why... yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then don't go to Hollywood.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you straight, if you have any serious ambitions, stay clear of the place. It'll crush you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sound as if you hate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again she walks on. He follows.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't hate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you ever going back?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Not if I can help it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gosh! You'll break a lot of hearts.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll mend.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances stops walking, her eyes shoot to the Young Man's face.</context>
      <utterance>What about your husband?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you be getting back together? When you quit Hollywood, I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young Man suddenly seems much older, and there is no sign of the awkward boyishness.</context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true you're getting a divorce? Comrade?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young Man grins.</context>
      <utterance>Why, you... you little bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for our chat, Miss Farmer. Be seeing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just one minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is gone.</context>
      <utterance>You're wasting your time, lady. Nothing's off the record with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates, still affected by the incident outside the theatre.</context>
      <utterance>How'd it go?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'But how do I know you love me?'</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your big speech?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'How do I know it's true? You'll get to be the champ. They'll all want you, all the girls! But I don't care. I've been undersea a long time. When they'd put their hands on me I used to say, "This isn't it! This isn't what I mean!" It's been a mysterious world for me! But Joe, I think you're it! I don't know why, I think you're it. Take me home with you.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, turns her back to him.</context>
      <utterance>I already have.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it sound?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The speech? Real good.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is crying.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yeah, tonight I think I got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Harold.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Clifford?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours. She drinks hers, watching him.</context>
      <utterance>Bourbon?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear you're meeting with the studio lawyers to get out of your contract.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. I don't want them breathing down my neck while we're in London.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances looks like she's been punched in the stomach.</context>
      <utterance>Well... well, you see, that's the point. You won't be opening in London.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think I'm good enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! Good Lord no, it's just... It's money. We needed backing and... well, we found it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An actress.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A rich actress.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's the deal. She plays Lorna.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... but wait a minute. We're supposed to be different, right? Clifford says... This theatre is supposed to be different! And this play... this play is all about what greed and money do to people!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does Clifford say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now we have to be practical.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does Clifford even know?  You didn't tell him, did you?  I'm gonna tell him. Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She collapses back into her seat. Her head is swirling.</context>
      <utterance>He knows, Frances.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's glaring at him. He hands her a letter.</context>
      <utterance>He approved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLURMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes fill with rage. She hurls her drink in his face.</context>
      <utterance>I'm very sorry, but... well, Hollywood wants you back, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands and, with as much dignity as he can muster, leaves. Frances is shaking. She rips open the letter he gave her. Stares at it in horror...</context>
      <utterance>Prick!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it can be done, "Mr. Jones," but it's how you do it. There's a way to pay off L.A. cops and a way to get yourself arrested. First you gotta know who to approach -- A Man at one of the phones looks up, calls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN AT PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry nods, startled. The Man at the table holds up the phone and goes to his next call. Harry takes the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You Harry York?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry? Harry, where are you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Frances, how'd you find me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called your god-damned office! I want you to kill him, Harry. You'll do that for me, won't you? I loved him, I loved him... that bastard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down, Frances.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me what to do, just give me his head on a platter!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two lines! Two fucking lines! 'My wife returns from Europe tomorrow. I can't see you any more.' Just like that!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, I hate being in love. I don't ever want to be in love again. I just hate it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, good. One more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For God's sake... why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Director glances toward Bebe, who nods with satisfaction. Frances watches this interaction. She hesitates, then approaches Bebe. She wipes some mud from her face and drops it at her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Because we want to get it perfect... just the right combination of fury and confusion. You can understand that, can't you, Miss Farmer? We're serious artists here, right? Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Mr. Bebe, you can hold me to my contract, but you can't break me. I'm back, and I'm gonna make the best of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and walks, with an air of pride, to her wardrobe trailer.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like nothing better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a mistake. No. This is a disaster.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, it's just what you need! Let everyone see you. Talk to them, live it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we've been at it since six this morning. At least you could've let me go home and change.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Frances, I didn't want this job. Think I'm crazy? But you begged me: improve your image. So please... lemme try, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. I'm sorry.  Okay, let's go get 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, take a few of these. Studio makes 'em in the basement. They keep the fat off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So not only am I a troublesome bitch, but I'm fat too?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, takes a few. They head for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. They make you feel nice and peppy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi! Bob Barnes! Looks like a swell party!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they embrace, Frances looks around with trepidation:</context>
      <utterance>Frances!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, who's here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees a flurry of waiting faces. Everyone's watching her.</context>
      <utterance>The usual vermin, I'm afraid. Barnes tries to pull Frances inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barnes nods, concerned, and crosses to the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Get me a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some people seem amused, some curious, some scornful. The Director from the mud scene nods to her. Connie is at her side for support. A voice from somewhere pierces the chatter:</context>
      <utterance>Hi everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Barnes returns with her drink, she turns to Connie:</context>
      <utterance>So nice to have you back, Frances.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Connie, can I use the upstairs bathroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FAT MAN ENTERS, stares at her.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is dumbfounded. He slowly retreats into the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't believe the offers! Just piling in. I mean piling. Some of the best scripts I've read in years!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes? My employer will be glad to hear that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louella? Is she here?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods toward a hard-faced OLDER WOMAN surrounded by admirers.</context>
      <utterance>How could you miss her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louella's here and I'm talking to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances?  Oh no.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Refill my drink, will you, Bob?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Putting on my armor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Frances. Louella Parsons is here. She wants to talk to you, help you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louella... didn't she call me a spoiled little bitch?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, she's an important columnist! What's the matter? I thought you wanted these people to forgive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Forgive'...? For What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances pulls down a dress and inspects it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... that was an unfortunate choice of words.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods and retreats out the door.</context>
      <utterance>You're not kidding.  Get me a refill, Bob. I'll be down in a minute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the Young Reporter steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances bristles. Barnes looks on nervously: It's all becoming unravelled again.</context>
      <utterance>Gee, awful good to see ya again, Miss Farmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances is broiling. She stares at him. Under her steady gaze, the snide smile gradually fades from his face.</context>
      <utterance>My employer would like to know something very important: is it true your friend Clifford sleeps in the nude?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem like an intelligent young man.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He blanches. This hits home. Frances turns on her heel and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you find a more dignified way to make a living?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over the car and sees Frances, her hair wild and tangled.</context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, where's the fire, sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my eyes, officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool off, beautiful. Didn't you see the sign says "Dimout Zone?"  There's a war on, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. You're seriously trying to tell me the Japs can't find Los Angeles without my headlights?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She switches her headlights back on.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't make the law, lady. I just enforce it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts the car. The Cop, angry now, lunges in and grabs the keys.</context>
      <utterance>God, you bore me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaps out of the car. The Cop turns off the car lights. As Frances passes his motorcycle, she switches on its lights.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs after her, turning off the motorcycle lights on the way. When he catches her, he grabs her arm. She struggles, grabs the flashlight from his belt. She switches it on and holds it high, its beam spearing wildly out to sea. He lunges for it, knocks her down. They struggle. He rolls on top of her, pinning both her arms with one hand... trying to handcuff her. She writhes, knees him in the balls. She crawls away, desperately clawing at loose stones. The Cop, angry now, hurls her down again and manages to get the cuffs on. As they dig into her wrists, she tries to bite him. The Cop, winded from the battle, yanks her to her feet and drags her, kicking and screaming, to his motorcycle. He pulls out his radio mike.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Santa Monica, this is motor six-sixty- six. I got a live one here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She turns, surprised and pleased to see him.</context>
      <utterance>Got any ginger beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks off into the kitchen. She puts her diary away.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell do you find me anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Animal magnetism!  No ginger beer. What's this red stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's left of my blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think I'll have a glass.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry returns, sipping the drink.</context>
      <utterance>Help yourself. Everyone else has.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Very tasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice joint. Can you afford it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. The studio pays. Thank you, Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For not chopping off his head and serving it to me on a platter.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I would have, you know? I just didn't know how to cook it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six months' probation...? You gotta learn when to do battle, Farmer. You're not going to win many bouts with 200 pound cops.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took the early rounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It hurts, Harry. Some things, no matter what you do with them, they just hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you drink, and you fight with a cop...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and you look at people and you wonder who the hell they are, what's going on inside their heads. Sometimes you can hear it, like a buzzing, the things that happen in their heads. And you wonder: does anybody ever love anybody, really?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Beats me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a thought come to him.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta get outta here. I gotta get out of this town.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey look, I got some business down in San Diego. Whattaya say you come with me, stay a few days?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Harry, I can't --</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're coming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grunts: what?</context>
      <utterance>You know... when I started acting, you know what I wanted?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to be part of something... one thing, one play or one movie, something that was really fine... memorable. And I could say: I did that, I made something good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the background, we SEE a DRUNKEN SAILOR lurching toward their table.</context>
      <utterance>Well... to get a crack at something good, you gotta earn it, you gotta climb the ladder first. So you do, you work hard, and all these people behind you are pushing you up, shouting you on. And then one day you realize you are, you're at the top... and there's nothing there. And you look behind you and there's no one below. You're just left there all alone... swaying in the god-damned breeze.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sailor trips and falls across their table, spilling beer on Frances and knocking things over.</context>
      <utterance>Well, like the man said: "You can make a fresh start with your last breath."</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, watch it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch what?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get away from me, you foul slime.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's no way for a lady to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a walk, pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said I was a lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I insulted you... bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sailor goes berserk, takes a swing at Frances. Harry leaps in to protect her, starts to fight with the Sailor. Frances joins in; she's not going to let anyone fight her battles. The Sailor's BUDDY enters the fracas. Everyone's getting hit. As the melee continues we:</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh, go eat a toilet seat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened? Who're you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who're you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I live here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Farmer? Oh... Well, look, they took your stuff out. Moved it to some hotel, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances stares at him, dumbfounded.</context>
      <utterance>I'm preparin' it for the next tenant, he's coming in tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a long drink, sifts through a pile, then throws it on the bed in disgust. We HEAR a voice on the phone.</context>
      <utterance>God damn it, god damn it...  Yes, I'll wait, I'm waiting...  I don't believe this. They can't do this to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slams down the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Barnes? It's my diary! They stole my fucking diary! Find it, will you? Find it! God damn it, that's my life!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances, looking pretty hung-over, enters blithely.</context>
      <utterance>Never. Never again. I swear, I swear I will never work with this broad --</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're four hours late! It's insane! It's unprofessional!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd say I'm behaving as professionally as anyone else in this town.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Director clenches his fists as though about to punch her.</context>
      <utterance>Terribly, terribly sorry; I overslept. What's the name of this fine entertainment we're all so involved in?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks to her dressing room as the Director explodes anew.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes. "No Escape." That's it. There's no escape.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances sits. Tora begins brushing her hair, yanking Frances' head back with each stroke. Building tension...</context>
      <utterance>It's about time! You're not the star on this show, y'know!</utterance>
   <speaker>TORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances cries out and twists around suddenly. Tora is thrown back: stumbling... falling... hitting her jaw against a chair.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, it's not up to me to say anything. I'm just crew... Y'know, you hair's so fine you'll lose it if you're not careful. Wonder you all don't, the things you do to yourselves. In fact, I think you are already... Fact, I think you better --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She storms out. Tora is left moaning, holding her jaw.</context>
      <utterance>That's it! I'm not taking this any more! I quit!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When she reaches the exit door, she turns and bows to them all, grandiloquently.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye!... goodbye!... goodbye!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone keeps RINGING. Her arm gropes for it. A loud POUNDING at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The POUNDING at the door becomes violent. Someone's breaking it down.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell's going on here?  Hold on!  Hello...  Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door splinters.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Men stream into the room. Back-lit from the hall they look like monsters, phantoms. They're carrying sticks. Frances screams and runs naked into the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>What...? Help!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slams the door on the advancing figures.</context>
      <utterance>Don't kill me! Don't kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's too much for her. She's shoved back, falling to the floor. The door flies open revealing THREE LARGE COPS. Leering at her. Frances clutches at the shower curtain, trying to cover herself.</context>
      <utterance>Mama, help me, help me, Mama! Don't let them kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your clothes on.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no right! You have no fucking right, you bastards! Get the hell out of here --</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your clothes on, lady --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Photographers laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe this! You jerks drag me down here in the middle of the night and you don't even know who the hell I am!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Age?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Address?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just put me down as a avg -- a vagrant vagabond. Come on, this is a joke! Assault and battery? I barely touched that bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances considers for a moment, then smiles matter-of-factly.</context>
      <utterance>Occupation?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sergeant reddens. Frances laughs as the Photographers snap their shots.</context>
      <utterance>Cocksucker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances looks disgustedly at the Photographers and lies down heavily on the cot.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! I'd like to leave a wake-up call for say, ten? Hey! I'll have my bread and water in bed!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHOTOGRAPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Frances! Why don't you comb your hair, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Take me the way I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Is that not true?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's writing this guy's lines?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer the question! Have you driven a car since you were placed on probation?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I couldn't get my hands on one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you reported to your Probation Officer as directed?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never saw him. Why didn't he show up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you expect him to look you up?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suppressed laughter ripples through the courtroom.</context>
      <utterance>Why, certainly. I wanted to get a peek at his face...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're on your way to a contempt citation, young lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fine with me...  Get it? Fine. A fine! Hey c'mon, c'mon, what is this, an audience or a jury?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Farmer, is it true you fought with the policeman who arrested you last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure it's true. I was fighting for my country as well as myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Farmer, you were advised at the last hearing that if you took one drink of liquor or failed to be a law-abiding citizen -- Frances moves closer to the bench.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you telling me you didn't have a little rum in your pineapple juice this morning? I can smell it from here, Your Honor. The courtroom erupts into surprised laughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances laughs triumphantly and spears the air with her finger, pointing at the Judge.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The laughter grows. The Judge bangs his gavel.</context>
      <utterance>It's the truth! I can smell it from here -- you old hypocrite!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Farmer! In light of your flagrant disregard for the conditions of your probation, coupled with the unwarranted assault on the Plaintiff here... I am forced to order you to begin serving a sentence of 180 days in the County Jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Judge ignores this.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute... I haven't got a lawyer...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lunges at the Matrons, trying to get past them.</context>
      <utterance>I want to make a phone call...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a right to make a phone call!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She suddenly sees the phone booths. Her eyes fill with tears, her shoulders slump forward and her lower lip begins to tremble. She no longer struggles.</context>
      <utterance>They're stealing my civil rights! Help me! I'm being kidnapped! Oh God, help me! Help me!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances throws herself at the door of the booth. The Reporter is delirious with joy: what a story!</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, she's loose!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances pounds at the door a few more times, then moves to the next booth... into the arms of Harry.</context>
      <utterance>She's attacking your correspondent! Right here in the Court Building! Good God, this bitch is crazy! Someone stop her!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry shakes his head. Before he can speak, Frances is grabbed from behind and dragged toward the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>Harry!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a right! I have a right!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With what must surely be the final act of madness, the curtain falls on Frances Farmer's once promising career. The crazed blonde who at</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and we feel that this would be more appropriate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods to the other Man who, together with the Woman, turn away from the bench. As they pass in front of one of the tall windows, Frances recognizes the Woman. It is Alma Styles.</context>
      <utterance>...a difficult decision, but, I'm sure, the proper one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She feels an arm slip around her shoulders and she stiffens. Her mother's face appears by hers.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's alright now, little sister, everything's going to be just fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama, what's...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhh, shhh. You're not going to jail, Frances. The Judge has put you under my care. I'll see you get the rest you need.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two other WOMEN appear at either side of Frances and Lillian. Lillian tenderly takes her daughter's face in her hands.</context>
      <utterance>You're taking me home!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lillian smiles enthusiastically at Frances, who stares accusingly back: she's not falling for that. An awkward moment of silence. Lillian fidgets, doesn't know what to say. She is rescued when the door opens and DR. SYMINGTON (early 30s, glasses, white coat and ingratiating smile) enters. He holds his right hand out to Frances.</context>
      <utterance>Why it's beautiful here! What a view!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances stares at the proffered hand. Lillian steps in quickly and takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon, Miss Farmer. I'm Dr. Symington.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor winks at Frances and puts a hand on Lillian's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles pleasantly. Lillian is obviously very put off by the idea. She looks at Frances who stares unseeingly out the window.</context>
      <utterance>I'm very pleased to meet you, Mrs. Farmer. I'm sure we'll have more of a chance to talk later. Right now I think it's important that your daughter have a chance to settle in. Perhaps it would be best if you said your goodbyes here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well, I have some background that you should probably know about if you're...</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the door and opens it. Lillian is momentarily at a loss, but she acquiesces. She bends down and tightly hugs Frances, who pats her on the back a couple of times.</context>
      <utterance>I have no doubt, Mrs. Farmer. If you'll speak to the girl at the desk, she'll arrange an appointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waits for a reply and then, getting none, starts out the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be back real soon, little sister. You be a good girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lillian turns back expectantly.</context>
      <utterance>Mama!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lillian looks to the Doctor, who nods sympathetically at her.</context>
      <utterance>...I want to go home, Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes out and down the hall. The Doctor closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>You'll see, little sister. Everything will be fine. The doctors know best.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I find these initial meetings to be much easier without the concerned relatives in attendance.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I supposed to say 'thank you'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks are hardly necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, shucks, ma'am. T'weren't nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad to see you haven't lost your sense of humor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't for lack of trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it seems. May we be serious for a moment?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reddens ever so slightly and looks away.</context>
      <utterance>Why, Doctor! We've only just met!</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances' face begins to set in hard planes.</context>
      <utterance>I feel I've known you for a long time... you see, I've followed your career... you're a fascinating case... I'm looking forward to resolving your predicament.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! Are you really?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops as Frances rises and leans over his desk:</context>
      <utterance>Among persons such as yourself, creative people under great stress, erratic behavior is not at all uncommon and certainly nothing to be ashamed of. It's just that the neuroses which fuel your talent can also generate certain character disabilities which...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you expect me, for one moment, to believe you have greater insight into my personality than I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please sit down...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may discuss my predicament, Doctor. You may discuss it with anyone you like, but not with me. I'm not interested. I can solve my problems without recourse to a veternarian.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, I don't want to be what you want to make me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Normal. Average.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Will you please sit down now?  Symington says.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Did you really say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little joke, Miss Farmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This whole thing is a joke!</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay calm, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you stay calm, Doctor! But you're finding that difficult, aren't you?  Why, are you attracted to me? Perhaps later, in some of our more intimate sessions... after we know each other a little better...  and you've torn my personality to shreds, and I'm weeping and vulnerable...  then you'll really get your kicks, won't you, "Doctor?"</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have someone show you to your room.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Symington stares at her. With a careful, almost scientific gesture he moves thumb and forefinger over his lip, then rubs the two fingers together. Yes, there is sweat.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's good, very professional. In control. But the tiny beads of sweat on your upper lip give you away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes a button on his desk and reaches for a folder. Frances hasn't moved. She gazes at him evenly.</context>
      <utterance>You really should get some rest now. Nurse will meet you outside. Good day.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there something else?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes are very calm now, he smiles at her patronizingly.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't say 'Symington says'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Symington says.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much on hospital corners, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something in her tone makes Lillian look up. The Matron closes the door behind her and advances. Lillian assumes her full height.</context>
      <utterance>You Farmer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Nurse smiles confidentially at her.</context>
      <utterance>So this is the nuthouse...</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get to the door and HEAR Lillian's protesting voice:</context>
      <utterance>Honey... take my word for it. This is a resort.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They enter and SEE the Matron struggling to get Lillian's coat away from her. Lillian pleads with Frances.</context>
      <utterance>You have no right!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them who I am! Tell them who I am!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances bursts out laughing. The Matron releases Lillian and comes for Frances.</context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy? Unhand that woman! That's Amelia Earhart!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CAMERA PULLS BACK TO REVEAL Frances strapped down on a white cot. The Nurse is holding the syringe while a THIN NURSE and an ATTENDANT stand by.</context>
      <utterance>But what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to tell me what it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>THIN NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances looks at her suspiciously, uncertain whether to believe this, and turns toward the Nurse with the hypodermic.</context>
      <utterance>It's insulin. It throws your body into shock.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE WITH HYPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This sounds more reasonable. Frances relaxes somewhat.</context>
      <utterance>It's just vitamins.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE WITH HYPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances does. The Attendant jams a rubber bar between her teeth. Frances squirms, fights. The Attendant holds the bar in place. And the Nurse pushes the plunger on the hypo. Frances goes rigid. Her eyes widen, her back arches. With a loud hoarse cry she starts to convulse. The SCREEN BEGINS TO FADE into bright white light. She is unconscious. The SCREEN</context>
      <utterance>A, C, B-Complex, certain minerals...  Just stay relaxed... Good, now open your mouth a sec.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands it to Frances, who lets it drop beside her on the bench.</context>
      <utterance>...and here's the one from Duluth. A war widow with five children. She works in a defense plant and she's very worried about you. I answered her that she shouldn't let worry over you affect her vital work; and that you'd be back on the silver screen in no time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And here's one from nice Mr. Zeiss. He says that...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are these all opened?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they needed immediate answers, Frances. It's good manners and good sense. You shouldn't be bothering yourself with these right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why did you bring them?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your fan mail, little sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kill me, Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances sighs. She looks for something to divert her attention.</context>
      <utterance>Go on...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'm sorry to keep you waiting, the staff review ran over. Did you enjoy your mother's visit?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It was very good to see her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Symington puts the folders in a drawer. All except Frances'.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Any problems?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. She brought me my fan mail.  I had no idea there were so many strangers concerned about me. But I guess that's the best thing about working in the movies. You make so many friends. I want to go back and show them that the faith they put in me wasn't a mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me you feel guilty.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... What I mean is... I'm just very excited by the prospect of getting on with my life, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really believe your mother's trying to kill you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She told me you said, "Mama, you want to kill me."</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never said... Oh look. That's just a figure of speech. She said something funny, and I said...</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you accused her of tampering with your mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances is wrapping and unwrapping a handkerchief around her knuckles. Looks a little crazy. Symington's watching it. She stops.</context>
      <utterance>Oh for Christ's...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. She misunderstood, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you tell me you had a pleasant visit and your mother says you were sullen and uncommunicative. Whom do you think I should believe?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor, I hate to break this to you, but my mother is a little batty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances, you're still filled with anxiety. You feel guilty and hostile toward your family and friends. Consequently, I didn't recommend your release at the staff review.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances stares at him. Stunned. Horrified.</context>
      <utterance>Mental illness is an elusive thing, and though I'm pleased you're feeling more... capable, it's perhaps unrealistic to expect you to be completely cured after so short a time. Don't you agree?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you'll see it my way in the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Symington, how big is your dick?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Symington smiles patronizingly.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause if it's long enough, which I doubt, why don't you wrap it around and fuck yourself in the ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want outta here, you understand? I'm ready to get out! So you go back there... you go back and you tell them to let me out!</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances, I'm warning you...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances tries to barrel past, but they easily restrain her.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm warning you! Who do you think you are, God? You bumble around with your folders...  ...and your pencils...  ...and your god-damn buttons...  ...all your badges of authority! But you have no authority! You're nothing! You're a zero! She tears open the door. Two huge ORDERLIES are waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Symington sits forward, his hands smoothing his hair. Frances smiles sarcastically at him:</context>
      <utterance>Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Symington says...</utterance>
   <speaker>SYMINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They haul her away.</context>
      <utterance>Sedate her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She looks to one side and sees him. Frowns. Takes off her glasses and runs her fingers nervously through her hair.</context>
      <utterance>Hi there. How 'bout a walk in the woods?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, I look awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've looked a whole lot better. C'mon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks down and weeps on Harry's shoulder. Harry looks around warily.</context>
      <utterance>They're doin' stuff to me, Harry. Can you see it? You feel it? They're putting stuff in my food or something, my water, and they're using it to put thoughts in my head. You understand? They're trying to re- arrange what's in my head, they're trying to drive me crazy! Oh, Harry!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry nods, squeezes her arm firmly -- a warning -- as a white-coated ATTENDANT APPROACHES. Frances straightens up.</context>
      <utterance>I can't stay here anymore, you understand? I can't, I can't. I gotta get home. I gotta get somewhere else, anywhere, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Miss Farmer! Time for your bath, Miss Farmer!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Attendant reaches them.</context>
      <utterance>Listen: to the left. Straight through the trees and over the wall to your left. My car is there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's time for your bath!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh good. I love my baths.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances starts to move off with the Attendant. For an instant Harry -- and we -- wonder if she really is crazy.</context>
      <utterance>Come along now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns. The Attendant turns. She smiles sweetly, madly.</context>
      <utterance>Frances! Did you hear what I said?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Attendant is between her and Harry. We SEE her face turn dark. She shoves the Attendant toward Harry and shouts:</context>
      <utterance>Of course, Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs. The Attendant staggers toward Harry, who knocks him down with two punches. ANOTHER ATTENDANT runs up. Harry whips out an icepick and brandishes it at them:</context>
      <utterance>Over the walls!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Attendants hold their ground. Harry runs after Frances.</context>
      <utterance>You want crazy? I'll show you crazy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evening, gorgeous.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sure looks like fun...  You know how long it's been since I was behind the wheel?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Frances. You're not driving.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry smiles. Frances climbs over the seat and starts to fiddle with the radio.</context>
      <utterance>Have I told you how mean you're turning, York?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we, mean man?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couple hours from Idaho. We'll cut across to Montana. I've got friends there with a ranch.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should've known...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is another one of your schemes to get me off alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass a poster: "BUY WAR BONDS!" Frances stares at it.</context>
      <utterance>...Take advantage of me. Harry laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I'd be much good in a war...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whattaya think you're in now?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Not a war exactly. It's more a... a misapprehension maybe...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry looks at her quizzically.</context>
      <utterance>A misunderstanding, people taking the wrong meaning from things. I wasn't declaring war, Harry. I was just saying my prayers.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Who to?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, I have to go home. I have to talk to Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances, you're fulla drugs. You don't know what you're saying. Who do you think put you into Meadow Wood? Your mother thinks you're crazy and she'll keep on thinking it as long as it suits her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, she just didn't want me going to jail, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rubs his neck and his attitude seems to soften. She looks at him fondly, thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? She's a shark, Frances. I'm not taking you there, and that's that!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know something, Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aside from meanness, you're almost perfect. There's only one other thing wrong with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't drink.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohhh, that's lousy Scotch!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Another shot for the lady and a double for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a man!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you're a good quarter-horse, kid, but you can't go a route of ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To quarter-horses.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knocks back his drink.</context>
      <utterance>No. To thoroughbreds.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BING'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances squeals with delight when she hears the song. She holds Harry forcefully and starts to lead him around the floor. Harry starts to sing along:</context>
      <utterance>Love is so terrific Such a funny feeling Makes you want to cuddle And coo...</utterance>
   <speaker>BING &amp; HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Around them an infection is spreading: all the women are leading their men. For an instant it is magical, liberating... She leans her head against his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Makes you sentimental, Makes you kinda gentle Ouch!  Terrific thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you always leaving me, Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should stickaround sometimes. Look out for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Frances, I'm only gonna ask this one time. I mean it. I swear after this, I'll never ask again: Will you marry me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know a thing or two about marriage. You... you understand me more than anyone, Harry... maybe even more than Mama. But... you're too important to me. I'd fail you. I don't know how or why, but I would. And that's a chance I just can't take. Do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are silent for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Well... I'll act like I do until I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's just one more thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs happily. He joins her, but his seems a little forced. She leans her head on his shoulder and holds him tight. They dance...</context>
      <utterance>Will you marry me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not too late to keep going, up to Vancouver? Be the smartest thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Harry, really, but... I can't explain it. She's my mother. She's just... I can't give up on her that easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You give up on her?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's just... something I gotta do, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances, You're crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs. We SEE Lillian come out onto the porch with uncharacteristic trepidation.</context>
      <utterance>I know. Don't tell anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway... if you need me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome home, little sister.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, who have we here...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances, you remember my lawyer, Alma Styles?</utterance>
   <speaker>STYLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Frances. You seem to be having quite a time of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called Alma because I think we'll need...</utterance>
   <speaker>STYLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances, the doctors at Meadow Wood have petitioned the court for your return. Your mother has asked me to intervene so you can stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bursts into tears. Frances takes her in her arms and rocks her like a child.</context>
      <utterance>I swear I didn't know what they were doing to you. I wouldn't have let them...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, Mama. It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>STYLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You realize, of course, your mother is now your legal guardian. In the eyes of the law, you no longer have any rights as an adult. You're going to have to hold your tongue and be selective about whom you mix with. That man who drove you here, for instance --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You leave him out of this!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances, please don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>STYLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind. We won't have to worry about him much longer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FBI MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin', Al?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got the wrong guy. Name's Slocum.</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it ain't. And it ain't Harry York, neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FBI Man pulls the hammer back on the revolver. ANOTHER MAN opens the passenger door.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm tellin' you...</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd give you till ten, Al, but we ain't got the time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances' brows mesh.</context>
      <utterance>Frances, play 'Flow Gently Sweet Afton'.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Mama, I'm so... tired of that song.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances sighs and begins to play it. Lillian scrunches down and begins to hum along.</context>
      <utterance>Please. I want you to. It would make me so happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles warmly at Frances. Frances abruptly stops playing.</context>
      <utterance>It's just a flow gently sweet Afton day. Life has been so good to me. Why, I have just about everything one could wish... but I still have so many blank pages in my scrapbook.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I need a little air.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I think I'll just go out for awhile.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up and Lillian rouses herself.</context>
      <utterance>For a walk, Mama. Just a walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long will you be?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances goes down the hall for her coat. Lillian follows part way.</context>
      <utterance>Not long.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have lunch ready by one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At one. Promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances returns wearing the coat. Lillian half-blocking her path.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say you promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lillian nods, moves aside. As Frances heads for the door:</context>
      <utterance>I promise I'll... I promise, Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, the surest way to lose an appetite, is to drink, little sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you drinking, Frances.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lillian enters and re-establishes herself on the couch with a happy smile. She begins to hum "Flow Gently Sweet Afton"</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mama.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...So what do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, honey. Your mother has such big plans for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that, Dad, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you have to understand, Francie, is that she... well... she wanted so much for herself too, and for me, and she never really got to... The only time I ever saw her happy was if her name was in the papers... but she could have been... if times were different she could have been a politician or... I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Dad, I'm asking about me. What do you think I should do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Francie, sometimes after you get your hands on something you want, it just doesn't look the same. Then you have to be real smart to know if you should hold onto it because it's all you've got... or just let it go. This is the way of things, but I guess you already know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad... whatever I decide, will it be okay with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances rises from her chair, looking around the room to hide her tears. Ernest rises too.</context>
      <utterance>Always. Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I... I don't have a desk in my room, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care, Dad. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other across the desk for an uncomfortable moment, then Frances slowly leaves. He looks sadly after her.</context>
      <utterance>I love you too, Francie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm back, Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Frances, do I have news for you! Guess who --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, Mama, wait. I have something to tell you. I've decided... well... I'm not going to make movies anymore. I thought that's what I wanted, and I went after it with all my soul, the way you taught me, but I was miserable, Mama, and it nearly killed me. So now... now it's over. I want a different kind of life, something... simple. I want to live someplace quiet and peaceful... in the country maybe, and I'll have dogs and cats -- I feel so light suddenly, so clear for the first time in... It's going to be okay, Mama, I know it. And I love you. She goes to hug her mother, but Lillian has changed. Frances' news has chilled her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't... talk crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to a stack of letters on the table.</context>
      <utterance>They want you back! Your agent called today! Don't you understand? He's sending the scripts. He wants to fly up here in a week with the publicity people! Frances, you can't do this to your fans! Why, they've been praying for you all through this nightmare. You can't turn your back on them now! Look at this fan mail I've been answering!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't you heard what I said?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told him to come up! I told him you wanted to show them all that there's nothing wrong with you any more, that you're completely cured!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not cured. I was never sick! They had no business putting me in there! My only responsibility is to myself now!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... you selfish, selfish child. At least talk to him, hear what he has to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to throw it all away, is that it? You had everything, little sister. Beauty... a brilliant career... a wonderful husband. You were a movie star!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama, shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now you're throwing everything away? You're gonna be a nobody! Nobody! You know what that's like?!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances grabs her coat.</context>
      <utterance>You... You'd send me back, wouldn't you? You would.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going out!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going anywhere!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am, and you can't stop me! You can't tell me what to do, mother. I'm a grown woman, and I can decide about my own life.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're wrestling, Lillian trying to prevent her from leaving.</context>
      <utterance>Frances!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs Lillian's wrists and twists them, throws her back.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you try and stop me. Don't you dare!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances storms out. Lillian sits back in the chair, suddenly looking very old. She massages her wrists...</context>
      <utterance>If you follow me, Mama, I swear I'll fucking kill you!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it. You've done it now, little sister.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All my life, I've tried to live up to my parents' example. To have the independence of mind and fortitude of spirit that have made this country great. I taught that to Frances: Speak out. Aspire. Make something of yourself, something --</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, Mrs. Farmer --</utterance>
   <speaker>ALMA STYLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DR. DOYLE, a psychiatrist, and the others are seated with Judge Hillier around a table.</context>
      <utterance>Frances has always been a battleground, Lillian.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The point is: it's your opinion that Frances is getting steadily worse?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle fills in a line on the printed form before him.</context>
      <utterance>Well... yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you feel you're unable to control her any longer?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alma holds up Lillian's bruised wrists as evidence.</context>
      <utterance>No... I mean, yes, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the only course open to you is to commit your daughter for a period of time to a mental institution?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alma looks coolly at Lillian.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Alma told me that...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hillier nods slightly, approvingly, toward Alma.</context>
      <utterance>...Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe that's all I need to know about Miss Farmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HILLIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think in all future documents she should be referred to as Mrs. R. H. Richardson.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her married name?</utterance>
   <speaker>HILLIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's less recognizable. I'm sure you'd prefer to keep unpleasant publicity to a minimum.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Oh yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HILLIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now. Can you tell us where we might find Frances?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind them is a large window covered by a gauzy curtain. In the street a police car cruises slowly past.</context>
      <utterance>...Looking for a drink, and the town is deserted, he can't understand it. Finally he finds a bar, goes in -- the place is empty, bartender's closing up. Salesman says, 'Gimme a martini.' Bartender's real nervous, he says, 'No, no, no, I gotta close. Big Otis is coming to town.'</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Salesman says, 'I don't care. I gotta have a martini.' So the bartender fixes him a martini real fast, grabs his money, and runs out the back. Salesman sits there sipping his martini,... he's got the bar all to himself... Then he hears it. This big roaring in the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO COPS appear at the window, looking in.</context>
      <utterance>Enormous hands reach in, grab the swinging doors and rip them off their hinges. This huge man stomps in. Picks up a chair and hurls it over the bar, smashing the mirror -- whiskey and glass flying everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs. A long moment of enjoyment. Then Frances turns, looks out the window and sees the cops.</context>
      <utterance>He turns to the salesman: 'What the hell're you doing in here!' Salesman says, 'I'm just drinking a martini.' 'Oh yeah?' the guy says. 'Well you better get outa here! Big Otis is coming to town!'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...From her history, it's apparent the patient suffers from a paranoid reaction with pronounced egotism. Her violent responses have recently included aggression against her mother. In view of the deep-seated nature of her ailments and her failure to respond satisfactorily to insulin shock, it is my opinion she may ultimately require permanent institutional care.</utterance>
   <speaker>HILLIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Counsellor, as Guardian ad litem for Mrs. Richardson, do you waive jury trial?</utterance>
   <speaker>STYLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, your Honor. She signs a paper which is passed to Hillier.</utterance>
   <speaker>HILLIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bangs his gavel.</context>
      <utterance>Having heard the testimony of a legally qualified and reputable physician... and being further satisfied of the truth of all matters set forth in the certificates of said physician, I do hereby order that the said Mrs. R. H. Richardson, an insane person, be confined to the Western State Hospital for the Insane at Steilacoom.</utterance>
   <speaker>HILLIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So ordered! Are the gentlemen from Steilacoom present?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOCTOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she getting, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Standard series to start.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doctor 2 nods and jams a rubber bar into Frances' mouth. The Medical Student steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Fifteen?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doctor 1 shoots a silent query to Doctor 2.</context>
      <utterance>Can I push the button on this one?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Medical Student pushes the button with great gravity. Frances' body immediately begins to convulse. It seems as if it will never stop.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor, it may sound odd, but I believe I've profited from my stay here. It's just what I've needed, to get away like this. But I'm recuperated now. I've had lots of time to think and I've made a few decisions about my life. I'm ready to get on with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you believe that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Attendants lower her into the empty tub.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid not. You see, we observe things that you're unaware of: signs, indicators. Your problem cuts very deep, Frances, and we have to get at that deeper stuff so that when you do get out, you'll really feel secure. Does that make sense?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Cut this runaround, Doctor. I know better.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to yourself, Frances. The resistance, the anger in your voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... I'm sorry, forgive me. Doctor, tell me honestly, what do I have to do to get out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be patient, that's all. Take an interest in your treatment and don't dwell on your resentments. You'll be yourself again, I assure you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll talk more about this. I'll see you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor smiles sympathetically.</context>
      <utterance>One question. If I'm not myself now, just who do you think I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he turns to leave, Frances laughs triumphantly. The two Attendants lower her into the bath and begin to fill it with ice-cold water.</context>
      <utterance>We'll talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shove a rubber bit between her teeth. She immediately spits it out and defiantly starts to sing in order to keep her teeth from chattering.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whole hall joins in. The Nurses make no effort to stop it. Others at Frances' table smile at her, try to push her to her feet. When they succeed, the hall breaks into applause and a new chaotic chant:</context>
      <utterance>Come and get it! Come and get it! Come and get it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chant is quickly silenced by hushing sounds. Everyone is watching Frances. She climbs up on her bench. Her eyes are glazed, her face expressionless. This feels like some kind of automatic behavior. She takes an exaggerated posture and speaks in almost a whisper:</context>
      <utterance>We want Frances! We want Frances!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hall breaks into riotous applause, catcalls, stomping. Frances climbs down from her bench. That was the entire performance.</context>
      <utterance>Come and get it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances! Frances!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances, it's me, Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Touch me again and I'll kill you, you pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry is on the verge of tears.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out, Harry. Let me look her over.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God! Let's get her out of here tonight, right now! Let's take her with us!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hearing's tomorrow. If she gets out legally, they can't come after her.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at her! She'll never pass that sanity test tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry holds her around the shoulders and straightens out her arm. Frances starts to struggle and moan loudly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm taking care of that, Harry. Just hold her.  Reserpine. I guarantee you this'll clear her head. She'll wake up feeling smart and sailright through the hearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry glares at the Doctor, but puts a hand over her mouth and the Doctor injects her. Her arm is covered with sores.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... she knows about these. Shut her up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor withdraws the hypo and massages her arm.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be okay, honey. He's just givin' you something to make you think, so that tomorrow you can tell 'em what they want to hear, okay? Tell 'em you were crazy as a loon and they cured you and you're grateful.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This stuff takes pretty quick. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Other women in the ward cry out: "Take me! Take me!!"</context>
      <utterance>Please! Take me!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here! I'll lose my job!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frances, we gotta do it this way. Just remember tomorrow, remember what I told you. What're you gonna tell 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm grateful... grateful.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMEN IN WARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm grateful! I'm grateful!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, please!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're all square now, Harry. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All square, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances' face appears at the tiny barred window. We can just hear her:</context>
      <utterance>Good. 'Cause I don't want to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Harry. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind Frances we HEAR the Women screaming: "I love you, Harry!" The Doctor takes Harry's arm and pulls him down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>I love you too, Frances.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I realize now that I was a very sick woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMEN IN WARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sick! She's sick!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't relate to others in a normal way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE PATIENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others laugh. We realize that if Frances can handle this, she can sail through it tomorrow. The catcalls gradually diminish as she concludes her speech.</context>
      <utterance>She's... not... normal...!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>astonishment, the other patients seem to believe her...</context>
      <utterance>And I was not taking responsibility for my actions. But now, thanks to your treatment, I feel ready to face myself, ready to resume the career which I so single-handedly shattered. I only hope... I hope I can make you all proud of me. Thank you. Thank you so much. The room is silent now. A very odd moment. To their</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, she hasn't anything definite in mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, it all depends on what offers I get.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches it shyly. It's swept up in a continental style.</context>
      <utterance>Who did your hair, Frances?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lillian laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I like to try different styles. Sometimes if you're old-fashioned enough, you find you're modern. Right, Mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think of all this, Mrs. Farmer?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a miracle. Just a miracle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, just leave those things for now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lillian smiles warmly at her.</context>
      <utterance>No, Mama, I'll take care of it. I'll wash them in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, little sister, I never resented you for refusing to see me in the... the hospital. I knew you had to manage on your own before you could come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lillian links her arm with Frances' and they go upstairs together.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for understanding, Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little sister, I don't want you to feel any rush to get back to work. I want you to rest... for a while anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hug each other.</context>
      <utterance>I will, I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lillian waits until Frances has shut her door before closing hers.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, dear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where to?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She approaches him tentatively.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Harry...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is it, kid. This is our chance. When you got a chance, you better take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't need to screw around anymore. You don't need Dwayne Steele or Odets or your mother. You need me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but... There were so many people in there, Harry. Every time I turned around someone was pressing against me... watching, looking over my shoulder, touching me, grabbing, sticking things into me. When I feel somebody near me now... anybody... my skin starts to crawl. Long beat. She turns and stares at him sadly.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods slowly.</context>
      <utterance>You can't change the things they did to me, Harry. Only I can do that... by myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been a lot of years, you know. A long time waiting. For what? End up feeling like a sap.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh please, Harry... don't even think it. You're the only person who ever... It's just... Can't you wait for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you do. If you love me you can wait, right? A month, six months, whatever it takes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Except... time has a way of --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Harry, it's not time, it's us. You and me. And I'm telling you now that I'll come to you, okay? I'll find you. I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hug. Together for an instant. Then she shivers as if the contact were too much.</context>
      <utterance>I hope so, Frances.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and walks slowly to his car.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be seeing you, kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's always beautiful at this time. Peaceful...</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And no people.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wherever they're going, I'm going.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know what that's like... Where you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops. She sees now that the car heading toward her is a cop car. She averts her face... then tries to hide her gesture.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I was picking fruit with some migrant workers until...</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances sighs as the cop car speeds away.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's uncertain whether to trust him. Takes the plunge:</context>
      <utterance>They're looking for you, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs. She shivers slightly, pulls her clothes around her. He takes out a small flask and offers, no strings:</context>
      <utterance>You know, I've never been able to figure that out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, truly grateful:</context>
      <utterance>I've got a little whiskey here, warm you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she sees a ball of dust nearing... a car on his side.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car stops. Its lights flashing. COPS jump out.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Maybe they'll pick you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does. She's pursued. The Hitchhiker makes an effort to impede the Cops' progress, but is tossed aside. The Cops are slowly, inevitably, gaining on her.</context>
      <utterance>Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernest writhes slightly with discomfort.</context>
      <utterance>Dad...? Why don't you stop at a side road and let me out?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Francie, you know I can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? It's such a simple thing. You just let me out and I disappear down a road and you never have to see me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We SEE them approaching a side road.</context>
      <utterance>They'll just catch you again, Francie. Besides, your mother will know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, here! You don't have to stop, just slow down. You can tell Mama I jumped out. She knows that's the kind of thing I'd do. She won't blame you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are nearer the side road.</context>
      <utterance>But I gave her my word. Besides, she's still your legal guardian. My hands are tied.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know where you're taking me. You know what she'll do. Just give me a minute, slow down, give me an instant for once in your life, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Francie...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass the side road. It disappears behind them. All the life seems to drain from Frances.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances buries her face in her hands.</context>
      <utterance>I'll try to protect you, Francie. I will, I'll talk to her. We'll have a real talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you... are you hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I pity us, Dad. I pity us both.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I go right away or do I have time to take a bath?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping for a kind word, little sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were hoping for a kind word?! You're my mother! You're supposed to nourish me! Support me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the window we SEE a white van pull up outside.</context>
      <utterance>I have!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! All you've done is try to break my spirit, try to turn me into you! But I'm not you, mother, and I never will be, and thank god for it!  That goes for you too! And frankly, I don't know how, with the two of you, I turned out as sane as I am --  Wait right there, gentlemen, I'll be with you in a minute... and believe me, I don't want to stay here one second longer than I have to!  But I've got to tell you, Lillian, that one day before you die, you will realize what you've done and hang your head in shame. In shame!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The way she goes out that door we know she's never coming back.</context>
      <utterance>No! You're not talking now. You listen. You can send me away, Lillian, you can pretend I'm crazy and pretend I'm still your little girl who can't take care of herself, but one thing you can't pretend anymore. You can't pretend I love you because I don't. I can't. Not after what you've done to me. Because you see... I'm still me... I'm trying real hard all this time to be me... and you, 'little sister', you haven't been any help at all.  Okay, boys, I'm ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two of the SOLDIERS, waiting their turn, are smoking cigarettes and chatting idly.</context>
      <utterance>We shall hear the angels, we shall see the whole sky all diamonds...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Best deal I ever made. Twenty bucks to fuck a fuckin' movie star.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's worth it I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she saying, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances keeps reciting as one rapist gets off. The Soldiers cheer as another quickly takes his place.</context>
      <utterance>Who knows. She's crazy, ain't she?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OLDER NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why they even bother. She's had enough of this to knock sense into a bull elephant.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I checked the files. This one holds the record for shock treatments. Four hundred seventeen and no end in sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, you know doctors. They sure hate to use that word.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Incurable.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry? Oh Harry, I knew you'd come. I love you, Harry. I love... Take me home, Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get you home, Frances.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's untied. The Orderly helps her up onto a gurney. She lies down. Doyle nods to the Orderly, who starts pushing her. She is wheeled out and down:</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Harry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DR. HARLINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The lights are bright, on her and the other patients. We cannot see, but we sense, an audience watching.</context>
      <utterance>One merely inserts the leucotome beneath the eyelid and presses up into the prefrontal lobe, manipulating it so as to sever the nervous connections between the thalamofrontal radiation and the body of the brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HARLINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Frances stares up at a fan in the ceiling. It's moving round and round. The voice drones on.</context>
      <utterance>Because of the speed and simplicity of the operation, I am able, as you are seeing, to perform the procedure on ten patients in less than a half hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HARLINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We now see vaguely that DR. HARLINGTON has moved to the patient on the adjacent gurney.</context>
      <utterance>The operation is completely painless and can be performed without any sedative whatsoever.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HARLINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances turns and stares mutely, without emotion, at what's happening next to her: the leucotome (an ice-pick-like instrument) is inserted into a woman's eye socket...</context>
      <utterance>We have always known that this form of radical treatment was effective, but until now it couldn't be applied on a large scale. The old procedure required a full day's work by a surgical team to perform a single operation. In the same time, working alone, I can treat fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HARLINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The leucotome is then shoved up into the brain and twisted.</context>
      <utterance>This procedure works best on patients with extreme over-reactions to emotional stimuli. It can also be used as a last resort on those who seem impervious to other forms of treatment.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HARLINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frances turns away and stares at the fan again. There is something simple and pleasing about its rhythmic whirring...</context>
      <utterance>In plain language, my technique severs the nerves which give emotional energy to ideas. Along with the cure comes a loss of affect... a kind of emotional flattening...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HARLINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We glimpse the leucotome being withdrawn.</context>
      <utterance>...with diminished creativity and imagination. Patients become like good solid cake with no icing. But, after all, it is their emotions and imaginations that are disturbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HARLINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harlington's face moves vaguely into Frances' view.</context>
      <utterance>These patients will soon be leaving the hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HARLINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves directly over Frances, his pleasant face obscuring the fan. As the leucotome descends, we:</context>
      <utterance>Lobotomy gets 'em home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernest is hunched in a chair by the stone fireplace. FOUR REPORTERS crouch on the floor, totally bored. Yesterday's headlines are now old news.</context>
      <utterance>What was I saying? Oh yes, it was the Communists that did it to Frances.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two Reporters rise and edge toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>They capture the mind by first seducing the heart. I suppose I never taught Frances to close her heart...</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... excuse us, Mrs. Farmer. We're going to have to... uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I better pack it in too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The last Reporter gets to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Pardon? Oh, would you like more lemonade?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernest looks at her wearily, as if she is stark raving mad. He knows damn well Frances isn't coming home... FADE IN ON: A TELEVISION SCREEN against a dark background The show is "This Is Your Life". We SEE a smiling RALPH EDWARDS, reading from a large black book. Next to him stands Frances. She has aged dramatically, but is still a very handsome woman. She seems uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>You know, Ernie, I think we should have Frances' room repainted for when she comes home. That'll brighten her day.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Throughout this, Frances' jaw works slowly back and forth, not from anger, but in embarrassment and doubt.</context>
      <utterance>...Dwayne Steele divorced you, and from this point on, your story takes a darker turn. Shunned by the Hollywood you criticized so harshly, alienated from your family and friends, you turn your back on professional commitments in New York, and alcohol and drugs enter your life. These are sad, desperate times for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...until finally your mother finds it necessary to commit you to a state mental institution. Were you mentally ill, Frances?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We MOVE AWAY from the screen to see that the TV set is in the living room of a comfortable, tastefully furnished home. On the couch in front of the set sits Harry York. He still looks athletic, young for his age. Tears stream down his cheeks.</context>
      <utterance>...No, Ralph. I don't believe I ever was sick. But when you're treated like a patient long enough, you're apt to act like one...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARDS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you an alcoholic?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARDS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you a drug addict?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ON THE SCREEN Edwards has moved Frances over to a seating area where various people from Frances' life are waiting, smiling at her. We've never seen any of them before.</context>
      <utterance>No. Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The curtains behind them open to reveal a car in a spotlight.</context>
      <utterance>...and over 200 producers have been invited to watch your appearance here tonight... so who knows, Frances Farmer, anything's possible on your comeback trail!  And since your friends tell me they have to drive you everywhere, look what we've got for you!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience applauds. Frances smiles guardedly.</context>
      <utterance>A brand new 1958 Edsel!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Ralph.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Applause.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Frances. And after the show we're hosting a reception for you and your friends at Hollywood's own Roosevelt Hotel!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience applauds. Frances smiles wearily and accepts congratulations.</context>
      <utterance>So, Frances Farmer, this is your life. Good night. God bless you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where shall we drop you, Frances? Home?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She turns. Harry is leaning against the side of a building, looking much as he did when they first met. But there is very little light of recognition in Frances' eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mere. I want to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry is a little puzzled by her reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Why, Harry York. How nice to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How... how ya doin', Farmer?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, thank you. Did you watch the show?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I did, that's why I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you...  ...ennh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are both silent a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>Well... you're looking well.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a new car. Only it's red. Did you know Mama died?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yeah, I heard about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, too. I sold the house. I'm a faceless sinner, Harry...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry is alarmed now.</context>
      <utterance>I'd ask you to take me home, but I'm a faceless sinner.  ...You smell good, Harry. Familiar, you know? I'd ask you to take me home, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She angrily bares her teeth; then just as suddenly she relaxes and becomes lucid.</context>
      <utterance>Frances!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds on like an old woman, stroking his hand. For an instant she gets lost in time, just holding his hand. Then she looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get mad at me, Harry. Please. It's just... Some things happen for the best. Beat. She takes his hand as if to shake it. Harry clasps hers tenderly.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going to be slow from now on. Do you know what I mean, Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very slow.  But we're not going to stop, are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is as if she is able to express in words the last remnant of her indomitable will... but the words bear no emotional power.</context>
      <utterance>No, we're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Harry. It was very good to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Would you like me to walk a little way with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers his arm. She takes it. All rather formal. They stroll on together.</context>
      <utterance>Just a little way.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
