<movie id="217" title="Freddy vs Jason">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lizzy. What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan looks at the drawings -- childlike renderings of Freddy.</context>
      <utterance>Playing with my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan slowly gets to her knees and takes a peek under Lizzy's bed. Suddenly, a doll-sized Freddy scurries out from under the bed, flashing past Meagan's face and running out the door. Meagan yelps and touches her face -- five tiny slash marks on her cheek. Lizzy clucks.</context>
      <utterance>He lives under the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan looks out the door, incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>You scared him...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But when Meagan looks back, Lizzy is gone.</context>
      <utterance>I scared him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy echoes away as Meagan finds herself standing in the...</context>
      <utterance>Lizzy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan screams. Freddy leaps out of the casket in a tuxedo, crooning:</context>
      <utterance>Where ya been all my death, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATANIC PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan looks to her left -- four girls hold bouquets, dressed in body bags.</context>
      <utterance>Are the bridesmaids in attendance?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATANIC PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy opens his tuxedo jacket to reveal several trapped souls struggling to get out of his chest.</context>
      <utterance>And the groomsmen...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATANIC PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>>From the back of the chapel, a voice:</context>
      <utterance>If anyone here believes that these two should not be joined in unholy matrimony, let him speak now or forever rot in hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan turns. It's her boyfriend -- JESSE. He stands in the chapel doorway, backlit by bright light, arms outstretched.</context>
      <utterance>Meagan!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan runs to Jesse and grabs him, their arms encircling one another. She looks up into Jesse's eyes... only it isn't Jesse. It's Jason. Meagan screams as Jason raises his machete, bringing it down between her eyes...</context>
      <utterance>Jesse!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the doll opens it's eyes and sneers:</context>
      <utterance>Freddy...</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY DOLL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Freddy doll flashes it's tiny glove of knives, thrusting them deep into Meagan's chest.</context>
      <utterance>Well it ain't Raggedy Ann, bitch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy's eyes flutter open. She smiles at her sister, then frowns.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up, sleepy head. Time to wake up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a bad dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry... they can't hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy hugs Meagan.</context>
      <utterance>Promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never let anyone hurt you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NEWS REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As the sun rises on yet another morning, still no end in sight for the standoff between police and the mysterious group known only as the "Freddy" cult who seized the abandoned house behind me just thirteen days ago. These cultists -- mostly run- away teenagers -- have managed to keep police at bay for almost two weeks while inside they take mind- altering narcotics in order to communicate with their god -- Freddy. The reporter babbles on as Meagan enters the kitchen where MEAGAN'S MOM is sitting watching the TV, gulping down orange juice. Across from mom is MEAGAN'S DAD, who is having coffee, reading the paper. Meagan pours herself a cup and sits.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan's mom grunts, transfixed on the news. Dad looks over his paper long enough to smile and say, just a little too cheerfully:</context>
      <utterance>Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan looks over at her mother, then back at her father, mouthing the words "How's mom?", when suddenly Meagan's mom bellows:</context>
      <utterance>Morning, Meagan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON TV -- a police booking photo of FRED KRUEGER.</context>
      <utterance>Lizzy! Get down here! Breakfast is almost ready! Meagan turns back to her dad but he has ducked back into his paper. Meagan sighs and sips her coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWS REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan's younger sister -- LIZZY -- comes down to breakfast. The microwave DINGS and Meagan's mom pulls out three Pop Tarts, dealing them out to her family like playing cards. Lizzy picks up her Pop Tart, whining.</context>
      <utterance>Alleged child murderer Fred Krueger was released on a legal technicality but later burned to death at the hands of a vigilante mob of grieving parents. Some years later, a rash of bizarre and unexplainable teen- age deaths began leaving many in the area to wonder... is Freddy really dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up and eat. You don't want to be late for special school.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom! Don't call it that!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan snickers.</context>
      <utterance>I hate that school. The other kids are mean... and they're all re- tard-ed!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad looks over at mom, who shoots him an angry look. Dad takes a bite of his Pop Tart, sinking back behind the paper.</context>
      <utterance>We don't use that word. They're "special" children just like you're "special".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>NEWS REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A horn TOOTS outside.</context>
      <utterance>The cult members have declined to an on-camera interview but did send out a note with a message. The note -- which, by the way, appears to have been written in blood -- reads...  To the parents of Springwood -- Freddy lives! Soon he will come and take one of your children as his virgin bride. Then Freddy will -BEEP- and his -BEEP- upon her -BEEP- and -BEEP- and behold, a soulless child shall be born. The vessel for Freddy to rise and rule the darkness forever and ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan collects her books and her sister. This is dad's cue to look at his watch and say:</context>
      <utterance>That's Jesse. Let's go, Lizzy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, look at the time! I've got to be going... anyone need me to bring anything home tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need an alarm clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with your old one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan kisses her dad as she and Lizzy hurry out the door. Meagan's dad looks over at his wife, who says:</context>
      <utterance>Broke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're almost out of vodka.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning! Hey, what's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mom...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had another dream last night...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was I naked?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You were Jason.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan playfully smacks him as Jesse's car ROARS off.</context>
      <utterance>Jason? Oh, yeech...  Was I any good?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mom reaches over and switches off the TV. Dad smiles slightly and exits. Mom waits until the door closes, then takes a bottle of vodka and pours a goodly bit into her orange juice. She takes a deep drink and switches the set back on. CLOSE ON TV as the news reporter interviews CAPTAIN RENTON MURDOCH -- State Trooper.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have to watch that crap all the time? Months and months of the O.J. Simpson trial, and now this...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWS REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm standing here with State Trooper Captain Renton Murdoch, the man the Governor has called in to deal with the cultists because of his past experience with occult-style murderers. In fact, Trooper Murdoch is the only law enforcement officer ever to survive a one-on-one encounter with notorious Camp Crystal Lake killer -- Jason Voorhees.  You received some pretty nasty injuries in your battle with Jason, didn't you, Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing serious... just a few stitches.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWS REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about these so called "Freddy" cultists? They seem like pretty tough customers. Think you'll have any trouble getting them out of there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Now that the Governor has given me complete authority to deal with these punks I should be putting an end to their situation pretty quick. Unless of course their attorney is able to get them to come out peace- fully... but I don't hold out much hope for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWS REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Renton Murdoch, ladies and gentlemen. A tough cop... for tough criminals.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn media... oughtta be a law.  Is that shyster still in there trying to talk them out?</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... he's making them some kind of deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn lawyers... what a bunch of assholes. Shakespeare was right -- kill all the lawyers. Then we could kill all the punks with no hassles and the world would be a safer place.</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smaller anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhhh... what did Shakespeare know? Long-haired, English freak. He was probably a punk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL HOSTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The S.W.A.T. commander rushes to the girl, kneeling down to look at the bomb. Then he takes a Leatherman tool from his vest and starts to work on the bomb's timer.</context>
      <utterance>Help me, mister... please.</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murdoch comes down the stairs. He goes to the secret passageway and says:</context>
      <utterance>Hang on, honey... I'll have you out of there in a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like we'll have to hunt the rest of them down. Let's go before they get too far.</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murdoch looks at the little girl and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>We can't leave! Can't you see we've got a situation here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave her.</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy! I can't just leave her!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's nothing you can do.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. I've seen this before.</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The S.W.A.T. commander wipes his brow and leans in to work on the bomb again. CLOSE ON TIMER: 24...</context>
      <utterance>I've got to try...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the dust settles, the S.W.A.T. commander rolls off the little girl and starts checking her for injury.</context>
      <utterance>Punks.</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the little girl jumps onto the S.W.A.T. commander, flashing a glove of knives. She hisses:</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL HOSTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a quick swing, the little girl slashes the commander's face. She dives back for a plunge to his throat when Murdoch walks up and kicks her off. He puts his boot on her, holding her down as he takes aim on her head with his pistol -- execution style.</context>
      <utterance>Freddy lives!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus... you were going to kill that kid, weren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you you were wasting your time. Once these kids go rabid, best thing to do is put 'em down.</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't be serious...</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead serious. See... the world is made up of rules. Kids don't like rules. They rebel for a while, but ultimately they start to fall in line and become ordinary Joe's like you and me. But some kids... dope smokers mainly, watching their MTV... Satanic lyrics melting what's left of their brains... these kids grow up to be punks. And when these punks step as far over the line as these "Freddy" punks have -- then we as peace officers have no choice but to kill them.</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't become a peace officer to kill kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Punks. There's a difference...  ...barely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MISS KREPPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meagan starts to drift off, when...</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS KREPPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meagan!?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS KREPPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked if you were ready to give your oral report?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... I'm ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS KREPPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan gets up and goes to the podium amidst the snickers of some of her classmates. Miss Krepps snaps her fingers for quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Please come up here to the podium.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS KREPPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't think it's funny when you haven't learned the fundamentals of a free market economy... oh, why do I waste my breath? You're all going to grow up to be gas station attendants and waitresses anyway. Go ahead, Meagan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fan on Miss Krepps' desk starts to CLICK louder, BLOWING harder. Meagan raises an eyebrow but continues with her report.</context>
      <utterance>My report is on Global Economic Trends.  Try and think of a world where there is no poverty... no sickness... no crime. A world where everyone is happy to be alive and everyone lives together in peace. This is my dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This dream is becoming a reality with ever-growing international business... CLOSE ON THE FAN as it changes... getting creepier... turning into a Freddy-fan. BLOWING harder... CLICKING louder.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS KREPPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan repeats the last few sentences, raising her voice to be heard over the fan. Then pages of her report start to blow away. She grabs at them as the WIND increases. A bottle of glue stowed in the podium overturns and spills to the floor at Meagan's feet. She bends over to pick it up, when her skirt blows up. She presses it down but the WIND is too great and the skirt billows up, revealing her underwear. The class roars with laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Louder, Meagan. We can't hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan screams, clutching at the last few tiny strands of cloth that cover her body. She calls to Jesse, pleading:</context>
      <utterance>Aww... all dressed up and nowhere to blow!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Jesse just sits at his desk -- dead. He reaches up and slowly lowers a hockey mask over his pale, expressionless face.</context>
      <utterance>Jesse... please, help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy pulls out an over-sized camera with a gargantuan flashgun attached. The flash bulb is the size of a beach ball and has a nuclear warning etched in the front. Freddy sizes Meagan up in the viewfinder and sneers:</context>
      <utterance>Looks like a photo opportunity to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PHOOMPH!!! -- the flash bulb goes off with an atomic light. Meagan screams as her skeleton is blown back against the blackboard -- vaporized!</context>
      <utterance>Say... cheesecake!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MISS KREPPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meagan? Meagan?! Meagan looks around, bewildered and confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS KREPPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked if you were ready to give your report? Meagan realizes that she was dreaming and pulls herself together.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan stands up and faints.</context>
      <utterance>Sure...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SCHOOL NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan is laying on a couch, a cloth over her head.</context>
      <utterance>Meagan? Can you hear me? Do you know where you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was day dreaming and then I woke up but then it was like I was still dreaming and then I woke up and then I guess I fainted and now I'm awake again...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHOOL NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan stares at the nurse for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHOOL NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meagan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm waiting to see if you're going to turn into Freddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHOOL NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freddy... I see. You've been watching too much CNN. That crazy "Freddy" cult thing -- it's all over the TV day and night -- you can't get away from it. No wonder you kids are all having nightmares.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this one was different... it felt real.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHOOL NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's just it, Meagan... dreams aren't real. They're just broken fragments of the subconscious mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear is real though, isn't it? And if nightmares are fear, then doesn't that make them real?!  And if the nightmares are real then is reality like a dream?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHOOL NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nurse slaps a wet towel over her face.</context>
      <utterance>Meagan! You've got heat prostration... that's all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old witch... what does she know? She isn't even qualified to give a shot and she's telling me that my dreams aren't anything to worry about.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So she said you were okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruined my makeup, too.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure... Madame Curie in there says it's just a case of heat pro- stration and an overdose of TV news.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're going back to class?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. She gave me last period off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what are you bitching about? I could have a compound fracture of the skull and she wouldn't excuse me from P.E.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesse! I've been having nightmares for almost two weeks now and they keep getting worse! Now I'm having daymares! I want to know why!</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan rolls her eyes in frustration.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... well, didn't the nurse say it was heat probation?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't understand... I want to know more about dreams. What they mean... why we have them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Meg, go look it up. You've got the rest of the day off, that's all I'm saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a good idea. Why don't you cut last period and come with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The library.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to cut school so we can go to the library?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse looks up suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>Find anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over Jesse's shoulder we see he has a copy of ROAD &amp; TRACK tucked inside his psychology book.</context>
      <utterance>What? Oh, no... nothing yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know that our sub-conscious retains everything that ever happened to us? Everything. From the time we're born until we die.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's how Freddy gets at us... by using our sub-conscious fears. Fears our conscious minds have repressed or forgotten.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy's dead.</context>
      <utterance>I've got a news flash for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not so sure... if Freddy exists in our sub-conscious then he can never be fully erased. Like a bad memory... you may blot it out of your mind but it will alway be hiding someplace in your dreams.  Weren't you scared as a child by something so stupid that you're ashamed to admit it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... when I was kid, my brother took me to the carnival. And in the penny arcade there was this robot gunslinger...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Black Bart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know about Black Bart?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duh. You put your quarter in and he says, "Go ahead and draw, tenderfoot." And then you pull your gun out and shoot him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So I always got killed.</context>
      <utterance>That's just it -- I never could! I'd point the gun right at him and shoot, and I could never hit the guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one can hit him -- it's a gyp.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan tries to hide her smile.</context>
      <utterance>Scared the shit out of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan laughs. Somebody shushes her.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that scary? I mean... for a kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dark mood falls over Meagan as her mind winds back.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, smartass... what about you? What scared you the most as a kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember... Lizzy wandered off one day and we couldn't find her. The police came and everything. I wasn't really worried until I saw her picture on TV... then I got really scared.  Jesse, I can't explain it... but I think something bad's going to happen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're stupid!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They forgot you again!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they didn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, they forgot and you're goin' to wait out here until it's dark and then the monsters are goin' come and get you!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy gets to her feet and starts walking. Leonard calls after her:</context>
      <utterance>No they won't, because I'm walkin' home!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy keeps going, marching across the deserted school yard. Leonard turns to go inside the school when he bumps into a passing CULTIST. The cultist pushes him down as he follows after Lizzy.</context>
      <utterance>Come back, Lizzy! You can wait with me! I got forgot too, you know!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you get my message?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What message?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I had to stay late after work...</context>
      <utterance>I called the school after lunch...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you dare blame this on her, you sorry bastard! It's all your fault!  Where have you been anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The library.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan's mom breaks down sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>A likely Goddamn story!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where's Lizzy?</context>
      <utterance>Dad... what's wrong? What's happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't come home from school today. The police got a report that a girl fitting Lizzy's description was forced into a car by some crazies. They're pretty sure it was this "Freddy" cult.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan's dad puts his arm around Meagan and tries to comfort her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan looks over and sees Murdoch talking to his men when a voice from upstairs calls down:</context>
      <utterance>Now don't worry. The police are doing everything they can.</utterance>
   <speaker>TROOPER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Cap'n... better have a look up here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TROOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like she was in the cult all along.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy wouldn't join Freddy's cult!</context>
      <utterance>No... no, she wouldn't do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>TROOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murdoch stares at the drawings, his jaw muscles tightening. He clenches his fist, pulverizing the little unicorn.</context>
      <utterance>I know it's hard to believe, miss. But a lot of good kids get caught up in this kind of trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murdoch drops the broken pieces of the unicorn on the table as he exits the room, brushing past Meagan.</context>
      <utterance>Punks...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Murdoch... is there any- thing we can do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murdoch and his men say "good-bye" and quickly exit.</context>
      <utterance>You can pray, sir. Pray we find your daughter before... well, before it's too late. But rest assured, if I can't persuade her to come back to her loving home, then I'll do what's best for her. I know you and your wife wouldn't want her to suffer.  Come on... I want to go talk to Erwin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over to Stormie's.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stormie? I thought you and her weren't friends anymore since she stole that twenty dollars from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She dumped him a long time ago.</context>
      <utterance>That was her "klepto" phase... when she was dating that gang member.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still don't understand. What has she got to do with Lizzy missing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exit to Jesse's car.</context>
      <utterance>She used to be in the Freddy cult. Maybe she knows where they took Lizzy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I did know I would call the police, you know that. I love Lizzy. No telling what those freaks will do to her. Those Freddy cult guys are hard core.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were in the cult?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was in the cult for a week cause my boyfriend at the time... Slasher, he was. But I just liked the music and the clothes... when they were clean, but not like the violence and stuff. But that was just my "cult" phase... but I got past that. You know, just like my "gang" phase when I was dating Ramon and then before that was my "death rock" phase when I was dating Stuart...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, excuse me... but what phase are we in now?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Militant feminist, man-hating phase, what's it fuckin' to ya?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just let the cops find her? That guy Renton Murdoch -- he knows how to deal with these cultist psychos. He was the man who got Jason Voorhees.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy in my dreams...</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jason kicked his ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's different about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One thing... he used to be a Democrat. Now he votes straight Republican.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he thinks Lizzy joined the cult or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God... he'll kill her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to find Lizzy myself. I've got to find her and save her from Freddy before that crazy cop kills her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just where are you going to look? I mean, these cult guys could be holding her anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Murdoch said something about going to talk to somebody named Erwin.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erwin Kelper! He used to be in the Freddy cult! I bet he knows where they took Lizzy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not Squirmin' Erwin -- that freak that used to eat bugs?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else?  Erwin is scary smart -- always brought home "A"s -- but he was kinda fucked up, too... I mean, who isn't really? Anyway, he quit the cult a few months back and the cops put him away for his own safety. They say Freddy's put a death hex on Erwin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A death hex?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, a death hex. You know... where someone wants you dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be mad... it's just that you might scare him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scare him?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What she's subtly trying to tell you is that this needs a woman's gentle touch... butthead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse grudgingly agrees. Meagan kisses Jesse on the cheek. Stormie sticks her tongue out at him, then turns as she and Meagan walk toward the main entrance.</context>
      <utterance>Just stay here... okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard exits. Meagan and Stormie peer through the thick window -- Erwin's padded cell appears vacant. They exchange anxious looks, then Meagan presses a little closer to the glass.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, Erwin... you've got a couple of visitors. Now be a good boy...  You've got five minutes. I'll be right down the hall if you need me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPLAT! -- ERWIN suddenly presses his horribly burned face to the glass as he screams:</context>
      <utterance>Erwin...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you shoot?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's talking about dream dope -- the stuff the cultists shoot up with so they can talk to Freddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't do drugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not in the cult?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't Freddy send you to kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN/STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't trust you... better take off your clothes so I can check you for tracks.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin flops the arms of his straight jacket, gesturing to the inside of his cell -- empty except for a small mattress.</context>
      <utterance>Chill, Erwin. We're here for some hard data -- not a floppy disk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what do you want? Can't you see I'm busy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freddy's cult kidnapped my sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told her you might know where they took her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already told the cops everything I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me... please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look... I'm sorry about your sister, but I've got my own problems with Freddy. I'm a marked man, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then tell me why they took her...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To bear his child. Freddy wants to be human again. In order to do that he has to be "reborn".</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can he do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has to marry a virgin on holy ground. Then the cult consumate the marriage by impregnating her.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whole cult? Yeech!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's sort of a tradition with him.</context>
      <utterance>Freddy's the son of a hundred maniacs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the cult gets Lizzy pregnant?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment as the girls take this in, then:</context>
      <utterance>And Freddy enters the soul of the fetus through a dream state. Voila! Rebirth.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the stupidest shit I ever heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, they're not my rules... some- body else wrote 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin thinks about this for a second, then:</context>
      <utterance>Erwin... you've got to help me find Lizzy. You're my only hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll help you find your sister, but you've got to help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything. Just name it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan and Stormie exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>You have to help me kill Freddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Freddy's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stormie grabs Meagan by the arm and starts to pull her away.</context>
      <utterance>Freddy lives...  If only in our dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Meagan stays put and asks Erwin:</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Meagan... our five minutes is up. He's giving me the creeps.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you kill a dream?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin presses his palm against the glass. Meagan thinks a moment, then puts her hand against the glass over his.</context>
      <utterance>When it's not a dream.  Do we have a deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I won't do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Jesse! Please...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's illegal! I could go to jail!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How will they ever know? Don't be such a pussy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah? Why don't you call then?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I will!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! They'll never believe her!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can disguise my voice...  Hello, how do you do? My name is Jesse. I think I'm a man but I'm actually a wimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll never believe that. Come on, Jesse... for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse sighs and steps into the phone booth. After a moment's hesitation, Jesse steps out and immediately both girls blurt out ten reasons why he should make the call. Jesse calls for quiet and as soon as both girls shut up, he says:</context>
      <utterance>Okay... okay... I'll do it.  And I'm not a wimp!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Springwood Mental Center... how can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a bomb planted in your building.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the background, we hear Meagan and Stormie whisper something to Jesse.</context>
      <utterance>If I were you -- I'd get my ass out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLICK! -- The guard's eyes grow wide.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah... Freddy Lives.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin ignores him, still moving towards the fence.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Erwin... where do you think you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not going to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With grim determination, Jesse starts his car. Jesse's car tears out of the parking lot, racing for the fence. With a loud, metallic CHING, Jesse's car drives into the fence, knocking that section down. Erwin dances over the downed chain-link, diving into an open window. Then, with a SQUEAL of tires and the RENDING of metal, Jesse's car backs out of the fence, does a 180, and PEELS off. ANGLE INSIDE CAR as Stormie and Meagan help Erwin out of his straight jacket. Once freed, Erwin extends his hand to Jesse.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to do something!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse looks at Erwin's outstretched hand -- the fingertips are all heavily bandaged.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, my name's Erwin. Thanks for busting me out of there!</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The security guard runs up to the fence, huffing and puffing, watching as Jesse's car disappears down the street. Then he spots something in the fence and plucks it out... Jesse's front license plate.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right... Look, Erwin, just do me one favor -- don't eat nothing disgusting. My stomach is tight enough as it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan spots Lizzy's shirt sleeve on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Damn! We must have just missed them!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God -- she was here! This is part of Lizzy's shirt! It's all torn!  Erwin... we've got to find her!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>except...</context>
      <utterance>We're too late! There's no way...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except what?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could go after Freddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin goes to a boiler, bends down and reaches way up underneath. After fishing around for a moment, he draws out a well-worn Mutant Ninja Turtles lunch box. Inside -- a vile of liquid, several syringes, and several pairs of cult shades.</context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan thinks about this for a moment, then nods her approval.</context>
      <utterance>We'll inject ourselves with Dream Dope. It's a mild narcotic that brings on a dreamlike state.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... let's do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse jerks a thumb toward Erwin.</context>
      <utterance>Meagan... we don't do drugs! I mean, what if one of us gets hooked or something?  We could turn out like him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. We need you wide awake anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin hands Jesse an old rusty revolver.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to go under and try to find Freddy. When we do, we'll grab him and bring him here. Then you kill him with this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This rusty chunk of shit? What good is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not the gun, it's what's in it -- silver bullets blessed by a priest.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will that work?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should. But then...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't make the rules... yeah, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin hands Meagan and Stormie each a pair of the sunglasses with flashing red diodes in each lens. Stormie puts hers on immediately and says:</context>
      <utterance>Have a seat over there and make yourselves comfortable. Roll up your sleeves and put these on...</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, cool!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All of this went over Meagan's head. Stormie shrugs:</context>
      <utterance>It's how the cult keeps in constant contact with Freddy. The little lights flashing are a sustained occular input that causes your brain to resonate at approximately the same frequency at which the dream state is most likely to occur.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(to Meagan; excited) Put 'em on -- they're really cool! Meagan and Stormie sit down in easy chairs, rolling up their sleeves. Erwin comes over and reclines the chairs, giving each girl an injection. Then Erwin takes a seat next to Meagan and injects himself. He lets the syringe drop to the floor as he lowers his glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan clasps hands with Erwin and Stormie. Jesse watches with skepticism and concern. Erwin ushers a final warning:</context>
      <utterance>It helps to hold hands if you want to go together...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then all three FALL THROUGH their chairs into...</context>
      <utterance>And remember... Freddy knows what scares you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meagan... help me... please... Meagan enters a shaft, following the sound when suddenly, the shaft closes up behind her. Stormie and Erwin try to find the opening again but can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freddy's trying to split us up...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy opens up his shirt to reveal a chest full of lost souls. In the center -- Meagan. Stormie charges Freddy, throwing her arms around him as she screams to Erwin:</context>
      <utterance>Looking for some-body?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Erwin is paralyzed with fear.</context>
      <utterance>I've got him! Wake us up! Wake us up!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't just stand there! Wake us up!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Stormie's arms have become huge lobster claws. She jerks away from Freddy, but too late -- Stormie starts to change into a giant lobster-woman! Freddy smiles -- now he's wearing a chef's hat and apron.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmmmm... I feel like seafood tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy knocks the lobster-woman over the side. She falls into the boiling water far below -- KER-SPLASH!</context>
      <utterance>Stew on this, bitch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse spins, aiming the pistol. But nothing is there.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot him! Shoot him!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin stares wide-eyed, frozen to the spot.</context>
      <utterance>Well, well, well... if it isn't my ol' pal, Erwin.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got something special in mind for you... Suddenly, Erwin reaches into his sleeve and pulls out a pin. Freddy gawks -- surprised. Erwin pricks his finger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up and quietly shushes her.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Meagan's dad disappears. Only the newspaper remains. Then Meagan hears Lizzy's VOICE again... upstairs. As she comes down the upstairs hallway, Meagan passes her mother's room. The door is open a crack. Meagan looks in and sees her mother putting an empty bottle to her lips. The bottle sucks the life out of Meagan's mom, who shrivels up into an ugly ol' prune face. Meagan starts to help her mother when Lizzy's cry for help draws her to...</context>
      <utterance>Shuuuuu! I'm trying to be invisible...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan pulls back the covers to reveal that Lizzy is pregnant, her naked, swollen stomach protruding from her night gown. Something inside is trying to push it's way out.</context>
      <utterance>Help me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy screams. Meagan moves to help her sister when Freddy's glove BURSTS OUT of Lizzy's stomach, stabbing Meagan in the chest.</context>
      <utterance>Meagan...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They help Meagan to her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He got away... I had him and he got away. Oh, God... Lizzy... I lost her...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, atleast you're not dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I'm not dead...  No... I'm not. But Freddy killed me!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stormie raises her shirt up to show Meagan she is unharmed. Erwin sneaks a look and Stormie smacks him. Meagan gets to her feet, asking:</context>
      <utterance>He killed me, too. But look...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that I think about it -- he's killed me in all my nightmares. But I'm not dead... what does it mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means we've still got some time left. Until his remains are host to the Dream Demons -- Freddy can't hurt us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello. The Dream Demons...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freddy made a pact with Satan when he died... so Satan bestowed upon him the Dream Demons. They're the source of Freddy's power to manipulate our physical reality. Without them... he's powerless -- nothing more than a bad dream.  Hey, like I said... I don't make the rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we've still got a chance, right? A chance to kill Freddy before he gets back his power?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We already tried that. There's no way for us to kill Freddy. He's too clever. He knows how to get to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let's get somebody else. Some- body strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! We could hire somebody to kill Freddy -- like a hit man!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would have to hire a thousand of them... or one really big guy who isn't afraid of anything. No fear. Nada. Then you got a shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse's last three words strike Meagan like a thunder- bolt and she stammers out a name:</context>
      <utterance>Where are you going to find a hit man? The yellow pages? In your dreams...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jason...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jason?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jason Voorhees...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The perfect dream warrior... no fear.</context>
      <utterance>Jason Voorhees... that's brilliant!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like our man!</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... excuse me, Einstein... but isn't Jason Voorhees dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seriously dead. Buried up by Crystal Lake somewhere. But don't worry, I know how to bring him back to life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somehow I just knew you would.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's not the problem. The problem is control. Once we bring Jason back from the dead... I'm not one hundred percent sure he'll do what we tell him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin rolls his eyes around -- uncertain.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's okay... as long as he doesn't chop us all up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erwin... I'm trusting you on this, so tell me the truth. Do you think if we do this -- if we go and get Jason and bring him back to life, that he could kill Freddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No doubt about. Jason could wreck Freddy on this side of the Dreamline. But if Freddy has home court advan- tage... I don't know. Too close to call. The trick would be to get Jason to enter a dream state, grab Freddy, and drag him out to our reality.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't got a choice. I've got to try something...  I can't ask either of you to help me do this... it's illegal, immoral, disgusting...</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan embraces Stormie, then all three turn to Jesse. He looks them over and sighs:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, we sisters have to stand together, right? Where you lead -- I'll follow. Count me in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me get this straight... we're going to go dig one dead maniac up to fight another dead maniac?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's about the size of it... and I'd be doing you a disservice if I said there weren't a modicum of risk involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meagan... I don't want to do this...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to, Jesse... it's not your fight. I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan hugs Jesse. Erwin tries to hug Stormie but she pushes him away.</context>
      <utterance>But I damn sure don't want you to do it without me. Count me in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look out Freddy... here we come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NIGHT WATCHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the old man hears it, too... A low RUMBLE. Moving closer. The night watchman steps out of his shack and squints into the darkness when a line of several hearses approaches. The lead hearse pulls up to the shack and the driver's window rolls down.</context>
      <utterance>What's matter, girl... you hear somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHT WATCHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this? A funeral procession? A Freddy cultist sticks his face out of the window and says:</utterance>
   <speaker>CULTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's exactly what it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHT WATCHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Whose?</utterance>
   <speaker>CULTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BANG! -- the cultist SHOOTS the old man right through the head. The night watchman falls to the ground with a lifeless THUD. The little dog starts BARKING ferociously when another SHOT silences her as well. Another cultist leaps out of the hearse and runs to the gate, cutting the chain with a pair of bolt cutters. He swings the gate open and the funeral procession proceeds inside.</context>
      <utterance>Yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're almost there...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should pull over and ask directions.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>ooops, sorry! There aren't any.</context>
      <utterance>If it doesn't offend the men...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very funny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think they're open.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse HONKS the horn and yells:</context>
      <utterance>It says, open all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Can we get some service out here?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a CRAZY OL' COOT appears on the opposite side with a shotgun. Everyone in the car jumps.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think there's anybody here...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you kids want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>somewhere.</context>
      <utterance>We're looking for the old cemetery that's supposed to be around here...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to know for?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We want to see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>'cept a bunch of ol' graves.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't nothin' to see, girly...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man gives the occupants of the car a going over with his one good eye, hesitating a moment over Erwin, who scrunches down in the back seat, hiding under a baseball cap.</context>
      <utterance>Look, mister... can you give us directions or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not goin' up there to do somethin' stupid, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stupid? Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone in the car takes a sharp breath -- cold busted! Then they start saying "No! No!" and shaking their heads innocently in a big performance that wouldn't fool a stick.</context>
      <utterance>Like dig up Jason Voorhees -- that's what!</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus... why would anyone do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno... but people do.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been dug up a few times already, has he?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More times than I care to remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ol' coot scans the foursome again closely as he acquiesces.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we're just doing an article for our high school newspaper about the dangers of breaking into cemeteries at night. You know, stuff that can get you hurt...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse is already standing on the gas, leaving the ol' coot standing in a cloud of smoke and dust.</context>
      <utterance>Well... okay... as long as you're not going up there to do something stupid.  Take this road up about a mile and make a left at the ol' saw mill. That road will take you right on in... Eternal Peace Cemetery -- can't miss it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the story on Jason Voorhees anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have you been? Jason was that guy who ran around in a hockey mask, chopping up camp counselors, duh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew that. What I mean was why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It started a long time ago, back in the fifties, when Jason drown at Camp Crystal Lake. His mother went berserk and started killing the counselors.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She got her head chopped off by one of the girls she was trying to kill!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. And then Jason came back from his watery grave to get revenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He came back from the grave?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Chopped up a number of people before they finally caught up to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to him then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They killed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you kill somebody who's back from the grave?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not very well apparently. Jason keeps coming back to life and chopping people up. It's a never ending cycle of terror up here at Crystal Lake -- a real problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why does he keep coming back to life and killing people?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON TOMBSTONE -- JASON VOORHEES. Born:1945. Died:1953. Beneath the death date, crudely scratched into the stone: 1981, 1982, 1984, 1985, 1986, 1988, etc. Jesse and Erwin start digging. ELLIPSIS -- cemetery statues watching them dig. Stormie and Meagan take their turn. Then... Jesse hits something solid. Hands brush away the remaining dirt, exposing the coffin below. Jesse takes a sharp breath and then jams a crowbar under the lid -- forcing it open. The casket lid cracks open a bit when -- SSSSSS! -- noxious gas escapes. Everyone covers their mouth and nose, suppressing the urge to hurl. Then roaches... hundreds of roaches. Meagan and Stormie run off, screaming, batting at their hair and clothing. Jesse rolls around on the ground. Erwin sighs, plucks a roach off his shirt, and calmly eats it.</context>
      <utterance>They say he's looking for revenge on the camp counselor who murdered him as a child. Jason just happens to go about it in the socially unacceptable way of hacking through every teenager he finds until he gets the right one.  Here it is... Erwin shines his light on Jason's grave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stormie slaps his hand away.</context>
      <utterance>Look... the boogerman!  Get it?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get back, you nasty-ass bastard! Ug! I thought I had seen the last of those when my brother graduated third grade!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse looks over at Meagan, curled up in a ball beside him. She purrs:</context>
      <utterance>We just dug up a rotting corpse and you're worried about a little snot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm exhausted... wake me when we get back home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This news sobers everyone up immediately.</context>
      <utterance>Uhhh... better not fall asleep -- we've still got a lot of work to do and Freddy's out there... waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that means we've all got to stay awake!</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duh?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan leads the none-too-enthusiastic group in another chorus of "Row Your Boat" as Jesse's car roars off into the night.</context>
      <utterance>I know! We'll sing a song!  Row! Row! Row your boat, gently down the stream. Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily... life is but a dream. Come on, everybody!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy starts the car and pulls out, but what comes out from behind the billboard isn't a patrol car -- it's Freddy's NIGHTMAREMOBILE -- big chrome pipes belching HELLFIRE. ANGLE IN JESSE'S REARVIEW MIRROR as Jesse's eyelids close and his head nods forward, revealing the night- maremobile closing from behind fast. The nightmaremobile runs up to the back of Jesse's car just an inch from the bumper. Freddy moves one of the dozen of levers on the dash. CLOSE ON FREDDY'S HOOD ORNAMENT -- a small version of Freddy's glove. It extends out towards the back of Jesse's car, one of the tiny knives inserting into the trunk lock and turning with a slight CLICK. The trunk lid opens. ANGLE INSIDE TRUNK -- the plastic bags with Jason's remains are moving! Freddy works another level and the tiny glove slits each bag. The various pieces of Jason (hands, boots, intestines, etc.) crawl out of the bag.</context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't dream and drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHAM! SPARKS fly. Everyone screams. Freddy laughs as he falls back for another shot. Meagan sees the dozens of lost souls trapped in the back of the night- maremobile, staring out at her through the back window. A small yellow sign reads: LOST SOULS ON BOARD. Jesse fights to keep the car on the road when suddenly, the pieces of Jason ATTACK, BURSTING from behind the back seat. One hand crawls up the back of the front seat, leaping onto Jesse's throat. Jason's intestines EXPLODE out of the backseat, SLITHERING and SNAKING their way around Stormie and Erwin. One of Jason's boots wiggles under the seat, making it's way towards the gas peddle. The other boot is content to lay under the back window and kick Erwin in the head. As Meagan fights to pull Jason's hand of Jesse's face, she looks down and sees Jason's other hand between her legs. Meagan screams. Jason's boot stomps on the gas and Jesse's car lurches forward with the acceleration. The nightmaremobile SLAMS into the side of Jesse's car again, causing it to swerve violently from side to side. Inside the nightmaremobile, Freddy pulls another lever. CLOSE ON THE NIGHTMAREMOBILE FENDER as a panel opens up and a circular sawblade arm extends out, CUTTING into Jesse's car with a flurry of SPARKS. Inside, Meagan screams as the saw blade just misses her leg, CUTTING forward towards... CLOSE ON JESSE'S FRONT TIRE as the saw blade CUTS into it. The tire BLOWS and Jesse's car lurches off the road, veering into a tree line. CRASH! -- Jesse's car plows fender-first into a tree, the HORN stuck on, BLARING. Freddy laughs and kicks the nightmaremobile into overdrive, ROARING OFF and disappearing with an EXPLOSION of FIRE that wisps away in an instant. In the distance -- an old farmhouse. The lights go on inside. The passenger door opens and Meagan falls out onto the ground, bleeding from a slight scalp wound. A rear door opens and Stormie and Erwin spill out, locked in embrace and not seriously hurt. Meagan staggers around to the driver's side and opens the door. Jesse is laying unconscious against the steering wheel. Meagan pulls him off the wheel and the HORN stops. Jesse is splattered with blood and his leg is a mess.</context>
      <utterance>It's Freddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesse's hurt real bad... we've got to get him to a doctor. Through the farmhouse window, Erwin and Stormie see the farmer on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan cradles Jesse's head in her hands, crying:</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry... an ambulance is on the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin goes to the trunk and opens it. Inside -- the garbage bags with Jason's remains still inside -- untouched. Erwin goes to Meagan and says:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God... Jesse...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meagan... listen to me... The cops are on their way. If they find me and Jason Voorhees in the trunk there, we're finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go... get out of here. Take Jason and Stormie with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin grabs the trash bags out of the trunk and says:</context>
      <utterance>I'm staying with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call you at the hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin takes off, disappearing with Jason's remains into the night as SIRENS WAIL in the distance -- growing close.</context>
      <utterance>Somehow!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he going to be okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan sits down next to Jesse, taking his hand. Stormie turns to the doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. But he needs a lot of rest. His leg is broken in four places and he has four broken ribs and a concussion.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey doc, is there someplace I could get us something to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor exits.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid the cafeteria is closed. There are some vending machines in the lobby.  I'll be back to check on him in a couple of hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan nods weakly. Stormie exits. Meagan lays her head on Jesse's hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back... I'm goin' go score us some munchies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Jesse can't hear her. He's too busy shaking with fear... staring at something coming down the street. It's Freddy. Dressed in a Black Bart cowboy outfit.</context>
      <utterance>Jesse!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Sheriff... This nightmare ain't big enough for the two of us... draw! Trembling with fear, Jesse fumbles for his pistol. He pulls it out and FIRES. Freddy laughs. Jesse FIRES again. Freddy just laughs. Jesse FIRES again and again and again and Freddy just laughs and laughs and laughs. From the saloon, Meagan screams:</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy looks over at her, annoyed.</context>
      <utterance>Jesse! Wake up! Wake up!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three's a crowd, bitch! Why don't you just go get [BEEP]</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus... get a grip, lady. You'd think a nurse in a hospital would have seen a dead body before.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Stormie spots Murdoch and his men getting off the elevator. They hear the nurse's screams and come running towards Jesse's room. Stormie pulls Meagan behind the nurse's station just as Murdoch and company go thundering past. Then a VOICE on the P.A. says:</context>
      <utterance>Jesse...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Attention. Would Meagan or Stormie please pick up the white paging phone for a message? Stormie and Meagan exchange worrisome looks. The announcement repeats itself again. Then again. Stormie can't stand it anymore -- she stands up and picks up the white paging phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murdoch and his men come running past the nurse's station again. Stormie turns her back to them but Murdoch goes back to the nurse's station, asking:</context>
      <utterance>This is Stormie...</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stormie gestures to the elevators.</context>
      <utterance>Did you see a couple of girls go by here a moment ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murdoch nods a quick thanks and takes off with his men right behind. Stormie exhales a giant sigh of relief as the HOSPITAL OPERATOR says:</context>
      <utterance>Just missed 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSPITAL OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The message is from Erwin... he says to meet him at the side entrance in two minutes. Stormie hangs up and grabs Meagan, running for the staircase.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get the truck?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same place I've got Jason hid.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stormie closes the door and the pick-up truck ROARS out of the parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>A place where no one ever goes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you do -- take him for a swim?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin jumps down on the diving platform. In the center, a large form is covered by a tarp. Erwin helps Stormie down onto the platform, leaving Meagan standing on the pier. She looks out over the lake -- eyes vacant. Erwin moves close to Stormie and, gesturing to Meagan, asks:</context>
      <utterance>Almost.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she going to be alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. She's pretty fucked up. God, I don't know why I'm not...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a strong woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stormie gestures to the tarp.</context>
      <utterance>Uhhh... nothing. I didn't mean anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(whips back tarp) Meet the new and improved Jason. ANGLE ON JASON laying spread eagle on the diving platform, cocooned in chicken wire with dozens of coiled leads trailing off into the water. Erwin has done a good job of sewing Jason back together with barbed wire and fishing line. His arms and legs have been reinforced with steel braces and even Jason's mask has been repaired, stitched down the middle with bailing wire. Jason looks nineties... and butch.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you put that stupid mask on him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stormie bends down and takes a peek under the mask and quickly replaces it.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look...</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly a beauty queen entry, is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do we do now -- sing an Ozzy Osbourne song backwards or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid it's not that simple...</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you said you knew how to bring him back to life?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do! But when I was putting him back together, I noticed something was missing. Stormie thinks about this for a second, then:</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awwww, he won't be needing that... I mean, what girl would let him put his rotten ol'...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>it's missing.</context>
      <utterance>No-no! Not that! It's his heart...</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... does it really matter? Can't you use an aquarium pump or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan speaks for the first time:</context>
      <utterance>No... he has to have a heart. A human heart. A good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A good one.</context>
      <utterance>I know where we can get a heart...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guard in there might pose a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin and Stormie exchange looks, then shrug -- why not?</context>
      <utterance>Do you think you and Stormie could keep him occupied for a few minutes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few moments later, the guard looks up as the pick- up swerves wildly into the parking lot. He gets up and goes to the glass door, peering out. ANGLE THROUGH GLASS DOOR as Stormie and Erwin start making out -- hot and heavy.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... let's do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Watch that!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to make it look real.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The windows are starting to steam up.</context>
      <utterance>Just keep your hands above the bra, pizza face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They said they were writin' for some newspaper...</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teenagers are notorious liars.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, after I heard about the accident on my police scanner, I came up here to have a look. When I found it I figured you'd want to know right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ol' coot shines his light down into Jason's empty grave.</context>
      <utterance>You did the right thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The S.W.A.T. commander comes up to Murdoch.</context>
      <utterance>Damn kids... I just knew they were comin' up here to do somethin' stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just got a call on the radio -- three juveniles just broke into the morgue -- one male, two female. The guard is pretty sure the male is in the Freddy cult -- burnt face.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZY OL' COOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like the same kids I saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did the guard say what they took?</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... that murdered kid, Jesse -- they carved his heart out.  They got away in a pick-up -- the guard didn't get the license. You want me to put out an A.P.B.?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... that won't be necessary. I know just where they're going, and just what they're up to. And this time... I'll be ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>it wasn't your fault.</context>
      <utterance>You've got to quit blaming your- self for what happened to Jesse...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>but he did anyway. He did it for me.</context>
      <utterance>He didn't want to come with us...</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sorry I came... I don't think Jesse would be, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just can't believe he's dead. I keep thinking he'll show up any minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin finishes sewing up Jason and climbs back onto the pier, cutting the diving platform free. He kicks it off and it floats out into the lake, drifting free. Then Erwin herds the girls down the shore, leading them over to where a short trench has been dug leading from the water's edge. In the bottom of the trench -- an uncovered power cable.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that just about does it...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you can see, I've excavated the power cable that runs across the bottom of Crystal Lake. I've cut away the insulation, exposing a patch of cable right near the water's edge. Erwin picks up a nearby bucket of water and sets it at the head of the trench.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now when I kick this over, the water will wash down the trench and bridge an eletrical gap between the cable and the lake. There's plenty of voltage, so it should work.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you kick the bucket and Jason lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Okay, keep your fingers crossed... Erwin kicks the bucket over. The water washes down the trench, over the cable, and -- POW! Z-Z-Z-ZAP! A huge SPARK HITS EXPLODES. Then the lake begins to glow and the water begins to churn. Erwin and the girls jump back as ELECTRICITY ARCS from the lake, engulfing the diving platform. The ARCS of ELECTRICITY leap from the chicken wire onto Jason's body, his massive frame convulsing. CLOSE ON HOCKEY MASK as we PUSH IN -- the electricity spirals down into the eye hole like water running down a drain. CLOSE ON JASON'S EYE as it opens! We dive into the eye and take a fantastic dream/time travel to...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JASON'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason jumps at his father's voice, hesitates only slightly, then runs toward him, stopping abruptly several paces away.</context>
      <utterance>Jason! Git your ass over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I teach you, boy? Don't ever take your mask off out in public. I don't want nobody to see that ugly mug of yours. Jason stands, looking at his bare feet. His father smacks him upside the head, shoving him towards the woodshed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason's pace slows as he enters the dark shed -- he knows what's coming next.</context>
      <utterance>Go git in the woodshed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drop them overalls and lay over them logs... Jason slowly complies as his father loosens his belt. Suddenly, JASON'S MOTHER is just outside the doorway, calling:</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason gives his father a sideways glance, then scurries towards his mother.</context>
      <utterance>Jason! Come here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason's mother gives him a mason jar stuffed with dollars and change.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saved up some money... I want you to take and go on up to that summer camp just up the road. Tell the man you want to stay there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just what the hell do you think you're doing, bitch?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sending him away for a few weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason holds his ground for a second, unsure whom to obey, when his mother shoos him away.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't sending him nowhere.  Bring me that money, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason takes off up the road. His father sneers:</context>
      <utterance>Go on now... go!</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason's mother pulls a knife from her apron.</context>
      <utterance>Goin' ag'in me? I'll take you to the shed, woman!</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason's mother charges at her husband, shoving him back into the shed with the knife. Jason looks back. Through the open window he sees his mother's arm coming down repeatedly with the knife, his father's arms flailing helplessly. Then both disappear from view. After a moment his mother appears in the door- way, spattered with blood. She smiles and waves to him, calling:</context>
      <utterance>You ain't ever taking anyone to the shed ever again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason turns and runs to...</context>
      <utterance>Go on, son... have a good time! Mommy will come and git you some day soon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan and Stormie bounce, excitedly. But something is wrong. Jason thrashes around on the dock, unable to break the crisscross of high voltage chicken wire.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit! It worked!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's kill him! Shut it off! Shut it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut it off... it suddenly occurs to me that I hadn't really planned for that contingency.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But all Erwin can do is scratch his head. Meagan rushes to the shore line and screams out over the lake:</context>
      <utterance>Just don't stand there! Do something!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason clenches his meaty fists and SLAMS them down against the diving dock. SMASHING it to bits. Water rushes over him and -- ZZZZT! KA-POW! A power transformer on shore EXPLODES, causing Meagan and her friends to cringe. When they look back, the electrical light show fades away, leaving nothing but smoke and floating debris. Meagan and Stormie turn to Erwin, who shrugs shyly and says:</context>
      <utterance>Jason! JASON! You've got to get up! Do you hear me? Get up!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan and Stormie begin a verbal barrage that would shrink any man to pus... much less Erwin. He cowers between them, offering quick excuses and humble apologies. All three are so wrapped up in laying blame that they never notice Jason's shadowy figure as it rises from the lake. Then they do see him... scream and run. Jason charges after the kids in his familiar "unstoppable killer" gait. Erwin ducks inside the tool shed as Meagan and Stormie dash past. He closes the door behind him and squirms out a tiny window just as Jason kicks open the door and steps inside. Erwin races around to the front and closes the door. He fastens the latch and padlock, then calls to the girls:</context>
      <utterance>Well... it's off now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you calling?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cops! Who else?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding?! They'll lock us up and throw away the key!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Erwin bursts into the cabin, slamming the door shut behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Fine by me!  Damnit! It's dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stormie and Meagan look out the window -- sure enough, Jason is storming towards them, holding the chainsaw.</context>
      <utterance>He's right behind me!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the one who brought him back to life!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin screams and runs for the closet, hiding inside. Stormie clucks:</context>
      <utterance>Well, do something!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, the chainsaw RIPS through the front door. Meagan and Stormie scream and follow Erwin into the closet, closing themselves inside. They cower in the closet, listening... for a long moment... nothing but the sound of their heavy breathing. Then, with the RIPPING of WOOD, Jason chainsaws the closet door -- knocking it to the floor. Erwin draws out his pin and starts stabbing himself in the finger. Jason charges forward, when Meagan suddenly stands up in front of him and yells:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, some hero!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now... just stop! We're the ones that brought you back to life. And you have no right to kill us with that chainsaw! In fact... you owe us...</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right! She gave you her boyfriend's heart, you know!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason cocks his massive head like a perplexed pup.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, I know that you've been through a lot. And I know that you're pissed off about being murdered and all.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I would be!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan sticks out her hand to shake. Jason stares at it, looks back at the locket, then to Meagan. Finally, he reaches out his huge hand for Meagan's when... Brilliant, blinding white light blazes through the windows, freezing everyone to the spot. Anxious to get out of the closet with Jason, Erwin crawls across the floor and peeks out over the window sill. ANGLE OUT WINDOW -- a dozen police cars shine their lights towards the cabin, two dozen COPS aim their weapons. In the middle of this impressive show of force is Murdoch. He raises a bullhorn to his lips.</context>
      <utterance>But if you help us kill Freddy Krueger... I promise to help you find the little bastard that killed you. What do you say? Have we got a deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You in there! This is Captain Renton Murdoch -- State Trooper! I am ordering you to come out with your hands up! I'll give you until the count of three...  Three! Meagan turns to Jason, shoving him back into the closet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jason, you have to hide! Stay in here and don't come out until we tell you. Stormie... help me! Stormie helps Meagan stuff Jason into the closet, closing the door. Then they quickly smooth down their hair and clothes, moving towards the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright... anybody else left in there had better say their prayers!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no one else inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, one of the cops points towards the cabin and shouts:</context>
      <utterance>Is that a fact?  Okay... you had your chance!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All heads turn towards the cabin, where Jason's massive frame is filling the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, look!</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy Mary, mother of God... would you look at the size of that guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the cops level their weapons at Jason when Murdoch suddenly steps forward, gesturing for everyone to get behind him.</context>
      <utterance>I knew it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murdoch takes a few steps towards the cabin and sneers:</context>
      <utterance>Stand back! I'll handle this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason raises the chainsaw -- he remembers Murdoch too. Murdoch goes for his gun, but instead of bringing out a pistol, he holds a laser designator. Murdoch fires. A big red dot appears on Jason's chest. Jason looks down at it like it was a harmless bug. He looks back up at Murdoch, who raises a radio to his lips and says:</context>
      <utterance>You...</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let her go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cop behind him says:</context>
      <utterance>That'll teach you to fuck with the law, Voorhees!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murdoch looks up -- sure enough, his Smokey Bear hat is burning above the brim. Meagan watches as Camp Crystal Lake is consume in flames, her last hope of saving Lizzy -- gone. Then a cop shoves her into a police car with Stormie. Erwin is put into another car and the three exchange worrisome looks through the windows just before the cars pull away. As the cops start to pull out, one of them notices something moving amidst the flames -- a large BURNING form, walking towards the lake. As it stumbles out onto the pier, the cop turns to his partner and says:</context>
      <utterance>Uhh, sir... your hat's on fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURIOUS COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But just then, the form falls through the BURNING pier, SPLASHING into the water below. The partner looks, sees nothing, and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Hey... do you see that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CURIOUS COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs it off and exits after his partner. Murdoch, his hat still smoking a little, surveys the sight one last time before climbing into his patrol car and driving away.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I saw something...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to try and stay awake.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting something to eat might help.  Yo, Butch!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Deputy Miller.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Deputy Miller but could we have something to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you psychos only ate human hearts?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I thought you pigs only ate donuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make me come back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cow! I hope she chokes on her three combo-burrito cud! Meagan leans up against the wall, sliding down to the floor in defeat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I going to do? I'll never be able to find Lizzy now.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stormie plops down on her cot.</context>
      <utterance>You should be worrying about your- self... I know I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet you're sorry you came with me now...</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah... what are best friends for? Afterall, you stuck by me through all my crazy phases, I figure I owe you one big crazy phase, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Deputy Miller steps in front of Meagan's cell, unlocking it.</context>
      <utterance>That's for being my best friend, Stormie.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Meagan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your parents are here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let me look at you...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Meagan... are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay, mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan stands handcuffed, her hair mussed, her clothes bloody and soiled.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother's been worried sick, Meagan. So have I.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Today has been a bitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the deputy at the end of the cellblock doesn't respond, finishing off the rest of the burrito and licking her meaty fingers clean. Freddy puts his forefinger knife to his lips and shushes Stormie, pointing to her cot. Stormie looks over and sees her- self asleep.</context>
      <utterance>Help! Help! Freddy's here! He's here!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up at Freddy, who smiles and says:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit! I'm still asleep!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy flashes the glove of knives.</context>
      <utterance>You know what they say... when you sleep -- you die!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meagan, Captain Murdoch here said you helped one of those cultists escape from a hospital?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A mental hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he said you desecrated a cemetery and some other really terrible things. Tell me you had nothing to do with it. Tell me there's some mistake...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no mistake.  What did you do with Erwin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your boyfriend is headed back to the looney bin where he belongs. But don't worry, you'll be seeing him soon enough... at the arraignment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't scare me, Freddy! Thanks to my various phases and many hours of watching violent televison, I have become immune to violence. Seen it all and done it all! Nothing you do can gross me out -- so why don't you give it your best shot, bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy swings the glove but Stormie ducks, keeping her defensive stance.</context>
      <utterance>Then maybe I'll just CUT to the chase!</utterance>
   <speaker>STORMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm warning you, Freddy... my father is a drill sergeant in the Marine Corps and he taught me just how to defend myself against slimy bastards like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy juts out his chin, gesturing for Stormie to take a punch. Stormie throws a right and pops Freddy right in the nose.</context>
      <utterance>Oh I'm so scared, honey. Come on! Hit me! Punch me right in the nose! I dare you!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stormie smiles but that soon fades as she realizes her fist is stuck in Freddy's nose. Freddy takes in a breath and Stormie's arm is sucked up past the elbow. She screams. Freddy takes a deep breath and snorts Stormie right up his nose, her screams turning into a faint BUZZ. Freddy smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Owwwww!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's what I call getting a buzz.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BOOGERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stormie screams, backing up into the "trees", trying to put distance between herself and Boogerman.</context>
      <utterance>Hi there! I'm the Boogerman! Heh- heh... get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOGERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aww, don't go... we can play "Star Wars". You can be Princess Leia and I'll be Jabba the Hutt! Boogerman licks his fat, nasty lips with a slimy green tongue -- he does kinda look like Jabba. Stormie screams again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan's parents stare at their daughter with confused, frightened looks.</context>
      <utterance>We're wasting time! We've got to close down all the churches -- Freddy has to marry Lizzy on holy ground!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you understand?! He has to come to our reality to do it! It's our last chance to kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A couple of DEPUTIES grab Meagan. She throws them off and they grab her again, roughly. Meagan's parents watch in pain and horror as the deputies drag their daughter back to her cell, kicking and screaming.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I think we've heard enough of this crap. Take her back to the lockup.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I have to save Lizzy!</context>
      <utterance>Dad! Mom! Don't let them lock me up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Meagan... you're sick. You don't even realize what you've done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did what I had to do to try and save Lizzy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, including murdering your boy- friend and cutting his heart out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan's mom and dad gasp, recoiling with horror.</context>
      <utterance>Liar! Freddy killed Jesse! He was already dead when I cut his heart out!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit, you don't understand! Freddy lives! FREDDY LIVES!!! Meagan's raving grows faint as she disappears into the cellblock. Murdoch pulls Meagan's dad aside.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know how you must feel... I had a dog once. I loved that dog. I treated her like my own daughter. We went camping, picnics in the park... I even had a little stocking for her nailed up on the mantle for Christmas. Then one day, she bit me... so I had to blow her brains out.  God, I loved that dog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOOGERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boogerman starts lumbering up into the back of the nostril cavern. Stormie watches the massive knife blade as it comes right for her, then at the last possible second she starts climbing after Boogerman. She pushes past the disgusting blob of goo, racing ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh, Freddy's picking his nose again -- gotta go!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Micro-Stormie comes blasting out of Freddy's nose with globules of snot. She flies across the massive cell, headed directly for the splattered Boogerman, screaming her head off. Boogerman sees Stormie racing towards him and he screams too.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh... ahhh... ahhh--CHOO!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The deputy pushes Meagan back as she moves forward cautiously, glancing around the wall into Stormie's cell... then promptly puking combo burrito. Meagan runs up and looks. The wall to Stormie's cell is splattered with blood and bits. Meagan falls to her knees, sobbing as more DEPUTIES come running into the cellblock, answering the deputy's puke-choked scream.</context>
      <utterance>Stormie?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We BOOM OUT of this chaos and go to...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God... what have I done? What have I done?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AMBULANCE DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver gets out and goes to the form laying in the road. He bends down to examine the charred, mammoth carcass when a fist flies up, smacking the driver in the face. He falls to the ground, unconscious. The corpse sits up in the glare from the headlights -- it's Jason! Burnt and blackened but ready for action! He starts towards the ambulance. The attendant gets out and pulls his service revolver, emptying into Jason's chest. Jason recoils only slightly as BULLET HITS BURST his coveralls, then he grabs the attendant by the head as he snaps the empty pistol in panic. Jason slams the attendant's face into the side of the ambulance. In the back of the ambulance, a terror-stricken Erwin watches as a face shaped dent appears in the wall with a sickening WRENCHING of METAL and FLESH. Then... silence. RIP! -- Jason pulls off the back door of the ambulance and climbs inside, the shocks bottoming out under his weight. He reaches out for Erwin, who closes his eyes... waiting for the inevitable. Then... nothing. After a second, Erwin opens an eye. Jason is standing over him, hand outstretched. In his big, burnt palm -- Meagan's necklace. Erwin looks from the necklace to Jason. Jason thrusts out his hand impatiently.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go check it out. You stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again with the thrusting.</context>
      <utterance>You... want me to tell you where Meagan is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason shakes his palm at Erwin yet a third time.</context>
      <utterance>Well why didn't you say so?! Jesus, for a minute there I thought you were going to kill me.  You're not, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... okay! I'll take you right to her. Could you help me out of this? Jason reaches over and yanks out the gurney straps. Erwin exits out the back with Jason following close behind. Erwin climbs in behind the wheel, saying:</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason pushes Erwin aside so roughly that he slams into the passenger side door.</context>
      <utterance>I'll drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Jason climbs into the driver's seat, a CHIME goes off as a female COMPUTER VOICE in a pleasant tone says:</context>
      <utterance>Okay... you drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin fastens his. Jason watches him and pulls the safety belt across his massive chest -- it won't reach. Jason pulls harder, ripping the belt out of the bolts. The CHIME goes crazy.</context>
      <utterance>Fasten your safety belt, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With tires SQUEALING, burning rubber and smoke, the ambulance roars away into the early morning.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck the bitch. Let's roll!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RELIGIOUS ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Channel 12 -- Station W.G.O.D. -- where the "W" stands for "Worship" And now... "Daily Affirmation" with Reverend Lawrence Lovejoy... A shot of the REVEREND LOVEJOY at the podium in his studio, giving kind words of encouragement.</utterance>
   <speaker>REVEREND LOVEJOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The good reverend goes on about it always being darkest before the dawn, have faith and your prayers will be answered, etc. Meagan turns and watches the sunrise -- glorious. Tears stream down her cheeks. Then a commercial comes on:</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, friends... the Good Book says that each morning brings a new light into our lives...</utterance>
   <speaker>RELIGIOUS ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can own a videotape of Reverend Lovejoy's Daily Affirmation for only</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GATE GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cultist sticks his head out the window and says:</context>
      <utterance>Hello. What can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CULTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're here to see the Reverend Lovejoy. We need him to perform a wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATE GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have an appointment?</utterance>
   <speaker>CULTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cultist produces a pistol -- BANG!</context>
      <utterance>No. I have a Beretta.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something just happened at the TV station.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it -- get undressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan looks back at the TV as she slowly starts to get undressed.</context>
      <utterance>Time to get you cleaned up for court.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>HEAD BITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, honey... you don't like our company?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like you... sure. It's just that I usually shower alone, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD BITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The head bitch grabs at Meagan, who resists. But this bitch is big and tough and holds Meagan by the wrists as she tries to kiss her. The other bitches laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! So you're shy? I like 'em when they're shy...</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD BITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you won't give me a piece then I'll just cut one for myself... The head bitch moves in. Meagan takes a cautious step back, bumping into tile -- nowhere to go. She holds up her hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The head bitch stops, curious.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a second... I didn't mean to do that... I'm sorry. It's just that you come on a little strong, that's all. Just give me a little time to adjust to my new surroundings...</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD BITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you saying you want me now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... I want you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD BITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan comes up to the woman, raising her arms. In a flash, the head bitch has the shiv to Meagan's jugular -- a warning. Meagan carefully puts her arm around the bitch and kisses her full on the mouth. After a long, uncomfortable moment, they break. The head bitch smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Prove it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD BITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other bitches smile as the head bitch slips her arm around Meagan's waist and pulls her tight.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's more like it!  Hey, this bitch is alright!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD BITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're okay, honey... what's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meagan.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD BITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... what're you in for, Meagan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my friend...</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD BITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bitch that died last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... they said she had some disease that made her... explode! Oh, God! Please hold me! The head bitch holds Meagan tight as she sobs, smoothing her hair. The other bitches share a look of concern as one asks:</utterance>
   <speaker>BITCH #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this bullshit about some killer funk make you explode?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD BITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy... honey. It's goin' be alright. But what I asked you is why you're in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The head bitch suddenly springs back as if Meagan were Satan himself. She runs for the other bitches but they aren't having anything to do with her. All the bitches race for the exit. The deputy comes to the shower room doorway and shouts:</context>
      <utterance>Oh... well... the cops? Well, they think I gave it to her...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHAM! -- the bitches run her over, stripping the keys from her belt. They unlock the cellblock door and go running into the police station, screaming butt-naked. After the bitches exit, Meagan's hand reaches out and drags the unconscious deputy into the shower.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is all the screaming about?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>REVEREND LOVEJOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the cultists puts a gun to Mrs. Lovejoy's head.</context>
      <utterance>I won't do it! It's a sin! Blasphemy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CULTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The reverend swallows and says:</context>
      <utterance>Wedding or funeral... your choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>REVEREND LOVEJOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy is brought forth. The cultists take her arm and inject her with the dream dope. Lizzy's head lulls around as she chants softly:</context>
      <utterance>And who would be the bride?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rest of the cultists shoot up -- passing the needle from one to another.</context>
      <utterance>One... two... Freddy's coming for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three... four... Better lock your door. The good reverend watches this with a lump in his throat. He shudders and asks:</utterance>
   <speaker>REVEREND LOVEJOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the groom.</utterance>
   <speaker>CULTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy is almost asleep.</context>
      <utterance>He's coming...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The neon cross behind the podium begins to flicker. Then with a sharp SNAP of electricity, the cross falls over, turning upside down. It hangs there for an instant then -- POW! -- the cross EXPLODES, catching the curtains on FIRE. As the FLAMES consume the curtains, a hole in reality appears -- a Dreamgate. Freddy comes springing out, leaping in front of the podium. He laughs and turns to Lizzy, asleep on the bench.</context>
      <utterance>Five... six... grab your crucifix...</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's for the lift sister!  Hiya, kids!</utterance>
   <speaker>CULTISTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Freddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready to get hitched?</utterance>
   <speaker>CULTISTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready, Freddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy looks up and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Then let's do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Freddy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We found your patrol car, Captain. It was abandoned near a local religious station.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Religious station? Is there a padre there?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. Reverend Lovejoy broad- casts out of that location.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's where they're hiding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>REVEREND LOVEJOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy holds up a finger -- "Ah-ah".</context>
      <utterance>...and if there be anyone among you who has any reason why these two should not be joined in holy...</utterance>
   <speaker>REVEREND LOVEJOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHAM! -- Meagan bursts in.</context>
      <utterance>...in matrimony. Let them speak now...  ...please God...  ...or forever hold their peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone turns and looks as Meagan comes to the pulpit.</context>
      <utterance>Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take me, Freddy. Take me instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a virgin?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy moves close to Meagan, running a blade over and around Meagan's neck as she struggles to remain calm.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's right -- tell everybody!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmmmmm! Yes, you are a bit juicier than your retard sister... okay, you've got the job.  Get her ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Captain Renton Murdoch -- State Trooper. I'm giving you until the count of three to come out with your hands up... A CULTIST SNIPER FIRES a shot at Murdoch, the bullet hit SMASHING the emergency lights atop his car. The other cops duck down, but not Murdoch, he turns calmly to the S.W.A.T. commander and says:</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The commander gives the flare gun to Murdoch, adding:</context>
      <utterance>Hand me that flare pistol.</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the commander speaks, Murdoch aims the pistol carefully and FIRES. PHOOMPH! -- the flare streaks to the roof of the TV station, SMACKING the sniper. He BURSTS into FLAMES and tumbles to the ground, screaming. Murdoch hands the flare gun back to the commander, going back on the bullhorn and saying:</context>
      <utterance>Good idea. Throw a little light on them -- see if we can spot their firing positions...</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, now I'm through playing "nice guy" -- I want the rest of you punks to come out right now with your hands up. The cultists respond by filling the air with hot lead -- BULLET HITS RIDDLE the cop cars, SMASHING glass and PIERCING metal. The cops FIRE back, BULLET HITS EXPLODING all along the sides of the TV station.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it doesn't look like they're going to surrender.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What we're going to need then is somebody to charge their lines -- make a hole for us to slip in.</utterance>
   <speaker>S.W.A.T. COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, an ambulance comes ROARING through the police lines, causing the cops to scurry like mice.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you going to find anyone that crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(yells)</context>
      <utterance>Here comes one now...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin looks ahead and screams. ANGLE THROUGH WINDSHIELD as three cultists stand directly in front of the speeding ambulance, FIRING machine guns. The glass EXPLODES just as Erwin ducks down. Two cultists suddenly scatter as Jason rams the ambulance into the middle one just before plowing into the side of the station with a CRASH. Erwin pushes down his airbag just in time to see a cultist closing in with a gun. He reaches through the smashed windshield and grabs the squashed cultist's machine gun laying on the hood. Erwin turns, SHOOTS the cultist just in time. As Jason kicks open the driver's side door he is greeted by two cultists SHOOTING at him. Jason RIPS OFF the driver's side door and hurls it at the two punks, knocking them down like bowling pins. Then Jason reaches back into the ambulance, pulls out the Jaws of Life and, with Erwin covering his back, starts towards the front door.</context>
      <utterance>That was easy enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>REVEREND LOVEJOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan looks around... no one says anything. The reverend clears his throat to continue when... WHAM! -- the studio door flies open and Jason appears in the doorway holding the Jaws of Life.</context>
      <utterance>Once again... if there be anyone among you who does not want these two people to be joined... let him speak now or forever hold his peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cultists attack Jason. Jason grabs the first one with the Jaws of Life -- folds him in half like a rag doll. Another attacks with a machete... bad idea. One more cultist down and now Jason owns the machete. Jason finishes off the last two cultists as Erwin barricades the studio door. The cultists on the other side start POUNDING. Jason starts swinging at Freddy with the machete, slicing through a camera cable. CLOSE ON CABLE as it falls to the floor. Freddy jumps back through the Dreamgate, closing it behind him. Erwin runs over to Meagan and Lizzy. He tries to wake them but can't. As Jason lumbers over, Erwin looks up and says:</context>
      <utterance>Uh, oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin thinks for a moment, then rushes over to a couple of dead cultists. He takes their syringes. Erwin jabs Jason in the neck with two syringes full of dream dope.</context>
      <utterance>I can't wake them up. Freddy's got them trapped!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason staggers forward, falling into...</context>
      <utterance>Go get him, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED BUNDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen... welcome to the fight of the century! I'm your ring announcer... Ted Bundy! BANG! -- a bullet hole appears in Ted's forehead, BLOWING his brains out the back. He falls over DEAD and the crowd cheers. Ted sits up and pulls the wig back over his shaved head and electric burns as he calls into the balcony:</utterance>
   <speaker>TED BUNDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE IN BALCONY -- OSWALD stands, his rifle still smoking.</context>
      <utterance>Verrrrrry funny, Oswald!</utterance>
   <speaker>OSWALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ted Bundy gets to his feet and finishes the intro:</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't me!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED BUNDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy holds up his arms and the crowd goes wild.</context>
      <utterance>In my left corner, weighing in at only ninety seven pounds... the nightmare master himself! The one! The only... Freddddddddy Kruuuuuuugerrrrrr!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED BUNDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHEERS and BOOS.</context>
      <utterance>And on my right... weighing in at a whopping four hundred and thir- teen pounds... that killer of countless teenagers... the big guy...  Jason Voorhees!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED BUNDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside -- Meagan and Lizzy clutch eachother.</context>
      <utterance>And the prize tonight... not one but TWO -- count 'em -- TWO virgins... ripe for the picking. Ted gestures to a large cage suspended over the arena.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED BUNDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LAUGHTER from the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, have one now and save the other for the ride home. That's what I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DING! -- the bell sounds. The first round begins... Freddy starts towards Jason, cocking his glove for a blow when -- CH-CHING! -- knife blades jut out of the glove. He punches Jason in the stomach and starts RIPPING him open, rotten guts spilling out. Jason spots a cocktail waitress walking past with an axe in her head. This is BLOODY MARY. Jason reaches over the side of the ring and pulls the axe out of her head. Bloody Mary whips around, yelling:</context>
      <utterance>Kick his ass, Jason!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy GROWS a new arm, complete with glove of knives. Jason throws the axe at Freddy, who ducks it. The axe flies into the audience, SMACKING MUSSOLINI square between the eyes. He falls back to the floor. HITLER turns to EVA BRAUN and says disdainfully:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, well... I just axed for that!</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DING! The bell sounds. Freddy and Jason break, going into their respective corners. As Jason sits down in his corner, the HUMAN HEAD mounted on his corner post starts in:</context>
      <utterance>Peasants...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMAN HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up in her cage, Meagan clutches a terrifed Lizzy.</context>
      <utterance>That's it, kiddo! You're really giving it to him out there! Use the left more -- jab! Make him hurt! That's the ticket to a knockout!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE UNDER THE MAT -- it's a dark, foreboding (under- water) abyss. Jason's legs kick, trying to get back up. Something slithers up from out of the deep... wisps of empty blackness clutching at Jason's boots. Freddy pushes down on Jason's mask, shoving him down. Jason struggles but keeps slipping. This looks like the end of Jason. Freddy laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Jason! Get up! Get up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jason! You've got to get up! JASON'S P.O.V. of Freddy looking down at him, pushing him down... drowning him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin gestures to Jason, trying to keep his voice low so as to not hurt the big guy's feelings.</context>
      <utterance>What took you so long?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan smiles at Jason.</context>
      <utterance>What ever you do... don't let this guy drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason and Meagan look over to where Freddy's body is fast decaying... turning back into blackened bones, scraps of cloth, and a rusting glove of knives. The Dream Demons squirm around on the studio floor, then swim into the open end of the camera cable and disappear. In the control room, Freddy's face appears on every monitor, laughing.</context>
      <utterance>I knew you would come...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erwin watches as an electrical Freddy-impulse races from the control room via a long thick cable running overhead.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no! Freddy's in the transmitter!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going for the satellite dish! If he uplinks with a communications satellite he can beam himself any- where in the world! We'll never be rid of him! Meagan and Jason look up at the Freddy-impulse shoots past them, going through the ceiling to the...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murdoch FIRES. The shotgun blast knocks Erwin across the room, where he lands in a heap. Meagan and Lizzy run to his side. Erwin struggles to breathe -- a large hole in his chest. With fading strength, Erwin pulls his pin out and pricks himself. Erwin smiles and dies.</context>
      <utterance>No! Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erwin? Erwin?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy turns and attacks Murdoch. He knocks her to the floor, taking aim on her head with the shotgun as he says:</context>
      <utterance>He's dead... and so are you if you don't put your hands up right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURDOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murdoch raises the shotgun, taking aim on Meagan.</context>
      <utterance>So... you wanna be a punk?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan clucks and bends down, peering under the bed -- nada.</context>
      <utterance>You forgot to check under the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No monsters here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what if they come back?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lizzy giggles.</context>
      <utterance>Then we'll just have to kick their ass again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Meagan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you too. Go to sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan looks down at her parents.</context>
      <utterance>Meagan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mom and I... well, we want to thank you for saving your sister's life... we know you went through a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to be there for you from now on... for both of you! And that nice lawyer we hired for you said he thinks he can get all the charges dropped... except maybe for the grave robbing and human desecration ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything is going to be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm going to get sober...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to be a normal, happy family again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight mom... goodnight dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Meagan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meagan puts the phone in a drawer and closes it. She climbs into bed and pulls back the pillow to reveal the pistol Erwin gave Jesse to kill Freddy. She smiles and puts the pistol back under the pillow.</context>
      <utterance>I know...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think they're coming back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED BUNDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the monsters get grumbling and start to exit.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, folks... show's over. Every- body can go home now.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
