<movie id="218" title="Frequency">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BUTCH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...oil all over the street. Cracked water and gas mains. Four companies coming in... Butch's voice continues as Frank calmly absorbs the information, while at the same time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, man. Hope it ain't like this in Baltimore tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baltimore?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibson taps his wristwatch.</context>
      <utterance>The game, Graham. The Series?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. Damn. My watch is busted.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Rookie. Be cool. Just stay with me. This is what we do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank laughs. Gibson grins, relaxes a bit. Frank checks his ROLEX DIVER'S WATCH. Multiple SIRENS fill the dawn.</context>
      <utterance>I seem nervous, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's 5:30, Gib.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank's eyes harden. His game face sets up.</context>
      <utterance>...two Con Ed men trapped in an underground electrical conductor vault.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fun one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks at the tanker over the manhole. There is now nobody around it.</context>
      <utterance>We got high voltage cables ripped loose in the underground. They hit water, that fault's gonna arc.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why haven't they killed the juice?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Switches are shorted out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're shitting me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish I was. Oldest part of the system down there. We're on it, but it's gonna take awhile.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta go underground. Get those guys out, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Won't budge.</context>
      <utterance>We tried. Bulkhead door's rusted shut.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch knows what he's thinking. But it's too late. Frank is gone...slogging through the oozing oil to the hull of the tanker. He kneels over the three-quarters covered manhole, using a flashlight to peer into the darkness below. Sparks from the loose cables spit off flashes of light as the cables hiss and slap against the ceiling and walls of the vault.</context>
      <utterance>The block is being evacuated. I don't want anybody... including our boys...within fifty yards of that tanker...it's a fucking bomb. Frank has been staring at the capsized rig.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the Fire Department. Frank Sullivan. You guys okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CON ED WORKER #1'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please man, you gotta get us out of here...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Frank is up, heading for his truck, signaling Gibson.</context>
      <utterance>That's exactly what we're gonna do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we get to the vault door?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a manhole at Canal and Bowery.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank grabs a "halaghan claw tool" and a walkie-talkie. Gibson nervously picks out two helmet lights...and they are off and running.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Frank. No way you reach those men in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can do it, Butch. Me and my 'tank man' here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMANDER O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Start spraying down the street. Let me know when we are fully evacuated.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, you hear me? Frank?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Butch?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank picks up the pace. Charges ahead. Guy's got balls.</context>
      <utterance>The gas level is getting serious. The underground's combustible - it could flashover. I want you to abort! Now! Get the hell out of there!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank. We gotta go back. Frank...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay with me, Gib. We're gonna do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank probes the dark vault with the FLASHLIGHT BLADE. Through smoke we see TWO MEN huddled in the corner, trapped by three loose 'HOT' CABLES - WHIPPING AROUND THE TINY VAULT LIKE AN ELECTRIC HYDRA. Con Ed Worker 2 shivers, ankle broken, leaning on older Con Ed Worker 1.</context>
      <utterance>We're in, Butch.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Gibson sprays the room, clearing out most of the smoke. Frank steps into the vault.</context>
      <utterance>Time to go home, fellas.</utterance>
   <speaker>CON ED WORKER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank drops to his knees, ducking under the cables, shuffles to center of the vault. Places his hands at opposite ends of the halaghan tool, hoping for the cables to pass directly over his head. A hairy beat, then... Frank jackknifes out of the water, ramming the halaghan into the ceiling. It worked. The teeth on the "claw-end" and the spike on the "adz-end" are embedded into the concrete -- STAPLING THE CABLES TO THE CEILING. Make that balls of steel.</context>
      <utterance>Careful. If the hot end of those cables hits you, it'll conduct to the water and we're all fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibson and Con Ed worker 1 help injured Worker 2 out of the vault. Frank checks to make sure they've cleared the vault and lets go of the tool. Frank jumps into the tunnel, hoists the injured worker over his back and races back down the tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>Go, Gibby! Everybody move it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haul ass, that claw ain't gonna hold for long...  Take cover -- she's gonna flash!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks over at the hyperventilating Butch and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You did good, Gib. Real good.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elvis has left the building.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, bud.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without breaking stride, he gives her a smack on the lips and steps to the screen door to the back porch.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, bud.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like two weeks worth of allowance, Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Sorry, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Frank drops the softball into Johnny's mitt, closes the screen door and turns back into the kitchen. Johnny turns away into the yard.</context>
      <utterance>Glad to hear that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about a little of the King?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Elvis' SUSPICIOUS MINDS plays, Frank steps back in, moves up behind Julia, and takes her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>I think I ruined the sauce...again.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, Jules? Trouble workin' an eight hour shift, watching the kid and whipping up a little bolognese?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't marry Donna Reed.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he turns her around and they start to dance as Frank sings along to Elvis, badly.</context>
      <utterance>I'd go with you and Chinese take-out over her any time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was your tour?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank spots Johnny and Gordo staring at them. He winks at the boys and swings Julia into a Fred Astaire dip.</context>
      <utterance>The usual.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Butch called.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was under control, Bud. Butchy's just getting tight in his old age.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a laugh, Frank drops Julia into another dip. As the music fades, we...</context>
      <utterance>Nothing wrong with old age, Frank...long as you get there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, start pedaling.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy put the wheels back on. I'm gonna fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think about falling, just keep pedaling.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy, I'm scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny takes a gulp of air, doesn't want to disappoint his father, nods okay. He starts pedaling. Slowly moving forward. Frank holds on to the seat. Frank's still hanging on - jogging along side.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Chief, show some guts.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank let's go. Johnny's pumping those little six year-old legs, but he starts to wobble out of control -- CRASH! Johnny starts to cry, quickly gets up and runs back to the house. Julia comes out of the kitchen door. Johnny runs into her arms.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna let go!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Johnny tears himself from Julia's arms, runs inside. Frustrated, Frank lights up another cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Don't quit on me now, Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank takes a deep drag on the butt. Steps onto the YARD and stares up at the starry night.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be so tough on him Frank, he's six years old.  He just needs to know you're right there behind him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, go ahead and save the whole world, Sam.  You don't gotta worry about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMANTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn you. I tried. But you wouldn't help me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam can't hold back anymore - she cries openly.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. We should've quit a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And suddenly Samantha's tears turn to anger.</context>
      <utterance>It's not your fault. It's mine. I can't change. Wish I could, Sam. But I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMANTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John has no reply. All he can do is watch as she takes her stuff and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>That's not true and you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMANTHA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>John stands immobilized in the middle of the room. He looks down and spots a TEDDY BEAR half stuck under a reading chair. And then to a photo of him and Sam at a CARNIVAL SHOOTING GALLERY. Sam's holding the teddy bear. John turns at the SOUND of the backdoor slamming. Looks out a window down to Samantha getting in her car and driving away.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Chief.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REVOLVER.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BRRIING. John grabs the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BANG. Slams down the phone. And stares around the room. WE'VE BEEN IN THIS HOUSE BEFORE -- 29 YEARS AGO. This was Frank and Julia sullivan's house. Time has not been good to it. Furnishings haven't changed much, but the house is missing the warmth it had when a family filled it with love. John's eyes dart to a PHOTOGRAPH next to the desk. It is a picture of THE SULLIVAN FAMILY from back then. Too many memories. He grabs his coat, heads out...</context>
      <utterance>What? It don't matter, Lady. Why?... Cause I don't got no friends or family.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the SOUNDS of CHEERING parents. The CLAPPING, WHISTLING &amp; SHOUTING is hauntingly juxtaposed against the empty playing field and bleachers we see on the screen. CRACK: sound of the bat solidly connecting with the ball. CAMERA follows invisible runner from home to first base.</context>
      <utterance>Batting next. Johnny Sullivan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>John takes a deep breath, glances from first base back to home plate...then looks off into the distance - a cold thousand yard stare.</context>
      <utterance>Sullivan's safe at first. Batting for Johnny's father is...Coach Newman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GORDY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John notices smoke filtering out of his kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Uncle John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not your uncle, kid.  Gordo, what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Follow John into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Sully! Is that you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Sull. My cable's out again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John glances at a mound of burnt bacon dripping on the stove.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that smell?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you believe Ellen still won't let me cook in the house? I melt one lousy frying pan, y'know? Gordy Jr. scoots into the kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, guess what? Dad's taking me fishing. Wanna come?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish I could, Gordy. But you bring me back a big one.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, OK if Gordy uses your old gear?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordy Jr. runs out. O.S. sounds of him rummaging through hall closet.</context>
      <utterance>I think it's somewhere in the closet... if you can find it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John puts the Bushmills bottle down, and grabs two Molsons.</context>
      <utterance>So Yahoo went up another two points. Man, did we miss the boat on that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John laughs, hands Gordo a beer, and lights up a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Coulda, woulda, shoulda, pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John reacts. Nothing else needs to be said. A beat, then...</context>
      <utterance>Sam called Ellen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you come with us? Three days of fresh air and barbecue would do you some good, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDY JR.</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, John, c'mere...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Gordy, what 'ya doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John thinks about it for a second. Noting the curious glee in little Gordy's face, nods OK. Gordy Jr. pops open the latches, opens the trunk. Gordo crouches down beside his son, checks out the dusty contents. HOLD ON JOHN'S REACTION to what Gordy Jr. finds in the trunk.</context>
      <utterance>Dad, check it out. Fire Department! Can I open it up?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDY JR.</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Gordy Jr. reaches in and takes out: FDNY HELMET &amp; JACKETS. Briefly puts on the enormous helmet, then sets it aside. Reaches back into the trunk and pulls out the disassembled pieces of a 12 gauge SHOTGUN.</context>
      <utterance>Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordo takes the shotgun from the boy and places it gingerly inside the closet. Simultaneously, Gordy Jr. hands off a leather-bound SCRAPBOOK to John. Before John can react, Gordy Jr. lifts up an</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Gimmie that!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GORDY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE BACK ON JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Powerful memories fill his face.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, that's your Dad's old ham radio. Remember? Remember how we used to beg him to let us talk on that thing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN/GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not a toy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordo looks at John.</context>
      <utterance>Can we try it Dad, can we try it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GORDY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this was what people used before the Net, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GORDO TURNS THE RADIO ON. Shows Gordy how it works. Gordy rotates the tuning dial, nothing but "dead bands." STATIC.</context>
      <utterance>Man, do I feel old.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOCK. Front door opens. John's head turning around. Meet ELLEN, 35, Gordo's wife. The grown-up in the family.</context>
      <utterance>It's junk, kid. Nobody uses those things anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gordo, do you know what time it is?  Hi, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen notices John's weary look but says nothing. We get the sense she knows what is wrong.</context>
      <utterance>Ellen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Gordy, let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDY JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, mom...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right, John?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen holds her glance for a moment. John smiles, thinly masking his sadness. Ellen nods okay, and she is gone. John looks up at the stars, then down to the HAM RADIO ANTENNA on his roof, now looking raggedy from 29 years of neglect.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John is back on the Bushmills. He races clumsily for the CORDLESS PHONE. CLOSE ON SPEED DIAL BUTTONS. John hits 3.</context>
      <utterance>TV: LARRY KING is interviewing STEPHEN HAWKING.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, this is Julia. Please leave a message after the tone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John puts down the phone. Stares at the FDNY trunk. He stumbles to it. Sits down and opens it up. It's filled with his Dad's stuff. He picks up and leafs through the old SCRAPBOOK - PHOTOS and CLIPPINGS illustrate FAMILY HISTORY... A quick glimpse of Dad's high school baseball team; Mom and Dad's 60's wedding.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ma, it's me. Checking in. Probably at work. Anyways, I'll see you tomorrow night. Love you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LARRY KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this anomaly connected to the space storm and the NASA satellite that disappeared in 1969?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWKING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NOTE: Larry King's show plays for the duration of this scene. John settles in, takes off his work shirt. Underneath he has on a T-shirt. We notice a NICOTINE PATCH on his arm. Doesn't stop him from burning another Marlboro.</context>
      <utterance>We don't know. But given the similarities of their location and appearance, this is a question that merits further investigation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Approaching the desk, John sits down at the radio. Reaches out to the mic -- presses down on the red squawk bar.</context>
      <utterance>CQ 15, come in 15.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WB2YKXB, who've I got?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the BACKGROUND of FRANK'S VOICE, we barely hear WALTER CRONKITE interviewing someone.</context>
      <utterance>Name's John.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you licensed to broadcast, buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't really remember how this thing works.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, you can't broadcast without a license. Unless this is an emergency, you gotta get off the band.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Pal, my whole life's an emergency.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you transmitting from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Queens, New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatta ya know. Bayside, born and raised.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought these things were for talkin' around the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>15-band closes down at night. During the day you can chew the band with China if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As John releases the squawk bar, the distant sound of Frank's TV filters out of the HAM.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe people are still using these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then John hears the sound of a door closing.</context>
      <utterance>Can you hold on a second?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry 'bout that. So Queens, you psyched for the Series?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't really follow baseball anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got fed up with all the bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite his mood, John has to smile.</context>
      <utterance>Fed up? Lemme tell you something, in a 1000 years, when school kids study America, they're gonna learn about three things: the Constitution, Rock 'n' Roll, and Baseball.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>John warms to the topic of his boyhood heroes.</context>
      <utterance>How can you live in Queens and not love the Amazin's?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Static crackles out over the radio. The signal weakens.</context>
      <utterance>If you're talking The Amazin' Mets, well, that's different. You know people talk about Seaver, but I'll love Ron Swoboda til the day I die.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm right with you, man. He's got the heart of a lion. Hey, how 'bout the first game of the Series?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More static.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It was all over after Buford nailed Seaver's first pitch outta the park.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BZZZSSSSHHHH - loud static. THE SIGNAL IS GONE.</context>
      <utterance>No way, brother. Ain't gonna happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind him, on TV, Larry King and Hawking continue talking.</context>
      <utterance>Who the hell was that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. The signal is gone. Frank leans forward, jiggles the frequency dial, trying to regain the signal. No luck. Slightly frustrated, he stands and opens the glass doors to the family room where Julia is watching TV - a very young STEPHEN HAWKING is being interviewed by WALTER CRONKITE, 52.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Queens. You there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankie, Johnny wants to say goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to take a step into the room, and stumbles over Elvis, sleeping by the door...KNOCKING INTO and CRACKING a GLASS PANE in one door.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I don't care if I never get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FADE TO BLACK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCTOBER 11th - FIRST GAME OF THE WORLD SERIES Blue sky. A SOFTBALL soars into view. It drops down and into a WILLIE MAYS' style basket catch by Frank Sullivan.</context>
      <utterance>The LEGEND reads:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucky throw, fire boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They square off. Pretending to fight. Julia steps between them. And they all descend into laughter. Frank and Satch each wrap an arm around Julia and start off. Within a step, Johnny slips in under Frank's other arm.</context>
      <utterance>Luck, my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See that, kid. Practice. Practice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't choke on your pride, Sull. You ain't ever gonna catch another one like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She made up her mind. Nothin' I do is gonna change it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spotting John and Satch, a UNIFORM approaches them. They keep on walking.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing you're willing to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the story?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIFORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The uniform leads John and Satch around some overgrown weeds to SEE a patch of freshly unearthed dirt...out of which sticks a HUMAN SKULL and COLLAR BONE. In the B.G., a CRIME SCENE unit can be seen arriving by van.</context>
      <utterance>Survey crew found a body. Actually a skeleton. Over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Satch turns to talk to a second UNIFORM and a couple of SURVEYORS, John notices a man raking leaves in a yard not far away. As he starts to him, to Satch:</context>
      <utterance>Be real careful when pulling it out. And get the dirt around it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll visit the neighbor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John looks out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John glances around the room - notes family PHOTOGRAPHS. There's a picture of Shepard in younger days on a commercial fishing boat. Next to it a faded black and white picture of Mrs. Shepard, 35. A few pictures of the Shepards and their YOUNG SON. And at the end, a color photograph of the same son, about 20, in DRESS BLUES, graduating from the Police Academy - CLASS OF '64.</context>
      <utterance>Used to get breakfast there all the time back from the boat. Them Greeks were good people. Once that McDonalds opened up on Dyckman, they lost all their business.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your son on the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>October '69.</context>
      <utterance>Was. Carl died in the line of duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shepard points to a frame above the fireplace: Distinguished Service Medal, CARL SHEPARD, awarded posthumously.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Mr. and Mrs. Shepard stand very still. John discreetly glances at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>My boy lived and bled blue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it'd be nicer to eat here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Sam couldn't make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure everything'll work out.  She really loves you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how are things at the hospital?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. You know Dr. Schwartz retired last month?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kidd'n, he musta been pushing 90!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Close.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how'd you like LION KING?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I loved it. I wish you'd gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I'm sorry. Work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You work too hard, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share a laugh. And then slowly the laughter dies. John's expression changes as he quietly lights a cigarette. Julia knows what he's thinking...</context>
      <utterance>Look who's talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat.</context>
      <utterance>29-years tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julia glances at an old photo of Frank, then back to John.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I could remember him better. Truth is, most of the stuff I know is from the stories you used to tell. But they're not mine. They're not my memories. They're yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PING. The microwave timer sounds off.</context>
      <utterance>You would have liked him, John. And he would have liked you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...WB2YXB calling unidentified station, Queens. CQ 15.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been Q-ing you all night. How the hell did you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The World Series. You called Buford's homer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't too tough, buddy. Game happened almost thirty years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? I'm talking about this afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Frank puts his finger on the squawk bar, about to say something, but just at that moment his son Johnny appears in the doorway in his pajamas.</context>
      <utterance>This afternoon?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy, come up and sing the baseball.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be up soon, Little Chief.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry 'bout that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you just say?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>John looks up at the photo on the wall: FRANK, JULIA AND SIX YEAR OLD JOHNNY SULLIVAN (CIRCA 1969). A beat, then:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that was my kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call your son Little Chief?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you say your name was?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this some kind of joke? Gordo is that you? Are you fucking with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look pal, I'm just askin' how you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me your name is Frank Sullivan, you live in Queens and you just saw the first game of the '69 Series...live?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right...and I'm asking how you called the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gordo, if this is you, so help me...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>John's POV - top of radio - in FADED PEN, on a piece of masking tape, is written: "WB2YXB"</context>
      <utterance>What the hell does Gordy have to do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you say your station...uh, your call letters were?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you listen to me. My name is John Francis Sullivan, I live at 1060 41st, where I've lived my whole life. And I saw the first game of the '69 Series at my Uncle Butch's house with my father...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>29-years ago.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad's name was Frank Patrick Sullivan, he was a fire fighter and a die-hard Mets fan. And every night when I went to bed he sang to me...  Take me out to the ball game, take me out with the crowd... Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm dreaming this. Shit, this is a dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>John reaches out to touch the radio. But he stops, his hand hovering just above it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not dreaming.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're Frank Sullivan, huh? It's 1969 and you're sitting at your desk in the study, just chewin' the rag?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ! Frank beats out the flame with the newspaper.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing...I just spilled something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just burned the desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening? John rubs his fingers over the old burn scar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eerie quiet, the only sound is the rain outside John's window.</context>
      <utterance>You burnt the desk...I can see it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if it's not...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Shockwave. A long moment of absorption. INTERCUT Frank and John.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could this be happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta be bouncing off the mother sun spot of all time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sun spot?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's how Hams work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank glances at DAILY NEWS HEADLINE - SPACE STORM. He says nothing for a long beat, struggling to understand.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a sec...there was something on the news. Something about this space anomaly. I think they said it was connected to some storm in '69.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sound...ground up...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thirty-five years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-five? That would make it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>1998.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank pulls back from the radio...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why are you doing this?</context>
      <utterance>1998...? This is wrong. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John's voice has a conviction that Frank cannot deny.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not doing anything.  Look, I don't know what's going on. But I swear on my life, I"m here at your old desk, on your Ham, in our house, right now...in 1998.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really you, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Both men trying to wrap their minds around the reality of the situation. Slowly accepting.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-five? Jesus, you're almost as old as I am...  What's your life like? You married? Got kids? Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too busy playin' ball, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, I gave it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John takes a sip, the answer caught in his throat.</context>
      <utterance>You happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're still my Little Chief, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quiet beat. A burst of static crackles the air.</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to be, Dad. I'm tyrin'.  It's good to hear your voice.  I missed you...so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm losing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No wait, don't go!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. I'm still here, Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More static. The signal breaks up, then returns weaker.</context>
      <utterance>But you're not...you're not still here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never knew you, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was an abandoned warehouse - hit by lightening.  Butch told Ma it was just one wrong turn. Said it wasn't your fault. You went with the training, with your instincts.  If you'd just gone left instead of right, you would've made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That can't be...that's not gonna happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It did, Pop. It did.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heavy static now. They can barely hear each other.</context>
      <utterance>October 12, 1969.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both men frantic. Their words overlapping...</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow. Jesus...it hasn't happened. It doesn't have to happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go. Don't go in that warehouse...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Final blast of static. The SIGNAL is GONE. The BAND is</context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOHN'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John scoots over to it, straightening it. But he slips, sliding down the roof, coming to rest against the chimney. A light pops on from an upstairs window across the street. Gordo appears in the window. Does a double take when he sees John, sitting on the roof, soaked, drunk.</context>
      <utterance>Rusted Ham radio antenna, half-fallen over.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sull! What the hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordo's heart starts to break. His best friend has slipped over the edge.</context>
      <utterance>I talked to him Gordo. I talked to my Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll play some Nintendo.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, man. Get inside. I'll come over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I gotta tell him the address, so he doesn't go in.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go in where?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The warehouse. Buxton seeds. It's tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCTOBER 12th - SECOND GAME OF THE WORLD SERIES</context>
      <utterance>I know pal. I remember. Twenty-nine years tomorrow. The LEGEND reads:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUDDENLY THE ALARM SOUNDS, moving the groaning firemen reluctantly to action, and freezing Frank in surging anxiety. Gibson is up and passing Frank...who begins to move like he's in a trance. A RAPID MONTAGE of Frank, Butch and the others readying to head out. Gibson grabs a little TRANSISTOR RADIO.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, man. Robinson is gonna nail it and we're gonna be dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks like he's going to throw up.</context>
      <utterance>Let's move it, gentlemen...three alarm. Lit up abandoned warehouse. West 49th.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank seems not to hear him.</context>
      <utterance>Sully, you cool?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank. Hey, man. You alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the RADIO we HEAR the last play of the game as Brooks Robinson grounds out 3rd to 1st. METS WIN! CHEERS are heard in the streets and from the CABS of the racing fire trucks. Gibson whoops it up. Frank barely acknowledges the win.</context>
      <utterance>I'm alright, Gibby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John shoots a look at Gordo, who quickly changes the subject.</context>
      <utterance>You get your roof fixed?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you believe it, Yahoo goes up another point today...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bastard's moving fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Surround and drown...nobody goes in. Frank nods in agreement. Directly above them, another BOLT OF LIGHTNING CRACKS through the darkening sky. A death shudder creeps up Frank's spine. And for the first time in his life, Frank Sullivan is SCARED SHITLESS. Frank stares up at the sky, transfixed. THUNDER punches the sky with a huge roar. RAIN starts to fall. And in the distance, as if from inside the burning building, a FAINT SCREAMING is first heard, and growing louder.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God it's abandoned.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, out of the building runs a STONED TEENAGE GIRL screaming and babbling incoherently.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Immediately galvanized, Frank moves to the girl.</context>
      <utterance>Help! Help! Oh, god. Help. She's up there. She's trapped! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to calm down.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey. It's gonna be okay. We're gonna help. Okay? Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now tell me, who's up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My girlfriend, Molly.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks to Butch. A beat. Butch gives him the nod. Frank and Gibson gear up and go.</context>
      <utterance>In a room...an office...or something. We live there. Top floor. Something fell on her. I couldn't help her. Please, you gotta...gotta...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You realize that if you'd bought a thousand dollars worth of Yahoo in '96, it'd be worth fifty-grand today?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You doin' okay, John?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satch and Gordo nod in sympathy. Gordo raises his glass. Satch and John follow. A yearly ritual.</context>
      <utterance>Tough day, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO &amp; SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To your dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To my dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks open on the other side.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know what's behind it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he barrels through the line of fire onto the 4th floor. Gibson starts to do the same when the 5th floor gives way above Frank, sending burning timber and debris cascading around him and cutting off Gibson's route. Now Frank's only way to go is up the stairs toward the 5th floor. He turns to Gibson. Coming up behind him is Butch. Across a gulf of flames Frank yells and waves at them to get the hell out. And then suddenly, part of the 3rd floor around Gibson and Butch starts to go.</context>
      <utterance>One way to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank turns and bolts for the 5th floor as a huge flaming BEAM CRASHES down onto the stairway behind him, forcing Gibson and Butch to scramble like hell back down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Get out...while you still can...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...it's not your time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta be another way up, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then fuckin' find it.  I'm going for the girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Billy, you better get up top.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck, GINO! Tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LADDER OPERATOR/GINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gear box cracked, Butch. We're fucked.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank! Frank!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...principal calls us in 'cause Gordy hacked into the school system - sent out a little X-rated e-mail.  Scary, huh? Eight-years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...something happens - TIME STUTTERS AND REPEATS:</context>
      <utterance>Just keep him away from girls.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little Chief.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John. John, you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Longbranch...?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not looking too good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, I just...I just...</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father didn't die in a fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father didn't die in a fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fire? What are you talking about? He had cancer, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cigarettes?</context>
      <utterance>Cancer. It was the cigarettes. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand shaking, John takes a long sip of his beer. Gordo and Satch exchange a concerned look.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, lung cancer. Ten years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you outta lay off a little...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gordo, I wasn't dreaming. I talked to him, it was real.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A loaded silence. Three guys looking at each other, thinking very different things.</context>
      <utterance>The Ham radio. That's how come he didn't die in the fire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing but static. Frank jiggles the frequency dial.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny? Johnny? You there? C'mon, Chief, answer me...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Silence. And then a voice...</context>
      <utterance>Chief?  Chief, are you there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Frank turns. Johnny, sleepy faced, wrapped in his blankie, stands just outside the room - he looks a little scared.</context>
      <utterance>I'm right here, Daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny shuffles over, Frank lifts him up on his knee - brushes the hair out of his face...and gets an idea.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, Chief.  C'mere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be scared. This time I'm right behind you if you fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy, Daddy, I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat. Johnny takes a deep breath, nods OK, slowly getting on the bike. Frank's holding on to the seat.</context>
      <utterance>No, but we can. We can do it together. Spirit and guts, Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Johnny takes a gulp of air, starts pedaling. Slowly moving forward. The bike picks up some speed.</context>
      <utterance>Take your time. I'm not gonna let go 'til you say okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank's still running alongside, holding on to the seat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm right here behind you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank lets go. Johnny keeps pumping those little six-year old legs. A bit wobbly at first, but he's gonna make it. On Johnny's eyes: determination &amp; self-confidence.</context>
      <utterance>Okay!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Way to go, Chief!</context>
      <utterance>Yes! That's it! You got it, you got it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm doing it! I'm doing it!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Atta boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief?! Is that you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the voice of an angel, Johnny. If you hadn't told me, no way I would'a ever made it. Frank cuts himself off in mid-sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, you there? You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John hesitates for a moment. Lights up a smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm okay.  What about you? I want to know. About you. And your mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're doing all right, Dad. We're doing good.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hard to explain. Something happened today. It was like a dream. And when I woke up I had all these new memories. Good times. Times we never had before.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But John looks troubled. Something bothering him. He takes a hit off his cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, I gotta tell you this...cause you should know. Cause I still remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, Johnny? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both men are silent for some moments. The hum of static. A breath, then -- JOHN (cont'd) We needed you. I needed you. So many times...I wished for you. But you weren't there for me. (beat) Mom tried. But she was hurting. I used to hear her, every night, for years, crying herself to sleep. Frank grips the radio mic, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>What it was like when you died in the fire...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The static grows. John leans into the mic</context>
      <utterance>I didn't think...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John's voice cracks, choking back the tears.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you think about it. And you remember, cause I don't wanna lose you again. I don't ever want Mom...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, this is Julia. Please leave a message after the tone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As John slowly hangs up the phone, something catches his eye. Something that wasn't there yesterday.</context>
      <utterance>Ma, it's me. Call me. We gotta talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank...what's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her in his arms, snuggling his head against her neck, losing himself in the scent of her hair. FRANK (cont'd) (whisper) I'm not goin' anywhere, Jules. For the rest of your life. It's hard to tell, we can't see his face, but it looks like Frank is crying.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I just wanted to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Frank is silent. So they just stand there, holding each other. And then Julia notices the burn and scrape marks on Frank's arms and neck. JULIA (cont'd) I got a bad feeling today...I was worried.</context>
      <utterance>Frankie, what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank pulls his head back, looks into his wife's eyes and kisses her on the mouth. It's a long kiss. As they come up for air.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here. Bruised but not broken.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Johnny?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tucked him in at Gordo's.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You give him his drops?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One in each ear.  What would you do without me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julia sees something through a glass door that stops her short. A YOUNG INTERN is standing over a gurneyed PATIENT. The YOUNG INTERN is changing the I.V. BAG. JULIA (cont'd) What's he doing? Frank, I gotta... He knows she's back on the job. Waves "no problem."</context>
      <utterance>Probably marry some rich doctor and never have to work...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me doctor, is that Benazepril?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julia quickly shuts off the I.V.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave this patient 50 mills of Benedryal on admittance.  Mix them and he's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wasn't I made aware?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The intern steps back: "Oh shit." Julia takes charge. The patient stirs: a SCRAGGLY HIPPIE, looks kind of like Pacino in SERPICO. A breathing mask covers his bearded face. Barely conscious, his eyes focus on Julia. After a quick double check of the patient, Julia looks up. Through the glass door she can see Frank watching.</context>
      <utterance>It's in his chart.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Bud.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you more. The clock on the wall now reads: 12:01 AM. And the LEGEND reads: OCTOBER 13th - WORLD SERIES TRAVEL DAY</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Confused, John clicks down the receiver. His hand is shaking as he punches the speed dial button for the second time.</context>
      <utterance>Noah's Deli. Can you hold?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>On the slam of John's phone, we got to...</context>
      <utterance>Noah's Deli.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JAMAICAN WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for Julia Sullivan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMAICAN WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you have the wrong apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Apartment 3C.</context>
      <utterance>But this is her place. 910 Riverside.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMAICAN WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John just stands there, lost, questioning his grip on reality. Liquor on his breath, fear in his eyes, he is a scary sight. Jamaican woman does the smart thing - she slams the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but no one by that name lives here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long silence.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another rough night, huh? That it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John moves for the door. But Satch grabs him, slams him against the wall. Startled, John freezes.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John shrugs, sagging against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Do not disrespect me. Disrespect yourself all you want. But not me. Or anybody else around here. You got that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is getting real old, John. And I'm tired up to here with it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I just...you know...I...</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm tired of the I'm sorrys. I don't need 'em. What I need is a partner I can count on.  I care about you. Not cause of me and your old man. Not cause of your mom. But because of you. Satch steps back. An awkward beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got the preliminary forensics on that skeleton.  Your gonna want to look at it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You imagine the odds...us diggin' up a Nightingale Murder? John looks from the photo to the file on Satch's desk. It reads: NIGHTINGALE MURDERS. John slowly sinks into his chair.</context>
      <utterance>Bad memories...</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She makes ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He killed three women.</context>
      <utterance>Ten? No. I remember this case. Three.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John fixes on the file. Then slowly reaches for it. It's filled with police and forensics reports. And PHOTOS. Crime scene shots of 9 DEAD WOMEN. Linked by TWO gruesome details - they were all GARROTED, wrists bound with GLASS TAPE. John turns over the last PHOTO and his heart stops...his universe crashing down on him.</context>
      <utterance>What're you talking'? You know better than anybody, John. You've read this file a thousand times.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK &amp; JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny's eyes close.</context>
      <utterance>Buy me some peanuts and cracker jack...I don't care if I never get back...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy is he excited about the game tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ain't the only one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish you weren't.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss. And dance. And kiss. And dance. He starts to slip her coat off. She laughs and wriggles away from him. Naughty boy. And she is out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, actually I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SAMANTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The answer is no. He looks terrible, as haunted as any man could possibly be. He doesn't mean to, but he snaps --</context>
      <utterance>John, are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Samantha jumps, frightened.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMANTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John turns, lost and ashamed. Sam walks to her car and starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Ellen said you were working. I just wanted to pick up the rest...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat. The hum of static. And then...</context>
      <utterance>Dad, you there? Can you here me?  Dad? I need you to be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right here, Chief. Sorry I lost you last night. Damn thing keeps cutting out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad...Dad... There's... I need to...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you alright"?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something happened, something...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Johnny, what's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatta you mean she's not here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She...she died. It's like it just happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She just died, your mother just died?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dreadful moment of silence.</context>
      <utterance>No Dad, it happened a long time ago, a long time ago for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>October 22, 1969.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ...that's...ten days from now.  How?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny, I gotta know. Long beat. You could hear a fuckin' pin drop.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eerie silence as John's words hang in the air.</context>
      <utterance>She was murdered.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Murdered? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was this case. A serial. He murdered three women, all nurses, between '68 and '69. The papers called them the Nightingale Murders. They never caught him. But the killings just stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kinda twisted animal.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, we did something. Something to make it worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatta you mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't just kill three women anymore. He killed ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something we did changed the case...changed history.  Mom wasn't dead. But then after you didn't die in the fire something must have happened. And this guy, this Nightingale guy, he kept on killing...it was like a spree...seven more women.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta take her away, John. I'm gonna take your mother away. He can't hurt her if I take her away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...  What about the other women?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll warn them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'll never work. They'll just think you're crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can we do? You don't even know who this guy is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Nobody got...  Wait a minute. I might not know who he is, but I know where he's gonna be. I got the case file. We know what he's gonna do before he does it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You think they'll believe me?</context>
      <utterance>So what should I do? Call the police?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will if they catch him in the act. You can make that happen, Dad. You can tail the victim and call it in at just the right moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is...this is different.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, John. I'm a fire fighter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John takes a long sip from the Bushmills.</context>
      <utterance>I do know. I'm a cop. This is what I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever talk to a victim's family? The one's left behind? They don't act like what you'd think. There's panic and fear. But mostly, it's like there's this logic problem. And if they could only solve it, everything would be okay.  But if you look real close - look at their eyes - you can see it. Just a glimmer. But somewhere they know. They know their world is never gonna be the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if the radio stops working? Christ, what if I can't reach you again?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you get Mom the hell out. But Dad, those other women weren't supposed to die. We don't try to stop this guy, we're gonna live with that for the rest of our lives. Frank takes a deep breath, swallows some air.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John grabs the THICK YELLOWED POLICE FILE. Opens to homicide report on Karen Reynolds. CLOSE ON FORENSIC PHOTO</context>
      <utterance>What do I gotta do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank jots down teh info.</context>
      <utterance>The next victim was Karen Reynolds...It happens tomorrow.  Case file says she left St. Vincents at six. Show'd up at Cozy's Bar around six thirty. She walked outta that bar around seven-thirty. They found her dead in an empty lot behind the place at eight o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not just get the cops to watch the bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close on NIGHTINGALE FILE on John's desk. Zoom in on the date below KAREN'S HOMICIDE PHOTO: October 14, 1969. The LEGEND reads: OCTOBER 14th - 3RD GAME OF THE WORLD SERIES</context>
      <utterance>They'll question her. Whatever they tell her could change what happens.  No, I want you to follow her. See if anybody's watching her, hittin' on her. I'm betting somebody's gonna walk outta that bar with her. When they do, you call the cops.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I tell them?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>progress... cause by the time they show up there will be. As Karen moves to the cash register, the CAMERA WIDENS TO REVEAL FRANK, awkwardly pretending to read a magazine. Frank readies to follow her when he suddenly trips over a crate of vegetables and goes down on one knee. Karen looks in the direction of the accident, and for a split second, her eyes lock with Frank's. Embarrassed, Frank looks away as he rights himself. Frank edges out of the grocery store as Karen steps into the street and dodges traffic towards a corner BAR/RESTAURANT at the end of the block, past a heavily overgrown VACANT LOT. Frank follows Karen across the street and finds himself, just as Karen enters the bar, at a point near the murder site described by John. He pauses to stare at it.</context>
      <utterance>Tell 'em there's a homicide in</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Chuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank wheels around just as Karen passes him from teh LADIES ROOM. There is the trace of a bump, enough for Karen to take note of Frank. Ad lib EXCUSE ME. She then starts moving down teh bar towards the booth of young women. Frank checks out everyone in the bar, not knowing quite what he's looking for. Karen slips into the booth with her friends. Ad lib HELLOS. Frank orders a beer, but his eyes are fixed on the booth. Karen and a friend take note of Frank staring at them. Embarrassed, he turns away, checking his watch: 6:40PM. And at just that moment a SCRAGGLY MAN passes by, taking a seat at the end of the bar. We have seen this man before.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Karen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John shakes his head no. Young Detective joins Satch at the coffee machine. John overhears:</context>
      <utterance>Any word on our bones?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how'd you think of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young Detective nods, impressed. John is less impressed.</context>
      <utterance>You're pulling over with a .44 bulldog tucked in your pants getting ready to blow somebody's brains out...I figure the last thing you're thinking about is alternate side of the street parking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we need here, Satch. A lucky break.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wasn't luck, Johnny boy. That was smarts and ten plus on the job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank glances at the women in the booth. They're all looking at him, smiling. A big one from Karen. His watch says 7:05. Taking the new bottle, Frank steps from the bar, past the Scraggly Man and walks to the booth. Charmingly shy, Frank is kind of at a loss for words.</context>
      <utterance>From the girls, pal. All of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was, uh, I'm not really...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fireman, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A married fireman.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, what the hell. Have a seat. What's your name, fireman?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Frank takes a seat, sliding in next to Karen. An awkward moment for him as she takes a closer look at his face.</context>
      <utterance>Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the Korean market up the street.  Mr. Lee make you pay for those veggies.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You following her, Frank? You're not some kind of stalker or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>General laughter all around.</context>
      <utterance>I follow fires, nothing else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satch is alerted by John's sudden burst of energy.</context>
      <utterance>Sullivan.  You're kiddin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mario, you are the best...right, right, right. Spell it out for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it was a close call, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close! The news said it was a miracle you guys got out alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In B.G. - at the bar - the Scraggly Man, looking frustrated, slides off his stool and strides out of the place.</context>
      <utterance>Close is just close if you're still alive to talk about it, y'know/ The women around him are clearly enraptured.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>April 16...? That means she was the first.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which means he probably knew her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But for some strange reason John has stopped listening to Satch. Something else has got his full attention. It is the Nightingale file that lays open on his desk. It is changing...Karen Reynolds' forensic photo disappears. In fact everything about her, all evidence of her murder - police reports, photos, witness reports - is GONE. John's eyes shoot to the corkboard. The head shot of Karen Reynolds and the date of her murder are also GONE. John looks between the file and the board.</context>
      <utterance>This case just got hot. We pull on this string...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank doesn't take the bait.</context>
      <utterance>I think I'm gonna head up, take a shower.  You wanna tuck the monster in and join me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something I need to tell you about.</context>
      <utterance>There's something I gotta take care of.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been talking to this...guy...this cop...on the HAM...and, uh, he...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, what is it? Just tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been talking to Johnny...on the radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. He loves that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes her a moment to absorb what he just said. And then she gets it... he's talking about a game.</context>
      <utterance>No. Not our Johnny. I mean, it's Johnny...but not now...in the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him on the forehead and heads into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds like fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be upstairs...if you want to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A quiet beat. And then...</context>
      <utterance>So am I.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are now...</context>
      <utterance>Karen Reynolds is alive and well. We did it, Dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be damned.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see him? Do you know who he is?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="52">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I just kept talking to her.  There was a lot of guys in that bar - could'a been any of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. This is working. This is gonna work.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatta we do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank jots down the info. Fires up a Lucky.</context>
      <utterance>Sissy Clark, 190 Riverside Dr., apartment 3C. Tomorrow.  She's a nursing student. Paying her way as a cocktail waitress at the Peppermint Lounge, on west 63rd. Left work at two A M...killed in her apartment, between two thirty and five.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, I think I may be able to get you enough information to make sure the DA can nail this bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coupla days ago they dug up a body in Washington Heights - Mary Finelli. Girl disappeared in '68. Turns out she was his first kill. Which means he probably knew her. Most serials know their first victim. I'm gonna do some checking - see if I can put any of this together...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A soft burst of static. The signal returns a little fuzzy.</context>
      <utterance>All right, I'm with you.  I just hope we know what the hell we're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me something good, Chief. Tell me about the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank takes a beat, contemplating the cigarette in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Well they found out cigarettes give you lung cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else, John. It must be different, huh? Are people living on the moon?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't happen, we got enough problems down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we like in...1998?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're okay...we're good, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what about the Amazin's? They pull it off?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really wanna know?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you betcha.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, game five was the big one. It turned in the bottom of the 6th. We were down 3-0. Cleon Jones gets hit on the foot - left a scuff mark on the ball. Clendenon comes up. The count goes to 2 2. High fastball. He nailed it. Weis slammed a solo shot in the 7th to tie. Jones and Swoboda scored in the 8th. We won, Pop.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julia walks into the study.</context>
      <utterance>Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang on a sec, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jules, I want you to say hello to somebody...  I'm on with John - that guy I told you about.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The future guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sensing that somehow this is important to her husband, Julia gives in, willing to play along with his radio game. She shares Frank's chair, he puts his arm around her.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but, no kidding around, he's a good guy, a real good guy...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, say hello to my wife...Julia.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>H-hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, future boy. Frank tells me you're a cop?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing voices, Johnny, Gordo and Elvis wander in from the family room. They are in their pj's...a sleepover. Julia gives them a smile, turns back to the radio.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My six year-old here keeps telling me he wants to be a policeman. Right after he retires from the majors. We just gave him a badge and a whistle for his birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...I remember.  I used to play cops and robbers but y-- ...my mom wouldn't let me have a toy gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're mom sounds like she's got some smarts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's pretty special.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a good cop, John?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I try to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'll bet she's real proud of you, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I just wish I'd told her how proud I was of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little Gordo reaches for the microphone.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I didn't realize...  But she knew, John. A mother knows what's in her son's heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Julia scoops Johnny up, carrying him off to bed. But little Gordo does not follow...fascinated by the radio.</context>
      <utterance>I better go. It's been good talking with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank laughs, as Gordo climbs up on his lab.</context>
      <utterance>I wanna talk on the radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the Space Cowboy. I'm an intergalactic traveler from the Federation planet earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gordo?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John sits back, marvelling at how young Gordo sounds. A thousand childhood memories playing in his head. And then he lights up...realizing the opportunity.</context>
      <utterance>How'd you know my name, mister?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordo looks at Frank: is this for real? Frank nods, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Gordo. My name is Santa Clause. And I'm gonna give you the biggest Christmas present you ever had.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I better give you my address then.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh don't worry kid, I know where you live. Now I want you to go upstairs and write this down, buy Yahoo. You got that Space Cowboy. Y-a-h-o-o. It's a magic word and I never want you to forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of Julia's voice calling Gordo to bed. Gordo scampers out. Static filters through both radios, then...</context>
      <utterance>You got a deal, mister. I mean Santa.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, you still there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm right here, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I think so...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BZZZZ-SHHH. A burst of loud static. The band goes dead. John takes a beat to come down. He gets up, making his way into the KITCHEN. There's a half-full bottle of BUSHMILLS on the counter. John reaches out to grab but the bottle. But then he stops. It is time to stop. John turns on the faucet and dumps the booze down the drain. The LEGEND reads: OCTOBER 15th - FOURTH GAME OF THE WORLD SERIES</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Chief. I'm not gonna let anything happen to her...no matter what.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOHN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On SOPHIA FINELLI, 55, a profound sadness sits at her core.</context>
      <utterance>Can I keep these for a little while?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINELLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John nods. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Detectives' been through that stuff already back then.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINELLI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll bring them back soon?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John pulls a clear plastic BAG from his pocket with a patch of the partially disintegrated clothing found on Mary Finellis skeleton.</context>
      <utterance>Promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mrs. Finelli gasps in recognition, her eyes turning to a closet door. John opens the door to reveal MARY's CLOTHES, lined up in perfect order. Visible among them is a "Candy Striper" uniform... a perfect match with the patch John holds.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know this?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINELLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Tears start to run down her cheeks. John understands this woman's pain. He looks around the room at Mary's possessions. Faded pictures. Mary and her family. Mary and her friends.</context>
      <utterance>Mary volunteered over at St. Vincents' after school. She loved it...was going to become a doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINELLI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>John does know.</context>
      <utterance>Her room...I just couldn't...it should only be her room...you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINELLI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Silence again. John nods.</context>
      <utterance>I'm happy you found her, Detective. It makes it easier...now, to know for sure. You know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, lemme walk you through it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John waits for Satch to finish. Then, as they head out into the hallway...</context>
      <utterance>Mind if I shake it off first...so's I can concentrate better.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three guys show up in both the yearbook and diary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satch looks, nods, and steps back. Waits for more. John hands him Daryl Adams' rap sheet.</context>
      <utterance>The third one is Daryl Adams.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ran him through BCI...got a hit. Busted for sexual assault: March 22, 1970. Eight days after the last Nightingale murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you figure the murders stop 'cause he's off the street. Then by the time he gets paroled, he's smartened up enough to control himself?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the first time that's been true. I'm telling you, I got a feeling about this guy. This is the guy, Satch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to figure what interests me more: the possibility that Daryl is the guy, or you making him absolutely the guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DARYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was over thirty years ago. I paid for that and then some.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go to Xavier High School, Daryl?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember Mary Finelli?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I'm saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I think you do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She casts a friendly eye at Frank.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a couple Bloodys, Gus, and a Dewars on the rocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin' there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just fine. You?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she's off with the drinks. He checks his watch. It reads: 9:35PM.</context>
      <utterance>Right now, just fine. Ask me later, fireman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sexual assault, Daryl. Five years. But you got lucky, right? You got away with something else. Something you figured nobody knows about.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I know is what I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you what I know, Daryl. You went to Saint Xavier with Mary. You lived five blocks from her. You liked her. But she ain't interested. That must've hurt, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what'd you do about it, Daryl?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satch can see this is going nowhere.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You spare a smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bartender laughs, as Frank stands and heads for the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to quite. Turns out those things'll kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get those away from me!</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God! What is that?! Why you showing me this shit!? JESUS! JESUS!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John looks like he's about to hit Daryl, but he glances towards the two-way mirror, controls himself.</context>
      <utterance>Nicky Moore. Patty Ryan. Mary Finelli. These names mean anything to you, asshole? Julia Sullivan! She mean anything? She means something to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fight fires, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. That's what I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bartender leans into the PA at the bar and announces.</context>
      <utterance>I bet you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank flashes his wedding ring at the sexy woman. Smiles at her and shrugs "I'm sorry."</context>
      <utterance>Last call.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daryl shakes his head "no."</context>
      <utterance>I gotta take a leak.  You need to use the head? You can, y'know. If you want to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And John starts up from his seat and walks toward Daryl.</context>
      <utterance>You know, Daryl, sometimes, despite all the training we cops go through. Despite all that we are taught about right and wrong. Despite all that we would like to honor in ourselves, we can come to a place where we don't give a fuck. Know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>SUDDENLY, in the door strides...</context>
      <utterance>You are going to tell me what I need to know, Daryl.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John freezes. Looks towards Satch.</context>
      <utterance>John.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satch opens the door and steps out. John collects his watch, badge and gun and follows.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ain't our guy, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just cause he didn't want to look at the photos doesn't mean he isn't the doer. Not everyone fits the profile. Long beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John pauses for several seconds, then nods slowly.</context>
      <utterance>If he was gonna give something up he would'a done it already.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KILLER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank is clearly incapacitated. Killer lifts him to his feet so they are eye-to-eye.</context>
      <utterance>I asked you a question, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look of absolute shock wipes across the Killer's face.</context>
      <utterance>Mary Finelli...</utterance>
   <speaker>KILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caught off guard, Frank is able to slam his knee into Killer's balls. Killer goes down like a stone, but Frank is too battered to take advantage. He collapses on top of Killer, who pushes him off, scrambles up, and delivers a massive kick to his head. Frank is out cold. Quickly, Killer rolls Frank over and rifles his pockets finding his WALLET. He grabs something from it, then tosses it aside. He then takes something out of his pocket, a thin leather garrote. He coils it around his hands and snaps it taut. He bends down to start the job when suddenly, the bathroom door opens and... TWO very stoned MEN stumble in.</context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STONED MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, dude. Is he okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Killer muscles Frank into a toilet stall and puts his head in the bowl. He closes the door, quickly leaving. In the stall, Frank spills onto the floor, his legs sticking out into the bathroom. His face flush to the tile, his eyes trying to focus on something lying just outside the stall... His WALLET.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. He just needs a little time kissing the porcelain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not your fault, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it is...we did this. We changed everything.  I've been having bad dreams, Johnny. Dreams where I die...in the fire.  I was supposed to die in that warehouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is wrong...it's like we cheated...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know...  But Dad, you can't go back. You didn't die in that fire. And no matter what you do, nothing is gonna change that. So all we can do is deal with this...and try to make it right.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I can. I'm not a cop. I can't. I can't stop this guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spirit and guts, remember?</context>
      <utterance>But we can, we can do it together.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank starts to light up a Lucky. But he stops, stubbing the cigarette out.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny, I know, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to believe in me. To believe that we can do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, he's got my driver's license.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He took my driver's license, John, he knows where we live.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He took your wallet?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he tossed the wallet, but he kept the license.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He touched your wallet! Where's your wallet?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got him! Dad you got him!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His prints. You've got his prints. I'll run them through criminal index. You gotta get me that wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell am I gonna do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, very carefully, take your wallet out, just touch it on the corners.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Dad, just do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank does as John asks. Taking out his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, now I need you to tape it up on the outside, where he touched it, so the prints keep.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you gotta hide it somewhere. Somewhere where nobody's gonna find it...for 29 years!  Put it under the loose floorboard by the window!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotcha, I gotcha Chief!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gonna work, Dad. We're gonna stop him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank fishes around the desk drawer for some electrical tape...quickly ripping off strips of tape...covering the wallet. Then he goes to the window. Crouches on the floor, digging his nails around edges of the loose floorboard.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>getting up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>John scrambles to window. Crouches down on floor, reaching to find: FRANK'S WALLET COVERED IN ELECTRICAL TAPE! John goes back to the radio.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And John is up, grabs gun &amp; shield. Sprints for the door.</context>
      <utterance>We're in business. Just sit tight...and don't worry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The old neighbor's son...the cop. But he's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talkin' about? I know this prick. He worked outta Brooklyn North.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never died...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thought I'd say "hello."</context>
      <utterance>Just came by to wrap up over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad you did. Come on in. Buy you a cup of coffee?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wife around?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Been dead 29 years.</context>
      <utterance>No. No. Well, sort of. In my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Sorry. How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John's breath catches. His look shifts back to the photo of Carl Shepard. Mr. Shepard reaches to open an album. There are several photographs of the young Mrs. Shepard. A couple where she is dressed in a NURSE'S UNIFORM. John is stunned. One can only imagine what is now racing through his mind.</context>
      <utterance>Well, she, Eve was murdered, Detective. An ugly one to tell you the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Blown away, John looks out the window to where Mary Finelli's skeleton was found.</context>
      <utterance>The mother of a cop, and they never found the bastard who did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happens that way sometimes.  Son still on the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John can only stay inside himself and wonder at the madness of the world.</context>
      <utterance>Nah. Doin' P.I. work now. Got caught up in them Knapp Hearings. Set up by some dirty cops who needed a fall guy. Hurt him bad. Would've broken his mother's heart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You used to be on the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, long time ago. I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look familiar?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John gets up, slides next to Shepard.</context>
      <utterance>No. What house you work?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The 2-3. Homicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hot shot, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, just working the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact, I caught a case that goes back to your day...one of the Nightingale murders. Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kiddin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John waits again for Shepard's reaction...</context>
      <utterance>No. Missing teenager. Disappeared thirty years ago. Found her bones last week. Buried behind some old diner, up by Dyckman street. Mary Finelli.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shepard says nothing, but his eyes are burning into John.</context>
      <utterance>Talk about dumb luck. Odds of anybody finding that girl, thirty years later. And then the chances of hitting a dental...forget about it. Bets part is she's the first victim. She knew the doer. I'm betting those bones are gonna do a lot of talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>John slips something on the bar, next to Shepard. It is a crime scene photo of Shepard's murdered mother. He reels back, totally losing his veil of composure. He is freaked.</context>
      <utterance>The past is a funny thing. We've all got skeletons in the closet. You just never know when they're gonna pop up and bite you in the ass, Carl.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, John gets up, leaving Shepard stunned.</context>
      <utterance>I'm the train wreck you didn't see coming. And I'm gonna steal your life away. You went down 30 years ago. You just don't know it yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me this maniac is a cop? What the hell am I supposed to do with that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the B.G. of Frank's house a DOORBELL RINGS. Julia can be seen going to answer it. It is Satch. There are ad lib greetings that we don't clearly hear.</context>
      <utterance>Call the FBI. Use a pay phone. Don't give 'em your name, Dad. Just tell 'em that it was Shepard who killed Finelli and Clark and the others. That he's the Nightingale.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them where Finelli's body is buried. They'll be able to connect him to her. Same high school. Same class. I'm betting they search his place they find some souvenirs. Satch steps into the study...1969.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm on it.  Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank's hand lifts off the squawk bar. He notes Satch's tone and demeanor.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here, Satch? You off today?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, you there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, we need to talk...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satch, you gotta just give me...Satch is here John. You hear me? Satch is here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny and Gordo remain fixed on the game, oblivious to anything else. In the kitchen, we can see Julia moving around putting away the groceries.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Frank, but you need to come outside. Frank releases the squawk bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, what the hell is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is going on here, Satch? What are those guys doing out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you know, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go outside and talk. We need to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat. Frank sees Julia staring at them. She is now a bundle of growing anxiety. Frank stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go. Do us both a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then he and Satch walk out the front door.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.  It's okay, Bud. I'll be right back.  Stay there, John.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rest of the penny drops. Frank stalls, trying to think</context>
      <utterance>Where were you last night, Frank?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he hands FRANK his missing DRIVER'S LICENSE. Frank looks like a truck hit him.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know where I found this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>415 Greenwich St. 302. Under the body of a murdered woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. This isn't what you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna be wrong here. But we need to go to the precinct and talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay. I need to go say something to Julia and finish up with the guy on the radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank nods. Takes stock of the cops by the cars and heads back into the house.</context>
      <utterance>You can talk to Julia. Forget the radio.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, you there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Dad. What the hell is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julia stares dumbfounded at Frank.</context>
      <utterance>Satch is busting me for Sissy Clark's murder. John...</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Satch strides by Julia and reaches to take Frank's elbow. Frank wheels at the sound of his name and the touch, and he lurches back from Satch.</context>
      <utterance>Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and the movement yanks the mic cord to the radio tight, dragging it to the edge of the desk. Johnny tears into the room and clutches onto his mother. "Daddy, Daddy!"</context>
      <utterance>...you gotta help me, Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Frank throws his hands up in front of his chest in an "I give up" gesture.</context>
      <utterance>That's not the deal, Frank. Don't do this to your family.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>And the HAM radio CRASHES to the floor in 1969.</context>
      <utterance>Dad! Dad! What's going on? Satch?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satch stares at Frank with utter incredulity. Phil lights a smoke, tossing the pack and the matchbook on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Carl Shepard. Detective out of the 15th precinct.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear, Satch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, huh...  Uh, huh. And you got this from the guy you were talking to on the radio when I came in?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As nuts as that sounds, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satch, would you listen to me here. Just you and me. Can I talk to you here, alone? Satch looks over at Phil.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil nods his understanding, steps out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a little time with this guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, this is not the time to be worried about covering up if you had a thing with this girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not gonna stop, Satch. He's gonna keep on...</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's quiet for a moment. And then a sound filters in under the door. The sound of cops cheering. It's the World Series. Frank sits up - takes a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Are you listening to me? You're in a world of shit. An eye witness has you outside the dead girl's apartment. We got your prints all over the place. Plus the fucking driver's license, Frank.  You gotta give me something here. Something I can believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if I could prove it to you, Satch?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if I told you that in the bottom of the 6th we're gonna be down 3-0. And Cleon Jones is gonna get hit in the foot. It's gonna leave a scuff mark on the ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The next batter, Clendenon, hits one outta the park.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, this is insane...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the bottom of the 7th, Weis is gonna hit a solo home run. Jones and Swoboda are gonna score in the 8th. The Mets are gonna win 5-3.  Go watch the game, Satch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the bolt slide, the knob turns and the door opens.</context>
      <utterance>Go watch the game? Go watch the fucking game? Frank, they're gonna make you for Sissy Clark's murderer. It matches the Nightingale's profile. You understand what that means?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satch nods okay to Phil. He closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>His wife is here. She wants to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank struggles for an answer...but comes up speechless. Satch looks like his heart is breaking. Unable to comprehend how Frank could have slipped this far. A long beat, then...</context>
      <utterance>Whatta you want me to tell her?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satch snorts, incredulous. Frank reaches over the table and takes his hand, deadly serious.</context>
      <utterance>She's in harm's way. He's gonna be coming for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Satch nods okay. They have an understanding.</context>
      <utterance>Promise me, as a friend. October 22, don't let her out of your sight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a collar in here for the Nightingale murders?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK SGT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm working with one of the victims outta Brooklyn North. You mind I take a shot at him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK SGT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Deleon and Hayes' collar.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They around?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK SGT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just missed Deleon. Hayes is up in the squad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the collar, in the cells?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK SGT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I think he's up in interrogation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shepard turns, gliding through the lobby like a shark...</context>
      <utterance>I'll go find Hayes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank waits a beat. Then very slowly, he stands.</context>
      <utterance>On your feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank steps back, slowly turning. Shepard holsters the gun. Kicks Frank up against the wall as he reaches into his pocket and takes out the leather garrote we saw in the Peppermint Lounge Bathroom. He coils it around his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Now turn around, face the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank is trembling.</context>
      <utterance>How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You twisted animal...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Frank turns.</context>
      <utterance>Evidence says you're the animal.  That's why you hung yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You try putting that thing around my neck and I'll rip your throat out. You want me dead, use the gun. Shepard smiles, unfazed...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shepard gives Frank a look that would make a Marine Drill Sergeant shit his pants. Shepard knows Frank's weakness, the one thing that would make him submit to death. Closing his eyes, Frank turns to face the wall...But the door handle rattles, someone is outside coming in. Shepard quickly yanks Frank away from the wall, shoving him in a chair at the interrogation table. The door opens.</context>
      <utterance>Let me draw you a picture. You live at 1060 41st Ave. You have a wife who works at New York Hospital. And a six-year old at P.S. 130.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shepard just laughs. Phil scans the room - everything looks normal, a cop questioning a perp.</context>
      <utterance>You got to help me. He's trying to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil shrugs okay.</context>
      <utterance>Mind if we take it outside?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Shepard and Phil step out - bolting the door behind them.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...didn't mean t step on your toes. They sent me up from downstairs, I thought you'd be in there with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you looking at him for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, half the uniforms are either at the game or on the street. It's gonna be a riot if they pull it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the score?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TV ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shepard inhales deeply, sneaking a glance down hall at the closed interrogation room door.</context>
      <utterance>Hadges is coming outta the dug out. He's calling for the ball. Can we get a shot of the ball?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julia seems bewildered as Satch gets up out of the booth, making his way through the restaurant and towards the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Can you excuse me for a second?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TV ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops erupt. Cheering.</context>
      <utterance>There's a scuff mark on the ball! The umpire has reversed his decision. He's sending Jones to first base!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mind I go back at teh fire boy for a while? I won't lay a hand on him, just want to see what he's got?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shepard gives Phil one last smile, then slips out - casually heading down the hall...towards the interrogation room.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, knock yourself out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on, Satch?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was right! Everything he said. He was telling the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you believe him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they hug. The weight of the world sliding off Julia's shoulders. But someone is trying to get Satch's attention. It is the counter man, he's holding a phone. Satch takes the phone, beat, his face goes ashen.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah I do. You bet your life I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He drops the phone, heading for the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm on my way...</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And Satch is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Wait here, I'll send a uniform.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell-</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have the right to remain silent. If you give up that right...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything you say can and will be used against you in a court of law.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sullivan?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have the right to speak to an att --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a small world, Carl. And I'm gonna find you. Real soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DESK SGT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>17th Precinct.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detective Deleon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK SGT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satch, you gotta listen to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank. We know. We know it's Shepard.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank clicks down the receiver, slides in a dime, dials another number. A beat, then...</context>
      <utterance>No kidding. I'm on the corner of 65th and CPW. Come get me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank smiles, and we dissolve to</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You missed a hell of a game, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time lets put some money on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satch sticks out his hand...Frank takes it. They hold each other's grip for some moments. Frank starts to say "thank you", but Satch silently cuts him off. Frank climbs in the car. Satch closes the door, taps on the roof, Frank is on his way home.</context>
      <utterance>Get him home safe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, bud.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she is out of the chair. They meet in a hug. Over her shoulder Frank takes a long look at his sleeping son.</context>
      <utterance>Frank...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A short pause, John looks confused. He sits down.</context>
      <utterance>We did it, John. We stopped him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. Something's wrong. I don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHACK! CLOSE ON FRANK, the back of his skull smashed by the butt of a .45 wielded by CARL SHEPARD. FRANK hits the floor with a thud, Shepard looming over him, reaching for a set of handcuffs.</context>
      <utterance>I don't remember. Why don't I remember?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHACK! The butt of a .45 smashes the back of JOHN's skull. He tumbles to the floor...fighting to stay conscious. CARL SHEPARD stands over him, the gun pointing at his head.</context>
      <utterance>Dad? Dad? What's...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My turn to steal your life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to meet the family.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is between you and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not any more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the shower curtain flies open to reveal SHEPARD.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Bud. Want to join me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julia lets out a bloodcurling scream and plasters herself against the shower wall.</context>
      <utterance>Sure do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your fucking hands off my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is right. Frank hesitates. Shepard LUNGES, grabbing the shotgun barrel. BOOM! Frank FIRES. BUCKSHOT RIPS THROUGH THE AIR. SHEPARD'S RIGHT HAND EXPLODES...blood spattering everywhere. Like a wounded animal, Shepard bolts, blowing past Frank. Frank gently wraps Julia in a towel. The fading sound of Shepard thundering down the stairs. Out the door. And then softer footsteps. Coming closer. Johnny appears in the doorway. Safe and sound.</context>
      <utterance>Don't. Don't do it, Frank. You're not a killer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keeping the gun pressed against John's temple, Shepard gets to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>You were the kid. I remember now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEPARD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>John closes his eyes. It's over, he knows he's gonna die. SILENCE. Then a sound. A sound we've heard before. A sound you never forget. Music to our ears.</context>
      <utterance>But this time, no Daddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK SULLIVAN - AGE SIXTY-NINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John looks up at his father, speechless.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still here, Chief.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Check out his eyes: they're different, he looks like his father. They've got that Frank Sullivan sparkle. John steps into the batter's box, cocks back to wood.</context>
      <utterance>John as he makes his way to the plate.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PHIRE POWER uncorks the fastest softball pitch you've ever seen. John jumps on it. Rips a massive shot to deep center, way over the fence. The crew in the stands are on their feet, cheering. Frank rounds third, John catches up. A double high-five from Julia and they jog home together. The game is over. Frank puts his arm around John. Heading for the bleachers. A little boy totters up to them. Jumping into John's arms. His name is Frank Jr.</context>
      <utterance>Bring me home, son! Bring me home!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John gives his son a kiss, glances up at Samantha in the bleachers. They share a smile. And as they step off the field, his little boy reaches up, takes John's hat off his head and puts it on his own...</context>
      <utterance>Hey there, Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elvis has left the building...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUE Bruce Springsteen's: TAKE ME OUT TO THE BALLGAME.</context>
      <utterance>John's face. In his eyes, bliss.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
