<movie id="223" title="G I Jane">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... last few years have brought many advances in the interests of women in naval service, particularly in the land-based maritime specialties. What's more, the Navy has instituted special sensitivity courses with an eye on --</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the center of a dais, LILLIAN DEHAVEN leans back to ponder the ceiling of the hearing room. Her plaque card reads "CHAIRPERSON -- SENATE ARMS COMMITTEE." DeHaven is a tough-hided old Southern belle, Scarlett O'Hara at 60. In her arsenal she carries conversational hand-grenades -- and she's apt to pull a pin at the slightest whim.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa, whoa. "Land-based maritime specialties." Gimme a second here to de-euphemize that...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHUCKLES from the packed gallery. The flag officers go stone-faced. Hayes forces a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Would that be anything like "typing"? "Restocking the cupboards"? That sort of thing, Mr. Hayes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hardly the case, Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On cue, aides begin distributing reports to other members of the dais. Hayes gets a copy, too. And it jars him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm just an old dame without much time left, so you'll pardon me if I jump right in here before they discontinue my blood-type. I am deeply concerned over the Navy's seemingly incontrovertible attitude toward women in the military. Case in point...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The Lark Report."</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam Senator... this is an internal document of the U.S. Navy. I must seriously question whether --</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Navy's conclusion regarding the crash of an F-14 aboard an aircraft carrier. Female aviator, it just so happens.  You're familiar with this report and its conclusion, am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was one member of the investigating commission.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I see your signature right here -- twice the size of everyone else's. And your conclusion was "pilot error," hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really not prepared for any kind of in-depth review of --</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A humorless smile. She's roasting his nuts over an open fire, and everyone knows it.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to think our next Secretary of the Navy would be prepared for anything, Mr. Hayes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The commission concluded that the aviator in question failed to execute a proper approach to the carrier.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That aside for the moment, I'm struck by the tenor, the ill-spirit of your report... the degrading remarks by other aviators... innuendo about her performance in unrelated situations... even a reference to her sexual activity the weekend prior.  In my seven years on this committee, I've never seen a downed aviator treated like this. Never. I'm deeply disturbed by this report, Mr. Hayes. Not just what it bodes for women in the military -- but for your own confirmation as well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... a full 35 percent of all jobs in the U.S. military are still, to this day, off-limits to women. And that's simply gotta change.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESS #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about those who say women aren't suited for all jobs? That they're physically weaker... they have less stamina...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEHAVEN'S AIDE catches up, pulls her aside.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. And we're gonna hog the bathroom, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>White House boys want a private meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll act surprised.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WHITE HOUSE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. DeHaven looks between the two WHITE HOUSE boys -- 1 young and eager, 2 older and cagier.</context>
      <utterance>... to reassure you that he has every faith in the ability of Mr. Hayes to guide the Navy into the next century. The task, as the Administration sees it, is to acknowledge changing realities without losing traditional values.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White House 1 looks spanked. Taking over, 2 pops a briefcase. An inch-think report appears before DeHaven.</context>
      <utterance>'Zat it? Ten minutes, nothin' on the table? Sweetcakes, you best go back to the President and tell him to open up the phone book and start lookin' for his next nominee.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE HOUSE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Surprised -- maybe even startled -- DeHaven flips through the report, absorbing by osmosis.</context>
      <utterance>Administration's plan for 100 percent integration. If female candidates measure up in a series of test cases, the President will support full integration within three years' time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE HOUSE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your gender-blind Navy, Senator. Surely you're not going to balk now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's just that askin' you all to integrate the Navy is like sending a man to do a woman's job.  How do you propose to handle the Combat Exclusion Laws?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE HOUSE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keep redefining.</context>
      <utterance>Keep narrowing the definitions.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE HOUSE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got around it in Saudi Arabia.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By calling women "Honorary Men." Ingenious.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE HOUSE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DeHaven riffles the edges of the report, thinking it over. Thinking light years ahead.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Senator, President's pitchin' right down the center of your plate. If women measure up to men, they've got the job. You going to take a swing? Or step out of the box?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE HOUSE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations, Mr. Secretary.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So she picks the women, we pick the programs. Seals?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAG OFFICER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd go Special Reconnaissance. Every bit as tough -- and we have a 60 percent drop-out rate among the men.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I suggest we start there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAG OFFICER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't matter who she picks. No woman is going to last one week in a commando training course. And I don't care who it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant O'Neil.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta situation here. Where are you? Stuck in traffic?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watcha got?</context>
      <utterance>Not due in for 22 minutes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A TACTICAL OFFICER reroutes the call via defense satellite, cryptography flashing on terminals. Lieutenant Commander ROBERT ROYCE joins other Intel officers at a conference table. They're pouring over weather charts, navigation logs, high-altitude NRO video.</context>
      <utterance>All right, stand by, we're going to switch over to COMSAT...</utterance>
   <speaker>TACTICAL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Voice-system now secure...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, fresh stuff: Lost a NATO plane over the Sea of Japan. ELB signals leads us to believe the pilot is alive and has made his way to the North Korean shore, near a fishing village, "Tamyung."</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we know it's him using the beacon? Not a decoy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Signals received only sparingly, in such a pattern that leads us to conclude it is a downed aviator trying to conserve his batteries.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chances of recovery?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the analyst for East China, O'Neil. Analyze.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Halfway 'round the world. So that's the problem -- we can get the team in, just not out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless you Whiskey Run.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blank faces here, O'Neil.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dubious beat.</context>
      <utterance>Quick-hit technique used by Capone. Rigged a getaway car with running boards and handles. All his guys had to do was jump on and take a ride. Check the files -- DPRK-57 -- I doped it out as a contingency plan: Seal Team infiltrates, picks up the package, links up with recovery sub. But don't waste time opening and closing hatches. They just grab the periscope and hang on for neutral waters.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You expect the extraction team to ride the sub bare-back? Is that correct, O'Neil?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence on the radio: They're discussing her scenario privately. During, Jordan's kayak reaches the junction of the Potomac and the Anacostia rivers. On the far bank lies... Naval Intel Center (N.I.C.), bristling with communication antennae. Jordan stares at the complex, waiting for a response.</context>
      <utterance>Only four minutes to neutral waters, sir. Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone goes dead.</context>
      <utterance>All right, sending the recommendation across the river. Royce out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thank you, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was good headwork, lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir. We hear back from the Pentagon?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably hear back from CNN first.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hate this part. Just sweating it out on the sidelines.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now they reach...</context>
      <utterance>Intel has its own glory, lieutenant -- no matter how subtle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the way, I'll need that option paper by 11-hundred today so I can review it with Admiral Hanover. And do we have any of that breakfast tea around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the upper walkway, a frazzled N.I.C. SECRETARY appears. She spots Royce and Jordan below.</context>
      <utterance>Is this my glory, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>N.I.C. SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but I have Senator DeHaven on the line for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bounds up the stairs toward his office.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus God, what now?</utterance>
   <speaker>N.I.C. SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Royce turns back and gives Jordan a hall-of-fame look. "Oh, really?"</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir no -- she asked to speak with Lieutenant O'Neil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So everyone I talk to says you're top drawer with silk stockings inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, ma'am. Um, may I ask what this is regarding?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>High-school pentathlete... ROTC scholarship, graduated with honors... top marks in Basic Training... and, as it just so happens, a constituent of my home state of Virginia. Oh, the things I'll do for one extra vote.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as Jordan's mind catches up to her ears. Now INTERRCUTTING the two:</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant O'Neil, I am prepared to nominate you for the Navy's Special Reconnaissance program. Should you accept, you'll ship out to Coronado next week and join in the big testosterone festival. Complete the course, and you'll have a fast ticket to any assignment you want. That's my personal promise to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Coronado."</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>California.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that, sir. Ma'am. It's just that... Beggin' your pardon, Senator, but... do you understand that this involves combat training?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is just a test case, O'Neil. But if it works out -- if you work out -- it could well change the Navy's official policy on women in combat. Or, actually, its official non-policy. Now who's your immediate superior there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Dwyer. Technically.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My office will fill him in and help expedite. Look forward to meeting you at the proper time. Jumping off now...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, question, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would I be the only one? The only woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The line goes dead. Jordan hangs up catatonically.</context>
      <utterance>There'll be more to follow -- but yes, dear, right now you're the pick of a very large litter. And your success would mean a lot. Jumping, now...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, shit-a-doodle-do...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Are you?</context>
      <utterance>So why're you even considering it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like you would be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spec-Recon. Those guys are world- class warriors. And they will not want you there, Jordan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dutifully, Royce massages her feet.</context>
      <utterance>I take it you don't either. Feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're doin' shit-hot at Intel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Royce. We're the same age, we started the same time -- and now you're sitting in the upperdecks while I'm still down in the bullpen. What does that tell you about the Navy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's haze grey and underway...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need operational duty to really advance... you need combat training to go operational... yet combat training is off-limits to people with tits. I'm topped out at Intel. Forget the glass ceiling -- I'm beating my head on a big brass ceiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So dump on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has nothing to do with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, guess I don't even need to be here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your dick back here. It has everything to do with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're such a ball-breaker sometimes. Especially at night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. But after our days...  So if I try this thing... if I ship out to Coronado... what happens here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try to keep the door open. If you wash out, I make it so that --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What then?</context>
      <utterance>Wai', wait. What happens if it works? Four months of training, three years of operational duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feel like doing an option paper on the rest of my life, Jordan. Maybe we should just let it happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is guy-speak for...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounded lame as soon as it came out of my mouth. But I'm trying to be honest, okay? Three years is a long time. Don't ask me to predict how I'll feel then, Jordan, because I don't know. And either do you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wounded, she gets out.</context>
      <utterance>You know, right up until you said that -- I thought I did know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jordan...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She punches into a robe and leaves. Royce considers drowning himself in the tub.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Royce. It was shaping up like such a tough call -- and then you go and make it so goddamn easy. Really, thank you so much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A DUTY OFFICER looks up to find Jordan across a counter. In no particular hurry, the duty officer makes his way over to check Jordan's orders.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, lieutenant. I was told this is where I check in.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing, other workers look up. Among them is a female ensign, KATHY BLONDELL -- no makeup, no nail polish, no concession to her sex. Throughout, she'll watch Jordan with more than passing interest.</context>
      <utterance>So you're the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The duty officer stamps her paperwork, returns it with room assignment and keys.</context>
      <utterance>Still don't have my bearings yet. Direct me to the officer's quarters?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He'd like a word with you.</context>
      <utterance>You'll proceed directly to the infirmary for eye tests, blood tests, urinalysis, pregnancy test. Uniform issue adjacent. Then you're to report to the Base Commander.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. And the officer's quarters?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a nasty little barb -- one that Jordan decides to let slide. Jordan turns for the door. Blondell catches up with a base map.</context>
      <utterance>C.O.'s office can supply you with directions. Enjoy your visit, lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>B.O.Q., south side. Take a starboard tack out the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, ensign.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem, lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A YEOMAN opens the door. Behind him is Jordan.</context>
      <utterance>Come.</utterance>
   <speaker>YEOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a beat, COMMANDING OFFICER (C.O.) TURRENTINE takes stock of the female in his doorway, sizing her up like a fighter across the ring. Then he stubs out a perfectly good cigar, rises with an amiable face, and touches the back of a chair -- stopping just short of pulling it out for her.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant j.g. O'Neil reporting, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course. Please, have a seat, lieutenant...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you care for a beverage? Tea?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. We're still coming to terms with the exact protocol for this -- for integrating the Spec-Recon training. It may not always be smooth, but we're trying to make it as painless as possible for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir. But I expect a certain amount of pain. More stock-taking. Is he looking at her hair?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barber was my next stop, sir. Would've had it regulation sooner, only --</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. If it's off your collar and out of your eyes, that's all I'm going to ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, I have no problem with --</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not out to change your sex, lieutenant. You'll have separate beds, separate heads. If you have specific medical needs, inform the infirmary. If a classmate or superior acts in an harassing or otherwise unbecoming manner, please inform me immediately so I can deal with it immediately. Questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None at this time, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another smile, another phantom gesture on the back of her chair. If Jordan was expecting a fight, the bell never sounded. She rises, salutes -- then turns back at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Then that's all I have to say. Dismissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I just want you to know... I'm not here to make a statement. I don't want to make men look foolish. All I care about is completing the training and getting operational experience -- just like everyone else, I suspect.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you were like everyone else, lieutenant, I suspect we wouldn't be making statements about not making statements, would we?  Take your leave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches Jordan. We can tell what she's thinking. "Just keep moving. Don't single me out."</context>
      <utterance>That is all that will be said about the special nature of this class -- by us or by you. Many of you have waited years for admission to this program. Opportunities like this are rare -- and those who seize upon them are rarer still.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Other than that, there is little to be said but "Good luck, gentleman."  "Gentlepersons." Jordan flinches.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking over, THE CHIEF stands before the class a moment, sizing them up while giving them -- get an eyeload of him, too: His body is 30 years old, his face 40, his eyes 50. An ageless warrior. Somewhere, the blood of Ulysses runs in this guy's veins. The Chief lifts a bullhorn to deliver his opening salvo -- and it's anything but the kick-ass rant the class is expecting:</context>
      <utterance>Now I turn you over to the chief training officer. He has earned six naval commendations, the purple heart, and the Navy Cross for heroism and valor. I give you Master Chief John James Urgayle.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trainees swap private looks.</context>
      <utterance>The sun and moon... the ebb and flow of the Pacific tides... global warming... the very angle of the Earth upon its axis... these are just some of the things I control in my world.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're fucked.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darth Vader reads poetry...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are so fucked.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Count down... one, two... count down... three, four...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLASS CADENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ambulance shadows the class. Perched on the front bumper like an hood-ornament, the Chief keeps working his bullhorn:</context>
      <utterance>One, two, three, four... One, two, three, four...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's also intimidating shit.</context>
      <utterance>You may think that you are the brightest, the best, the strongest. I assure you, that is a total delusion on your part. It is my job to show you just how weak human beings can truly be. 60 percent of you will not finish this course. How do I know? Because that is an historical fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The earth literally shakes as the phone poles hit the damp sand. Approaching on foot, the Chief loads fresh batteries into his bullhorn. He does it like a man thumbing rounds into a shotgun.</context>
      <utterance>Poles down.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He passes right by Jordan, never meeting her eyes. INSTRUCTOR PYRO steps up. He's the Chief's bulldog.</context>
      <utterance>Now for the bad new: I always like to get one quitter on the first day. And until I do, the first day does not end. So look around right now -- go on, do it. I wonder who it's gonna be...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guys strip down to boxers. Jordan settles for boxers and jog bra.</context>
      <utterance>Down to BVDs!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class wades in. The first wave takes Jordan's breath away: It's February, and the water is cold. When they move out of instructors' earshot:</context>
      <utterance>Now face the Pacific... link arms... and take a stroll!</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it with the damn phone poles? We sign up for Spec-Recon or</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the guys are glancing Jordan's way, cashing in on a cheap wet T-shirt contest. Jordan covers herself instinctively -- and hates the instinct. Modesty isn't going to get her through this.</context>
      <utterance>Just trying to thin the herd. That's all they want to do right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man. Doesn't she know it's rude to point?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWBERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. You see that girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got eyes, Newberry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One night. Just one night in my room, she'd forget all about playin' commando.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tone that shit down, Slutnik. You heard with they said.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class breaks for the beach.</context>
      <utterance>Out of the water!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The trainees hit their bellies and roll. Indeed, they look like sugar cookies.</context>
      <utterance>Now make like sugar cookies and roll in the sand for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Groaning, the trainees grab poles. Jordan's pole, wet slips from their collective grasp... And bangs Stamm's ankle. He HOWLS through his teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Collect those poles, gentlemen. Still a lotta beachfront you haven't seen...</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How bad? Stamm?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We better get a medic over --</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, goddamnit. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamm swallows the pain. Poles go back on shoulders. Looking like drunk centipedes, the class staggers off down the beach.</context>
      <utterance>Up! Up! Up! Up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pain is your friend. You ally. It will keep you awake in times of emergency... it will tell you when you are seriously injured... it will keep you angry and remind you to finish the job and get the hell home. But you know the best thing about pain?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instructors roam, RASPING ORDERS, kicking students into proper position. Jordan struggles with the reverses.</context>
      <utterance>It lets you know that you aren't dead yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around. A lot of the guys are having trouble with the reverses, not just her.</context>
      <utterance>Go regulation if you can't do the reverses, O'Neil.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir. But I like these just fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not doin' them very fine, O'Neil.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try anyway, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She switches to standard push-ups, her face disappearing into the ooze with every downstroke. Soon the Chief's boots slosh into FRAME. He's still looking for his human sacrifice.</context>
      <utterance>You'll try what we tell you to try, O'Neil. Go regulation.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's it gonna be. I just wonder, who is it gonna be...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nervous eyes flick to the bell.</context>
      <utterance>You have noticed a ship's bell hanging at the west side of this courtyard. If, at any time, you feel you cannot continue with your training -- that bell is your salvation. Strike it three times, and the ordeal is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his back to the class.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it is a long walk. So I'll make it as easy as I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA SEARCHES their faces. There isn't one trainee here who hasn't thought about it. Including Jordan.</context>
      <utterance>Now you don't have to watch me watching you break rank. Because I know someone here wants to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I know what you're thinking...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinkin' we could jump him right now...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Following the Chief's lead, Instructors lift their dive watches.</context>
      <utterance>"Can I really take 15 weeks of this bubonic asshole?" If you don't know the answer to that question, the answer is "No, you cannot." And that is another historical fact. So do it. Admit you don't have what it takes... admit you are out of your depth -- or we're all heading back to the beach right now.  Instructors! Time hack!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GROANS behind him. The groans give way to the SOUND OF BOOTS breaking rank.</context>
      <utterance>Six... five... four... three... two... one... HACK!  The time is now 12-hundred. The sun is shining brightly. Plenty of daylight left for another phone-pole run...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamm drops his helmet and limps away.</context>
      <utterance>Leave your helmet there, Stamm. Back to the barracks.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rest of you should remember one thing. The only easy day was today. Lieutenant Wickwire? Turning it over to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They march off.</context>
      <utterance>Cuh-lass, face right!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ENGLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan glares. None of them meet her eyes. She wheels around -- and now all eyes are on her, watching her ass walk away. FEATURE Slutnik, the walking sperm bank.</context>
      <utterance>Better look elsewhere, O'Neil.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan tries another table. This one, too, becomes abruptly full. As Jordan leaves, HOLD on Miller. He's a human eclipse -- six-three, 220, the perfect commando physique. Instructors wish they could clone him.</context>
      <utterance>Half a night, Lord, just gimme half a night to set her straight...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Think about that.</context>
      <utterance>Average woman is 25 percent body fat. That's one-quarter fat, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice distribution, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After wandering the mess hall like a homeless person, Jordan finds refuge at a table with female mess stewards. They look at her with blank faces. No understanding. No compassion.</context>
      <utterance>No way does she makes this program. No way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan looks. Someone is sitting on an outdoor table, smoking. He leans into the light so she can see his face. It's Wickwire, the mid-30s lieutenant who doubles as class officer. He's dangerously handsome.</context>
      <utterance>It's not so much that they hate you...</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're more afraid of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, now I feel so much better.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was made clear before you came -- harassment equals career suicide. Can't say anything good, so they don't say much at all. To your face, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose orders were those?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was made clear.  Anyway, stay ballsy. First week's hell, then it levels out. Until S.E.R.E. training, anyway. That's hell-and-a-half.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how do you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Made it to Week 10 last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know they let you try again. Especially at your age.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A faint grin from Wickwire before he shadows back across the courtyard that separates the two B.O.Q. buildings. Back across no-man's land.</context>
      <utterance>You're kind of a surprise yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>England, 88 seconds. You're good to go for the slide-for-life. Wickwire, roll back till you get south of 90.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck. Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The starting line. Stepping up next is Cortez, the human fighting cock. Jordan lines up beside him and psyches up for the first obstacle -- and eight-foot sheer wall.</context>
      <utterance>Who'd you kiss to get back in here, anyway? Wickwire dusts off and starts back for...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR JOHNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs something off a truck and positions it at the base of the wall. It's a little two-step platform. SNICKERS, MOANS from the guys. Cortez can barely contain his disgust.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on, here...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, what is this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR JOHNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't have to use it, O'Neil, but it's gotta go out.  Five... four... three...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can make this wall without --</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR JOHNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cortez blurs away. Jordan starts a step late. Cortez takes the wall clean. Eschewing the two-step, Jordan jumps right over it -- but jumps too far out because of it. She takes the wall awkwardly. INTERCUT the others as they break rank to follow, eager to see Cortez blow her off the course.</context>
      <utterance>... two... one... MARK!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cortez belly-flops into the sand pit -- and snags going under the barbed wire.</context>
      <utterance>Lesgo, Cortez, LESGO, GO, GO!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catching up, Jordan clears the wire without a hitch and leads going into... The rolling logs. They both tight-rope across nimbly and bound on toward... Rope climb. Jordan starts up at a decent clip -- but Cortez comes from behind like a chimp on white sugar, doubling her speed.</context>
      <utterance>Shit of a saint...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cortez reaches the top platform. Now he's faced with... The high poles. He's seen others land sideways and pay the price. Trying another way, Cortez takes a flying leap... And WHUMPS down with legs astraddle. He tried to cushion the landing with his hands -- and failed magnificently. His balls took the brunt. Jordan WHUMPS down beside him with legs astraddle -- and shoots Cortez a "Hey, no problem" look. She rolls off the poles... And drops to the pit below. Cortez lands right behind. Now it's a flat-out sprint for... The finish line. He takes her at the tape.</context>
      <utterance>Take her, take her here, Cortez... lookit that monkey-man go... hoo- yah, hoo-yah...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heading back to the starting line, Jordan wheels around.</context>
      <utterance>Cortez, 93 seconds. O'Neil, 94. Cortez, do a little rescue-recovery on your gonads and line up again. O'Neil... move ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say again, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me. Move on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Others GRUMBLE in commiseration. Jordan flushes with anger.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, this is such bullshit...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief, sir, I don't understand why --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Educate her, Pyro.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Automatic five-second deduction, which slips you under the wire. It's called "gender-norming," O'Neil -- standard procedure for all females in physical training courses. Where you been the last few years?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What "all females"? If I'm the only --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his back, leaving no possibility of discussion. Jordan stares after.</context>
      <utterance>Twice now, I have said the words "move on."</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't live with them, can't kill them. What's the point?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody throw a tent over this circus.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just let it go. If it's in your favor, just shut the hell up and take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon the hour, sir. But you told me to come to you immediately if I felt I was being mistreated in any way.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves her inside.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't take long.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, lieutenant, give me a name and specifics, I'll have the X.O. file an action first thing in the morning.  A name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's you, sir. And it started the day I came here.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's this double-standard, the separate quarters, the deferential treatment. It's how you pulled out my chair and nearly served high tea the first time we met.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I was civil, now you're complaining.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't afford civility, sir. How am I supposed to fit in with these guys when you've got me set up as an outsider? Even if I make it under these rules, I still lose, because there'll always be a flag in my file -- "Yeah, she made it, but..." I mean, really -- why didn't you just issue me a goddamn petticoat to wear around the base?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you just have a brain-fart?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you just barge in here and curse at your base commander? If so, I regard that as a bonafide brain- fart, and I resent it when people fart inside my home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now, finally, her opponent steps into the ring. And he's a bare-knuckle brawler.</context>
      <utterance>I think you've resented me from the start, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I resent, lieutenant, is some politician using my base as a test tube for her grand social experiment. What I resent is the sensitivity training that is now mandatory for my men... the day-care center I have to build where an officer's lounge used to be... and the OB/GYN I have to keep on staff just so someone can keep track of your personal pap smears.  But most of all, lieutenant, I resent your perfume, however subtle it may be, competing with the aroma of my fine three-dollar-and-fifty- nine cent cigar, which I will happily put out this very instant if the phallic nature of it happens to offend your goddamn fragile sensibilities. DOES IT?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir, WHAT?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dangerous beat -- before the C.O. disengages.</context>
      <utterance>The shape doesn't bother me. It's just that goddamn rotten stench.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. 'Least now we're talking the same language.  So one standard. Is that what you're after?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same rules for everyone, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Straight up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Across the board, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if you just happen to wash out, I won't have to contend with you bitchin' to some hairy-chested female Senator? And please note I did not identify any one in particular.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A deciding beat.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't dream of it, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'll get a fair shot?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll get everything you want, O'Neil. Let's see if you want what you're gonna get.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, who the shit you think you are? Comin' in here like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slutnik's face curdles. Jordan dumps her bag on an open bunk and starts unpacking.</context>
      <utterance>Your new roommate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody usin' these drawers here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey, HEY. No possibility. You can't stay in here. You can't sleep right next to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slaps orders on his chest, continues to unpack.</context>
      <utterance>Funny, the C.O. says I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, lookit this, lookit this -- she's bringin' Tampax in here. C'mon, you got nothin' but rooms over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That your desk? I'll take this one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Sex Ape. I'm here to stay. And if you don't want me for a roommate or classmate, you got two options -- move out or ring out. End of file. Slutnik stalks out. Jordan fires a look at the innocent bystander here, McCool. He was studying at his desk when the fireworks began.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McCool -- an imperturbable black lieutenant -- just goes back to his manuals.</context>
      <utterance>What about you, McCool? Any problem with the room assignment?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"It's not a job -- it's an adventure."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>58 degrees this morning! That's not a bad water temp, really -- if you're standing where we are!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR JOHNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slurred speech, lack of proper motor control, short-term amnesia -- all early signs of hypothermia! Advanced hypothermia is easy to detect in a classmate! He'll look like he's dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUTTING trainees and instructors:</context>
      <utterance>Body heat. In situations of extreme cold, you can always count on body heat to keep you alive -- and I do not mean your own. We will break you of the cultural barriers that dictate you should not invade another man's space. Are any of you in a situation of extreme cold right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class pivots 90 degrees and starts to close rank. Behind Jordan, Montgomery (a.k.a. "Flea") hesitates: He's a bantam-weight from Georgia, his manners bred into the bone. He just can't find a delicate way to grab Jordan without mounting her.</context>
      <utterance>Then why aren't you all over the man next to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just do it, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR JOHNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I want nuts to butts!</context>
      <utterance>If you can't feel the other guy's pecker, you ain't in tight enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Montgomery...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR JOHNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally Jordan grabs Flea by the neck, pushes him ahead and mounts him. The class closes down into a long human snake.</context>
      <utterance>Flea! O'Neil! Why is there a break in that line?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Montgomery, why do they call you "Flea"?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really "F. Lee Montgomery" -- but that gets whittled down to just "Flea." For short, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it really has nothing to do with actual brain size?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Flea, I appreciate the respect you just showed me. But I don't need it and don't want it -- not that kind of respect, anyway. It's just gonna hurt us both, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll work on it, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA POLLS the grim, blue-lipped faces in the water. Jordan feels Flea starting to shake. Badly.</context>
      <utterance>Check your watch, Pyro. Seems fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. You okay, Flea?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two bodies ahead, it's the big bruiser, Miller, who's shuddering. Jordan feels him shaking through Flea.</context>
      <utterance>'Snot me. It's him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, my hands... they aren't workin' right...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWBERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long i'zis for?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Sposed to be 20-minute intervals, no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWBERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swear each time's gettin' longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This where you bailed last time, Wick?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh-uh -- but wasn't middla February last time, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Bad sign. On shore:</context>
      <utterance>How you doin', Miller? Miller?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignoring, the Chief lifts his bullhorn:</context>
      <utterance>22 minutes...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A portable light comes on. Indeed, an instructor is setting up coffee service.</context>
      <utterance>Remember, all this is completely voluntary. For any of you who don't want to continue, Instructor Johns is now serving coffee and danish at the ambulance.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any takers?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the fuckin' Antichrist.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wick! They really got donuts over there? Or just some'a last night's dinner rolls?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look like donuts to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you guys doing? Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just askin'</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the line rips apart. It's Miller, breaking for shore.</context>
      <utterance>What, you gonna give it all up for a maple twist? How dumb you gotta be? That's exactly what they --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MEDICS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A medic nods to the Chief. No hypothermia. Not yet.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me what day this is... look at me now... what city are you from, sailor... here, look right here...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Avoiding his eyes, Miller wags his head.</context>
      <utterance>You want another minute to think about this? Huh?  Do any of you want to reconsider?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a death sentence. As the quitters slouch for the coffee truck...</context>
      <utterance>Johnson. Get 'em out of my scan.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT on the Chief. Scanning the remaining trainees. Thinking about holding out out for one more. TIGHT on Jordan. Knowing who he's waiting for. Wondering if she can outlast him.</context>
      <utterance>By my watch... which, of course appears to be broken... they've been in 27 minutes without the benefit of protective gear.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a SHIVERING CHEER, the trainees stampede ashore, grabbing blankets, trading body-bumps and high-fives. Jordan gets swept up in the esprit: They've conquered a common enemy. But when she tries to get high-fived... The guys turn their backs. It's a cold rebuff, worse then any water. HOLD TIGHT on Jordan. Shivering. Watching the guys drift away. Hating them.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody out.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Way to gut it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Wick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miller. Thought the guy was made of depleted uranium. Really didn't expect to lose him.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This one'll be no different.</context>
      <utterance>Every class has its surprises, Pyro.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class scatters. Slutnik hits the brakes when he sees Blondell and her friend.</context>
      <utterance>Change those clothes, be back here in six minutes! And I am timing you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ. And I only got three minutes apiece...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O'Neil! What're you gawking at?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>P.R. FLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"... last week at Coronado. The woman, identity unknown, is believed to be the first female candidate for the elite Special Reconnaissance program. Her presence could signal a shift in the Navy's long-standing policy that excludes women from combat positions." The P.R. FLAK drops the newspaper on the C.O.'s desk. It's the San Diego Tribune. Under the headline "G.I. JANE," a photo shows a chesty sailor running the obstacle course.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm asking again. Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>YEOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inbound now, sir. Had to pull her out of the dive bell.</utterance>
   <speaker>P.R. FLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have interview requests from two local TV stations. And a sociologist from U.C. San Diego called, wanted to know if she could examine the interaction between "G.I. Jane" and the men.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"A sociol..." Kill the interviews. I don't need civilians nosin' around in matters that are supposed to be covert in nature. Just kill 'em before this whole thing gets outta con --</utterance>
   <speaker>YEOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The C.O. gets an instant headache.</context>
      <utterance>Senator DeHaven calling, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>In the Senate barber shop, DeHaven is having her hair colored. She holds a fax of the Tribune article in one hand, a cell phone in the other.</context>
      <utterance>Base Commander Turrentine speaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commander, are you of the habit of letting photographers traipse around your base snappin' their fill? These were supposed to have been discreet test cases --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator, they stand out on the public highway with telephoto lenses --</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and now I got reporters from Toadsquat, Iowa, calling my office and askin' what I know about this "G.I. Jane" thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- nothing I can do about it unless you're suggesting I infringe on their civil liberties -- which I'd happily do if you'll just trim a little fat off the Constitution.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you truly mouthin' off to a senior member of the Senate Arms Committee? I mean, I'll give you points for style -- just nothin' for smarts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See me, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses her the paper. Jordan scans the article as DeHaven continues over speakerphone:</context>
      <utterance>You makin' friends with the press, lieutenant?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, seein's how this thing is out, you let me handle the r.p.m. From this point forward, I want all press matters coordinated via my office. I'll be god-damned if I'm gonna watch Hayes pull flowers out of his ass and take credit for this one. Him or the President.  This my shade? "Midnight Mahogany"? 'Cuz I'm comin' dangerously close to lookin' like Ronald Reagan here.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your prerogative, Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright. How's our girl doin', anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Standing right here in my office.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jordan, dear. How are they treating you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't complain, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. Maybe I'll ask when I see you in person.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deafening silence. We aren't sure who dreads the idea more -- the C.O. or Jordan.</context>
      <utterance>Gonna be visiting that all-woman's America's cup team in a few weeks -- If I were a gambler, I'd say Dennis O'Conner's days are numbered. But they're in San Diego, so I thought I'd take a quick promenade of the base.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, V.I.P. security arrangements generally take some time, Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Security"? What the hell you talkin' about? Your base isn't secure?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, but there's more --</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phone goes dead. The C.O. gives Jordan a look one might reserve for a lab technician who inadvertently unleashed Ebola upon the world.</context>
      <utterance>Then set out the good plates, we'll all have lunch. My office will follow up with details. Jumping off, now...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I want you to know that I had nothing to do with any of this. Not this article, not --</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"We'll all have lunch." Good idea. Oh, and let's be sure to invite this sociologist, too -- just in case we want to have a FUCKING BRIDGE GAME</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YEOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The C.O.'s headache becomes a migraine.</context>
      <utterance>Sir? Secretary Hayes calling.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Permission to leave, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Permission to evaporate, O'Neil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think I overplayed it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congress and the Pentagon share a lot of plumbing. They'll never know whose leak it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boat Five -- Wickwire, Cozad, Vinyl, Intagliata, Ayers, and Wise. Lieutenant Wickwire is your senior officer. Follow his orders to your death.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crew Five finds their Zodiac, hoists it onto their heads.</context>
      <utterance>Get it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan rolls her eyes: At least two of the guys in her crew are blue-ribbon misogynists. Cortez and Slutnik don't like it any better.</context>
      <utterance>Boat Six -- England, O'Neil, McCool, Montgomery, Cortez, and Slutnik. Lieutenant England is your senior officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, c'mon...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Motherachrist...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Again?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody got a problem with the muster?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine by me, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exchanging looks across their Zodiac, Jordan and her new crewmates lift the boat overhead.</context>
      <utterance>Full of joy here, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boat Seven...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ENGLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So shutup and stroke, McCool!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flea checks on Jordan. She paddles hard, really digging in. Flea grins: On some level, he has to admire this women. Jordan catches the grin, gives one back. Ahead, buoys mark the finish line. And just when it seems victory is at hand... THWUNK. Something hits Boat Six. Suddenly it's losing air. Jordan torques around to see... The Chief on a nearby boat, speargun in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Hoo-yah! Hoo-yah!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you do now?</context>
      <utterance>Your boat just hit razor coral.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patch and pump! C'mon! Whose ass is on the kit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say keep paddlin'! We're almost --</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They flail to save their sinking boat. Boat Five noses past, stealing the lead. Wickwire tosses Jordan a passing look. "Sorry, but..."</context>
      <utterance>Forget it, McCool! Pri One is to save the boat, not win a race! So let's get on it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four years I petition to get into this program. Four years. Finally get here, and now it's co-ed? Such bullshit. Now I'm gettin' hammered just 'cuz she's on our crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Least you don't have to sleep with her every goddamn night.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tellin' you, I'd rather be the last class with balls than the first one with chicks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had a grandaddy who wanted to be a Navy man. Wanted to fire them big guns on a big-ass battleship. But Navy said to him, "Oh, no. You can only do one thing on a battleship." "Well what's that?" grandaddy said. "Cook," they said. Now this ain't 100 years ago -- I'm talkin' United States Navy, middla World War II. And you know the reason they gave him? You know why they tol' my grandaddy he couldn't fight for his country?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He talked too much?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Negroes can't see at night. Bad night vision."</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan jumps in the hole, ready to take over shoveling.</context>
      <utterance>You're kiddin' me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs out. HOLD on Jordan, looking off down the dunes, seeing the other crews covering up and going underground for the night. How the hell did she wind up here? So far from home?</context>
      <utterance>See, you just the new nigger on the block, O'Neil. That's all. And maybe you moved in too early.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CNN COMMENTATOR</speaker>
      <mode>TV</mode>
      <context>Half-shaven, Royce leans out of the bathroom in time to catch... Footage from Coronado: A woman in Navy greens is on a beach run, loaded down with backpack and M-16. The NEWS FOOTAGE ZOOMS IN, FREEZE FRAMES with the indelible image that will be used over and over in coming weeks: Woman cradling rifle. Madonna for the 21st century.</context>
      <utterance>... is denying that it is considering changing its long-held policy of exclusion -- but it isn't denying the presence of at least one female in a heretofore all-male program. Dubbed "G.I. Jane" by the media, this woman is now undergoing commando training at the Special Warfare Command Center in San Diego...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn. My poster girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CNN COMMENTATOR</speaker>
      <mode>TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator DeHaven's office still has not released the identity of the woman, but DeHaven is confirming that "G.I. Jane" has outlasted many of her male counter-parts in the program, said to be one of the most grueling anywhere. Joining us now on "Washington Tonight" for the feminist perspective is Gloria Allred, live from -- Royce snaps it off. He can't take anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COMPLIMENTS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations, Mr. Secretary. Say hello to the President for me... Maybe now you can change that carpet in your office, Teddy... So what was the deal you made with DeHaven? Or was it the Devil? Always get them confused...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you hear? Effective immediately, all navy vessels can no longer be referred to as "she." BRAYS of laughter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VOICE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... women are child-bearers. Life- givers. Now we're going to make them killers?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... just don't have the upper-body strength...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Royce can't get away from it.</context>
      <utterance>How strong do you need to be to launch a rocket? To push a button or pull a trigger?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIAL-A-DATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we going to dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just yards from the bar, a Pentagon E-RINGER snags Royce's elbow.</context>
      <utterance>Not right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>E-RINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commander Royce. How's life across the river?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little slow, sir. When's the Pentagon going to send me a good crisis?</utterance>
   <speaker>E-RINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The E-Ringer turns to make introductions -- but finds his CIRCLE OF FRIENDS embroiled in the topic du jour:</context>
      <utterance>I'll check my out-basket in the morning. Say, do you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>CIRCLE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... but men have trained as athletes for 5,000 years. Women have been at it for, what, couple of decades? Do we really know the limits of their strength?</utterance>
   <speaker>CIRCLE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or their endurance? You know, 30 years ago, women marathoners were 90 minutes off the pace of the men. Now, the women's time is probably only 20 minutes off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIRCLE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try 15.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIRCLE #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes drift to Royce, inviting him into the fray.</context>
      <utterance>But what do female soldiers really contribute? I mean, why is this "G.I. Jane" there instead of a man?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wait right here. I'll get the drinks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VOICE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take my word for it. It's just not going to happen. Not now, not anytime soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Royce frowns: He thought he was alone. He tracks the voices to a forced-air vent beside the chaise.</context>
      <utterance>You're guaranteeing that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alarms go off in Royce's head. He moves quickly to a railing, looks down. ROYCE'S POV: Of two naval officers on the floor below. They stand beside a matching vent. It's impossible to see faces from this angle -- but one man has a distinct bald spot.</context>
      <utterance>I have it on unorthodox but reliable authority that combat positions will remain off-limits. Despite what's happening with our Babe in Boyland.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAVAL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>VOICE #1</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, isn't that what these test cases are supposed to decide?  Unless, of course, you're suggesting that "G.I. Jane" is on her way to becoming "Jane Doe"...</utterance>
   <speaker>BALD SPOT</speaker>
      <mode>VOICE #2</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I'm saying is that we won't be integrating -- despite the rhetoric coming off Capitol Hill, despite what's happening in Coronado. And you did not hear it from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAVAL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>VOICE #1</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hear what? A conspiratorial handshake. The men split up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DIAL-A-DATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over her shoulder, Royce spies Bald Spot heading for the cloak room. Royce commandeers the nearest J.O.</context>
      <utterance>There you are. Can we please dance now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant!</utterance>
   <speaker>J.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a dance!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crew Six! Stand by!</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>England's crew lines up for cast-and-recover drills: One by one, they speed-roll off the transport... ... and drop into the life boat. After quickly stabilizing, they roll off the life boat... ... and disappear underwater like human bullets. England is last to cast off.</context>
      <utterance>Flea! 'Cool! O'Neil! Cortez! Slutnik! In that order! Five- second intervals! Let's go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jordan recoils. Christ, how long has he been there? Just standing in the doorway?</context>
      <utterance>You know, the Israelis...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With forced calm, Jordan squeaks off the water and finds a towel.</context>
      <utterance>... they tried women in the 1967 War. Female soldiers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Permission to get dressed, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems the men couldn't get used to the sight of women blown open and their viscera hanging from tree limbs. Israeli men would linger over wounded females -- often to the detriment of the mission, often endangering their own lives. They don't use women anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, someone mentioned you received the Navy Cross. May I ask what you got it for?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For pulling a 210-pound man out of a burning barrack in Saudi Arabia.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. So when a man tries to rescue another man, he's a hero. But when he tries to rescue a woman, he's gone soft.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't say yes. She wants to but can't.</context>
      <utterance>Could you have pulled that 210-pound man clear, lieutenant?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Females in combat situations impact unit cohesion. Men fight better without women around. And that is an historical fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shoulders past. The Chief gives her a few steps before dropping his bomb:</context>
      <utterance>It also seems like a problem with the men's attitude, sir. So maybe you should be sniffing around their shower room instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>England went out with a stress fracture. That puts you in charge, lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McCool's that same rank. We're both j.g.'s.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were commissioned one month earlier, which makes you the senior officer.  Remember. There are no bad crews -- only bad leaders.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unbelievable.</context>
      <utterance>No operational experience, and now she's callin' the shots?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan overhears them BITCHING. She steps up to an open slot -- and proceeds to WAIL AWAY with her M-60, tracer rounds blazing. Her target vaporized, she keeps WAILING madly, taking out Slutnik's target... then Cortez's... then...</context>
      <utterance>Suppose she'll wanna eat with us now...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR JOHNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally she stops.</context>
      <utterance>O'Neil... O'Neil... O'NEIL!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR JOHNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reloading, Jordan tosses a look at Slutnik and Cortez. Ain't nobody bitchin' now.</context>
      <utterance>One burst, one body, O'Neil! What the fuck you trying to do? Spell your name?  You are not infantry! Your firepower is limited! Excessive killing only risks compromise...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Eating at a table with other women, Jordan turns to see Blondell setting down her tray.</context>
      <utterance>S.E.R.E. training coming up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They take you away to San Clemente Island. Half the guys quit when they come back. Supposed to be just hell-and-a-half.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you somethin', lieutenant? How come you're doing this? I mean, we're kinda curious.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's "we"?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just some of the women.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if there's any single reason. But my father was Navy. And he had this old-time recruiting poster in his den. It showed a girl trying on a sailor's uniform while saying, "Gee, I wish I were a man! I'd join the Navy!" Was maybe 10 years old when I first saw it, and even then it felt wrong. Made me mad. And I don't think a month has gone by that I haven't thought about that poster. "Gee, I wish I were a man."</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been accused of that wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The woman I saw you with...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a friend. We have friends, too, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But are there... I mean, how many...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh.</context>
      <utterance>More than you'd guess. It's just that we don't hold coffee klatches. If more then three of us get together at any one time, the guys think it's some kind of uprising.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reaching the quarterdeck, they scan a message board. Jordan finds a half-dozen phone slips for her.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds funny now, but it's really not. We have to be careful. The Navy still knows how to put on a witch-hunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Royce...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't they give you messages?</context>
      <utterance>I've been trying you for five days.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hard to find time to sleep, Royce. Much less keep up with my phone life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How hard they making it on you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUTTING Jordan and Royce:</context>
      <utterance>I feel like there's men here, there's women here -- then there's men. But hey, what'd I expect?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, not this. I was doing the Pentagon scene few nights ago. Got some fresh stuff -- about you. You may be in a hostile camp. I think someone may be taking steps to ensure that you crash and burn.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Why me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you know? How they're talking about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw an article...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan's face sours with an errant thought.</context>
      <utterance>I can't walk two blocks in Washington without hearing about "G.I. Jane." You're all over the place, and whether you wanted it or not, the feminists are sizing you up for that poster.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why are you telling me this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big symbols make big targets, Jordan. I think someone's gunning for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Royce, I got enough heat on me without you turning up the jets, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm only trying to warn you in case --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let me warm you: I'm going though with this. The more everybody fucks with me, fucks with my head, the more it just makes me want to finish. So don't expect me back crying in your arms any time soon, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what I want, Jordan. I mean... it is and it isn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gotta go, Royce.</context>
      <utterance>Still can't make up your mind, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jordan. You watch your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. I'll join the crowd.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Newberry is the new sixth man. He's young enough to still have a hyperactive Adam's apple.</context>
      <utterance>Infiltrate... establish your hide- site... record any movement of troops, vehicles, patrols -- any activity inside your scan. If you are compromised, you have two options! Newberry!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWBERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evasive maneuvers or radio for emergency extraction, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you are extracting, be damn sure to follow procedures you have learned in your classroom training! A helo cannot extract you from a wooded area! You must bring it down in a clearing! What's the minimum clearance for an MH-60 Black Hawk, McCool?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>32 feet, six inches, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rescue! Evacuation! Welcome to</context>
      <utterance>You will be penalized for early extraction, but you will be penalized more for capture -- trust me, far more! Survival! Evasion!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan looks back. "What the hell does that mean?" Offering no elaboration, Pyro signals "GO!" Jordan springs clear...</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant! Don't back down!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They secure weapons atop their waterproof rucksacks. Jordan checks a heat-bearing compass.</context>
      <utterance>Feel right at home, McCool?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moonlit shoreline. Half-mile ahead.</context>
      <utterance>South-southeast. And I don't want to hear another word till we're underground. Pushing rucksacks ahead of them, they start swimming towards...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan REPEATS THE INFO into a digital tape-recorder, adds the time.</context>
      <utterance>Got two FAVs moving south. I make... four banditos aboard, carrying... H-60 machine guns...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Newberry, get a photo. South?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Entering my scan now...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>West?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>North?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCOPE POV: Of the FAVs disappearing down the road.</context>
      <utterance>Clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone relaxes -- as much as six people can in a hole five feet-wide. McCool opens up MREs (Meals Ready to Eat) Slutnik guts his snake.</context>
      <utterance>FAVs clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mind? I'm trying to eat here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cortez finishes pissing into a tin pot. He transfers the waste to a zip-lock baggy, offers the pot.</context>
      <utterance>So am I.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Jordan. She eyes the pot, tempted and nettled at the same time.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abruptly Jordan unzips, drops her pants, sticks the pot under her. It raises eyebrows: It's a far cry from when she was covering up in cold water.</context>
      <utterance>Don't wanna evacuate 'cuz someone came down with uric poisoning, el- tee.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't even bitch about the seat, did I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pile up at McCool's scope. Jordan bulls her way through. SCOPE POV: It's a women. Dressed in civilian clothes, she collects firewood. And she's coming this way.</context>
      <utterance>What the... Got an unknown here. 100 yards north-northeast.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She part of the training?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCOPE POV: Of the women drawing closer... closer... and finally looking dead-bang at us. She does an about-face and walks away. Quickly.</context>
      <utterance>"She?" There's another one? McCool takes a second look.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. Think we're had.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smoke her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't gonna shoot her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only blanks. Lemme do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to Jordan.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Ain't your call, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pleased, Cortez slips his rifle under a roof panel.</context>
      <utterance>Pri One is to protect the mission. If she represents a real threat, we have to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McCool doesn't. Not for sure.</context>
      <utterance>But did she see us? Do you know for a fact that we are compromised?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If not, firing will only give away our position to hostiles in the area. Now how smart is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mighta been civilian.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWBERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got regular peeps on this island, don't they?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Banditos on the east perimeter! 150 yards! Shit, she was part of it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on Jordan, heart skipping. Did she really make the wrong call?</context>
      <utterance>What's the word, el-tee? We're about one minute from a major take- down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, fire-and-evade maneuvers. Drop everything but weapons and the PRC radio -- we're gonna be high speed, low drag all the way to the link-up site. Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Now she wants to shoot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This ain't workin' right!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's our go-to-shit plan, O'Neil?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as Jordan deliberates. She doesn't want to go out like this.</context>
      <utterance>This ain't even workin' wrong!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really don't wanna be captured, el- tee. Heard some bad things.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stand by for a PRC fix...</context>
      <utterance>Fuck.  Basher-Basher, this is Ground Crew Six requesting emergency extraction.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>32 feet, six inches!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally they break into a clearing. Is it big enough?</context>
      <utterance>I'm lookin', I'm lookin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cool?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan chucks a smoke grenade.</context>
      <utterance>Smoke it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LID BANGS closed. A LOCK RATCHETS, FOOTSTEPS RETREAT. Daylight sheets in through ventilation slats. When her eyes adjust, Jordan finds markings on the lid and walls. Scratchings made with a nail. The memoirs of previous tenants.</context>
      <utterance>How long?  Please, HOW LONG?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Don't know how much I can take"... "A little taste of death"... "Save the nail"...  "It's been three days now"...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I had an apartment about this size once.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wick. They got your crew, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Intagliata was out chasing breakfast. They found his tracks. Well, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really came back for more? Of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was sittin' behind a desk in Washington, it made sense, somehow. Blame it on my big brother. He was Spec-Recon. And the stories he used to tell...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anything to get her mind off this box. Out of this box. Now INTERCUT Jordan and Wickwire, lying like fraternal twins in their wombs of steel:</context>
      <utterance>If you got a good one, Wick...</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One time he was doing a rekkie of the Libyan coastline. This is, like, right before we bombed Khadaffi into the past tense. So his crew does a nighttime infil, maps all the big artillery placements and stuff, then turns around to get the hell gone. But between them and the water are five Libyan guards, all armed to the nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They had to kill 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, they were dead-ass asleep. But on every guard's chest,they left one Marlboro cigarette. Just a little calling card to say they'd been there -- and could come back any time they wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a good story.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>worth anything.</context>
      <utterance>So the shit you gotta go through? To get from here to there? Brother said it was worth it. Worth the training... worth the divorce...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was married?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At first.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got anybody, Wick?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It hurts to think about it. The Potomac. The gunkhole harbor. Royce.</context>
      <utterance>Not me. You?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O'Neil?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How'd you get through this part?</context>
      <utterance>How'd you make it last time, Wick?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last time I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's keep talkin', Wick. Just keep talkin' to me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reading as he walks, a former CIA spook looks up to find Royce in lockstep. It surprises him: Not many people here talk to him -- unless they're in trouble. THE SPOOK is physically unremarkable except for a face that would be right at home on Easter Island: This is a man who's seen most of the world's ills -- and forgotten none.</context>
      <utterance>Got time for a brain-pick?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Subject?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O'Neil, Jordan.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought you two were file-closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew about us?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Thought you knew I knew.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All around, screens go blank, phone lights extinguish. They sit at the conference table. No Computer. No files. Just two guys doing headwork.</context>
      <utterance>Computer -- no transcription, no com-link, no data-link. In fact... shut-down sequence 0-Niner-0-8, mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. So who stands to gain if Jordan flames out in a big way?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The E-Ringers? Full integration is gonna cost the services billions at the worst possible time -- when Congress is already swinging the axe.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congress cuts, military bleeds. But Pentagon's a big place. Let's narrow the sights.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Navy? They've made it clear they don't want to pull missiles out of subs to make room for women's heads. What's it gonna cost to make a fleet of Trident's co-ed?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sabotage born of economics? Wouldn't be a first. But is Hayes really going to start his watch with such a public failure?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Possibly. Just to spite DeHaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Royce blinks. "What's higher?"</context>
      <utterance>Hmm. Let's aim higher.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The White House. If Jordan wins, DeHaven wins in spades. Why? Well, it's been said that the only man the President fears -- ain't no man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first female President?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't for a second think she didn't leak this story. "G.I. Jane" gives DeHaven a symbol that taps into the biggest constituency of them all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Women.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you were the President, wouldn't that put a little piss in your shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Seems...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This ain't about some little soldier girl sloggin' her way through commando school. The implications go way beyond.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, I don't want to see her take a fall. She thinks I do, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I take it this file is still open.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even tough I don't talk to her every day -- I still talk to her every day. Know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, so now work it from the other end. Think about California -- and how things might be handled there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't...  What, someone on base? A "mole"?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is what you get for brain- picking an old CIA spook. but if I needed to control the outcome of this test case, that's how I'd do it. A man-in-place. Makes everything very controllable.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan seated. Prowling the hut is her interrogator. Her tormentor. Her chaperon through Hell.</context>
      <utterance>What is your father's name?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simple question, lieutenant. No reason not to answer. What is your father's name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Dad."</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any brothers? Sisters?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dick, Jane, and Spot.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you hungry? What's your favorite food? We'll try to get it for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Green Eggs and Ham. You're not going to get anywhere. You might as well put me in the cage.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are in the cage, O'Neil. Right here, right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I be afraid?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It makes Jordan think -- and yes, it makes her afraid. Continuing the psychological strip-search:</context>
      <utterance>Right down to your worthless womb, and I'll tell you why. This is my island. My world. And here I can get away with shit that would get me arrested anywhere else in the world. Take another scan of my little joy- boy outside. If I can do that to a Navy Seal, what's gonna happen to you? Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you shoot the woman, O'Neil?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't deemed a threat.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan rubs her head. So long ago. How did the call come down?</context>
      <utterance>She led us right to you. That's no threat?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you have shot if it was a man?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Yes. I mean, depends on --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The others already told me, O'Neil. They wanted to shoot, but you wouldn't let them. Because you went soft on another women --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not right.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what your crew said. Are they lying? Or are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're the liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not the one who got five good men thrown in a bamboo cage. You wear the bars, you made the call, and you got your whole crew --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't know we were compromised. Firing would only've given away our position.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares a beat, knowing it's a loaded question.</context>
      <utterance>You think we should go easy on women, O'Neil?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With stunning ferocity, he grabs her by the neck, pushes her out the door...</context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad we agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you know you'd be raped if you were captured? Didn't you even think about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Just like your men do.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flips her over, rips off her belt, starts tearing open her pants.</context>
      <utterance>I think we oughtta practice it, just so you know what to expect.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He covers her mouth -- her whole face -- with one hand.</context>
      <utterance>Should I practice bleeding, too, sir? Would that make me a better soldier?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the pen:</context>
      <utterance>Any of you can stop this! Just give me the location of one more hide- site, and it ends right here!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men trade itchy looks. Some do know.</context>
      <utterance>Three crews are still on this island somewhere. Who knows where?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chief throws her down like garbage.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it, don't do it...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men shift anxiously. Should they talk? Behind the Chief, Jordan staggers to her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Who's gonna tell me? Who's gonna be chivalrous and stop this abuse? What, you want to see her get mauled? Is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chief whirls, decks her a crescent-kick. Instructors lurch forward instinctively.</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell him shi --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She licks her bloody teeth -- and considers kicking his balls into his brainpan. Instead she makes a move to get up. He grinds her back down with a crowbar forearm.</context>
      <utterance>She's fine!  When I put you down, O'Neil, take the hint and stay down.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am saving your life, O'Neil. You may not know it, but I do. You're an inferior soldier, a bad officer, and I don't want you learning that inconvenient truth when you're stuck in a muddy bomb crater behind enemy lines and don't know how the fuck to get out. You get out now, O'Neil. Seek life elsewhere. And if you can't do it in front of me, do it behind my back. Pinning her down with just his eyes, he rises -- and starts away. Behind him, Jordan struggles to rise. An ANXIOUS MURMUR races through the men: They don't want to see this. They don't want to see her crucified.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eye-lock.</context>
      <utterance>Down... stay down... Hearing, the Chief turns back to see... Jordan wobbling to her feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT on the faces of her crewmates -- Slutnik, Cortez, McCool. In their eyes, a new respect. The Chief see it. Instructors see it. Everyone does.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you and the boat you rode in on. Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beaten, he walks right out of camp. Wordless, instructors open the pens, unlock the boxes. Wickwire rises like a vampire in daylight. But this time he made it. A medic tries to help Jordan, but she pushes him away, walking drunkenly for... Flea. She begins wiping the makeup from his face.</context>
      <utterance>We're done here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make you a deal, Flea. Never tell me how I look -- and I'll never tell you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think she'd be raped if she were captured? You don't think the threat of rape would be used to leverage the men?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You broke a dozen training rules back there -- before I lost count.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had it. Just because they pay me like a baby-sitter doesn't mean I'm gonna be one.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a trainee, just like the others. Why are you coming down so hard?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's an officer. There's a higher standard.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a women, and that's why you're ridin' her bareback.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it is. And I'm gonna stay on her until everyone realizes this is not some bullshit equal-rights thing, that real lives are gonna be lost. Maybe mine, maybe yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I oughtta report you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you probably would -- if you didn't know I was right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She made it through S.E.R.E. training. Got a call this morning from --</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The phone suddenly weights a ton, DeHaven dumps it on the seat beside her. HOLD on her disbelieving face.</context>
      <utterance>Not that. The White House just announced that it was sponsoring legislation that would, in one stroke, void all remaining elements of the 1948 Combat Exclusion Laws.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You there? Senator?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At his desk, Hayes scans the report with a deepening frown.</context>
      <utterance>Without telling us they do this? With absolutely no lead time?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAG OFFICER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Secretary, if this bill passes...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAG OFFICER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget our three-year plan. They're rushing the cadence. We'll be forced to reorganize the Navy from top to bottom -- overnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is the President trying to do? Steal DeHaven's thunder?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAG OFFICER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's more important, sir, to decide what we're going to do -- since it's apparent this issue is not going away quietly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flags squirm. Shaking his head, Hayes moves to a window that offers a stunning view of Arlington National Cemetery.</context>
      <utterance>"G.I. Jane." And which one of you told me she wouldn't last a week? Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>20 years in the Pentagon, I finally rate an office with a window -- and it looks out over the world's largest graveyard. Think it's a sign?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, didn't mean to --</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And know I remember why.</context>
      <utterance>That's okay. Just an ex-girlfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First big night of liberty and no date? You're pathetic, Wickwire.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'll just head over to McP's with the others, have a drink or four. Don't wanna come, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't go out. Not like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you look beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catching up, Blondell exits the exchange.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for lying. But you're the class officer, Wick, and it'd just be weird if we hook up. Besides...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees Wickwire. An awkward beat for them all.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Forgot I needed oregano and...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you, uh, know...</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going over to her place to make salad and pasta. Just, you know, nothing special.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan and Blondell head for the parking lot. HOLD on Wickwire, looking after them. Thinking it through.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Well... thought I'd ask.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR JOHNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MILITARY COP fills the classroom doorway. Frowning, Johns joins the cop for a private discussion.</context>
      <utterance>... underwater detonation devices employ mechanical timers, and as such, they are subject to variances due to water temperature. That's why when clearing mines, we always use two timers. The charts now being passed out contain calculations you must memorize before...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR JOHNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O'Neil?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR JOHNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wanted at the C.O.'s.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The C.O. and X.O. are both here.</context>
      <utterance>See me, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know of any delicate way to say this, lieutenant, so I won't try. Claims have been made that you have engaged in fraternization -- of the same-sex variety. Specifically, that you were...  "... seen leaving the apartment of another female officer at such a time and in such a manner as to suggest conduct unbecoming."</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The C.O.'s face remains grim. He isn't relieved.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, if someone is suggesting that I'm a lesbian, they're wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the C.O.'s nod, the X.O. opens an adjoining office. Wickwire enters. He's stiff as a groom on a wedding cake.</context>
      <utterance>They're very wrong. And I'd like to know where you got this information.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, O'Neil. But as class officer, it's my obligation to report all violations.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is insane. You've got no proof.</utterance>
   <speaker>X.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were seen leaving Ensign Blondell's apartment at approximately 0-200, whereupon physical affections were exchanged in public.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We hugged.</utterance>
   <speaker>X.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In addition, you have been seen frequenting the base exchange, the mess hall, the --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because the men didn't want me eating with them. Jesus Christ, let's get this right.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough. Everybody.  Rejoin your class, lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKWIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I didn't have to do this, Jordan.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wickwire exits.</context>
      <utterance>Dismissed, lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're just friends.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I just want you to know that this is either a gross mistake -- or someone's vindictive bullshit. In no way did anything happen between Ensign Blondell and myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>X.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan opens her mouth to confirm -- and hesitates, realizing where this might be headed. What the collateral damage might be.</context>
      <utterance>So you're saying the charges have no validity whatsoever?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm saying, we're just friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I find this as distasteful as you, lieutenant. But if it's on my desk, it's on my shoulders. There's going to be an inquiry -- it will not be quick and it will definitely not be pretty. You should prepare yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, please... if there's any way to do this without dragging everyone through the mud...</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan moves to the door. Again she makes eye-contact with Blondell. Now we understand why she's so scared: There's a witch-hunt brewing.</context>
      <utterance>I don't see how, O'Neil. Dismissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir. If tomorrow... I was not under your command... would the inquiry still go forward?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure what --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's offering her own head on a silver platter -- and the C.O. actually hesitates before answering.</context>
      <utterance>Would you have the discretion to end it right then and there?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She passes them robotically. Flea realizes where she's going.</context>
      <utterance>So what'd he want? O'Neil?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lurch after her, grabbing her, stepping in her way.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no... no, no, no, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McCool and Flea jerk to a stop: The Chief has emerged from the instructor's office. Helpless, they watch as... Jordan mounts the stairs to the bell... takes up the baton... and HITS THE BELL like a tyko drummer. RING ONE: On the pained faces of her crewmates. RING TWO: On the Chief. Taking no joy in it. Just accepting it as inevitable.</context>
      <utterance>Stand fast!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I wanted was an honest chance. And If I couldn't get it, I couldn't stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this class officer... "Wickwire." You think he was just trying to get even? Striking back for...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Though it didn't seem like he was getting any satisfaction out of it. Almost like...  Did I say he was class officer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost like someone put him up to it. Okay, who?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shortage of suspects.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him sidelong.</context>
      <utterance>The Chief? Or maybe even Turrentine? Your C.O.?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Royce. Tell me you didn't keep a file on me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head, resisting.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody was yankin' your stings, Jordan -- maybe from 3,000 miles away. I wanted to know who. I still do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Jordan. Do the headwork with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's done with, Royce. Let it go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone screwed you over like this, left unanswered charges hanging over your head, and you're not gonna fight back?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm tired of fighting back. I just wanted to come home and be safe and have you here and the river there and just forget the rest of the world, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agitated, she walks away. B.G., a PHONE RINGS until the machine picks up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, before you crawl off to die, Jordan, give me five minutes of good headwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"John James Urgayle." The Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Instructors typically pull three year assignments. This guy's in and out in one year -- your year. That sound right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like an amazing coincidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or like maybe he was baby sitting a problem child for the Navy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UNDER DIALOG, we hear some of the INCOMING CALL:</context>
      <utterance>Well, pardon me if I do. Now who else? Who could've leveraged a class officer like that? C'mon, Jordan, keep your head in the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A HANG-UP. Something stirs in Jordan's memory.</context>
      <utterance>... just got word today. The Senator wants you to know that she's disturbed by the matter, and she'll be looking into it carefully to make sure you were treated fairly. If you need to reach us, we're here in Washington, 202-224-3121.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"In Washington..."</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can see her mind gathering speed. Royce switches files quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Wickwire said he was dry-docked in Washington between stints at Coronado...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Wickwire, Thomas Dane"... Second run at Coronado... and correct, they had him stashed in the "Appropriation Liaison Office," whatever that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't crap out of Spec-Recon and get another shot without dispensation from someone up in flag country.  He's got a Sea Daddy somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd sure like to know who.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Administration, Ensign Blondell.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's...  Lieuten --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or rank. But can you do me a favor and pull a transfer order?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, but... You didn't have to do what you did. Not for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Wickwire, Thomas Dane." See what you can find.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who signed as his "sponsoring officer"?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finds a crisp sheet of stationary, out of place among the smeared government forms.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... don't see it. There's no signature. But hang on -- there's a note to "See Addendum." Checking...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE on the stationary. It bears an image of the Capitol dome.</context>
      <utterance>What'd you find, Kathy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>D.C. COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't even dream about leaving that vehicle there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not waiting for directions, Jordan takes the Capitol steps two at a time. We've seen this look on her face before -- and last time, she nearly knocked the grinder bell into orbit.</context>
      <utterance>Government car -- tow it if you want. Just point us to DeHaven's office first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Capt'n.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAVY CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The captain moves on. Royce holds in the doorway a beat, memory nagging him. Again he looks at... The captain. He has a distinct bald spot.</context>
      <utterance>Commander.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get started here. I'll catch up. Picking up where he left off a few weeks ago, Royce follows Bald Spot around a corner...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a side office, DeHaven's aide overhears. He rises quickly and enters the foyer.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant j.g. O'Neil.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How can I help you?</context>
      <utterance>Ms. O'Neil. Yes, of course. I'm Douglas Champeau. Unfortunately, the Senator is in chamber right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What chamber? Which way is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, she's on the floor of the Senate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, which way?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She really can't be disturbed. But if you care to wait, I'll find you an office with a phone. It might be several hours, but -- A TOURIST pokes in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOURIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Scuse me, but I'm here to pick up gallery tickets? Are you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over the aide's shoulder, Jordan watches as... The tourist claims tickets. HOLD on the bureau near the secretary's desk where the tickets are stored.</context>
      <utterance>See the secretary, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>DeHaven looks behind her. Nobody.</context>
      <utterance>Senator DeHaven...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she looks up to behold... Jordan standing in the gallery. Staring down on DeHaven as she is, it's hard to read anything into her expression but open disdain. Drawn by Jordan's voice, a CAPITOL GUARD hurries down the gallery steps. Royce runs interference.</context>
      <utterance>DeHaven...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the floor, half the U.S. Senate stops what it's doing and looks up. In the gallery, the guard is thrown off-balance by the naval uniforms: Do Royce and Jordan belong here or not? Confused, he looks for guidance from... DeHaven. She notes C-SPAN cameras swinging Jordan's way. Summoning a page:</context>
      <utterance>We can talk here or we can talk outside, Senator. You tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just her.</context>
      <utterance>Cloak room. I'll meet her there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jordan. I always hoped we'd get together -- though just now I'm gearing up for a child-care vote that --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant Thomas Wickwire. About to hug Jordan, DeHaven stops awkwardly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds familiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It should. You nominated him for Spec-Recon just three days after you nominated me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jordan. Might we do this over lunch tomorrow? I do very much want to talk, but now is scarcely --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you set me up? Did you set me up just to see me fail?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DeHaven glances back at the doors to the Senate chamber -- the open doors. Walking Jordan a few steps away:</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wickwire was there to help. To be my eyes on the inside, to make sure you were getting a fair shot. At least that was the intent.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What changed?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should probably ask him that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a threat DeHaven doesn't appreciate. The Senate DOORKEEPER appears.</context>
      <utterance>If I have to ask again, Senator, I'll be asking in front of cameras.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam Senator? Your esteemed colleagues are requesting --</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To demolish that legal foundation.</context>
      <utterance>Two seconds, Walter.  In 1981, the Supreme Court was asked to rule on the issue of women in combat positions. The Court cited the 1948 Combat Exclusion Laws as a legal foundation for keeping women ineligible. That decision held for all these years -- until the White House, 10 days ago, moved to have the Exclusion Laws voided.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? Isn't the President jumping on your bandwagon?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What he did was light the bandwagon on fire. Because he knows what I know -- that American families are not prepared to put their daughters in harm's way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In face, I do: Roper, Harris, Gallop -- they all come back the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying? That a women's life is more valuable than a man's? That a women's death hurts a family more?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan shakes her head in disbelief. She has met the enemy -- and she is us.</context>
      <utterance>I'm saying it's not going to happen. Not when the President is set to turn this into a third-rail issue should I choose to ever campaign against him. He will fry me six ways to Sunday for sending daughters and young mothers off to war -- and, quite possibly, for bringing them back in body bags.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were never going to let women serve in combat. You always had a safety net. Or thought you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jordan. I don't expect you to fully understand this -- but sometimes there's more to be gained from the fight than the victory.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the reality gets you in trouble.</context>
      <utterance>So the rhetoric gets you headlines.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The reality is this: We send far too many men off to war. I don't need to compound the problem with women.  Can you honestly tell me you wanted that life? Squat-pissing in some third-world jungle with --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted the choice. The chance to prove myself, my skills, my work, me. That's how it should've been.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam Senator, once again I must --</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not happy about it, the doorkeeper reaches into an alcove, grabs a broom he keeps around for just these occasions. He enters the chamber...</context>
      <utterance>Just hold the goddamn clock, Walter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I once promised you a fast ticket, Jordan, and I always meant to make good on that. Come work for me. I can always use a hard-charger on my team.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promise Wickwire a fast ticket, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had no direct communication with him since this whole thing began. And that's quite verifiable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll think about my offer?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I wonder what the SecNav would think about it. If I spoke with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I spoke with Mr. Hayes this morning myself -- and told him the deal was off. No more test cases. He was only too happy to oblige.  Don't play politics with me, little darlin'. You'd be up way past your bedtime.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam Senator, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flashes a winning smile and turns away. As the chamber doors start to close behind her:</context>
      <utterance>I'll call you in a few days.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The last image we have of DeHaven is her whirling back, startled. The DOORS BOOM CLOSED in her face.</context>
      <utterance>So I wonder what the President would think.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you had to go over my head, lieutenant, that's the way to do it. Christ, nothin' like a 0-200 call from the Commander and Chief to get the bowels movin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir? What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basically -- he asked me if I could unring a bell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of you here understands better than anyone what this is all about. Someone who has engaged in conduct unbecoming. Someone who knows, I would hope, what he must now do. CLOSE on Wickwire. Feeling the heat. Wondering if they really know who it is. Now the C.O. parks himself right in Wickwire's face.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wickwire breaks rank and heads for the bell. He slows when reaching Jordan, considering an apology he knows would be inadequate.</context>
      <utterance>And unless that someone takes the honorable way out in the next 10 seconds -- I will make certain he faces action under the Uniform Code of Military Justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does. As Wickwire RINGS OUT:</context>
      <utterance>Just walk away and never stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes swing to Jordan. Way ahead of them:</context>
      <utterance>It seems we have an opening for class officer. Any nominations?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CHORUS OF AYES. Jordan puddles up.</context>
      <utterance>All those in favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On his way to the front, the Chief stops to check in with Jordan.</context>
      <utterance>Chief Urgayle, turning it back over to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm trying to figure out if you're stupid, unlucky, gluttonous -- or some new alloy of all three.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good to see you again, too, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, O'Neil. So you've impressed all the others. Now try me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The HELO PILOT slows to five knots. The Chief gives Jordan the go-ahead nod.</context>
      <utterance>Remember! The one thing you can count on in any mission is that anything mechanical will fail! If you get stuck out here, do not call me, for you will no longer be in my class! Try the Coast Guard!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One-second intervals! Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cortez tries to help. The handle spins in his grip.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, c'mon...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan looks skyward. 100 feet overhead, the Chief gives her a parting salute as the helo lifts away.</context>
      <utterance>This tank's not gonna cut it, el- tee. Handle's stripped.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wonder how that happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cortez, see if you can dig out the tools without losing the rest of out gear. Try a wrench on that thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happening?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to bank clear -- but not fast enough.</context>
      <utterance>Fucking pelicans! Hang on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan whirls. She's just in time to witness... The helo hitting the water. In seconds it's gone. A stunned beat. We never knew the ocean could be this quiet. When the anesthetic of shock wears off:</context>
      <utterance>What the shit is...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't suppose this is just part of...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close as I can get, el-tee!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They grab masks and mini-tanks and dive in like dolphins. Jordan snaps up the radio.</context>
      <utterance>Flea, 'Cool, Cortez, Newman -- take your minis, hit the water. Go, GO!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over.</context>
      <utterance>Base, this is Crew Leader Six. What is your E.T.A. on that rescue helo?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Crew Leader, we have a Medevac rerouting from Long Beach, but no other helos prepped at this time. Seafox One and Two are launching now. Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Base, don't think you copied me. We are 12 miles out. Seafox tops out at 30 knots, which makes it a no- show for 18 minutes. Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We're looking for options ourselves.</context>
      <utterance>You copied right, Crew Leader.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should call the Coast Guard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut your hole, Slutnik.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others surface and swim in.</context>
      <utterance>Visibility drops dead at 40 feet. If they're deeper than that...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A grim beat -- and then A CRACKLE on the radio. With a voice seemingly from the far side of the moon:</context>
      <utterance>Nobody's comin' outta that crash, el-tee. Nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jaws drop.</context>
      <utterance>Base, this is Basher One. I've got a small problem here. Do you copy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basher One, this is O'Neil. We are barely reading you. What is your situation?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got one other heartbeat here, looks touch and go. I've got a questionable leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief, sir -- rescue team won't be here for 15 minutes. What's your air situation? Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say again? How many micks?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>15, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That... may not be adequate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we could just fix on him...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beacon's a no-go for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over.</context>
      <utterance>Chief -- did I see a flare box aboard? And can you get at it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FLEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six o'clock! Marking, marking!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ominous beat.</context>
      <utterance>Spotted you, Chief. Pri One is to slip you some air, so we're coming down with a tank -- just something until the A-team shows. Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O'Neil... there's no air in your main tanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They scramble to check their main dive tanks. Even through the gauges show full, they're dead empty. All of them.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan surveys the equipment they do have aboard -- the stuff she can count on. Mental turbos kicking in:</context>
      <utterance>He's circlin' the drain, el-tee.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we got two full mini-tanks, three minutes each. 'Cool? How much air in yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe half. Not even.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grab an oar, find a way to weight it down, we're gonna need it. Cortez, help him. Flea? You take one of the two full minis -- and just follow my lead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, we're gonna pry 'em out with paddles?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O'Neil. Our air's gonna crap out as soon as we get down there. You know that, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I guess we get one shot at it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief, sir... still with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take him first. Once he's clear, come back with --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, let me suggest you stop giving orders and start doing exactly what I say, because that's the only way we're all getting out of here. Now how's your vest check out? Still good?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O'Neil...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The recovery loop comes at her like a big brass ring. SEAFOX THUNDERS past. Jordan plunges her free arm through the loop... And suddenly they're gone, whisked away by the boat. Throwing a rooster tail a mile long, Seafox pivots on the water and heads back to base.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, sir. I'm concentrating.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCOOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hoooooo-yah!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWBERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go, go, go, go!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUTNIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh! That's right! Just like we always practice it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator DeHaven is here for the graduation ceremonies.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are all these other vehicles?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a small press corps. Routine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that pickup truck at the end?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That? That would be the all-woman America's Cup team.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a small case. Jordan opens it to find a medal of bronze and blue enamel.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant? I was asked to give you this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Navy Cross...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe he earned it for saving a man's life in Saudi Arabia. He wanted you to have it. He was very clear on that point.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was looking for him earlier, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Chief was granted early retirement as of 17-hundred yesterday. By 18-hundred he was gone. Out of the Navy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a coincidence?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan nods, understanding.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's not my place to speculate on his private thoughts. But I think the Chief knew that his way -- his world -- had come and gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan approaches. Spotting her, the PRESS PLEADS for a photo-op with both women.</context>
      <utterance>... of course, we always prefer peace to war. But if we're going to war, give women a piece. Give them the choice to defend their country. And if the President doesn't like that idea -- if he wants to continue to deny women their equal rights -- then I'll be happy to step out back with him any time, anywhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEHAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Letting silence be the ultimate expression of scorn, Jordan walks right past DeHaven... And joins Royce. Together they turn and leave.</context>
      <utterance>Jordan? Jordan, dear...</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator, perhaps this would be a good time for that lunch. Will the America's Cup team be joining us?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So here we are again. Staring three years of operational duty in the face.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. It's not like you'd be completely out of reach. And maybe we could call in a few favors, get you stationed at Norfolk instead of Coronado. There are ways of dealing with these things -- I mean, if people are so inclined.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is guy-speak for...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Yes, Jordan -- I'll wait for you no matter how long." Finally, the right answer.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
