<movie id="225" title="Gandhi">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MURROW'S VOICE-OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the throng, following the weapon-carrier bier of Gandhi as it slowly inches its way along the Kingsway. Mountbatten, tall, handsome, bemedalled, walks at the head of dignitaries from many lands... and behind them a broad mass of Indians. For a moment we see their sandalled feet moving along the roadway and realize their quiet, rhythmic shuffling is the only noise this vast assemblage has produced.</context>
      <utterance>Mahatma Gandhi was not a commander of great armies nor ruler of vast lands, he could boast no scientific achievements, no artistic gift... Yet men, governments and dignitaries from all over the world have joined hands today to pay homage to this little brown man in the loincloth who led his country to freedom...</utterance>
   <speaker>MURROW'S VOICE-OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Canterbury, President Truman, Chiang Kai-shek, The Foreign Minister of Russia, the President of France... are among the millions here and abroad who have lamented his passing. In the words of General George C. Marshall, the American Secretary of State, "Mahatma Gandhi had become the spokesman for the conscience of mankind..." In the crowd following the bier we pick out the tall, English figure of Mirabehn, dressed in a sari, her face taut in a grief that seems ready to break like the Ganges in flood. Near her a tall, heavy-set man, Germanic, still powerful of build and mien though his white hair and deep lines suggest a man well into his sixties (Kallenbach). He too marches with a kind of numb air of loss that is too personal for national mourning. On the edge of the street an American newspaperman (Walker) watches as the bier passes him. He has been making notes, but his hand stops now and we see the profile of Gandhi from his point of view as the weapon-carrier silently rolls by. It is personal, close. Walker clenches his teeth and there is moisture in his eyes as he looks down. He tries to bring his attention to his pad again, but his heart is not in it and he stares with hollow emptiness at the street and the horde of passing feet following the bier.</context>
      <utterance>Pope Pius, the Archbishop of</utterance>
   <speaker>MURROW'S VOICE-OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera picks out those who ride on the weapon-carrier with Gandhi's body... the stout, blunt, but now shattered Patel, Gandhi's son, Devadas, the strong, almost fierce face of Maulana Azad, now angry at the Gods themselves... and finally Pandit Nehru -- a face with the strength of a hero, the sensitivity of a poet, and now wounded like the son of a loving father.</context>
      <utterance>...a man who made humility and simple truth more powerful than empires." And Albert Einstein added, "Generations to come will scarce believe that such a one as this ever in flesh and blood walked upon this earth."</utterance>
   <speaker>MURROW'S VOICE-OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A news truck is parked in the mass of the crowd. As the cortege nears, the photographers on it stand to snap their pictures. There is a newsreel crew center. The camera features a woman photographer (Margaret Bourke-White) who sits with her legs dangling over the side of the truck, her famous camera held loosely in her hand, un-regarded, as she watches the body of Gandhi approach. The intelligent features are betrayed by the emotion in her eyes. For an instant we see Gandhi from her point of view, and read the personal impact it has on her.</context>
      <utterance>... but perhaps to this man of peace, to this fighter who fought without malice or falsehood or hate, the tribute he would value most has come from General Douglas McArthur: "If civilization is to survive," the General said this morning, "all men cannot fail to adopt Gandhi's belief that the use of force to resolve conflict is not only wrong but contains within itself the germ of our own self-destruction."...</utterance>
   <speaker>MURROW'S VOICE-OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera is high and we see the cortege from the rear, moving off down the vast esplanade, its narrowing path parting the sea of humanity like a long trail across a weaving plain... and as the shuffling sound of sandalled feet fades in the distance we dissolve through to</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps for the rest of us, the most satisfying comment on this tragedy comes from the impudent New York PM which today wrote, "There is still hope for a world which reacts as reverently as ours has to the death of a man like Gandhi."...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me -- do you think about hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Hell!"</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The porter has glanced down the corridor, where from his point of view we can just glimpse the European talking with the conductor.</context>
      <utterance>No -- neither do I. But...  but this man is a Christian and he has written --</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, baas, but how long have you been in South Africa?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A -- a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up suddenly then turns back quickly to his work. Gandhi glances at the door to see what has frightened him so. The European and the conductor push open the door and stride in.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know how you got a ticket for --</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi is incredulous that he is being addressed in such a manner.</context>
      <utterance>Here -- coolie, just what are you doing in this car?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why -- I -- I have a ticket. A First Class ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get hold of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's taken out the ticket but there is a bit of bluster in his attitude and it is cut off by a cold rebuff from the European.</context>
      <utterance>I sent for it in the post. I'm an attorney, and I didn't have time to --</utterance>
   <speaker>EUROPEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures to the back of the train. Gandhi is nonplussed and beginning to feel a little less sure of himself. The porter, wanting to avoid trouble, reaches for Gandhi's suitcases.</context>
      <utterance>There are no colored attorneys in South Africa. Go and sit where you belong.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take your luggage back, baas.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into this waistcoat and produces a card which he presents to the conductor.</context>
      <utterance>No, no -- just a moment, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, Mohandas K. Gandhi, Attorney at Law. I am going to Pretoria to conduct a case for an Indian trading firm.</utterance>
   <speaker>EUROPEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi is still puzzled by his belligerence, but is beginning to react to it, this time with a touch of irony.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't you hear me? There are no colored attorneys in South Africa!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Porter stares -- amazed!</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I was called to the bar in London and enrolled in the High Court of Chancery -- I am therefore an attorney, and since I am -- in your eyes -- colored -- I think we can deduce that there is at least one colored attorney in South Africa.</utterance>
   <speaker>EUROPEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and walks out of the compartment.</context>
      <utterance>Smart bloody kaffir -- throw him out!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You move your damn sammy carcass back to third class or I'll have you thrown off at the next station.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always go First Class! I have traveled all over England and I've never...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are in a large Victorian parlor in a well-to-do home. Facing Gandhi are Khan, a tall, impressive Indian. Singh, slighter and older than Khan, but wiry and looking capable of physical as well as intellectual strength, and Khan's twenty-year-old son, Tyeb Mohammed.</context>
      <utterance>But you're a rich man -- why do you put up with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In England, I was a poor student but</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi is holding a British legal document; he lifts it pointedly.</context>
      <utterance>That was England.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This part of "England's" Empire!</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks at Mr. Baker almost in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gandhi, you look at Mr. Khan and see a successful Muslim trader. The South Africans see him simply as an Indian. And the vast majority of Indians -- mostly Hindu like yourself --  were brought here to work the mines and harvest the crops -- and the Europeans don't want them doing anything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Baker smothers a smile.</context>
      <utterance>But that is very un-Christian.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYEB MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks at Khan incredulously.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gandhi, in this country Indians are not allowed to walk along a pavement with a "Christian"!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you employ Mr. Baker as your attorney, but you can't walk down the street with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, but his eyes show that it is no joke. Gandhi glances from one to the other them -- absorbing the inconceivable. And then almost before our eyes his innocence of the world fuses with his anger at the injustice of it all.</context>
      <utterance>I can. But I risk being kicked into the gutter by someone less "holy" than Mr. Baker.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then, it must be fought. We are children of God like everyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allah be praised. And what battalions will you call upon?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts the documents threateningly.</context>
      <utterance>I -- I will write to the press -- here -- and in England.  And I will use the courts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Its tone is chilling, and Gandhi's firmness is shaken a little.</context>
      <utterance>You will make a lot of trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sturdy Khan is studying him with a look of wry interest.</context>
      <utterance>We are members of the Empire. And we come from an ancient civilization. Why should we not walk on the pavements like other men?</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi glances at Tyeb Mohammed and Baker, then stiffens, plainly frightened by the challenge, but just as plainly determined to take it.</context>
      <utterance>I rather like the idea of an Indian barrister in South Africa. I'm sure our community could keep you in work for some time, Mr. Gandhi -- even if you caused a good deal of trouble.  Especially if you caused a good deal of trouble.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the English reporter waiting skeptically. Near him, trying to be inconspicuous on the edge of the small crowd, are five policemen (one sergeant and four constables). A horse-drawn paddy wagon is drawn up beside them.</context>
      <utterance>There's the English reporter. I told you he'd come.</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see five or six women in saris standing together.</context>
      <utterance>You also said your article would draw a thousand people.  At least some of the Hindus brought their wives.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We feature Gandhi's wife, Ba, standing at the front of the women. She possesses a surprising delicacy of feature, with large expressive eyes and a beautiful mouth -- but at this moment she is ill at ease and uncertain, forcing herself to do that which she would rather not.</context>
      <utterance>No. I asked my wife to organize that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is flat and dull, like someone reading a speech to themselves, and those in the crowd who had hesitated before wandering off shrug and continue on their way. Gandhi is unnerved by it a little but he struggles on -- louder, but just as colorlessly.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentlemen, we have asked you to gather here to help us proclaim our right to be treated as equal citizens of the Empire.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This last has come more firmly, and he lifts his head to the crowd, as though expecting a reaction. Three or four committed supporters applaud as on cue, but his technique is so inexpert that it draws nothing but blank faces from the bulk of them. He glances nervously at Ba, who is embarrassed for them both now. She wraps her sari more closely around her and her expression is a wife's "I told you so" -- sufferance, mortification and loyalty, all in one. Gandhi wets his lips again -- and takes a square of cardboard from his pocket -- his "pass."</context>
      <utterance>We do not seek conflict. We know the strength of the forces arrayed against us, know that because of them we can only use peaceful means -- but we are determined that justice will be done!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds it up. A constable glances at the police sergeant.</context>
      <utterance>The symbol of our status is embodied in this pass -- which we must carry at all times, but no European even has to have.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>status is to eliminate this difference between us. And he turns and drops his pass in the wire basket over the fire. The flames engulf it. The police sergeant's eyes go wide with disbelief. The crowd murmurs in shock. At last Gandhi has got a reaction, but the dropping of the card has been as matter-of-fact as his speaking, with none of the drama one might expect from so startling a gesture. Even so, a constable glances at the police sergeant again, "Do we take him?". The sergeant just shakes his head, "Wait." Khan moves up to Gandhi as the tremor of reaction ripples through the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>And the first step to changing our</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes Gandhi's notes from him, and faces the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>You write brilliantly, but you have much to learn about handling men.</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is the end of the speech. He looks at the crowd. No one knows quite what to do. Gandhi harumphs -- gesturing to a shallow box Singh holds. Kahn turns back, extemporizing rather lamely.</context>
      <utterance>We do not want to ignite... the fear or hatred of anyone. But we ask you -- Hindu, Muslim and Sikh -- to help us light up the sky... and the minds of the British authorities -- with our defiance of this injustice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will now burn the passes of our committee and its supporters. We ask you to put your passes on the fire with --</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has stepped forward with his constables, who have faced the crowd, halting the tentative movements of the few committed supporters toward the fire.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, you bloody well don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is facing the crowd. Behind him, Khan holds himself erect and slowly takes his own card from his pocket. He holds it aloft and then lowers it resolutely into the wire basket. The crowd reacts and the sergeant turns just in time to see it dropped in the flame.</context>
      <utterance>Those passes are government property! And I will arrest the first man who tries to burn one!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures to a constable, who turns from the crowd and marches to Khan, seizing him by the arm and marching him to the paddy wagon. As he passes the sergeant, the sergeant takes his billy club, and faces the crowd, rapping the club menacingly against his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Take him away!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind him, Gandhi wavers indecisively a moment, then takes the box from Singh and moves to the fire. Ba holds her hand to her mouth -- terrified. Again the crowd's reaction turns the sergeant. Gandhi is at the fire. For a second, his eyes lock with the sergeant's -- and then nervously, he takes a card and drops it in the wire basket, and another.</context>
      <utterance>Now -- are there any more?!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has leapt across the distance between them, knocking the box from Gandhi's hands, sending the cards flying and shoving Gandhi to the ground. He turns and faces the crowd angrily, pointing the billy club threateningly.</context>
      <utterance>You little sammy bastard -- I --</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, a murmur from the crowd turns him. Gandhi, on his hands and knees, blood trickling from his abraded cheek, has picked up a card from the ground and he leans forward apprehensively, his eyes fearfully on the sergeant, but he drops it defiantly in the basket. The sergeant's fury bursts -- and he slams the billy club down on Gandhi's head. Gandhi sags to the ground. Ba screams. She starts to run to him, but the other women seize her.</context>
      <utterance>You want that kind of trouble -- you can have it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fights loose, but one of the constables takes her firmly. The sergeant turns from the commotion to see that Gandhi, his head oozing blood, has crawled to his knees again and is picking up another card. The crowd watches. The newspaper reporter watches. Ba stares in anguish. Gandhi lifts the card. The sergeant stares at him, angry but his emotions somewhat in control after the first blow.</context>
      <utterance>Let me go!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An instant of hesitation, then Gandhi drops the card into the basket. The sergeant almost stops, but he strikes again. A quiver of distaste at his own act crosses his face as Gandhi sags. Ba's anguished face is wet with tears. The newspaper reporter stares without making notes. Khan, at the paddy wagon, watches in wonder. Gandhi, his head bleeding badly now, rises to his knees -- a breath and he gropes around the ground for another card. His fingers finally clutch one. The sergeant stares, his face wracked with uncertainty and confusion. Gandhi lifts the card and painfully holds it over the fire, then drops it in the basket. The sergeant slams the billy club down again -- firmly, but with a manifest reluctance. The crowd watches breathlessly, the newspaper reporter stares. The sergeant draws a breath, grasping the club, but he bites his lip as he sees Gandhi lift his head feebly, his shaking hands, stained with his own blood, groping for another card...</context>
      <utterance>Stop!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba reaches forth, gently touching the bandages on his head.</context>
      <utterance>You saved the papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi doesn't take his eyes from the papers, but he shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I wish you were still struggling for work in Bombay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles whimsically, then turns back to the papers.</context>
      <utterance>I hated that -- all the pettiness, the little corruptions.  And I was more laughing stock than lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba stares at the back of his head, wounded by that remark, bearing it as stoically as he bore the blows against him.</context>
      <utterance>But they needed me here. If I'd never been thrown off that train, perhaps no one would ever have needed me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"A high court judge has confirmed that Mr. Gandhi would have been within his rights to prosecute for assault since neither he nor Mr. Khan resisted arrest." -- I told you about English law.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Gandhi can retort there is a knock on the door.</context>
      <utterance>As I told you about English policemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A small, round ayah (an Indian nursemaid) pushes open the door and proudly admits her charges, Gandhi's sons: Harilal (ten), Manilal (six) and Ramdas (two). They are all dressed in European suits, ties and stiff collars. They step forward, one by one, making the pranam (the Hindu gesture of greeting), then bending and touching the hands and lips to Gandhi's feet in the traditional obeisance of child to father.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARILAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi smiles.</context>
      <utterance>We are glad to have you back, Bapu.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Ramdas runs to him and Gandhi bends to kiss him as Ramdas put his arms around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>And I am glad to be back.  Come...</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi pats him indulgently, then carefully stands erect, looking at them all with satisfaction.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two older boys show the expected apprehension -- and interest. Gandhi nods to the ayah. She claps her hands smartly.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow I will tell you what it feels like to be a jailbird.</utterance>
   <speaker>AYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys bow and leave like boys used to household discipline. The ayah closes the door and we hear their chatter at they go down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Come. Come.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like proper English gentlemen. I'm proud of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi is stretching out on the bed, taking up another paper.</context>
      <utterance>They are boys. -- And they're Indian.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba comes and sits down on the bed beside him, maneuvering so that she can get at the bandage.</context>
      <utterance>Hm. Will you take this off?  It pinches every time I speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, you see? Even the South African papers apologize -- "a monstrous attack."</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba pulls one of the strands of tape and Gandhi flinches.</context>
      <utterance>Pull!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oww!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans forward to pull at the remaining piece.</context>
      <utterance>If you would let me teach you to read, you could see for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi is watching her as she leans across him, her beauty and proximity obviously stirring him.</context>
      <utterance>I could have told them you were merely foolish.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has pulled the other piece.</context>
      <utterance>It proves what I told you. If I had prosecuted him as everyone advised -- even you -- they would have hated me -- by showing forgiveness I -- ouch!</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she slowly pries the gauze free from the strands of hair above his lip. As she does Gandhi watches her more and more intently, and slips his arms around her back.</context>
      <utterance>There...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba examines the bandage and gently touches the wound, but she is aware of his burning eyes and arms around her back.</context>
      <utterance>You see there is such a thing as moral force -- and it can be harnessed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It slows Gandhi uneasily for a moment and Ba must grin at his discomfiture. He leans back -- still holding her, but looking at the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Not always. You have told me twice now that you were giving up the pleasures of the flesh.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba makes a moue of acceptance and starts to pull free of him -- but his arms still hold her. She smothers a smile and lies down, her face next to his, but neither of them looking at each other. A long beat... and then Gandhi turns his head. She is aware of his eyes on her, but she doesn't move. Gandhi leans forward and touches his lips to her neck.</context>
      <utterance>I am. I am convinced the holy men are right. When you give up, you gain. The simpler your life the better.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba smiles. Still not looking at him, she places her hand behind his head, gently.</context>
      <utterance>I will fast tomorrow -- as a penance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi laughs... and buries her in love.</context>
      <utterance>If you enjoy it a great deal you must fast for two days.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TALL CIVIL SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The London papers have arrived from the Cape, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tall civil servant checks his notes.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TALL CIVIL SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The worst was the Daily Mail, sir. They said, "The burning of passes by Mr. Gandhi was the most significant act in colonial affairs since the Declaration of Independence." Smuts has given the reins to the stable boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he strides into the building, past the smartly saluting sentries.</context>
      <utterance>Did they? Well, they'll find we're a little better prepared this time. Mr. Gandhi will find he's on a long hiding to nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be Gandhi --  ...I thought you'd be bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I -- I mean it's all right. It doesn't matter.  I'm -- my name is Andrews, Charlie Andrews. I've come from India -- I've read a great deal about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and waves to the parlor window. The three boys are there -- all bigger -- and Ba holds a new addition; they all wave. And Gandhi turns back, and starts down the long, hilly street.</context>
      <utterance>Some of it good, I hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures Charlie on and starts walking. Charlie nods uncertainly. He looks back at the cab in confusion, then signals the driver to follow and hurries on to match strides with Gandhi's brisk pace.</context>
      <utterance>Would you care to walk?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a clergyman.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I've -- I've met some very remarkable people in India... and -- and when I read what you've been doing here, I -- I wanted to help.  Does that surprise you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore.  At first I was amazed... but when you are fighting in a just cause, people seem to pop up -- like you -- right out of the pavement. Even when it is dangerous or --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>FIRST YOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- look what's comin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND YOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A white shepherd leading a brown sammy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps I should -- Gandhi restrains him and shakes his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to move forward. Charlie hesitates, then follows nervously, more nervous for Gandhi than himself.</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't the New Testament say, "If your enemy strikes you on the right cheek, offer him the left"?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are getting closer. The youths laughing, whispering.</context>
      <utterance>I think perhaps the phrase was used metaphorically... I don't think our Lord meant --</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One youth has flicked his cigarette -- hard. It lands at Gandhi's feet. He pauses, looking at the youth.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not so certain. I have thought about it a great deal. I suspect he meant you must show courage -- be willing to take a blow -- several blows -- to show you will not strike back -- nor will you be turned aside... And when --</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts forward again, he is almost on the youths -- clearly frightened, but...</context>
      <utterance>...and when you do that it calls upon something in human nature -- something that makes his hate for you diminish and his respect increase. I think Christ grasped that and I -- I have seen it work.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST YOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he reaches forth to haul Gandhi from the pavement, but --</context>
      <utterance>Get off the pavement, you bloody --</utterance>
   <speaker>A WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A woman is leaning out of an upstairs window, looking down at the fracas disconcertedly. It is the first youth's mother and her presence reduces the pitch of his hostility considerably.</context>
      <utterance>Colin! Colin! What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST YOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A snickering response from the other youths -- but they are embarrassed by the questioning disapproval of Colin's mother's attitude. There's no note of apology in her cold stare at Gandhi, but she clearly believes her son should not be doing what he is doing.</context>
      <utterance>Nuthing... nuthing. We were just cleaning up the neighborhood a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment of crisis has passed. Nothing will happen while she is there. Gandhi steps back on the pavement, addressing the first youth.</context>
      <utterance>You're already late for work. I thought you'd gone ten minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he steps around him, Charlie trailing, as the first youth stares at them sullenly. As they stride on, Charlie glancing back --</context>
      <utterance>You'll find there's room for us both.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were a man of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi laughs as they turn the corner.</context>
      <utterance>I am. But I'm not so egotistical as to think He plans His day around my dilemmas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has paused before an office and a young girl (Sonja) has come from it to speak to him about something of urgency, but she hovers, not interrupting.</context>
      <utterance>...you could call it a "communal farm," I suppose. But we've all come to the same conclusion -- our Gita, the Muslim's Koran or your Bible -- it's always the simple things that catch your breath -- "Love thy neighbor as thyself" --  not always practiced -- but it's something we Hindus could learn a lot from.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the sort of thing you'll be seeking on this "farm"...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now he turns to Sonja. Behind her we see the small office "M.K. Gandhi/Attorney." Several clients waits, most of them conspicuously poor. Sonja's tone is loaded with foreboding.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we shall try.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi absorbs the news stiffly.</context>
      <utterance>They're going to change the pass laws.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SMUTS'S VOICE-OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beneath the signature we see the boldly printed identification: Jan Christian Smuts.</context>
      <utterance>It's taken time, but it needed to be done fairly. We didn't want to create an injustice simply because Mr. Gandhi was abusing our existing legislation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another angle. A cameraman records the moment with a flash photo. General Smuts, whose presence is equal to his office, addresses someone out of shot as a male secretary removes the document.</context>
      <utterance>Just one second, sir, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The reporter who stands opposite him is Walker, much, much younger, almost boyish compared to the way we saw him at the funeral.</context>
      <utterance>But on a short trip, I wouldn't spend too much time on the Indian question, Mr. Walker. It's a tiny factor in South African life.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smuts has risen. He knows how to concede with grace.</context>
      <utterance>It's news at the moment. I will certainly report on your mines and the economy -- but I would like to meet this Mr. Gandhi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gaze is firm, strong, cynical...</context>
      <utterance>Of course. We Westerners have a weakness for these -- these spiritually inclined men of India. But as an old lawyer, let me warn you, Mr. Gandhi is as shrewd a man as you will ever meet, however "otherworldly" he may seem. But I'm sure you're enough of a reporter to see that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've reached the entrance to the tent, and he gestures in.</context>
      <utterance>...so it's not "spiritualism" or "nationalism" -- we're not against anything but the idea that people can't live together.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This last remark has been directed toward Charlie Andrews, who sits near them at a cluttered table, typing on an old typewriter. He waves, and Gandhi shouts out to them all over the putt-putt of the generator:</context>
      <utterance>You see -- Hindus, Muslims, Sikhs, Jews -- even Christians.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They nod. One of the Hindus bows with his hands clasped together. Gandhi hands Walker a copy of Indian Opinion and they start across the relatively barren field toward some other tents, Walker glancing at the paper. Gandhi watches him, grinning.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Walker! Of The New York Times!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without a paper -- a journal of some kind -- you cannot unite a community.  You belong to a very important profession.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hm. And what should an "important professional" write about your response to General Smuts's new legislation?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I'm still searching for a "response."</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will respect the law.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi seems trapped by an ineluctable fact.</context>
      <utterance>You're a very small minority to take on the Government -- and the Empire.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctant as it is, it too carries commitment and Walker senses it. But they have come by a site where a building is being erected, and a European (Kallenbach) is perched above a doorway on the half-completed structure, getting a level. Some Indians are working below him. Gandhi turns to him, light-hearted again.</context>
      <utterance>If you are a minority of one, the truth is the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walker waves his notebook at him and Kallenbach lifts his level in greeting. On his bronzed chest there is a Star of David. Walker looks around, grinning, shaking his head. We see two women in saris trying to quell some squabbling children in the background.</context>
      <utterance>This is Mr. Kallenbach. He is our chief carpenter -- and also our chief benefactor. He has made this experiment possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's quite a place, your "ashram" -- is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walker looks at him appraisingly.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. The word only means "community." But it could stand for "village"... or the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're an ambitious man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of embarrassed doubt, then he starts toward a half- finished building -- wooden sides, door, but canvas still covering the roof. It has an awning spread before it. Walker's carriage is tethered nearby, a Black driver standing in the sun, waiting. In the background we see two women cleaning a latrine. Walker glances at the latrine.</context>
      <utterance>I hope not.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As we have approached we see a table set for tea under the awning. There are two places. Having set the places, Ba is walking along the side of the building, away from them. She glances at Gandhi tautly and deliberately avoids speaking or acknowledging him.</context>
      <utterance>They tell me you also take your turn at peeling potatoes and cleaning the "outhouse" -- is that part of the experiment?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba looks at him coldly.</context>
      <utterance>Ba -- we will need another place set for Mr. Walker's driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns back and walks into the building by the rear entrance. Gandhi is disconcerted by her attitude, but he tries to answer Walker.</context>
      <utterance>I will tell Sora.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A grin -- but forced. When a girl (Sora) comes from the building bringing another cup and place setting, Gandhi calls to the driver.</context>
      <utterance>It's one way to learn that each man's labor is as important as another's. In fact when you're doing it, "cleaning the outhouse" seems far more important than the law.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he goes into the building, determined to find the source of Ba's aloofness.</context>
      <utterance>Please come and join us -- you'll need something before your journey back.  Excuse me a moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Ba looks at him hostilely.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sora was sent to tell me I -- I must rake and cover the latrine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone takes his turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is the work of untouchables.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In this place there are no untouchables -- and no work is beneath any of us!</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am your wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds her gaze as angrily as she holds his.</context>
      <utterance>All the more reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she starts to rise he grabs her arm, but she pulls free.</context>
      <utterance>As you command.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She says it derisively and it stings, but Gandhi is aware of Walker and he fights to hold his temper.</context>
      <utterance>The others may follow you -- but you forget, I knew you when you were a boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba settles back defiantly.</context>
      <utterance>It's not me. It's the principle. And you will do it with joy or not do it at all!</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment Gandhi stares at her, and she back at him, resentfully. He suddenly reaches down and grabs her arm, pulling her roughly to her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Not at all then...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is hushed but violent as he pulls her toward the rear door, opening it to push her out as she struggles against him.</context>
      <utterance>All right, go! You don't belong here! Go! Leave the ashram! Get out altogether! We don't want you!</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lurches free of his grip, glaring at him angrily. For a moment they both stare at each other, shattered by their violence.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it! Stop it! What are you doing!?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment, then she soothes the top of his head -- like the mother-wife she is.</context>
      <utterance>What is the matter with me...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks up at her, blankly, abjectly.</context>
      <utterance>You are human -- only human.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Gandhi grins weakly. Ba catches it and sends it back, warmer, less complicated by doubts. Gandhi sighs, putting his arms around her and she leans into him so that their heads are touching.</context>
      <utterance>And it is even harder for those of us who do not even want to be as good as you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba mutters "Hm" and holds him a little firmer. A moment.</context>
      <utterance>I apologize...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba nods.</context>
      <utterance>I must go back to that reporter.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi holds her back so that he can look at her. She looks at him evenly -- no smile, but the warmth still in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>...And I must rake and cover the latrine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A buzz, then applause -- loud and defiant. When is subsides Gandhi looks down at the plainclothes policemen, fixing his gaze on them.</context>
      <utterance>I want to welcome you all!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And again the audience bursts into applause. The policemen just sit like stone -- confident, sure, immune to rhetoric.</context>
      <utterance>Every one of you.  We -- have -- no -- secrets.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the gallery a rhythmic pounding signals the anger and protest and is taken up around the hall. The police stare imperturbably. Khan leans towards Singh, nodding to Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>Let us begin by being clear about General Smuts's new law. All Indians must now be fingerprinted -- like criminals. Men and women.  No marriage other than a Christian marriage is considered valid. Under this Act our wives and mothers are whores... And every man here a bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Singh smiles at the understatement. Gandhi holds up his hand, silencing the hall.</context>
      <utterance>He's become quite good at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And a policeman passing an Indian dwelling -- I will not call them homes -- may enter and demand the card or any Indian woman whose dwelling it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>A VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi just waits.</context>
      <utterance>God damn them!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now a violent response -- a large, powerful merchant rises in the third row.</context>
      <utterance>Understand! He does not have to stand at the door -- he may enter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCHANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another cheer. When it subsides, Tyeb Mohammed rises near the back, where he is seated with a number of other young men.</context>
      <utterance>I swear to Allah I will kill the man who offers that insult to my home and my wife!  And let them hang me!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYEB MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The police half rise to look back at him, but there is a smattering of applause and several stand to look back.</context>
      <utterance>I say talk means nothing. Kill a few officials before they disgrace one Indian woman -- then they might think twice about such laws!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYEB MOHAMMED'S FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now there is general applause. Gandhi waits, then</context>
      <utterance>In that cause, I would be willing to die!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the audience. This is the more sober Gandhi they have come to know.</context>
      <utterance>I praise such courage. I need such courage -- because in this cause, I too am prepared to die...  But, my friend, there is no cause for which I am prepared to kill.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at the police, making the point stick. There is a tentative reaction from the audience, but uncertain.</context>
      <utterance>I have asked you here tonight because despite all their troops and police, I think there is a way to defeat this law. Whatever they do to us we will attack no one, kill no one... But we will not  give our fingerprints -- not one of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will imprison us, they will fine us. They will seize our possessions. But they cannot take away our self-respect if we do not give it to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE FROM THE GALLERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been to prison? They'll beat us and torture us! I say --</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has their attention now.</context>
      <utterance>I am asking you to fight -- !  To fight against their anger -- not to provoke it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now he gets the response he has wanted. Firm, mature, determined. Gandhi holds up his hand.</context>
      <utterance>We will not strike a blow -- but we will receive them. And through our pain we will make them see their injustice  and it will hurt, as all fighting hurts!  ...But we cannot lose. We cannot.  Because they may torture my body, may break my bones, even kill me...  They will then have my dead body -- not my obedience.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the audience. A second, then a merchant stands, signifying his pledge. And then another. Then Tyeb Mohammed and the youths about him. Then all over the theater they begin to stand and on the stage until everyone is standing. It is all done is silence. Gandhi looks at the full theater -- all standing. He takes a step forward.</context>
      <utterance>We are Hindu and Muslim -- children of God, each of us. Let us take a solemn oath in His name that -- come what may -- we will not submit to this law.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A prison door slams: we are close on one face, another slam, another face, and again and again in the rhythm of marching feet...</context>
      <utterance>God save our gracious King... Long live our  ...noble King.  God save the King!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CIVILIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These men are contracted laborers. They belong in the mines.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The civilian smiles slowly. He looks from Gandhi to the miners.</context>
      <utterance>You have put their comrades in jail. When you free them they will go back to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIVILIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've warned you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The civilian looks at him sharply, then smiles derisively, signaling the car off. As it pulls away, Tyeb Mohammed and Singh come up to Gandhi, both made wary by the man's evident satisfaction with what has transpired.</context>
      <utterance>We have warned each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi watches the disappearing car worriedly, then turns and signals the miners on. They start forward. Their point of view. The car rides on past the factory building out of which it turned, and suddenly mounted police come swinging out from the buildings and face the procession. Tracking back before Gandhi, Singh and Tyeb Mohammed as they move forward, fear suddenly making their pace more labored. Tracking back before the mounted police.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think that is very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come on fast, batons at the ready. Gandhi screws up his courage, marching on. Tyeb Mohammed sets his jaw in defiance. Singh forces himself along at Gandhi's side. The mounted police riding on, batons at the ready. Featuring an Indian miner. He is in the front rank of the procession, watching the horses approach. He has a blunt farmer's face.</context>
      <utterance>At the canter -- for-ward!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the miners begin to go down, some face up, shielding their faces with their hands, some burying their faces in the earth and covering their heads with their hands. Close fast traveling, the sergeant's point of view. We arrive at the prone miners. Close on Gandhi, his arms crossed in front of his face, staring up, frightened, but determined to bear it. Wide angle. The horses cannot bring themselves to gallop over the human carpet; they rear, plunge, swerve. Close shot -- miner who shouted "down." He is peering through his crossed hands, a tight smile of satisfaction at knowledge confirmed. He turns to see: The sergeant thrown off his horse. He lands heavily, scrambles up, furious, darts after it. Mounting, he is enraged to hear laughter. Close shot. Singh and the miner who shouted "Down" kneeling, grinning at the chaos.</context>
      <utterance>Lie down! Lie down!</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Singh smiles, but suddenly looks up fearfully. The sergeant looms over them.</context>
      <utterance>The horses have more mercy than the men.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And without taking his booted foot from the stirrup he swings it into the miner's face. The man goes down, bleeding. An angry roar from the miners. Several stand and shake their fists. "Bastard!," "God damn you, Englishman!," "Jackal!" The wounded miner himself starts to stagger up. The sergeant sweeps them, his eyes glittering -- this he can deal with. But --</context>
      <utterance>You're right!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a command, and angry in its own way, but it carries all the weight of his influence on them. They begin to go down again and the sergeant wheels his horse and rides at Gandhi. With deliberate, almost fatalistic pace, Gandhi goes first to his knees and then sprawls down flat, his hands over the top of his head, awaiting the blow of the horse's hoof. Close shot, the horse's head, its eyes rolling as it swerves again. Close shot, the sergeant controlling it, cursing, but unable to make it plunge down on the man. Full shot, the sergeant wheeling his horse, angrily -- surveying the whole of the procession as they lie sprawled on the ground, his mounted police circling in front of them, not knowing what to do.</context>
      <utterance>Lie down! Lie down!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his horse angrily and gallops back toward the factories. Gandhi, Singh and Tyeb Mohammed are looking off at the retreating horses. The car with the civilian has returned in the distance. Gandhi looks at the miner who first shouted "Down" -- a smile, a nod of recognition and thanks. The miner grins, rubbing at the blood on his face, shrugging off Gandhi's implied praise. Featuring the police. The sergeant wheels by the car with the civilian; his police turn their horses, lining up across the road again. Their point of view. Gandhi and the miners coming on once more, chanting forcefully. "One King! One Law! One King! One Law!"</context>
      <utterance>Follow me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are we supposed to do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>CIVILIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let them march... In our own sweet time, in our own sweet way -- we'll get them.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>unsympathetically, and there is more than one murmur of assent at his words. The clergyman who has given Charlie the use of his pulpit sits beneath it, embarrassed, but sticking resolutely to his decision to give Charlie a hearing.</context>
      <utterance>Some of you may be rejoicing that Mr. Gandhi has at last been put into prison. The congregation is listening to him stiffly,</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few men in the congregation rise and pointedly escort their families from the church. Charlie struggles on.</context>
      <utterance>But I would ask you -- assembled here in this house of God -- to recognize that we are witnessing something new, something so unexpected, so unusual that it is not surprising the Government is at a loss. What Mr. Gandhi has forced us to do is ask questions about ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More of the congregation rise and march from the church... though a few pointedly do not.</context>
      <utterance>As Christians, those are difficult questions to answer. How do we treat men who defy an unjust law -- men who will not fight, but will not comply?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're sparing no one, I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You were the surprise. It's been all over the prison. We thought they'd be too afraid of the English press.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his soup from Khan.</context>
      <utterance>So did I.</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know who they've left out there to do the work. There can't be one mine left open. Have they touched the women?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My wife publicly defied the law. They've arrested her and four others.</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fools!  Sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's split the Government.</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks around the crowded yard at the soiled bandages, the defiant, determined faces.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's one victory.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we hold firm, it won't be the last.</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is distracted by a phalanx of guards (an officer and four men) pushing their way through the prisoners.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry -- I've never seen men so determined. You've given them a way to fight... And I don't think --</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISON OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoners are moving back from them resentfully but their glances reveal who Gandhi is. The prison officer's eyes fall on him.</context>
      <utterance>Gandhi! I want Gandhi! Which sammy is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods to the tall civil servant, who bows and closes the door. Smuts crosses the room toward a small cabinet.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, Mr. Gandhi. I thought we might have a little talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you have a glass of sherry?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smuts looks at Gandhi, a little surprised at the frigid tone of that refusal.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps some tea?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dined at the prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He appraises Gandhi, measuring the irony of his words, his determination. Then with a little sigh at the lost opportunity he replaces the stopper on the sherry, turns and gestures Gandhi on into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Ahh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has indicated a chair near his desk, but as Gandhi goes forward he pauses by a spread of papers from England on a long table near the middle of the room. We see one headline in close shot: "Thousands Imprisoned in South Africa/Mines Close. Crops Unharvested," a subhead, "Gandhi Leads Non- Violent Campaign." He looks at Smuts. Smuts smiles, a passing nod at the papers.</context>
      <utterance>Please -- please do come and sit down. It's prison I wanted to talk to you about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gandhi, I've more or less decided to ask the House to repeal the Act that you have taken such "exception" to.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smuts smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if you ask, General Smuts, I'm sure it will be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hm. Of course it is not quite that simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wry smile, and he sits on the edge of the chair Smuts has directed him to. Smuts measures him again, not absolutely certain how to deal with him. A pause, and he affects to take Gandhi's irony at face value.</context>
      <utterance>Somehow I expected not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad to hear you say that... very glad. You see if we repeal the Act under pressure  under this kind of pressure it will create a great deal of resentment. Can you understand that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Gandhi does understand it -- as a guiding principle. Never humiliate your enemy. And his tone conveys it.</context>
      <utterance>Very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Good.  I have thought of calling for a Royal Commission to "investigate" the new legislation.  I think I could guarantee they would recommend the Act be repealed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smuts does a slight double take, a smile, then the "tough" politician.</context>
      <utterance>I congratulate them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He measures Gandhi challengingly, obviously expecting some contest. Gandhi mulls it, then</context>
      <utterance>But they might also recommend that future Indian immigration be severely restricted -- even stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smuts stares at him... a moment, then</context>
      <utterance>Immigration was not an issue on which we fought. It would be wrong of us to make it one now that we -- we are in a position of advantage.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're an extraordinary man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now Smuts smiles with him. He bends suddenly and signs a group of documents.</context>
      <utterance>I assure you I feel a very ordinary man at this moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi stands, a little uncertain about the sudden change in his status. Smuts signs the last document, then sees Gandhi's doubt -- and misreads it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm ordering the release of all prisoners within the next twenty- four hours. You yourself are free from this moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Assuming we are in agreement?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- yes. It's just that... in these clothes I'd -- I'd prefer to go by taxi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm -- I'm afraid I have no money.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tall civil servant (Daniels) enters.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!  Neither have I.  I'm awfully sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel stares.</context>
      <utterance>Daniels, would you lend Mr. Gandhi a shilling for a taxi?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far will you be going, Mr. Gandhi?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still a little confused, Daniels reaches in his pocket and produces a shilling. He hands it to Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>Well -- now that this is settled -- I had thought seriously of going back to India  but a shilling will do splendidly for the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thank you both for a very enlightening experience. He bows slightly and starts out the door. Daniels immediately starts to accompany him, but Gandhi stops. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's either a great man or a colossal fraud... Either way, I shall be glad to see the last of him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>YOUNG ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their point of view. A British general is coming down the gangplank accompanied by his ADC. The officer commanding and the Guard of Honor await him.</context>
      <utterance>By God, he loves it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young Englishman glances at him quizzically. The General has taken the salute and moves to inspect the troops to the accompaniment of the military band.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure he hates it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is suddenly aware of a well-dressed Indian half-listening to their conversation. He glances at him and the well-dressed Indian simply nods slightly and moves off a little. The second Englishman grimaces at the young Englishman and looks down again.</context>
      <utterance>Generals' reputations are being made in France today, fighting on the Western Front. Not as Military Governors in India.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another far less elaborate gangplank extends from the aft section of the ship. Third Class passengers are disembarking here, and on shore, separated by a wire fence from the rest of the pier. A large crowd of Indians is reacting excitedly to someone coming down the gangplank but we can't yet see that person. The young Englishman glances back at the well-dressed Indian to make sure of his distance, then speaks quietly.</context>
      <utterance>What the devil's going on back there? He is looking aft. His point of view.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must be that Indian that made all that fuss back in Africa. My cabin boy told me he was on board.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why haven't we seen him?  Gandhi?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There has been a little hiatus in those disembarking but now Gandhi has appeared, coming down the gangplank with Ba and the children (grown-up sons now), and three or four people behind them, including the tall figure of Charlie Andrews. But Gandhi is wearing an Indian tunic and sandals and he has shaved his hair except for a central section on the top.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's it. He was traveling Third Class. There he is. Their point of view.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND ENGLISHMAN'S VOICE-OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young Englishman glances back cautiously toward the well- dressed Indian again, then</context>
      <utterance>God -- he's dressed like a coolie! I thought he was a lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After he came out of jail he refused to wear European clothes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He speaks with an uncertainty and tentativeness that he had lost in South Africa, patently overwhelmed by the reception. An English journalist catches him as he turns.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, I haven't "refused"... I -- I simply wanted to dress the way my comrades in prison dressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH JOURNALIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An exuberant woman puts a garland over his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Will you support the war effort, Mr. Gandhi?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles uncertainly again. As he turns he is face to face with an American reporter.</context>
      <utterance>I -- I have demanded rights as a British citizen, it is therefore my duty to help in the defense of the British Empire.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMERICAN REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do now that you're back in India?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An Indian reporter has cornered Ba behind him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND INDIAN REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi half-twists to hear Ba's answer, but his arm is taken by a young Indian (Nehru) in elegant European clothes. Another garland is thrown over his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>As an Indian woman how could you accept the indignity of prison?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Featuring Ba. Offhand, her eyes on Gandhi ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Mr. Gandhi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She joins her hands, acknowledging a garland placed around her shoulders, and pushes on after Gandhi. Charlie helps to guide her. Featuring Gandhi. The young Nehru, somewhat amused by all the excitement, leads Gandhi through the crowd to a little flower-covered platform. We see a banner: THE CONGRESS PARTY</context>
      <utterance>My dignity comes from following my husband.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I -- I thank you for your greeting. He makes the pranam and starts for the steps. The crowd is a little disappointed, but they manage a cheer and applause. Nehru is standing next to a heavy-set, well-dressed man (Patel). They exchange a wry glance, "Not exactly a world- beater." A car door slams. The camera pulls back. Nehru has slammed the door of a gleaming Rolls Royce touring car, the top down. He has seated Gandhi in it beside Patel, taking Gandhi's knapsack. An Indian chauffeur rides in front. The crowd still surges around and Gandhi is looking apprehensively back for Ba.</context>
      <utterance>I -- I am glad to be home.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins boyishly, in part to comfort, in part unable to contain his amusement at Gandhi and his evident confusion.</context>
      <utterance>We'll follow with your wife -- don't worry, everything's arranged.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that young man?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are crowds along the street, and Gandhi -- in surprise that they are for him -- waves tentatively. Patel waves too but he eyes Gandhi rather critically.</context>
      <utterance>That's young Nehru. He's got his father's intellect, his mother's looks and the devil's charm. If they don't ruin him at Cambridge -- Wave! Wave! -- he may amount to something.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must say when I first saw you as a bumbling lawyer here in Bombay I never thought I'd be greeting you as a national hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hardly that, Mr. Patel.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, you are. It's been two hundred years since an Indian has cocked a snoot at the British Empire and got away with it. And stop calling me Mr. Patel, you're not a junior clerk anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have come to a main thoroughfare. A crowd still lines the streets but it is thin and around and between we see groups of desperate poor, parked on the pavement, staring with blank curiosity at the passing car, but too listless and too out of touch to move from their little squatters' patches. Patel looks at Gandhi's clothes rather disapprovingly.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi is staring at the street. From his point of view we hold on a gaunt young, aged woman holding a baby wrapped in rags as threadbare as her sari. Another hollow-faced child leans against her.</context>
      <utterance>The new Military Governor of the North West Province was on that ship. Too bad you came back Third Class -- he might have been impressed by a successful barrister who had outmaneuvered General Smuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... I'm sure...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi has bowed to Jinnah, now he looks a little startled at Prakash. Prakash grins and makes the pranam to Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Jinnah, our joint host, member of Congress, and the leader of the Muslim League and Mr. Prakash, who I fear is awaiting trial for sedition and inducement to murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRAKASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi nods...</context>
      <utterance>I have not actually pulled a trigger, Mr. Gandhi, I have simply written that if an Englishman kills an Indian for disobeying his law, then it is an Indian's duty to kill an Englishman for enforcing his law in a land that is not his.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He meets Prakash's gaze firmly, the first moment we have seen any sign of the Gandhi of South Africa.</context>
      <utterance>It is a clever argument; I am not sure it will produce the end you desire.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We hope you intend to join us in the struggle for Home Rule, Mr. Gandhi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi bows to the others and is led off to an Indian bishop in full clerical robes. Behind him we see Patel regaling a small group with some story of court or society. As Gandhi leaves, Jinnah, Nehru and Prakash watch him clinically. Except for the servants, Gandhi is the only Indian male not in European clothes.</context>
      <utterance>May I? Mohan -- I would like you to meet someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told the press he would support the British in the war.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRAKASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's non-violence for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru grins slowly, thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>Is he a fool?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We get a shot of Ba in a gathering of Indian women. She stands listening, seemingly tongue-tied in the sophisticated patter. And we cut to Charlie introducing Gandhi to a man in obvious ill health, but well dressed, looking like the professor, philosopher and elder statesman he is (Gokhale).</context>
      <utterance>I'm not certain... But I wouldn't be surprised.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gokhale is pleased, Gandhi amused. He bows very respectfully.</context>
      <utterance>I lied to you, Mohan, when I told you I decided to come to South Africa to meet you. Professor Gokhale sent me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOKHALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has offered his hand during this, and Gandhi has helped him from the garden chair he has been seated on, handing him the cane that is resting against it.</context>
      <utterance>We're trying to make a nation, Gandhi -- and the British keep trying to break us up into religions and principalities and "provinces." What you were writing in South Africa -- that's what we need here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOKHALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense.  Go on, Charlie. This is Indian talk -- we want none of you imperialists. It is brusque but affectionate; we know he regards Charlie as Gandhi does... and Charlie does too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right -- I'll go and write my report to the Viceroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOKHALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He still hasn't smiled, but Gandhi and Charlie have.</context>
      <utterance>Go and find a pretty Hindu woman and convert her to Christianity -- that's as much mischief as you're allowed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GOKHALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget your practice. India has many men with too much wealth -- it is their privilege to nourish the efforts of the few who can raise India from servitude and apathy. I will see to it -- you begin your journal.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins self-deprecatingly but Gokhale persists.</context>
      <utterance>I have little to say. India is an "alien" country to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOKHALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses and looks at Gandhi -- and for the first time he smiles. When he speaks his voice is thick with feeling.</context>
      <utterance>Well, change that. Go and find India. Not what you see here, but the real India. You'll see what needs to be said. What we need to hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOKHALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes are watery with emotion, but he stares at Gandhi rigidly.</context>
      <utterance>When I saw you in that tunic I knew... I knew I could die in peace.  Make India proud of herself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The murmur of resistance from the crowd is louder at this. Gandhi shakes his head at the dissent.</context>
      <utterance>I ask you to pray for those who died.  For the English soldiers...  who were doing what they thought was right.  And for the brave terrorists whose patriotism led them to do what was wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up.</context>
      <utterance>It is not my law, it is the law of creation. We reap what we sow. Out there in the fields -- and in our hearts. Violence sows hatred, and the will to revenge. In them. And in us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru takes an iced drunk from a servant.</context>
      <utterance>I agree with Jinnah. Now that the Americans are in, the war will end soon. The Germans are worn out as it is...  and our first act should be to convene a Congress Party convention and demand independence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others assent. Nehru shakes his head wistfully.</context>
      <utterance>And we must speak with one voice -- united.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah -- we should invite Gandhi. What the devil has happened to him anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's "discovering" India.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is a lot better than causing trouble where it matters. Invite him -- let him say his piece about South Africa -- and then let him slip into oblivion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please! You're being foolish!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grimaces severely and tugs at him.</context>
      <utterance>There's no room! And the air is lovely.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No violence, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Featuring the roof. And Indian squats right on the edge of the roof above Charlie. He is looking down, offering a hand.</context>
      <utterance>Let me hang on with two hands or I will fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie, who has been grinning, suddenly looks baffled, not to say appalled.</context>
      <utterance>Englishman Sahib!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand still dangles in offering to the tall Charlie. Another angle. Two other Indians on the roof move to where they can grip the first Indian's other arm, as counterforce to the weight of Charlie.</context>
      <utterance>Come! Come! There is room!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close shot. Charlie. His face flat on the roof of the train as his arm is still gripped by the Indian, but his leg is being pulled from behind.</context>
      <utterance>Charlie! Be careful!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Resume Gandhi and Ba. Gandhi quickly moves to free Ba's hand from Charlie's leg and almost loses his own grip. He grabs the window again.</context>
      <utterance>Mohan -- !!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba is confused.</context>
      <utterance>Let go! You'll kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With one hand he pries at her grip. In the chaos of instructions others in the coach are helping Gandhi, and Ba senses she is doing something wrong, but is still not sure what. She lets go. Close shot. Charlie. A desperate sigh of relief. Long shot. Charlie is pulled on up to the top of the coach. Featuring Charlie as he sits, puffing and recovering from the fright.</context>
      <utterance>Let go! Let go!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST INDIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Featuring Gandhi and Ba. Gandhi, smiling, goes on the tips of his toes to get a better view. Ba grabs him desperately.</context>
      <utterance>You see -- most comfortable. Charlie nods grimly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Featuring Charlie. He looks around at the rest of the passengers on the roof, their bundles and baskets clutched beside them. Their poverty is appalling, but they are all smiling at him, a sense of gaiety made in part by his Englishman's participation in their experience. They must shout over the train.</context>
      <utterance>Please, God, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND INDIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you Christian, Sahib?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, I'm a Christian.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND INDIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie stares at him in surprise.</context>
      <utterance>I know a Christian.  She drinks blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND INDIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is nodding, smiling, expecting Charlie's understanding. And Charlie gives it -- somewhat bleakly. Suddenly</context>
      <utterance>The blood of Christ -- every Sunday!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Indians turn. Charlie turns.</context>
      <utterance>Charlie!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST INDIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the Indians are crouching. Charlie closes his eyes ruefully -- he's had better ideas than this -- and he gets as flat as he can.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right, Sahib! Very safe -- bend -- bend!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were asked for toleration. We were asked for patience. Some gave it and some did not. Well, their war is over! And those of us who supported it, and those of us who refused must forget our differences! The camera has been moving in; now it jumps to Jinnah in close shot and intercuts with the impact of his fervid delivery on the audience.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the audience cheers him. Newspaper cameramen crowded around the platform photograph him. Patel comes forward from the back of the platform, clapping. He is chairing the Congress. Jinnah bows, taking his notes, gesturing to the auditorium. A man made for the spotlight, a man loving the spotlight. At last he moves back to his place on the platform. Nehru clasps his hand in congratulation. Others crowd around him. And fleetingly, just in the edge of picture, we see Gandhi -- again, the only one in an Indian tunic -- sitting at the end of the second row on the platform. He is just watching the flood of enthusiasm for Jinnah. Featuring Patel approaching the microphone, stilling the house with upraised hands.</context>
      <utterance>And there can be no excuses from the British now! India wants Home Rule! India demands Home Rule!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And again the audience cheers and applauds his little coda. He raises his hands, stilling them again.</context>
      <utterance>And let no one question that Mr. Jinnah speaks not just for the Muslims -- but for all India!</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi has already started to come toward the podium. He is greeted with mild applause, but already the convention is performing like a convention now that the spell of Jinnah's major speech has dissipated. As Gandhi reaches the podium, Patel gestures him to it.</context>
      <utterance>And now I'm going to introduce to you a man whose writings we are all becoming familiar with... a man who stood high in the esteem of our beloved Professor Gokhale... a man whose accomplishment in South Africa will always be remembered. Mr. Mohandas Gandhi.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patel has wandered back toward the others, his mind already on them. But he has half heard Gandhi's comment and turns -- a smile, a politician's flexibility --</context>
      <utterance>I am flattered by Mr. Patel  I would be even more flattered if what he said were true. He means about the journal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Gandhi grins -- and takes glasses from his sleeve. This is the first time we have seen them. He has one slip of paper with notes on it which he has put on the podium. He puts his glasses on and faces the convention.</context>
      <utterance>But it's true! I -- I read it... often.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the platform, the whispered politics go on. On the floor of the convention, some listen, some talk of other things.</context>
      <utterance>Since I returned from South Africa, I have traveled over much of India. And I know I could travel many more years and still only see a small part of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru has turned, having caught that last remark. He touches Patel on the shoulder "Listen."</context>
      <utterance>...and yet already I know what we say here means nothing to the masses of our country.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now they are beginning to pay attention on the floor of the hall too.</context>
      <utterance>Here we make speeches for each other -- and those English liberal magazines that may grant us a few lines.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jinnah too is listening now -- aloofly, challengingly.</context>
      <utterance>But the people of India are untouched. Their politics are confined to bread and salt.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is dissent on the floor and on the platform -- but it is muttered and English "polite." Gandhi goes on.</context>
      <utterance>Illiterate they may be, but they are not blind. They see no reason to give their loyalty to rich and powerful men who simply want to take over the role of the British in the name of freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off his glasses and folds them and in silence starts back toward his place on the platform. A cameraman flashes a picture, and someone begins to applaud; it is taken up here and there, tepidly. On the platform, the leaders join in perfunctorily. We see one peasant face (Shukla) -- which we will come to know -- watching from the crowd of outsiders who stand in the doorways. Nehru, who has been looking at Gandhi with interest and some surprise turns to Patel.</context>
      <utterance>This Congress tells the world it represents India. My brothers, India is seven hundred thousand "villages" not a few hundred lawyers in Delhi and Bombay. Until we stand in the fields with the millions who toil each day under the hot sun, we will not represent India -- nor will we ever be able to challenge the British as one nation.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you read his magazine?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- but I think I'm going to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FIRST FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru is looking a little harassed, from the ragging he is taking and from the ride. The ashram is only half-finished, the ground unworked, the buildings only partially completed and the whole looking like some primitive frontier outpost. They are finally brought to a halt by a goat that is tethered right across the path.</context>
      <utterance>This can't be the way!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others laugh; Nehru suffers.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm sure this is the direction India is taking.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To think I almost got excited by Mr. Jinnah when all this was awaiting me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're looking for Mr. Gandhi!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, you'll find him under the tree by the river.  You'd better leave the car -- the ground is rather soft.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you . . . He looks around the ashram a little dismally.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on! I'm anxious to meet this new "force"!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His smile is sardonic, but genuine, theirs embarrassed and self-conscious.</context>
      <utterance>I try to live like an Indian, as you see... it is stupid of course, because in our country it is the British who decide how an Indian lives -- what he may buy, what he may sell. And from their luxury in the midst of our terrible poverty they instruct us on what is justice and what is sedition.  So it is only natural that our best young minds assume an air of Eastern dignity, while greedily assimilating every Western weakness as quickly as they can acquire it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru in his fine linen suit takes the pail awkwardly. His friends watch with amusement, but they too rise to follow as they head for the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Would you, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He re-directs Nehru toward a trough where two or three goats are tethered, but he keeps right on talking.</context>
      <utterance>And why should the English grant us Home Rule? Here, we must take the peelings to the goats.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We only make wild speeches, or perform even wilder acts of terrorism. We've bred an army of anarchists but not one single group that can really fight the British anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have reached the trough.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you were against fighting.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru has carefully walked around something distasteful on the ground, now he dumps the peelings along the trough and spreads them "delicately." Gandhi scoops some peelings from the trough to feed a goat that nudges him.</context>
      <utterance>Just spread it around -- they like the new peelings mixed with the rotting ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi's eye. He looks off. Ba stands, watching him, waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Where there is injustice, I've always believed in fighting.  The question is do you fight to change things, or do you fight to punish.  For myself, I have found that we are all such sinners we should leave punishment to God. And if we really want to change things there are better ways of doing it than by derailing trains or slashing someone with a sword. He meets Nehru's gaze, and for a moment something deeper than argument passes between them. Then something catches</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi turns. The goat is reaching for his bowl of potatoes. He pushes it away and starts for the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>The fire is ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru grins, captured by Gandhi's seriousness, and his humor. He hasn't moved, and neither have his friends. They watch Gandhi as he carries his bowl of potatoes to Ba.</context>
      <utterance>You see, even here we live under tyranny.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi plods on toward the kitchen, carrying the bowl of potatoes.</context>
      <utterance>Hm... but look at him. Some "fighter"! I can see the British shaking now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, because coming along the riverbed toward them is a man (Shukla) who looks as though he has come a long, weary way. His face is gaunt, his little bundle of belongings pathetic. As he nears them, he pauses.</context>
      <utterance>But it's the ink that is the most diffic --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHUKLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am looking for Mr. Gandhi...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHUKLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at Gandhi almost sheepishly. He does not eat yet, but his hunger is evident. Ba sits at one side in the shadows watching him as intently as Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>...I've wanted to speak to you for a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHUKLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice is choked and near to tears, resonant with the unspoken agony his words mean for him and the others like him. He looks at Gandhi nervously for a moment, then puts the food to his mouth like a man who is starving, and trying desperately not to show it. Close shot. Ba. The solemn intensity of her gaze reflects her identification with the man's agony. She glances up at Gandhi...</context>
      <utterance>...our crops... we can't sell them... We have no money... but the landlords take the same rent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ENGLISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A detail of British troops, already on the station, moves in his wake, just as aggressive toward the crowd as he is.</context>
      <utterance>Clear the way there! Get out of the way!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT PUTNAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant is on the low sloping roof of the station. The captain turns briskly to two of his detail.</context>
      <utterance>Sir! Up here!</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men join hands and the captain is hoisted up with an assist from Sergeant Putnam. We hear the train stop in the background. On the roof. The captain stands erect.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a leg up, will you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is now standing and his face has frozen. It needs no answer from Putnam.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is it, Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his head slowly, his mouth agape at His point of view. The whole of the obscurely lit platform is covered thick with waiting crowds. They engulf the station house, back and front, and on the other side of the train more people are packed all along its length, and beyond them along the narrow street that stretches through the little collection of houses adjoining the station, every rooftop is covered -- men, women with babes in arms, children. There is no excitement, hardly any movement -- just a vast congregation of people, waiting silently is the darkness -- and as the camera pans we see that the crowd extends, indiscernible, even beyond the range of light.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus...!</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT PUTNAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, sir. The agent says they got a telegram and it just said, he is coming... and gave the time of the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT PUTNAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Featuring Gandhi. He has stepped down from the train. Shukla guides him, Ba and Charlie a step or two behind. Gandhi moves through the silent crowd, his hands in the pranam, bowing a little to either side. As he advances, the crowd parts -- it is almost eerily silent. As their clothes indicate, the area is Muslim, so some salaam (a touch of the hand to the forehead) and a few tentatively make the pranam back to Gandhi as he moves through them. Most of the faces are gaunt and lean. A destitute people. And suddenly there is a commotion and the sound of boots on the concrete platform, and the English captain shoves his way through to confront Gandhi down the little aisle that was being made for him. The sergeant and part of the detail and behind the captain. The captain stares. Then he looks around at the crowd, suspiciously, a touch of inner fear, then back to Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the devil are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a flicker of recognition, but uncertain. The captain stiffens; a steeling of the will. Another glance at the crowd, this time with an air of outraged authority.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Gandhi. Mohandas K. Gandhi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, whoever you are, we don't want you here. I suggest you get back on that train before it leaves the station.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They seem to want me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now look here. I'll put you under arrest if you'd prefer?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It has the cold assurance of a lawyer, and the Captain is a little shaken by it. He glances at Charlie who stands behind Gandhi now, and it makes him all the more uncertain.</context>
      <utterance>On what charge?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to make it severe, but it is a comedown.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want any trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is firm and there is an edge of assertiveness to it that the Captain doesn't like, but Gandhi's unrelenting stare unnerves him. He glances at Charlie again.</context>
      <utterance>I am an Indian traveling in my own country. I see no reason for trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, the empty severity of weakness. He looks around, then turns and marches off briskly shoving his way through the crowd. "Out of my way, there! Come on, move!" Gandhi smiles reflectively, and the crowd suddenly begins to buzz. Where all was silence before there is now the hum of excitement. Already he has scored a victory -- and as he moves forward again, making the pranam, they return it with flushed greetings. "Gandhi -- Gandhi -- Bapu -- Gandhiji"...</context>
      <utterance>Well, there'd better not be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MEHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi sits cross-legged, listening. It is the kind of listening that opens the heart. Behind him a mass of villagers sits stoically, outside the dwelling, waiting while their case is heard. Meha tries to speak unemotionally but under Gandhi's sympathetic gaze his despair keeps cracking through.</context>
      <utterance>For years the landlords have ordered us to grow indigo, for dyeing the cloth. Always they took part of the crop as rent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Near to breakdown, he gestures around the empty house.</context>
      <utterance>But now the English factories make cloth for everyone. No one wants our indigo. And the landlords won't take their share. They say we must pay our rent in cash.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What we could, we sold... The police have taken the rest. There is no food, we -- He cannot go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(He examines his hands a moment.) The landlords are British? It's a rhetorical question. Meha nods. Gandhi looks around the crude dwelling, almost nothing remains. We see two young men, one seventeen perhaps, the other older, and a girl, sixteen. And finally Meha's wife, sitting near Ba, the two women listening together but Meha's wife looks like a woman who has given up, her hair is dead and hardly combed, her sari dirty. Meha looks at Gandhi and shakes his head hopelessly. Gandhi nods... He stands slowly.</context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words are said bleakly, not to raise false hopes. He glances at Meha's wife. Water comes to her eyes, and she lowers her head. Ba puts her hands on her shoulders and clasps her to her, and the woman breaks, and sobs and sobs...</context>
      <utterance>What we can do... we will try to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is all Champaran like this, Shukla?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHUKLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It registers with Gandhi -- but inside. A moment.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Bapu...  The whole province... hundreds -- thousands.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi shakes himself from his absorption and looks back. Ba and Charlie are mounted on a similar howdah on another elephant, both being led by peasant boys. Charlie is pointing behind them. Coming along the path is a tall Indian policeman on a bicycle. He rides right past Charlie and Ba and comes alongside Gandhi. His attitude is superficially polite, but he is full of righteous authority.</context>
      <utterance>Mohan -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you Mr. M. K. Gandhi?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry but you are under arrest.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It contains more anger than we have seen him display to anyone but Ba.</context>
      <utterance>I am not sorry at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BATSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wicket keeper makes a rude, facetious gesture, but as the batsman turns to settle in his crease again</context>
      <utterance>Who did you say would be buying the drinks?</utterance>
   <speaker>BATSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has looked up. A car is pulling hurriedly in near the clubhouse, an officer in it, and people are streaming toward it. The car. A major is standing on the back seat. An Indian corporal drives.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I've got no idea. All I know is there's a riot or something at Motihari in Champaran, and the whole company is ordered out.</utterance>
   <speaker>A VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's two days' march!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Featuring the batsman and some of the players as they walk across the field toward the car. They know something's up.</context>
      <utterance>That's why the match is off. It's mostly Muslim territory and the old man's taking no chances.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, and it's the best innings I've had since Oxford.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKET KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The batsman "takes" on him facetiously, and we cut to:</context>
      <utterance>India's full of grief, old man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reverse on Charlie. He looks down at Gandhi and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Charlie--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close shot. Gandhi. Head and shoulders. He returns the grin, but anger and determination still dominate his mood.</context>
      <utterance>...Shades of South Africa.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite. They're only "holding me" until the Magistrate's hearing. Then it will be prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now we see Gandhi in full shot for the first time. He is wearing only a white loincloth, the shawl over his shoulders and sandals -- the costume he will wear for the rest of his life.</context>
      <utterance>Did they take your clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie studies him a moment, and being Charlie, he understands.</context>
      <utterance>These are my clothes now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins, and it elicits a little grin from Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>You always had a puritanical streak, Mohan.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I want to be one with them, I have to live like them.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Gandhi laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I think you do.  But I thank God we all don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure your legs are quite as handsome as mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And again Gandhi laughs. Charlie turns to the guard.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, but my puritanism runs the another way. I'm far too modest for such a display.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The police guard hesitates, and then unlocks the cell. Charlie enters and sits on a little wooden stool opposite Gandhi, his long legs awkwardly filling most of the space between them. Gandhi has remained seated, pensive. Charlie studies him a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Couldn't I be let in with the prisoner? I am a clergyman.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're calling you "Bapu." I thought it meant father.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little grin, but his mood remains pensive -- and remote.</context>
      <utterance>It does. We must be getting old, Charlie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks up -- his anger, his determination there, but then broken by a hopeless sigh.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie is stunned, and obviously hurt. Gandhi proceeds more gently.</context>
      <utterance>I think, Charlie, that you can help us most by taking that assignment you've been offered in Fiji.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now Charlie understands. Gandhi smiles; warmth, and sadness. Then he speaks with a determined purposefulness, a friend's trust.</context>
      <utterance>I have to be sure -- they have to be sure -- that what we do can be done by Indians... alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has taken some scratched notes from under the bedding and handed them to Charlie. Charlie nods. He sighs, and rises slowly.</context>
      <utterance>But you know the strategy. The world is full of people who will despise what's happening here. It is their strength we need. Before you go, you could start us in the right direction.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi rises, glancing wryly at the prison walls. He nods.</context>
      <utterance>I must leave from Calcutta, and soon. You'll have to say goodbye to Ba for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now he faces Charlie; this is the moment of farewell.</context>
      <utterance>When I get the chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't know what to say, how to say it. Gandhi meets his eyes -- a smile that shelters Charlie's vulnerability, returns his love.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The very English, very steadfast Charlie fights to contain his emotions.</context>
      <utterance>There are no goodbyes for us, Charlie. Wherever you are, you will always be in my heart...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MAGISTRATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am going to clear the courtroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The magistrate frowns.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure we'd be able to. And it is a first hearing, it's supposed to be public. And he's a lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGISTRATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know where they found the nerve for all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure I don't either, but the troops won't be here until tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGISTRATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the front row from his point of view. Two or three Indian journalists and one European.</context>
      <utterance>How the press get here before the military?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The magistrate receives that news with some alarm. He indicates that the clerk take his place. Gandhi stands. The courtroom is silent, but we can still hear the sound of the chanting outside.</context>
      <utterance>That English clergyman sent a number of telegrams yesterday afternoon. I understand one of them even went to the Viceroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGISTRATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have been ordered out of the province on the grounds of disturbing the peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGISTRATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to go to jail?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clerk lowers his eyes to his pad. The magistrate searches the distant wall, the top of his desk, his twitching hands for an answer. Finally</context>
      <utterance>As you wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGISTRATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. I will release you on bail of one hundred rupees until I reach a sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again the magistrate stares. And so do the journalists. The magistrate wets his lips --</context>
      <utterance>I refuse to pay one hundred rupees.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGISTRATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now the court explodes. In the chaos of cheering and delight, the magistrate rises, looks around the room and heads for his chambers. The journalists are scribbling furiously. Gandhi turns and starts out of the courtroom. We hear cries of "Gandhi! -- Gandhi! -- Bapu!"</context>
      <utterance>Then I -- I will grant release without bail -- until I reach a decision.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>A VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Four young Indians -- elegantly dressed in English clothes -- are following him, having plunged through the crowd in the courtroom. A beat -- and the first young man addresses him over the chaos.</context>
      <utterance>Gandhiji! -- Gandhiji! Mr. Gandhi!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi reacts -- with surprise and caution.</context>
      <utterance>Gandhiji -- we are from Bihar. We received a cable this morning from an old friend who was at Cambridge with us.  His name is Nehru and I believe you know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Gandhi is surprised -- but even more cautious. Behind him, the crowd begins to chant "Gandhi -- Gandhi."</context>
      <utterance>He tells us you need help. And we have come to give it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to document, coldly, rationally, what is being done here. It may take months -- many, many months.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It sounds casually ironic, but they look determined, even angry.</context>
      <utterance>We have no pressing engagements.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is looking at them with a soupon of skepticism but he is beginning to smell victory. His name echoes around him and is taken up even louder as the news spreads to the street.</context>
      <utterance>You will have to live with the peasants.  I have nothing to pay you.  Hmm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SIR GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Governor, Sir Edward Gait -- the portrait of the King prominent behind him -- is feeling as cornered as Sir George but for different reasons. His desk is arrayed with several tall stacks of folders -- all with exactly the same covers -- and on one corner of the desk, some folded newspapers. We can just read "Gandhi" in a headline. He taps one of the folders irritably with his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what this country is coming to!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir George looks at him -- half defensive, half defiant. They are old friends -- the same school, the same social class, long together in India -- and their argument is an argument between friend who accept the same premises. But even so the Governor feels the game has not quite been played fairly.</context>
      <utterance>But good God, man, you yourself raised the rent simply to finance a hunting expedition!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir George is staring out of the window, vexed, bristling but defensive.</context>
      <utterance>And some of these others --  beatings, illegal seizures, demanding services without pay, even refusing them water! In India!...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody knows what it is to try to get these people to work!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up one of the papers irritatedly, the London Daily Chronicle.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you've make this half-naked whatever-he-is into an international hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir George looks at him and sighs heavily. Sir Edward stares back, then drops the paper back on his desk.</context>
      <utterance>"One lone man marching dusty roads armed only with honesty and a bamboo shaft doing battle with the British Empire."  At home children are writing "essays" about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir George turns, and paces back toward him. For the first time we see Sir Edward's personal secretary (a male civil servant) sitting at a small desk and listening with highly developed unobtrusiveness.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't take another two years of him to save my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is the first sign of concession. Sir Edward lifts his eyes to his personal secretary.</context>
      <utterance>What do they want?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONAL SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir George looks from him to Sir Edward. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>A rebate on rents paid.  They are to be free to grow crops of their own choice. A commission -- part Indian -- to hear grievances.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would satisfy him?...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir George looks at the document on the secretary's desk. A moment. The secretary turns it slowly so it is facing him. Sir George looks at it like a snake. The secretary picks up a pen and offers it. A second, then Sir George takes the pen and signs angrily.</context>
      <utterance>And His Majesty's Government. It only needs your signature for the landlords.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir Edward is at the liquor cabinet.</context>
      <utterance>It will be worth it to see the back of him.  We're too damn liberal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns, offering Sir George a whiskey in a finely cut glass of crystal.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps. But at least all this has made the Government see some sense about what men like Mr. Gandhi should be allowed, and what they should be denied.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things are going to change.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Mr. Gandhi?</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Prophet give me patience.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a disdainful comment and he drives the car off toward the garage. Gandhi comes around the corner of the wall into the entrance. He is carrying a bedroll and a bamboo walking stick. Herman Kallenbach is with him, dressed informally, also carrying a bedroll. Jinnah makes a "sophisticated" salaam.</context>
      <utterance>He came Third Class.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi grins, dismissing the formality.</context>
      <utterance>My house is honored.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The honor is ours. May I introduce Mr. Kallenbach. He's an old friend  and his interest is in flowers. I presumed to tell him he could wander your gardens while we talked.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll send my gardener. I'm sure you'll have much to discuss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Gandhi grins at the extravagance.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen -- the hero of Champaran.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only the stubborn man of Champaran. A polite little laugh; Jinnah introduces him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Maulana Azad -- a fellow Muslim... recently released from prison. Gandhi makes the pranam, studying him with interest after that comment. Azad gives a gentle salaam.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Patel you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Featuring Nehru. He stands, awaiting Gandhi's attention. All the others have been dressed in European clothes. The handsome Europeanized Nehru now wears an Indian tunic -- much like the one that Gandhi once wore. For a moment Gandhi studies the costume, then a broad smile.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kripalani.  And of course you know Mr. Nehru. Gandhi turns.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am beginning to know Mr. Nehru.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I've called you here because I've had a chance to see the new legislation. It's exactly what was rumored. Arrest without warrant. Automatic imprisonment for possession of materials considered seditious...</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi nods at the "compliment," but they are all angered by the severity of it.</context>
      <utterance>Your writings are specifically listed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIPALANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So much for helping them in the Great War...</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again the temper of it produces a little silence. Then</context>
      <utterance>There is only one answer to that. Direct action -- on a scale they can never handle!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to a servant who stands, holding a large tray with a silver service of tea. Of them all, Nehru's manner is the most naturally patrician and Jinnah watches him with a somewhat envious awareness of it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His stand has produced a little shock of surprise. Holding his tea, he turns to Gandhi with a little smile.</context>
      <utterance>Terrorism would only justify their repression. And what kinds of leaders would it throw up? Are they likely to be the men we would want at the head of our country?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He means Gandhi's of course. Jinnah looks at the two of them. Gandhi has removed his sandals and is sitting cross-legged on a fine upholstered chair. Jinnah's eyes rake him with anger and distaste.</context>
      <utterance>I've been catching up on my reading.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I too have read Mr. Gandhi's writings, but I'd rather be ruled by an Indian terrorist than an English one. And I don't want to submit to that kind of law.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must say, Panditji, it seems to me it's gone beyond remedies like passive resistance.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all stare at him, startled by his words and the fervor with which he speaks to them.</context>
      <utterance>I am with Mr. Jinnah. We must never submit to such laws -- ever. And I think our resistance must be active and provocative.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds their gaze, then turns to the immobile servant and with a little smile, takes the tray from him and places it on the table next to him. It makes them all aware that the servant, standing there like an insensate ornament, has been treated like a "thing," a slave. As it sinks in, Gandhi pours some tea then looks up at them with a pleading warmth -- first to Jinnah.</context>
      <utterance>I want to embarrass all those who wish to treat us as slaves. All of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It impresses each one of them. But for all his impact, they still take the measure of him with caution.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive my stupid illustration. But I want to change their minds -- not kill them for weaknesses we all possess.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what "resistance" would you offer?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Prayer and fasting"? They are not overwhelmed.</context>
      <utterance>The law is due to take effect from April sixth. I want to call on the nation to make that a day of prayer and fasting.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean a general strike?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patel is the first to recognize the implications.</context>
      <utterance>I mean a day of prayer and fasting. But of course no work could be done -- no buses, no trains, no factories, no administration. The country would stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, it would terrify them...</utterance>
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three hundred fifty million people at prayer. Even the English newspapers would have to report that. And explain why.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIPALANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But could we get people to do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Champaran stirred the whole country.  They are calling you Mahatma -- the Great Soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fortunately such news comes very slowly where I live.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps I should have stayed in the garden and talked about the flowers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ADC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lord Chelmsford turns expectantly.</context>
      <utterance>Sir -- it's Mr. Kinnoch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHELMSFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>KINNOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing... nothing is working, sir -- buses... trains... the markets...  There's not even any civilian staff here, sir... Everything has stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>KINNOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at the general.</context>
      <utterance>No, sir -- Karachi, Calcutta, Madras, Bangalore. It's, it's total.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHELMSFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe it...</utterance>
   <speaker>KINNOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going to sell his own paper tomorrow in Bombay. They've called for a parade -- on Victoria Road.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHELMSFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arrest him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi, who also looks worn, rises his eyebrows whimsically at the use of that name.</context>
      <utterance>Bapu...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He means "Bapu" -- "Father."</context>
      <utterance>You too...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi sighs, and their faces and minds go to more somber matters.</context>
      <utterance>It seems less formal than "Mahatma."</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi has listened to it all with a growing sense of despair.</context>
      <utterance>Since your arrest the riots have hardly stopped. Not big --; but they keep breaking out. I run to stop them... and Patel and Kripalani -- they are never at rest. But some English civilians have been killed, and the Army is attacking crowds with clubs -- and sometimes worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'm wrong... maybe we're not ready yet. In South Africa the numbers were small...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Government's afraid, and they don't know what to do. But they're more afraid of terrorists than of you. The Viceroy has agreed to your release if you will speak for non- violence.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never spoken for anything else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long shot -- his point of view. The two platoons of sepoys, rifles at the port, trot smartly through the gate and fan out on either side of the motionless and dominant figure of Dyer. Resume the speaker.</context>
      <utterance>...If we riot, if we fight back, we become the vandals and they become the law! If we bear their blows, they are the vandals -- God and His law are on our...  side.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant major issues the command. The troops port arms.</context>
      <utterance>Port arms, Sergeant Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, the sergeant major barks the command, the bolts slam back and forth, the magazines clatter. Featuring the platform and the front of the crowd. They have all turned now to watch, frozen in incredulity and fascination. The sound of the sergeant major's orders and the sinister rattle of breeches and bolts drifting to them.</context>
      <utterance>Load.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we issue a warning, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Major --</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long shot over the sepoys and their sights, the wavering crowd distant.</context>
      <utterance>Take aim!</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flash shot along the line of sepoys; the rifles jerk and bang. The crowd, running, screaming.</context>
      <utterance>Fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dreadful press of panic-stricken people flying toward the walls. And again the crash of rifles. Some fall. Others run off-screen in an aimless, irresistible wave. Dyer is walking behind his men, telling them, with a view to maximum accuracy, what he has told them on the firing range (it makes him a little irritable to have to repeat it).</context>
      <utterance>Reload!</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks off at the crowd. His eyes narrow. A group of men are hurling themselves at a breach in the top of the wall, hanging there, scrabbling for a purchase, some disappearing, a few heroic individuals astride the wall reaching down to assist their women and children in the swirling crowd below.</context>
      <utterance>Take your time. Take your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Corporal!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORPORAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. The corporal looks.</context>
      <utterance>Over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORPORAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He directs the attention of his neighbors in the firing line toward the new target; they shift their aim. A man reaching for a child -- who is also propelled upward by its mother from below -- is hit, falls, so that he and the child crash into the crowd below. Sepoys firing ad lib. Dyer watching the effect, careful and conscientious. Swift tracking a man running through the staggering crowd, over the litter of bodies, his mouth open, his eyes wild. He arrives at a well, throws down the rope and slides down it. Others seize the idea and in panic throw themselves into the well, dropping out of sight. Featuring Dyer. Meticulously, he taps a corporal on the shoulder with his swagger stick and indicates the well. The corporal signals his line of men. At the well. The gathering crowd -- men, women -- and laced with rifle fire. From behind the sepoys we see the whole Bagh, littered with dead and dying, a thick ruck around the well, the walls hanging with wounded and dying, the firing continuing, loud, loud, louder... until --</context>
      <utterance>Sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ADVOCATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dyer glances woodenly at the panel -- a man in some shock at the consequences of what he assumed was an act worthy of praise.</context>
      <utterance>General Dyer, is it correct that you ordered your troops to fire at the thickest part of the crowd?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Advocate looks at him with a degree of disbelief -- more at his attitude than his statement.</context>
      <utterance>That is so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADVOCATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A slight reaction from the public section. Dyer's jaw tightens.</context>
      <utterance>One thousand five hundred and sixteen casualties with one thousand six hundred and fifty bullets.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at the panel like a reasonable man making a reasonable point. The evasiveness, the only half-buried embarrassment of their response only deepens his own withdrawal into himself.</context>
      <utterance>My intention was to inflict a lesson that would have an impact throughout all India.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIAN BARRISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dyer thinks about it. Then unashamedly --</context>
      <utterance>General, had you been able to take in the armored car, would you have opened fire with the machine gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A muted reaction from the public section. The Indian barrister stares at him a moment, then simply lowers his eyes to his notes.</context>
      <utterance>I think, probably -- yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General, did you realize there were children -- and women -- in the crowd?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time there is the hint of uncertainty in his manner.</context>
      <utterance>I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADVOCATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that was irrelevant to the point you were making?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is just a tremor of distaste quickly suppressed among the panel. Not so quickly in the public section.</context>
      <utterance>That is correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADVOCATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dyer looks at him quickly. The question is unexpected, even a little "clever." The officers listening clearly resent it.</context>
      <utterance>Could I ask you what provision you made for the wounded?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that answer stops the Advocate. He smiles dryly.</context>
      <utterance>I was ready to help any who applied.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADVOCATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dyer faces him stonily, a seed of panic taking root deep in his gut.</context>
      <utterance>General... how does a child shot with a 3-0-3 Enfield "apply" for help?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CHELMSFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chelmsford is pacing along one side of a large conference table. Just in front of this is the "British" side -- two generals (a full general and a brigadier), a naval officer, two senior civil servants, a senior police officer. Across from them is the "Indian" side: Gandhi, Nehru, Patel, Jinnah, Azad. This time Gandhi is in the middle and speaks with the full authority of a leader. The Indian side acknowledges Chelmsford's disclaimer -- coolly, but accepting it. That lifts Chelmsford's hopes a little.</context>
      <utterance>You must understand, gentlemen, that His Majesty's Government -- and the British people -- repudiate both the massacre and the philosophy that prompted it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHELMSFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I would like to do is to come to some compromise over the new civil legis --</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is spoken with the cold determination of a man still angry. It stops Chelmsford in mid-pace.</context>
      <utterance>If you will excuse me, Your Excellency, it is our view that matters have gone beyond "legislation."</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The British are stunned almost to speechlessness -- the audacity, the impossibility of it -- and from Gandhi of all people. The senior civil servant, Kinnoch, is the first to recover.</context>
      <utterance>We think it is time you recognized that you are masters in someone else's home.  Despite the best intentions of the best of you, you must, in the nature of things, humiliate us to control us. General Dyer is but an extreme example of the principle. It is time you left.</utterance>
   <speaker>KINNOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With respect, Mr. Gandhi, without British administration, this country would be reduced to chaos.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kinnoch, I beg you to accept that there is no people on earth who would not prefer their own bad government to the "good" government of an alien power.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chelmsford is realist enough to recognize that a faux pas has been made, and he strives to get the meeting back on the course he intends.</context>
      <utterance>My dear sir -- India is British! We're hardly an alien power! Gandhi and the others just look at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHELMSFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has deliberately if delicately caught the eye of both Jinnah and Maulana Azad during this. Gandhi knows the trouble this can cause and he answers more for those on his side than the Viceroy's.</context>
      <utterance>Even if His Majesty could waive all other considerations, he has a duty to the millions of his Muslim subjects who are a minority in this realm. And experience has taught that his troops and his administration are essential in order to keep the peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Its finality is such that for a moment there is no response at all, but then the General smiles.</context>
      <utterance>All nations contain religious minorities. Like other countries, ours will have its problems.  But they will be ours -- not yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His smile flitters cynically on the mouths of the others on his side.</context>
      <utterance>And how do you propose to make them yours? You don't think we're just going to walk out of India.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at them all, then up at Lord Chelmsford behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... in the end you will walk out. Because one hundred thousand Englishmen simply cannot control three hundred fifty million Indians if the Indians refuse to co-operate. And that is what we intend to achieve -- peaceful, non-violent, non-co- operation.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until you yourself see the wisdom of leaving... your Excellency.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"You don't just expect us to walk out?" "Yes." And they all laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are some smiles, but not all of them are quite so amused.</context>
      <utterance>Extraordinary little man! "Nonviolent, non-co-operation" -- for a moment I almost thought they were actually going to do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHELMSFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is an instruction they all find correct.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- but it would be wise to be very cautious for a time. The Anti- Terrorist Act will remain on the statutes, but on no account is Gandhi to be arrested. Whatever mischief he causes, I have no intention of making a martyr of him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We intercut with the crowd, listening raptly. Gandhi holds up one finger.</context>
      <utterance>My message tonight is the message I have given to your brothers everywhere. To gain independence we must prove worthy of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neither of these goals is easy, and the audience reaction shows it. Now Gandhi raises a third finger.</context>
      <utterance>There must be Hindu-Muslim unity -- always.  Secondly, no Indian must be treated as the English treat us so we must remove untouchability from our lives, and from our hearts.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the crowd breaks into stamping and applause. Gandhi lets it run for a time, then stills it with the one small gesture as before.</context>
      <utterance>Third -- we must defy the British.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This has sobered the audience somewhat. Now he looks out across them as though seeking something. Then</context>
      <utterance>Not with violence that will inflame their will, but with firmness that will open their eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an excited stir; he silences it.</context>
      <utterance>English factories make the cloth -- that makes our poverty.  All those who wish to make the English see, bring me the cloth from Manchester and Leeds that you wear tonight, and we will light a fire that will be seen in Delhi -- and London!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close shot -- the ground. As suitcoats, shirts, vests, trousers, are flung into a pile. Featuring the two British soldiers -- later -- on the edge of the crowd, staring off, their faces now brightly lit by darting flames. Their point of view. A huge triangular pile burns before the platform, an excited half-naked crowd swirling in the shadows around it. Resume the two British soldiers. They look at each other with a kind of fear a rampant crowd can excite in those who must hold it...</context>
      <utterance>And if, like me, you are left with only one piece of homespun -- wear it with dignity!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up; it is Kallenbach who is the insistent "helper."</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- just let me get out of your way, please.  No, thank you, I'll manage.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kallenbach is smiling too. He reaches for the bags again.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, Herman!  No, no -- don't destroy my good intentions. I'm feeling guilty about traveling Second Class.</utterance>
   <speaker>KALLENBACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do it as a friend -- and admirer -- not a servant.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And grandly, he relinquishes the bags and looks back.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, in that case!</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their point of view. In the chaos of the Third Class we see Maulana Azad coming out of a section of the coach. He is carrying a baby wrapped in rags. The child's mother with two little ones hanging on her has followed him out.</context>
      <utterance>Maulana is made of sterner stuff. Our trains met in Bombay, but he's back there in that lot somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL'S VOICE-OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Azad hands the woman the baby and she obviously thanks him. He makes a little salaam to her and moves through the confusion of the platform toward the camera. Resume Patel and Kallenbach.</context>
      <utterance>There he is -- out Gandhi-ing Gandhi.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I think what our "beloved Mahatma" asks, I don't know how he ever got such a hold over us. Is he back?</utterance>
   <speaker>KALLENBACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Azad approaches them.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Now that things are moving he's going to write and only take part when it's necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. A Muslim beef eater -- I'm only surprised he missed.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a she.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, that explains it.  Well, do I carry your luggage as penance or --</utterance>
   <speaker>KALLENBACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the camera pans with their glances at they look back with real interest toward the First Class coach. Porters are unloading the baggage of two or three passengers here and helping some others (English and Indian) to board. In the foreground we see a tall Indian woman in a red sari. Farther along there is a large stack of luggage being added to by a porter. An English woman is hovering about it. She is well dressed, but rather dreary and unprepossessing, and the camera zooms in toward her.</context>
      <utterance>There's another passenger -- a Miss Slade.  She's the daughter of an English admiral.  She's been corresponding with him for a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what does the daughter of an English admiral propose to do in an ashram -- sink us?</utterance>
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patel grins. Like most witty men, he loves wit in others.</context>
      <utterance>From the looks of the luggage, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KALLENBACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patel groans. They turn back to the train and just as they do, the tall Indian woman in the red sari tips a porter, taking one small bag from him and turns: Mirabehn (Madeleine Slade) is tall, quite pretty and extremely English despite the sari. The minute she turns, she stops on seeing the now startled Kallenbach.</context>
      <utterance>She wants to make her home with us -- and Gandhiji has agreed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kallenbach recovers sufficiently to --</context>
      <utterance>You'd be Mr. Kallenbach.</utterance>
   <speaker>KALLENBACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...And you would be Miss Slade.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might Mr. Nehru be there too?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The irresponsible young Nehru is in prison -- again. Though there is a rumor that under pressure from your country, they will let him out -- again. Mirabehn has turned to look at him. She has the same sophomoric eagerness and intensity as the young Gandhi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't know how closely we follow your struggle --  how many in England admired what you did in Bardoli. It must have taken enormous courage.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mirabehn is enthralled by the wit, the modesty that underlines the words. She faces Kallenbach.</context>
      <utterance>Well, in this country one must decide if one is more afraid of the government or Gandhi.  For us, it's Gandhi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're German...</utterance>
   <speaker>KALLENBACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks she does, and that he would want to.</context>
      <utterance>And do you feel Indian?</utterance>
   <speaker>KALLENBACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It surprises, but it doesn't deflate.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kallenbach, whose size and stillness carry the aura of some great piece of primitive sculpture -- solid, true, disturbingly profound -- searches inside himself for the answer.</context>
      <utterance>But you've been with him so long -- why?</utterance>
   <speaker>KALLENBACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is so profoundly simple and deeply felt that it obviously touches the deeply emotional Mirabehn.</context>
      <utterance>...I'd come to believe I would never meet a truly honest man. And then I met one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans across and tries to extricate his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Stop -- stop...</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God gave you ten thumbs.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Ba laughs again and Gandhi smiles, tapping her with playful reproval on the top of her bent head. There are footsteps and Gandhi looks up. Patel stands in the doorway. Gandhi's face changes to something like elation. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Eleven.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It means "leader" and it is the name the peasants have given Patel. Gandhi uses it with an intonation of novelty and respect. He stands and crosses to Patel, clutching him emotionally, and it brings a bit of emotion from the sophisticated Patel. Gandhi holds him back to look at him.</context>
      <utterance>Sardar...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patel gets hold of himself, and affects his usual glib cynicism.</context>
      <utterance>What you've done is a miracle. You have made all India proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must have been the only Non-violent campaign ever led by a man who wanted to kill everybody every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles again, then, his arm still around Patel's shoulder, he turns to greet the others. Azad looks at him, then facetiously, as though to put down Patel.</context>
      <utterance>Not true!  The secret is mastering the urge.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi laughs again, squeezing Patel's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>He came Second Class.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Azad shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we can't expect miracles all the time.  Your news I understand is not so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi reaches forward and touches his hand, and he sees Mirabehn on the porch. For a moment their eyes meet and then Mirabehn moves forward quickly and takes his hand, kissing it, tears running down her cheek. Gandhi touches the top of her head.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come, come -- you will be my daughter...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks up at Azad, Azad shakes his head solemnly</context>
      <utterance>...but then some rioting broke out between Hindus and Muslims -- violent, terrible...</utterance>
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he does not go on. It has a terrible sobriety.</context>
      <utterance>Whether it was provoked...  But it gave them an excuse to impose martial law throughout Bengal.  Some of the things the military have done...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Azad shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Is the campaign weakening?</utterance>
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi reaches out and touches his hand.</context>
      <utterance>The marches and protests are bigger if anything but with the censorship here  they know more in England than we do, and it saps the courage to think you may be suffering alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds Azad's eyes, giving strength. Then he turns to Mirabehn, made more aware of her by Azad's reference. For a moment he looks at her sari.</context>
      <utterance>They are not alone. And martial law only shows how desperate the British are.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tone suggests he thinks it is homespun. Mirabehn nods, a little choked that his attention is turned to her.</context>
      <utterance>Is that homespun? Or cotton from Leeds?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi smiles approvingly. Then a shadow --</context>
      <utterance>I -- I sent for it, from here. I dyed it myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mirabehn beams.</context>
      <utterance>What do the workers in England make of what we're doing? It must have produced hardship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has. But you'd be surprised. They understand -- they really do. It's not the workers you have to worry about.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.  Ba will have to teach you to spin too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would rather march.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mirabehn nods and looks resignedly at Ba. Ba is spinning. She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>First spin. Let the others march for a time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mirabehn looks down at the shoes on her feet -- and then at the others and their bare feet -- and she looks up in grinning, self-conscious embarrassment. Ba smiles at her affectionately.</context>
      <utterance>First lesson: To march, wear shoes, to spin, do not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mirabehn looks at her, accepting the warmth behind the teasing. It is the beginning of an enduring friendship.</context>
      <utterance>I'll teach you all our foolishness, and you must teach me yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARCHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We have cut to the parade -- and it is the tail end, going around a corner ahead. Some of the marchers wave their cloth tauntingly at the police. One policeman suddenly steps out and grabs at a piece of cloth waved at him. He pulls it viciously from the marcher.</context>
      <utterance>Home Rule! Long live Gandhi! Buy Indian! Long live Gandhi!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He chases the marcher and boots him with his foot. Another marcher runs at the policeman, swinging at him with his piece of cloth.</context>
      <utterance>I'll stuff your damn mouth with it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MARCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another angle -- sudden. He is whacked across the face with a billy club and falls, clutching his face and spouting blood from his nose. Another angle. The police are now all attacking, swinging clubs and kicking at the tail-enders of the march. And the tail-enders begin to scream</context>
      <utterance>Leave him alone -- he wasn't harming you!</utterance>
   <speaker>TAIL-ENDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help! Help us! as they try to scramble away from the attack. Out of shot we can still hear the disappearing chant: "Home Rule! Long live Gandhi!"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PATEL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another angle. Patel leans with one arm on a table, his mood as devastated as Gandhi's; he is looking at an Indian paper on the table by his hand. A moment then</context>
      <utterance>That's one bit of news they haven't censored.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has been standing, looking out of a window. He turns, and tosses a newspaper on a desk. It is a New York Times and we just glimpse the picture of the severed head lying in the smoldering ashes. And now we see Nehru and Azad in the background too. And Desai. Jinnah as usual in a finely cut European suit, the others are dressed in tunics of homespun as they will be to the end.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's all over the world...  India's "non-violence."</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn to him -- a sense of surprise, but they don't really believe he means the statement.</context>
      <utterance>We must end the campaign.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After what they did at the massacre -- it's only an eye for an eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An eye for an eye only ends up making the whole world blind.  We must stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Gandhi with a mounting sense of annoyance. Gandhi is listening, but still withdrawn into himself.</context>
      <utterance>We would never get the same commitment again -- ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we obtain our freedom by murder and bloodshed I want no part of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was one incident.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi stares into nothing -- mulling that. Finally</context>
      <utterance>Bapu -- the whole nation is marching. They wouldn't stop, even if we asked them to.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will ask. And I will fast as penance for my part in arousing such emotions -- and I will not stop until they stop. Nehru stares at him -- surprised. Azad is not.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks up at him -- a resigned fatalism.</context>
      <utterance>But -- but Gandhiji people are aroused... they won't stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I die, perhaps they will...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi struggles to turn, and Mirabehn helps him. When he turns we see that his face is wet with sweat from the dry heaving and his hands and arms are quivering and he cannot stop them. She looks at him nervously, then pours a glass from the pitcher.</context>
      <utterance>I've brought your drinking water. May I turn you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns back, and propping up his head, helps him to sip.</context>
      <utterance>There is a little lemon juice in it. That is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi swallows with difficulty. He pauses, letting his head fall back and she lowers it down to the mat again. He tries to smile.</context>
      <utterance>Herman has gone to meet Pandit Nehru -- there was a telegram. Almost everywhere it has stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When it is everywhere, then my prayers will be answered. Mirabehn looks daunted by his intractability.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you find me stubborn?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We intercut their faces, very close, as he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>When I despair, I remember that all through history the way of truth and love has always won.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the very last of it Mirabehn has turned her face to him, touched with emotion.</context>
      <utterance>There have been tyrants and murderers, and for a time they can seem invincible. But in the end they always fall. Think of it -- always... When you are in doubt that that is God's way, the way the world is meant to be... think of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mirabehn straightens up, smiling, wiping the tear from her cheek with mock discipline. She starts to pour water from the pitcher into the glass again, then she turns suddenly, her attention caught. Her point of view. The doorway. Nehru stands in it. Kallenbach and Desai are a step or two behind him.</context>
      <utterance>And then -- try to do it His way.  And now -- could I have another feast of lemon juice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands, moving back from Gandhi. Nehru crosses and kneels in Mirabehn's place. Gandhi looks up at him and his eyes light. He moves his shaking hand out and Nehru clasps it. A moment of personal feeling between them, then</context>
      <utterance>Panditji -- come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a victory. Gandhi's face cracks into a tearful grin.</context>
      <utterance>Jinnah, Patel, all of Congress has called for the end of non-co- operation. There's not been one demonstration. All over India people are praying that you will end the fast. They're walking in the streets, offering garlands to the police -- and to British soldiers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reverse angle. Gandhi is walking, holding Ba's shoulder for support with one hand, and Mirabehn's with the other. It is some days later.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Bapu!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy grins at Gandhi's feigned alarm.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning.  Don't let her go. If she bumps me I am done for.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of a motor disturbs them. Gandhi turns. His point of view. Coming into the entrance, along the bumpy path are two police cars (early 1920s Morris). They have to stop because they are impeded by Gandhi's ox-Ford. Four Indian policeman hop quickly out of the second car. A British police superintendent, and his British deputy get more decorously out of the first. Another angle. Gandhi has turned with his two props, Ba and Mirabehn. The police are approaching him. Kallenbach is running from the fields. Nehru is hurrying from another building carrying sheaves of page proofs. Other ashramites converge from the fields and buildings. The British police superintendent (who is Scottish) stops before Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I milk her every day, she's not --</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SUPERINTENDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sedition.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't be serious! This man has just stopped a revolution!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE SUPERINTENDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's as may be. I only know what I am charged to perform. Nehru stares at him and the policemen with growing incredulity.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it -- even the British can't be that stupid!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It stops Nehru. He looks at Gandhi and sighs in unmastered frustration, but he moves to Gandhi's side. Gandhi turns to Mirabehn.</context>
      <utterance>Panditji -- please, help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at them, then slips his free hand on Nehru's shoulder and he turns to the superintendent.</context>
      <utterance>You must help Herman -- and Ba.  I have been on many trips -- it is just another trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Featuring Gandhi, Ba and Nehru, as they walk to the car behind the somewhat surprised superintendent.</context>
      <utterance>I am at your command.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs and Nehru struggles to join in the joke.</context>
      <utterance>I know India is not ready for my kind of independence. If I am sent to jail, perhaps that is the best protest our country can make at this time. And if it helps India, I have never refused to take His Majesty's hospitality.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant-at-arms turns and moves to the door at the side of the bench. The courtroom immediately falls silent. The sergeant-at-arms opens the door -- a moment -- and Gandhi enters slowly. He has recovered a bit more, but he still moves slowly. Featuring Judge Broomfield. As Gandhi enters, he lowers his glasses, places them on his desk, and rises, facing Gandhi. Featuring two English court reporters. One nudges the other in astonishment, signaling off toward the judge. Their point of view. The clerk, confused as well as astonished, see the judge standing, facing Gandhi in respect, and dutifully, he too stands. Resume the reporters. A disbelieving exchange of glances, the sound of others standing around them. They glance back. Full shot -- the courtroom. The whole court rises, the astounded reporters the last of all. Featuring Gandhi. He takes the prisoner's stand. He looks around, a little surprised, a little affected by the demonstration. He looks up at the judge. For a minute their eyes meet, the judge makes a little bow to Gandhi. Gandhi reciprocates... and the judge sits down. Featuring the reporters shrugging incredulously to each other, as they sit once more. Later. The Advocate General is speaking from a folded journal.</context>
      <utterance>Call the prisoner to the bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADVOCATE GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..."Non-co-operation has one aim: the overthrow of the Government. Sedition must become our creed. We must give no quarter, nor can we expect any."  Signed M. K. Gandhi, in your journal Young India, dated twenty-second March of this year. Do you deny writing it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And I will save the Court's time, M'Lord, by stating under oath that to this day I believe non-co-operation with evil is a duty. And that British rule of India is evil. There is a little shock of reaction around the courtroom. The Advocate General smiles with a brittle disdain, then he turns to the judge.</context>
      <utterance>Not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADVOCATE GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The judge nods. He turns, glancing at the empty table for defense counsel, and then to Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>The Prosecution rests, M'Lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE BROOMFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I take it you will conduct your own defense, Mr. Gandhi.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is almost a cruel challenge to the obviously humane Broomfield. The reporters scribble, watching the Judge even as they write, because the mere doubt in the Judge's face reflects on the whole position of the British to India. Featuring Judge Broomfield. He lowers his glasses soberly, staring at them for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I have no defense, My Lord. I am guilty as charged.  And if you truly believe in the system of law you administer in my country, you must inflict on me the severest penalty possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE BROOMFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at Gandhi and his own respect for him is almost poignantly manifest.</context>
      <utterance>It is impossible for me to ignore that you are in a different category from any person I have ever tried, or am likely to try.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE BROOMFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He folds, and refolds his glasses and then without looking at anyone he rises. The court rises and he walks stiffly to his chambers. Featuring Gandhi. He stands, staring at Broomfield, and now it is his face that shows the respect.</context>
      <utterance>If however His Majesty's Government could -- at some later date -- see fit to reduce that term, no one would be better pleased than I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>COLLINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he certainly wasn't forgotten! And as soon as he got out he was back tramping the country, preaching non-violence and demanding a free India. Everybody knows another showdown's coming -- but when, and over what -- He shrugs, "Nobody knows"...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Collins has suddenly slowed the car, then swerves around a pair of elephants hauling logs.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I read you account of that crowd in Calcutta and that he was twisting the Lion's tail again...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and I knew something had to give. And I was determined to be here when it did.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does a reporter in Central America learn that Gandhi was born in Porbandar anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Collins glances at him in surprise as he steers the car around another procession of camels heading toward the port.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I've been a Gandhi buff for a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He certainly makes good copy.  The other day Winston Churchill called him "that half-naked Indian fakir." Walker smiles too, but it soon passes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Collins looks at him in real surprise.</context>
      <utterance>I met him once.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean Gandhi?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back in South Africa...  long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was he like?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lots of hair... and a little like a college freshman -- trying to figure everything out.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He honks as he goes around a wooden-wheeled cart.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he must've found some of the answers...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I will ever live devoted to you, speaking words of love and praying for your happiness." Close shot -- Gandhi.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Take a fifth step, that we may serve the people."</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Featuring Walker, now too entranced by the ceremony, by the depth of layered emotions in Gandhi and Ba's voices and eyes to take any notes...</context>
      <utterance>"I will follow close behind you and help to serve the people."</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Take a sixth step, that we may follow our vows in life."</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I will follow you in all our vows and duties." Ba and Gandhi. Near to meeting now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment their eyes hold -- the many dreams, and hopes and pain -- the love of many years. Walker watches, his own face taut with emotion. Resume Gandhi and Ba. And Gandhi slowly lifts his hand.</context>
      <utterance>"You are my best friend... my highest guru, and my sovereign lord."</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches Ba's lips with his extended fingers and she kisses them gently.</context>
      <utterance>Then I put a sweetened wheat cake in her mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has lifted her fingers to his mouth and he kisses them gently. Featuring Walker and Collins both touched, the overtly cynical American obviously even more than the likeable Englishman. Gandhi turns to them.</context>
      <utterance>And I put a sweetened wheat cake in his mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And with that we were pronounced man and wife.  We were both thirteen...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walker looks down at him. Gandhi scowls up in the early light.</context>
      <utterance>Even as a boy I thought so.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Trying to keep track of you is making me change all my sleeping habits.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you've come all this way because you think something is going to happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hm.  Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both watch the waves beat on the shore a moment, the changing hues of the sunrise on the whites of Porbandar.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps. I've come here to think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you remember much of South Africa?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A great deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks out to sea, and we intercut his face with Walker's, the sea, and the town itself as the sun turns it white.</context>
      <utterance>I've traveled so far -- and thought so much.  As you can see, my city was a sea city -- always filled with Hindus and Muslims and Sikhs and Jews and Persians.  The temple where you were yesterday is of my family's sect, the Pranami. It was Hindu of course but the priests used to read from the Muslim Koran and the Hindu Gita, moving from one to the other as though it mattered not at all which book was read as long as God was worshipped.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walker studies him as this profound man reaches, in his middle years, a profound insight. Featuring Gandhi staring out to sea, his mind locked in reflection, and suddenly his head lifts, his eyes become alert, he is caught by some excitement which he weighs for a moment, then he stands, his manner suddenly tingling with optimism. Walker stares at him, then at what Gandhi seems to be looking at. His point of view. The waves lapping the shore below them. Walker turns back to Gandhi, puzzled. But there is no mistaking the sudden glow in Gandhi's face.</context>
      <utterance>When I was a boy I used to sing a song in that temple: "A true disciple knows another's woes as his own. He bows to all and despises none... Earthly possessions hold him not." Like all boys I said the words, not thinking of what they meant or how they might be influencing me.  I've traveled so far... and all I've done is come back home.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks at him, a teasing smile.</context>
      <utterance>You know what you're going to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The grin broadens, and then he starts briskly down the promontory. Walker scrambles up after him.</context>
      <utterance>It would have been very uncivil of me to let you make such a long trip for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gulls fly over them, squawking in the growing light. Gandhi pauses, looking up at the gulls, then back down to the sea.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns from the sea to Walker, his eyes confident, elated, then he continues on down the promontory. Still baffled, Walker glances at the sea, at him, then hurries after. Full shot. The waves running against the shore...</context>
      <utterance>I'm going back to the ashram  and then I'm going to prove to the new Viceroy that the King's writ no longer runs in India!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>IRWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another angle. He is looking in astonishment at his principal secretary. His ADC, a general, a brigadier, a senior police officer are with him. Like him they hold the same offices, but are a new team.</context>
      <utterance>Salt?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irwin looks at him, still trying to penetrate the significance of the act. The senior police officer helps.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. He is going to march to the sea and make salt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irwin has listened; it's beginning to make a little sense.</context>
      <utterance>There is a Royal Monopoly on the manufacture of salt, sir. It's illegal to make it or sell it without a Government license.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right -- he's breaking the law. What will he be depriving us of, two rupees of salt tax?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a serious attack on the revenue, sir. Its primary importance is symbolic.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The principal secretary blanches.</context>
      <utterance>Don't patronize me, Charles.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irwin looks at his ADC, then paces a bit, pondering it.</context>
      <utterance>No, sir. I -- in this climate, sir, nothing lives without water -- or salt. Our absolute control of it is a control on the pulse of India.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's the basis of this "Declaration of Independence"?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment as Irwin considers it, then it is the general who speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. The day he sets off everyone is supposed to raise the flag of "Free India." Then he walks some two hundred and forty miles to the sea and makes salt.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say ignore it. Let them raise their damn flags, let him make his salt. It's only symbolic if we choose to make it so.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irwin has turned to him. And this makes up his mind.</context>
      <utterance>He's going to arrive at the sea on the anniversary of the massacre at Amritsar.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is concerned enough to be angry, but certain enough to be dogmatic.</context>
      <utterance>General Edgar is right -- ignore it. Mr. Gandhi will find it's going to take a great deal more than a pinch of salt to bring down the British Empire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the real test will come if I am arrested. If there is violence we lose all our moral advantage. This time it mustn't happen. He looks at Nehru and Azad solemnly to emphasize the point. Nehru nods; a little smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He means Gandhi of course, and Gandhi accepts the reference, but it is the acceptance of the strict sergeant major: "Don't fail me." Then he looks to Azad.</context>
      <utterance>We're not beginners anymore. We've been trained by a strict sergeant major.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru nods. Ba moves to massage the top of Gandhi's head.</context>
      <utterance>If I'm taken, Maulana is to lead the march. If he is arrested, Patel, then Kripalani, then yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi grins, looking at Mirabehn, who is massaging his legs.</context>
      <utterance>You should be relaxing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure I'm fit for at least five hundred miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks at Nehru, a benign shrug.</context>
      <utterance>You should ride the pony. It is not necessary to walk to prove the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru smiles. He stands, having taken the last proof sheet. Azad rises with him.</context>
      <utterance>I have two of them bossing me now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi is pleasurably impressed with that.</context>
      <utterance>We must get these to the printer.  I know it will succeed. Even my mother is prepared to march.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Jinnah?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's waiting. He's not prepared to accept it will mean as much as you think.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it over if they arrest you now?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walker smiles -- a little uneasily -- for they are now near the police. Gandhi nods to them amiably as he passes along in front of them. Walker is turning, watching for a move from the police but begins to grasp that there may be none. He hurries along closer to Gandhi again, one eye still on the police.</context>
      <utterance>Not if they arrest me -- or a thousand -- or ten thousand.  It is not only generals who know how to plan campaigns.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi glances at him. Walker too wears a knapsack. Gandhi nods to it, though never breaking his pace.</context>
      <utterance>What if they don't arrest you? What if they don't react at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods politely toward the British police officer at the end of the police line. Walker stops, letting the procession march on by him, looking at the British police officer, then writing busily in his notebook. Collins stop by him.</context>
      <utterance>Do you still have your notebook?  The function of a civil resister is to provoke response. And we will continue to provoke until they respond, or they change the law. They are not in control -- we are. That is the strength of civil resistance.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he's in charge...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to walk all the way?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi smiles and turns back. He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Walk-er. And I intend to report it the way it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GANDHI'S VOICE-OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi in the center of the wildly cheering crowd, the camera pulling back and back... and the shot becomes black and white, and we hear the music of Movietone News.</context>
      <utterance>Man needs salt as he needs air and water. This salt comes from the Indian Ocean.  Let every Indian claim it as his right!! A wide-angle shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER'S VOICE-OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that we get the Movietone Music tag and as the film fades, the lights go up on</context>
      <utterance>...and so once more the man of non- violence has challenged the might of the British Empire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SENIOR POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irwin sighs.</context>
      <utterance>They're making it everywhere, sir -- mobs of them -- publicly. Congress leaders are selling it on the streets of Delhi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're being made fools of around the world!</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irwin nods.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't there any instruction from London?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time he is truly angry.</context>
      <utterance>We're required to stop it.  And stop it we will.  I don't care if we fill the jails, stop it. Arrest anyone, any rank -- except Gandhi. We'll cut his strength from under him. And then we'll deal with the Mahatma.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRITISH SUBALTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The beach. Subaltern's point of view. Packed with people making salt, selling salt, buying salt. Resume the British subaltern. He looks back. His point of view. Behind him there is an open military truck and about twenty sepoys. Formidable for an ordinary crowd, nothing to handle this. The subaltern stiffens bravely and signals the men somewhat unconvincingly from the truck.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUBALTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right -- jump to it -- clear this beach!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And a lathi is brought smashing across the side of Nehru's head. He is knocked to his knees; blood streams from his head. He feels the side of his head, the blood soaking his hand. He struggles to his feet, facing the policeman who has struck him.</context>
      <utterance>No violence, Zia!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It stops the policeman for a second, and a sergeant suddenly intrudes, recognizing Nehru.</context>
      <utterance>...no violence.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Nehru --</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant sighs grimly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm an illegal trader in salt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SENIOR POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...There's been no time to keep figures, but there must be ninety -- a hundred thousand under arrest.  And it still goes on.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's leading them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know! Nehru, Patel, almost every Congress Official is in jail... and their wives and their children -- we've even arrested Nehru's mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has there been any violence?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, in Karachi the police fired on a crowd and killed a couple of people and --  and in Peshawar the Deputy Police Commissioner lost his head and... and opened fire with a machine gun.  But he's facing a disciplinary court! You can't expect things like that not to happen when --</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, sir -- no, I'm afraid not.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He means incite violence. The Viceroy ponders it -- favorably.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps if we arrested Gandhi, it might --</utterance>
   <speaker>IRWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's addressed this letter directly to you, has he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir, he has. The usual -- India's salt belongs to India -- but then he says flatly that he personally is going to lead a raid tomorrow on the Dharasana Salt Works.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he turns to leave Irwin speaks -- almost offhandedly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. Yes, sir. It will be my pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Fields, keep that salt works open. The senior police officer stares at him, then</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would like admission to the Works.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and starts down the dip toward the gate and the waiting lathis of the police. A series of shots, as Azad leads the first row of volunteers down and up the dip. We intercut Walker, frozen, watching the inevitable onslaught, the British police commanding officer ready to give the first order.</context>
      <utterance>Last night they took Gandhiji from us. They expect us to lose heart or to fight back. We will not lose heart, we will not fight back. In his name we will be beaten. As he has taught us, we will not raise a hand. "Long live Mahatma Gandhi!"</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE COMMANDING OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with the volunteers a foot from them, the police strike with their lathis. A groan of empathic anguish from the waiting volunteers, but then we get A series of shots As the next row moves forward and the horror of the one-sided mayhem proceeds heads are cracked, faces split, ribs smashed, and yet one row of volunteers follows another, and another into the unrelenting police, who knock bleeding bodies out of the way, down into the dip, swing till sweat pours from their faces and bodies. And through it we intercut with Mirabehn and the Indian women rescuing the wounded, carrying them on stretchers to be bandaged. We see Walker helping once or twice, turning, watching, torn between being a professional spectator and a normal human being. And always the volunteers coming, never stopping, never offering resistance. And finally on sound there is an insistent click, click, click, like a thud of the lathis but becoming clearly the slap of an impatient hand on a telephone cradle and out of the carnage of the salt works we dissolve to</context>
      <utterance>Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello! Ed! Ed! Goddammit, don't cut me off!  Ed! Okay -- yeah -- right. And he continues urgently reading the story that lies on his notes on the little stand before him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shifts the mangled notes and comes to his last paragraph. He speaks it trying only half successfully to keep the emotion from his voice.</context>
      <utterance>"They walked, with heads up, without music, or cheering, or any hope of escape from injury or death."  "It went on and on and on. Women carried the wounded bodies from the ditch until they dropped from exhaustion. But still it went on."</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Whatever moral ascendance the West held was lost today. India is free for she has taken all that steel and cruelty can give, and she has neither cringed nor retreated."  "In the words of his followers, 'Long live Mahatma Gandhi.' "</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reverse angle. Irwin is in shadows behind his desk looking, still, in some kind of shock, staring at Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>I am aware that I must have given you much cause for irritation, your Excellency. I hope it will not stand between us as men.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRWIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whirr of a camera, and a swift cut to</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gandhi, I have instructions to request your attendance at an All- Government Conference in London to discuss -- to discuss the possible Independence of India. He faces Gandhi stiffly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MACDONALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beneath its unctuous political veneer it is blatantly divisive and clearly reveals the true intent of the Conference. As Gandhi looks at MacDonald, we read on his face his perception of the sad truth. E. Gandhi, Mirabehn and Charlie walking under an umbrella in the rain, their heads bent in glum conversation. F. Gandhi being welcomed and kissed by a group of millworkers outside a large mill entrance identified by the sign GREENFIELD COTTON MILL, LANCASHIRE. He is hugged and squeezed by some hefty female millworkers, all grinning happily, Gandhi not least. G. Gandhi in a radio studio, seated at a table, a large microphone labeled "CBS" before him, technicians and Mirabehn in the glass booth behind him, Walker across the table from him, the "On the Air" sign bright...</context>
      <utterance>I think our first duty is to recognize that there is not one India, but several: a Hindu India, a Muslim India, and India of Princely States. And all these must be respected -- and cared for -- not just one.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walker cringes, glancing at the lighted "On the Air" sign. He signals "Yes" frantically.</context>
      <utterance>Do I speak into that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at the booth. Everybody including Walker and Mirabehn are nodding "Yes." Gandhi shrugs, grins at everyone's excitement, and begins.</context>
      <utterance>Are they ready? Do I start?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the speech continues in the thin, static-y tones of thirties' radio, we see Mirabehn and the technicians listening in the control room./ Walker, across the table from Gandhi./ The outside of Broadcasting House./ The Empire State Building and Manhattan./ A mid-western farmhouse./ A thirties' radio set in a thirties' American living room./ A family, listening, kids playing on the floor, half ignoring it, the mother ironing, the father in an armchair, a newspaper open.</context>
      <utterance>I am glad to speak to America where so many friends exist that I know only in my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>H. Gandhi shaking hands with MacDonald outside No. 10 Downing Street, MacDonald smiling the politician's smile, Gandhi smiling rather sadly. I. Gandhi on the deck of a boat, sitting on a deck chair, wrapped in blankets, staring somberly out to sea. Reverse angle: the wake of the boat in the vast ocean.</context>
      <utterance>I think your interest and the world's has fallen on India, not only because we are struggling for freedom, but because the way we are doing so is unique as far as history shows us. Here in Europe mighty nations are, it seems, already contemplating another war, though I think they, and all the world, are sick to death of bloodspilling. All of us are seeking a way out, and I flatter myself that perhaps the ancient land of India will offer such a way. If we are to make progress we must not repeat history, but make history. And I myself will die before I betray our belief that love is a stronger weapon than hate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another angle. He is spinning (expertly), and gathered on the porch with him are Nehru and Jinnah and Patel and Azad and Kripalani. Desai and Pyarelal are inconspicuously in attendance as always, Pyarelal now clearly sharing Desai's role as secretary.</context>
      <utterance>It is only a sprain. Take her to the river, and we'll make a mud-pack for her. Go -- I won't be long. He turns back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is in his white suit, the black-ribboned pince-nez. He sits on a wicker chair, Nehru and Patel lean against the railing, Azad and Kripalani sit on the floor like Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>So the truth is, after all your travels, all your efforts, they've stopped the campaign and sent you home empty-handed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are only clinging to old dreams  and trying to split us in the old way. But the will has gone -- Independence will drop like a ripe apple. The only question is when  and how.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say when is now -- and we will determine how.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi winds up what he has done, and starts to rise.</context>
      <utterance>Precisely.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are preparing for war. I will not support it, but I do not intend to take advantage of their danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi has moved toward the steps. He stops and looks at Patel. A wry, gentle smile.</context>
      <utterance>That's when you take advantage.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Featuring Nehru. He looks at Jinnah and shrugs. Jinnah takes it less philosophically and his eyes burn with anger as he watches Gandhi head for the young girl with the injured goat.</context>
      <utterance>No. That is just another way of striking back. We have come a long way together with the British. When they leave we want to see them off as friends.  And now, if you'll excuse me, there is something I must attend to.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Mud packs."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRITISH COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi stops, looks up at him, at the troops behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gandhi -- sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRITISH COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi shakes his head with a weary grin.</context>
      <utterance>I have instructions to inquire as to the subject of your speech tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The British Colonel signals back to the troops.</context>
      <utterance>The value of goat's milk in daily diet.  But you can be sure I will also speak against war.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRITISH COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As a detail marches up to them, the colonel's adjutant speaks gently to Ba.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir. That can't be allowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADJUTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right, Mrs. Gandhi. I have orders to return with you and your companion to the Mahatma's ashram.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at the adjutant belligerently. He looks flummoxed. Later. Long shot -- high. The colonel and his adjutant striding toward the exit of the station. Following behind them, a detail of six soldiers accompanying Gandhi. The camera tracks across the platform and we see they are being followed by a detail of six soldiers accompanying Ba. And the camera tracks again and we see they are being followed by a detail of six soldiers accompanying Mirabehn!</context>
      <utterance>If you take my husband, I intend to speak in his place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bourke-White slips back down into her seat; we see the arm band on her jacket: "Press." The lieutenant starts the jeep up and they head toward the gate, where we see a British soldier on guard.</context>
      <utterance>It was the Aga Khan's palace, but they've turned it into a prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bourke-White just absorbs it, staring at the palace, taking in the experience with the appetite of her breed, and her own particular sensitivity.</context>
      <utterance>They've got most of the leading Congress politicians in this one. But Nehru and some others are over in Dehra Dun. Your timing's pretty lucky. They had your Mr. Gandhi cut off from the press but last month his personal secretary died and they've let up on the restrictions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bourke-White -- who has been moving, crouching to shoot him and the light -- sags back against the wall, relaxing at last. She has a smile as penetrating and warming as his.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I have heard of Life Magazine.  I have even heard of Margaret Bourke- White. But I don't know why either should be interested in an old man sitting in prison when the world is blowing itself to pieces.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi grins and glances toward his dhoti.</context>
      <utterance>You're the only man I know who makes his own clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meaning he doesn't wear many clothes. Bourke-White bursts into an appreciative radiance -- already she has assessed him, and been won.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, but for me that's not much of an accomplishment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- prison is rather agreeable to me, and there is no doubt that after the war, independence will come. My only worry is what shape it will take. Jinnah has --</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has Gandhi in the foreground, a soldier on the wall above and behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi shrugs but suffers it. We feature him, low, from her point of view, as he walks on, the soldier pacing on the wall in the background.</context>
      <utterance>Now go on -- just as you were.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"...what shape it will take." Jinnah has -- what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She clicks.</context>
      <utterance>Jinnah has -- has cooperated with the British. It has given him power and the freedom to speak, and he has filled the Muslims with fears of what will happen to them in a country that is predominantly Hindu.  That I find hard to bear -- even in prison.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's grinning at her own frustration and she keeps trying, but there's no doubt she means it. Gandhi's smile broadens. Wryly he lifts his own "product" -- a tiny roll of thread.</context>
      <utterance>I do not see it as the solution of the twentieth century's problems!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they both laugh... a guard on the wall distantly looks at them wonderingly.</context>
      <utterance>I have a friend who keeps telling me how much it costs him to keep me in poverty.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she responds to the sophistication of that observation. He pivots around, moving beside her, and slowly demonstrates the process, taking her hands, guiding her. Bourke-White watches him as much as the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>But I know happiness does not come with things -- even twentieth century things. It can come from work, and pride in what you do.  It will not necessarily be "progress" for India if she simply imports the unhappiness of the West.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But do you really believe you could use non-violence against someone like Hitler?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he smiles a little wisely at her.</context>
      <utterance>Not without defeats -- and great pain.  But are there no defeats in this war -- no pain?  What you cannot do is accept injustice. From Hitler -- or anyone. You must make the injustice visible -- be prepared to die like a soldier to do so.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is my finger supposed to be wrapped around that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That is what you get for distracting me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you expect when you talk like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bourke-White looks at him and there is enough sense in this argument to give her pause.</context>
      <utterance>Every enemy is a human being -- even the worst of them. And he believes he is right and you are a beast.  And if you beat him over the head you will only convince him. But you suffer, to show him that he is wrong, your sacrifice creates an atmosphere of understanding -- if not with him, then in the hearts of the rest of the community on whom he depends.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him, and we know she thinks him much more profound than she had thought initially.</context>
      <utterance>If you are right, you will win -- after much pain.  If you are wrong, well, then, only you will suffer the blows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bourke-White accepts it at face value. She opens another line of inquiry.</context>
      <utterance>...not at all. Bapu has always said there were two kinds of slavery in India -- one for women, one for the untouchables -- and he has always fought against both.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ba pauses.</context>
      <utterance>Does it rankle, being separated from him this way?</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... but we see each other in the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's terribly curious, but she doesn't want to offend. Ba sees both the curiosity and the hesitancy. She smiles across at Mirabehn, then</context>
      <utterance>But not at night...</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Hindu philosophy the way to God is to free yourself of possessions -- and the passions that inflame to anger and jealousy.  Bapu has always struggled to find the way to God.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Ba smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You mean he -- he gave up --  married life.</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs... the implication is it was a long time ago.</context>
      <utterance>Four times he tried -- and failed.  But then he took a solemn vow...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he has never broken it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at them soberly and then they all burst into laughter like girls.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I've got permission to move her -- he can go too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The major looks defeated and depressed by the news.</context>
      <utterance>She's had a coronary throm -- a serious heart failure. She wouldn't survive a trip. It's best to leave her -- and hope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru and Patel are approaching from the conference room, both of them looking worn and angry too. Jinnah raises his voice deliberately so Nehru will hear.</context>
      <utterance>I don't give a damn for the independence of India! I am concerned about the slavery of Muslims!</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not sit by to see the mastery of the British replaced by the mastery of the Hindus!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jinnah sneers at the idea, though he cools a little.</context>
      <utterance>Muslim and Hindu are the right and left eye of India. No one will be slave, no one master.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world is not made of Mahatma Gandhis.  I am talking about the real world.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The "real India" has Muslims and Hindus in every village and every city! How do you propose to separate them?</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where there is a Muslim majority -- that will be Pakistan. The rest is your India.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mohammed -- the Muslims are in a majority on two different sides of the country.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUNTBATTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi nods, and reluctantly the adversaries move back to the conference room. Gandhi is last through the door. He pauses by Mountbatten, a little sigh -- "How difficult, how difficult" -- then he puts a friendly hand on Mountbatten's shoulder and the two of them enter together.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, perhaps we should recommence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mirabehn is spinning across the room. She lifts her head as a signal to someone out of shot. Gandhi's two grand nieces, Manu and Abha, who help Mirabehn now that Ba is gone, rise quickly at Mirabehn's signal, Manu to help with his shawl, Abha to hold his sandals so that he can slip into them.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God, they've stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's cross -- he's worried about other things. Mirabehn just smiles at it. Gandhi looks down at Abha, and taps her sharply on the top of the head.</context>
      <utterance>I'm your grand uncle but I can still walk either of you into the ground and I don't need to be pampered this way!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods obediently, the flicker of a smile around her mouth, youthful, irrepressible. The beauty of it almost saddens Gandhi. He taps her again -- gently -- and goes out.</context>
      <utterance>Finish your quota of spinning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HINDU YOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are all awed, timid even in his actual presence, and the mood of their gathering has changed altogether. Gandhi looks at the youth and the line of others.</context>
      <utterance>Bapu -- please. Don't do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me not to do? Not to meet with Mr. Jinnah?  I am a Muslim!  And a Hindu, and a Christian and a Jew -- and so are all of you. When you wave those flags and shout you send fear into the hearts of your brothers. He sweeps them sternly with his eyes, all his fatigue and strain showing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he lowers his head and moves on to the car, where Kallenbach holds the door for him, Nehru, Azad and Pyarelal following. Another angle. As they get into the car, we see the car that sits by the two trucks that have brought the youths. In the back seat we see two men, one of whom is Prakash (The bearded man at Gandhi's assassination).</context>
      <utterance>This is not the India I want. Stop it. For God's sake, stop it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has been looking at Gandhi, who sits on the floor of the large room some distance from him, just lifting his head from prayers. Nehru, Patel and Azad are on the same side of the room as Gandhi. They rise from prayer as Jinnah comes down the steps to them. Gandhi hesitates, then begins.</context>
      <utterance>Now, please, if you've finished your prayers, could we begin with business.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Jinnah has drawn himself up. His vanity is too great not to be touched by that prospect. He measures Gandhi for a moment to see that he is sincere, and when he is satisfied with that, he turns slowly to Nehru, Patel and Azad. Nehru glances at Patel. They have all been taken by surprise by the offer -- and do not feel what Gandhi feels. Nehru looks hesitantly at Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>My dear Jinnah, you and I are brothers born of the same Mother India. If you have fears, I want to put them to rest.  I am asking Panditji to stand down. I want you to be the first Prime Minister of India  -- to name your entire cabinet, to make the head of every government department a Muslim.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bapu, for me, and the rest,  if that is what you want, we will accept it. But out there  already there is rioting because Hindus fear you are going to give too much away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It bears the stamp of undeniable truth. Gandhi's eyes sag with the despair of a man whose last hope, whose faith, has crumbled around him. Jinnah smiles cynically, he spreads his hands "See?"</context>
      <utterance>If you did this, no one could control it. No one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JINNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi stares at him numbly.</context>
      <utterance>It is your choice. Do you want an independent India and an independent Pakistan? Or do you want civil war?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kallenbach looks at her. Her tone criticizes more than his stilling the goat's bell.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't you being a little overprotective?</utterance>
   <speaker>KALLENBACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow. Tomorrow photograph him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kallenbach stands and looks across at her, judging, then appealing to her humanity.</context>
      <utterance>I came all this way because I believed the picture of Independence Day was of him here alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KALLENBACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bourke-White grabs a clump of grass, twists it free, and sighs. She tosses the grass vaguely at the goat.</context>
      <utterance>It is violence, and the fear of violence, that have made today what it is... Give him the dignity of his grief.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kallenbach stops, staring absently at the ground ahead, then</context>
      <utterance>And while we're sitting here feeding goats, what will happen to all the Muslims in India and the Hindus in Pakistan?</utterance>
   <speaker>KALLENBACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gandhi will pray for them...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. There just are not that many troops.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILITARY AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns. Patel has a message he was going to present to him. He hesitates, grins dismally, and crumples the message -- "No use." Nehru sags. He looks at Patel with haggard eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What he can!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was right. It's insane -- anything would have been better.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru nods solemnly.</context>
      <utterance>Have you found him?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patel reacts to that -- surprise, apprehension.</context>
      <utterance>He's in Noakhali.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patel nods grimly -- the noisy chaos of the room. Someone shouts at Nehru, "Prime Minister!"</context>
      <utterance>He's tramping from village to village -- no police, no troops -- trying to quell the madness single-handedly.  Maulana has gone to bring him back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Calcutta it's like civil war. The Muslims rose and there was a bloodbath, and now the Hindus are taking revenge -- and if we can't stop it there'll be no hope for the Hindus left in Pakistan.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is an empty and despairing echo of Gandhi's words.</context>
      <utterance>...an eye for an eye making the whole world blind.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't there any troops to spare?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing -- nothing. The divisions in Bombay and Delhi can hardly keep the peace now. And each fresh bit of news creates another wave of mad... ness. He has turned and seen Gandhi standing slowly. It has almost stopped him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could we cut all news off? I know --</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bapu -- please. Where are you going.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is moving toward the door. It stops them all. Pyarelal moves tentatively to open the door.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to hear more...</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need your help!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is nothing I can give.</utterance>
   <speaker>AZAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi turns, looks at him bleakly.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calcutta.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>POLICE COMMISSIONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, please, I don't have the men to protect you -- not in a Muslim house. Not this quarter.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a sudden commotion just below them and angry shouts: "Death to Muslims!," "Death to Muslims!" Gandhi peers down. His point of view. A surging gang of youths, many carrying torches, and far outnumbering the little group of police and soldiers, are shouting up at the roof. We see three or four black flags and stains of blood on many of them. A few hold knives still wet with blood.</context>
      <utterance>I am staying with the friend of a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>A YOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A feral roar goes up at the sight of Gandhi, but he stands unmoving.</context>
      <utterance>There he is!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes it mean the youth. For a second it makes an impact, but then the youth shouts his defiance at him and his message.</context>
      <utterance>Because forgiveness is the gift of the brave.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An angry chorus of acclamation; when it dies</context>
      <utterance>To hell with you, Gandhi!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The commissioner looks at him, uncertain, not knowing what to do, as the angry chanting continues above the sound of rioting.</context>
      <utterance>I have lived a lifetime. If I had shunned death -- or feared it -- I would not be here. Nor would you be concerned for me.  Leave me -- and take your men.  You have more important things to worry about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are tears in Gandhi's eyes now.</context>
      <utterance>Bapu... Allah be with you...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the weight of his helplessness hangs on him.</context>
      <utterance>And with you.  Pray... I cannot help you -- pray... pray.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The aide shakes his head -- there's no answer. Nehru lowers his head again; it is like another burden on a man who already has too many. He grips his temples... a terrible sigh.</context>
      <utterance>Why must I read news like this in the paper?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell Patel. Arrange a plane. We will go -- Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru thinks on it solemnly, then nods yes.</context>
      <utterance>Four days?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi turns to pat their joined hands with his other hand. He does so with effort, and at last he sees Patel.</context>
      <utterance>Bapu...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patel sits near the head of the cot so the three of them are on a level. Outside the canopied area, Bourke-White is crouched, her camera framing the three of them.</context>
      <utterance>Sardar...  You have gained weight. You must join me in the fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi smiles and reaches to touch hands with him.</context>
      <utterance>If I fast I die. If you fast people go to all sorts of trouble to keep you alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Bapu, forgive me -- I've cheated. I could have come earlier. But your fast has helped. These last days people's minds have begun to turn to this bed -- and away from last night's atrocity. But now it is enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is despairingly sincere. But Nehru feels he has an antidote for that despair. The distant sound of an explosion.</context>
      <utterance>All that has happened is that I've grown a little thinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bourke-White captures the sense of elation in his face. From her discreet distance, she lowers the camera, holding it against her mouth, waiting for Gandhi's response. Gandhi nods to Nehru, accepting the news with a sad wistfulness.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow five thousand Muslim students of all ages are marching here in Calcutta -- for peace.  And five thousand Hindu students are marching with them. It is all organized.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru isn't prepared for this resistance. He glances at Patel, and we see that they recognize that their bland conviction that they could talk him out of the fast was deeply misplaced. Nehru turns back -- this time no confidence, only concern. A forced smile.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad -- but it will not be enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi smiles, pain etched in his eyes. He touches Nehru's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Bapu, you are not so young anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru stares at him, feeling the sudden fear that Gandhi means it. Patel, Mirabehn, Azad, Bourke-White are gripped by the same realization.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry for me -- death will be a deliverance.  I cannot watch the destruction of all I have lived for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks at her, and then the microphone. When he speaks into the microphone his voice is very weak.</context>
      <utterance>Bapu...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now we go into the streets, intercutting with Gandhi but seeing Hindus listening around loudspeakers on corners, in little eating houses, Muslim shops where people live in the back, and neighbors gathering defensively in groups.</context>
      <utterance>Each night before I sleep, I read a few words from the Gita and the Koran, and the Bible...  tonight I ask you to share these thoughts of God with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans back, exhausted. Mirabehn is looking at him; she starts to sing softly.</context>
      <utterance>I will begin with the Bible where the words of the Lord are, "Love thy neighbor as thyself"... and then our beloved Gita which says, "The world is a garment worn by God, thy neighbor is in truth thyself"... and finally the Holy Koran, "We shall remove all hatred from our hearts and recline on couches face to face, a band of brothers."</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi, his eyes closed, takes it up in his weak, croaking voice.</context>
      <utterance>"Lead Kindly Light, amidst the circling gloom..."</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI/MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The night is dark, and I am far from home, Lead thou me on..."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru looks across at Gandhi. The doctor, who is testing Gandhi's pulse yet again, glances at him -- no encouragement -- and moves away. Nehru moves to the side of the cot and Gandhi smiles weakly and holds out a hand, but he is in pain.</context>
      <utterance>His pulse is very irregular -- the kidneys aren't functioning.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks up at Suhrawardy, who nods. Gandhi looks back at Nehru. There is no hint of him changing his mind.</context>
      <utterance>Bapu, I have brought Mr. Suhrawardy. It was he who called on the Muslims to rise; he is telling them now to go back to their homes, to lay down their arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nehru looks at him hopelessly.</context>
      <utterance>That the fighting will stop -- that you make me believe it will never start again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>GOONDA LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi is looking at him, testing, not giving or accepting anything that is mere gesture.</context>
      <utterance>It is our promise. We stop. It is a promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Goondas stand. They glance at Suhrawardy; he smiles tautly and they start to leave, but one (Nahari) lingers. Suddenly he moves violently toward Gandhi, taking a flat piece of Indian bread (chapati) from his trousers and tossing it forcefully on Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>Go -- try -- God by with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAHARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mirabehn and Azad start to move toward him -- the man looks immensely strong and immensely unstable. But Gandhi holds up a shaking hand, stopping them. Nahari's face is knotted in emotion, half anger, half almost a child's fear -- but there is a wild menace in that instability.</context>
      <utterance>Eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAHARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eat! I am going to hell -- but not with your death on my soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only God decides who goes to hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>NAHARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi stares at him, breathless.</context>
      <utterance>I -- I killed a child...  I smashed his head against a wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is as though the man has told him of some terrible self- inflicted wound.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAHARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Almost reflexively he holds his hand out to indicate the height of his son. He glares at Suhrawardy and then back at Gandhi.</context>
      <utterance>They killed my son -- my boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>NAHARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is sobbing, but in his anger it seems almost as though he means to kill Gandhi in retaliation. A long moment, as Gandhi meets his pain and wrath. Then</context>
      <utterance>The Muslims killed my son... they killed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nahari sneers, but there is just a flicker of desperate curiosity.</context>
      <utterance>I know a way out of hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his hand to the height Nahari has indicated as his son's.</context>
      <utterance>Find a child -- a child whose mother and father have been killed. A little boy -- about this high.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nahari has listened. His face almost cracks -- it is a chink of light, but it does not illumine his darkness.</context>
      <utterance>...and raise him -- as your own.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now the light falls on Nahari. His face stiffens, he swallows, fighting any show of emotion; then he turns to go. But he takes only a step and he turns back, going to his knees, the sobs breaking again and again from his heaving body as he holds his head to Gandhi's feet in the traditional greeting of Hindu son to Hindu father. A second, and Gandhi reaches out and touches the top of his head. Mirabehn watches. The Goondas watch. Suhrawardy watches. Finally</context>
      <utterance>Only be sure... that he is a Muslim. And that you raise him as one.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go -- go. God bless you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't have believed it, Mr. Gupta.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, it's a bloody miracle...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the police commissioner, Suhrawardy, two doctors, Abdul Ghaffar Khan, and some others. Nearer Gandhi, behind Mirabehn, are Nehru, Patel, Azad and Pyarelal. Gandhi turns to Mirabehn, his face shaking, peering into her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Bapu, there's been no fighting -- anywhere. It has stopped -- the madness has stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is foolish if it is just to save the life of an old man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His weary eyes look at her; he looks up slowly to Azad. Azad nods "It's true." Then Patel</context>
      <utterance>No... no. In every temple and mosque they have pledged to die before they lift a hand against each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi looks at Nehru. Nehru just nods tautly. Gandhi looks down, then lifts his head to Azad.</context>
      <utterance>Everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The relief brings water to their eyes and grins to their faces. Nehru bends to Gandhi. Gandhi holds his hand out to him, and Nehru clutches it. Then</context>
      <utterance>Maulana, my friend, could I have some orange juice... Then you and I will take a piece of bread together...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEHRU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a joke in their way with each other and Gandhi's eyes light, his smile comes. But it is tired. He puts his other hand over Nehru's and Nehru lowers his head to it, crying silently.</context>
      <utterance>You see, Bapu, it is not difficult. I have fasted only a few hours and I accomplished what you could not do in as many days.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manu hands him a cloth and he wipes his hands. Another click of a camera. He is not fully recovered, but well on the way.</context>
      <utterance>That is how you eat muli.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she shoots him again, as he hands the cloth back to Manu. Abha is sitting next to Manu, looking at a collection of pictures of Gandhi, obviously Bourke-White's.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, with luck you may not be.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is wry, but waspishly chiding. Abha suddenly holds a picture up for Gandhi to see. It's one of him, ears wide, eyes round.</context>
      <utterance>No, he'll be remembered for tempting fate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gandhi taps her on the head with his finger as she smiles. But Bourke-White has looked from Patel to Gandhi, clearly shaken by the implication in Patel's words.</context>
      <utterance>Mickey Mouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really are going to Pakistan, then?  You are a stubborn man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abha has signaled to the cheap watch dangling from his dhoti. He glances at it, and holds his arms out. The two girls help him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm simply going to prove to Muslims there, and Hindus here, that the only devils in the world are those running around in our own hearts -- and that's where all our battles ought to be fought.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is photographing his getting-up and leaning on the two girls.</context>
      <utterance>And what kind of a warrior have you been in that warfare?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves off, but has a sudden thought and turns to Patel.</context>
      <utterance>Not a very good one. That's why I have so much tolerance for the other scoundrels of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patel nods soberly and Gandhi starts for the door, Bourke- White moving with him.</context>
      <utterance>Ask Panditji to -- to consider what we've discussed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has passed her, he's in the doorway. We see the crowd at the end of the garden, where the light of the day is beginning to soften. He turns, teasing in his slightly flirtatious way with women.</context>
      <utterance>One more.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shoots him against the door -- the crowd milling distantly, waiting -- then she lowers her camera.</context>
      <utterance>You're a temptress.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just an admirer...</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns; the last words have betrayed the smile on his face; they have a painful sense of truth about them. Bourke-White watches as he moves into the garden toward the crowd in the distance. She turns to Mirabehn.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing's more dangerous, especially for an old man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's an observation -- and a question. Mirabehn accedes gravely.</context>
      <utterance>There's a sadness in him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bourke-White stares at her, then turns to look out at him.</context>
      <utterance>He thinks he's failed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOURKE-WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mirabehn nods, but she keeps on spinning and tries to sound cynically resigned but her innate emotionalism keeps breaking through in her voice and on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Why? My God, if anything's proved him right, it's what's happened these last months...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRABEHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is laced with pain. Bourke-White turns and looks out at Gandhi -- so tiny, so weak as he walks between his "props." He has now reached the end of the garden and is moving among the crowd assembled there.</context>
      <utterance>I am blinded by my love of him, but I think when we most needed it, he offered the world a way out of madness. But he doesn't see it... and neither does the world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiling, he turns back. A jostling, the sound of beads falling.</context>
      <utterance>Allah be with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANDHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manu and Abha bend over him, silent in their first shock. The sound of panic and alarm begins to grow around them, they suddenly scream and begin to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God... oh, God...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANU/ABHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bapu! Bapu!</utterance>
   <speaker>FUNERAL PYRE - EXTERIOR - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment -- we sense the blackness moving -- like dark smoke. The camera is pulling back very slowly and we can tell the blackness is smoke rising from a fire. And now we see that it is a funeral pyre. And all around that pyre a mass of silent humanity. Through the smoke, sitting cross-legged near the rim of the flames, we see Nehru... and Azad and Patel, Mirabehn and Kallenbach, the drawn faces of Lord and Lady Mountbatten, Manu and Abha...</context>
      <utterance>Blackness. Silence.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
