<movie id="235" title="Ginger Snaps">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Around them, many candles burn. There's a dead bolt on the door. An attached full bath. The floors are thick with paranormal books. The walls are covered in images of UFO's and horror flicks. A framed photo of Kurt Cobain with Courtney Love has a place of honor. There's an old Polaroid of the girls at five in Halloween costumes; Lill Red Riding Hood and the Big Bad Wolf. Ginger is the wolf. Brigitte produces an enormous darning needle. It glints. she levels it at Ginger's navel, her hand shaking.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger's ten months older than me. we're seriously tight. Share everything. Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger gives Brigitte a look over the top of her comic. Brigitte takes a deep breath, and lines the needle up again. Brigitte swallows hard and applies pressure. The needle pierces Ginger's skin. Her stomach muscles flinch.</context>
      <utterance>.I can't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said it wouldn't hurt!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The needle has stopped moving half-way through the skin.</context>
      <utterance>Jus' hurry up!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte wiggles the needle. Blood wells up around it.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh .</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger lowers her comic. she takes one look at the needle half-.in, half-out of her belly button - and cracks up.</context>
      <utterance>Um. I think it's stuck. Oh man. There's blood...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughing her head off, Ginger gives the needle a good tug from her end. The skin tugs with it, resisting.</context>
      <utterance>snot funny, Ginger!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger yanks the needle, hard. This time it moves.</context>
      <utterance>Ali, gawd, gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger grits her teeth. The needle begins a slow progress.</context>
      <utterance>I got it, I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte grabs at a tiny silver ring on the bed spread but knocks it to the floor. Brigitte scrambles after it. Ginger yanks the needle.</context>
      <utterance>It's goin', it's goin'- gimme the ring</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte finds the ring and hands it to Ginger. Ginger sets the ring on the end of the needle, looping it not-so-neatly through.</context>
      <utterance>Bee?! C'mon!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bloody needle pops clear. Ginger grinds on the ring to close it. Ginger wipes her bloody hands on the bed. Brigitte is taking deep, gulping breaths.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, groo-oo-o-ss!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bee? Feeb. Y'okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode>TEASING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I think not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger beams at her new piercing.</context>
      <utterance>If you din't say it hurt, I'd a been fine!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flesh around the navel is hot pink and bruising. Brigitte grins too.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty cool, unh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>very cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte bravely hangs onto to her smile.</context>
      <utterance>Now I'll do you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>[3A! You got no idea.</context>
      <utterance>We do everything together. But, at fifteen? A chick can change. Ya know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Brigitte takes a long, ponderous drag on her cigarette as - unmoved - she takes in Ginger's mortal wound. Brigitte eyes the identical homes and gardens that stretch on to the horizon.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get me wrong. It's not like we were all happy or nothin' to begin with.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Brigitte flicks her smoke into a pile of neatly raked leaves. It smolders then goes out. She scowls.</context>
      <utterance>The suburb of Bailey Downs? Basically a well lit black hole. The Kingdom of cul du sac. That's French for Dead End.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>A truck with COUNTY REGREENING PROGRAM on its side pulls up a few houses over. Brigitte watches a shirtless sun-bronzed Adonis - SAM -- climb out of the cab.</context>
      <utterance>You had a gram of personality out here? Life bit the big one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>A tarty teenage girl - TRINA - bounds up to Sam and gives him a big wet one.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I'm generalizing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/0</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte raises a 35mm still camera to her eye and frames her sister's corpse in the viewfinder.</context>
      <utterance>The fuck, Bee. Take a picture already.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were always considered freaks. For as long as I can remember, there was Us. And there was Them. Like from kindergarten.</utterance>
   <speaker>ART TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The students trade constipated looks.</context>
      <utterance>Very -um. Class? Comments?</utterance>
   <speaker>ART TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte shrugs and squirms.</context>
      <utterance>Brigitte. What does it mean for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Fitzgeralds look expectantly at row after row of blank faces. Brigitte shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Means there's more to life than -- well, li.fe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>JASON McCARDY- a good-looking high school Casanova - looks Ginger over appraisingly. Ginger ignores him.</context>
      <utterance>Attempts at communication wore futile.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Brigitte glances from Ginger's breasts to her own flat chest. Brigitte takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>Some of Them did seem to wanna reach Ginger?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>The bell goes.</context>
      <utterance>But nobody wanned to reach me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I cared.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gawd, People! They hurt my brain!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They didn't even get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're retards.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're cretins.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're bone-heads.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'t'hey' re somnambulists.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're leems.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls stop before their locker. A folded up piece of loose leaf has been crushed into it, its end sticking out.</context>
      <utterance>They're the goddamn walkin'-/</utterance>
   <speaker>BR I G ITTE</speaker>
      <mode>UNIMPRESSED</mode>
      <context>Ginger opens the locker. She unfolds the paper. There's a big fat joint inside, and a note that says: GINGER, CALL 555-</context>
      <utterance>Another one?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>8</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger offers her a sucker and has one herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FAT JANITOR scoops up the wad of loose leaf with great resentment and jams it into the trash. Brigitte and Ginger pass a NECKING COUPLE practically dry- humping, GIRLS applying make-up to one another, and BOYS snapping each other with their sports cups. Jason and his fellow jock-pals TIM, FRANK, and JEREMY are scoping babes. Ginger bends to tie her boot lace and a collective groan swells from the guys.</context>
      <utterance>No pe .</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? She's weird, but hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte gives them a disgusted look.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody poled Fitzy yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte's face falls. Ginger gives them a Death Stare. The boys try flirty smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Not that one. The cute one.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte laughs. Ginger pulls her on, past a sign: GYMNASIUM.</context>
      <utterance>Sad. Must be hard to think with yer brains slappin' around yer thighs like that all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Ginger applies her boot to a swinging door and they enter,</context>
      <utterance>We didn't do guys. Guys were too gross. Everyone at Bailey High was just too incredibly gross.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Ginger digs at her lower abdomen painfully.</context>
      <utterance>The only thing worse than most teenage boys are most teenage girls. Trinas are the limit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gingler opens a locker and tears off her clothes. Other girls glance at her navel piercing with disgust.. Brigitte is very self-conscious: she steps almost inside the locker, hiding behind the door while she changes into the revolting school gym outfit. She eyes the buxom bubble heads with contempt, as</context>
      <utterance>No, J. mean really.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRI.GITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Trina finds the Fitzgeralds' open locker door a nuisance. She pushes it out of her way, hard enough to whack Brigitte in the head on the other side.</context>
      <utterance>There was really only one Trina, but they were all the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINA</speaker>
      <mode>FAKELY</mode>
      <context>Ginger gives Trina a very dirty look. Brigitte tries to rub her sore head while clutching her uniform to cover her chest. Trina and her posse cackle as they prance out, their butt cheeks waggling. The sisters continue changing.</context>
      <utterance>Ooops. Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y' okay's</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger grips her sides painfully and bends double.</context>
      <utterance>I HATE her. Like to feed her ground glass with tacks for desert. Then make her puke it back up and swallow it again until she's like shredded to a bazillion pieces from the inside out...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>what's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They slap hands, laughing. They look down at their gym outfits, which are SO unflattering. Brigitte and Ginger exchange identical looks of agony.</context>
      <utterance>I got gas...Maybe I'll try an, cut one right in her face out there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>The gym teacher. M7.,. SYKES - an aging former-traffic cop - hucks the players sticks with nets on one end. Sykes is given to screaming.</context>
      <utterance>After two weeks a' high school., ya come to the conclusion it's all about agony. Take Phys. Ed, sus' practise takin' pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Trinas giggle at Sykes. Ginger bends forward, holding her sides.</context>
      <utterance>Field lacrosse is no pussy-assed tea party, ya get IN there, get a LOCK on your target and PUSH IT! I want SWEAT I want ACTION!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MZ.SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shake a leg, Fitzgeralds. An, butt out, you gotta death wish!?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel really sick, Mz. Sykes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MZ. SYRES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger flicks the smoke at Sykes' turned back. It falls short, of course. The sisters trudge to their places on the field. Ginger is on the offensive line. Brigitte is in goal.</context>
      <utterance>Cigarettes'll do that for you! Move!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Sykes blows the whistle. A fast-moving, hard-hitting lacrosse scrimmage begins. IN RAPID-FIRE MONTAGE: Ginger gets caught in the crunch of sticks and bodies, pushed, kicked, and punished by the Trinas, who are having 'fun'. IN RAPID-FIRE MONTAGE: Brigitte visibly cowers as a tangle of marauding, ball-whacking bodies descend on her. She takes a number of direct hits from the hard rubber ball. on a powerful press for a goal, Trina slams into Brigitte so hard Brigitte flies right out of the net area. And skids face-first .into a mangled dog's body. The whistle blows and play stops. Ginger lopes over, breathless, gripping her sore stomach.</context>
      <utterance>Phys. Ed. is not optional at Bailey High.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Brigitte slowly climbs out of the mucky canine remains to her knees. She's covered in doggie guts and maggots.</context>
      <utterance>I been waiting for this. There'd been a lot of dead dogs around lately, but this was my personal first.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, HOW GRO-O-O-O-OSS!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Kay, here's the weird thing about me. I dig dead stuff. Live things make me sick, they're all warm and snotty and shitty and pissy. And live things jus' suffer, which I can't take. But a dead thing? S'kinda beautiful, 'cause a dead thing's really I dunno -like, free.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get up and hit the SHOWERS!</context>
      <utterance>Don't TOUCH it, Fitzgerald! What's WRONG with you two?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINAS IN CHORUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>/Gawd stop, you'll make me PUKE!</context>
      <utterance>The cult? Drains the blood out and drinks it, ya know! /1 heard they have sex with them first !</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/0</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone was all like, Oh it's a teen cult, or aah, it's some looney, the Beast a' Bailey Downs. What crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All RIGHT, ladies, settle! This is no joke! You have information about the dog deaths you do</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLASS IN CHORUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell a teacher, Principal Fardor, or the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte looks up in time to see Ginger's eyes roll back in her head. Ginger faints. The class inhales as one.</context>
      <utterance>Teen cult my ass. Look Ginge', something went for its throat - it's not cut, it's chewed...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sykes and the class stampede up. Sykes pushes Brigitte out of the way.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/0</mode>
      <context>Brigitte stumbles over the dog carcass. She hugs herself.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger's no pussy. She doesn't faint. I might faint. Like, if this pooch were only HALF-dead, I could faint.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fainting' s worrisome you don't diet do you dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte looks relieved.</context>
      <utterance>Hm. Anemia's very common at your age. Eat more red meat, try an iron vitamin supplement. If it happens again, straight to a proper doctor, all righty?</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now as for 'the headache, cramps, lower back pain .I'm guessing your period is due.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't got a, um, period.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never? Flow old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen. our mother says we're late bloomers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte pulls a face. Ferry produces numerous samples of feminine hygiene products and heaps them onto Ginger.</context>
      <utterance>Well judging by your troubles, I'd say you can expect to blossom any time now!</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Are you familiar with all these?</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nurse Ferry produces a pocket calendar with a tampon or pad advertisement for every month.</context>
      <utterance>Now what suits one girl might not be comfortable for another. The proper form of protection is a personal choice, and may have a lot to do with your menstrual flow, which naturally changes during the time you'll have your little miracle of nature. It could start thick and syrupy, move to a straight-forward basic bright red bleeding and then perhaps a deep brownish to blackish slime, signaling the end of the flow. Twenty-eight days later or there abouts, it'll start all over again and continue every month until menopause, in about thirty years' time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRY</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context>Brigitte Looks horrified.</context>
      <utterance>Here's a little calendar to keep track, count from the day it starts twenty-eight days. That'll be your next time. You have any questions, come see me again.  You too sweetheart, be your turn shortly, I expect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Ginger and Brigitte trudge homeward looking completely depressed. Brigitte flips through the feminine hygiene calendar. Ginger watches the pavement beneath her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Here's a dirty word. Inevitability. That fate fully intended us to be typical in any way, sooner or later, was so insulting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What does that mean?</context>
      <utterance>"Some days it's all you need."-?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you pulled a Quincy on that dog, unh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger grabs the calendar and sticks it in her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Hunh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quincy, that guy with the stiffs on cable. Alls I remember is you goin', "Teen cult my ass".</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte shrugs. She gives Ginger a funny look.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Right. Well, I dunno.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you looking at me like that? Do I look - different?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you tell I'm going to-?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger squints at her, unconvinced.</context>
      <utterance>No. .Really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exchange grins.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. If I start simpin' around tampon dispensers and moanin' over cramps, or even think about buying somethin' that says Baby Powder Fresh? You'll. shoot me, right? BR TG.'i"I'L of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out by sixteen</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger raises her hand and Brigitte smacks it hard. As they mount the drive, Ginger picks up a stone and hucks it at Norman, who's still barking. She misses.</context>
      <utterance>.or dead in this scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we failed to get a life by Ginger's sixteenth birthday? we were s'posed to gas ourselves in the garage. For smart girls, we could be pretty dumb. we prob'ly never woulda done it, but we seemed to need a deadline.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was school today?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/U</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The nicest thing I could say about Henry and Pamela was also the meanest thing I could say.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How'd it go?</context>
      <utterance>Didn't you have a presentation?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pamela and Henry exchange irritatingly patient smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>A rogue's gallery on the wall depicts Henry and Pamela's transformation over the years from angry young Ban The Bomb- types into middle-class mundane.</context>
      <utterance>They were easily satisfied.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry studies his plate. Ginger almost imperceptibly shakes her head at Brigitte. Brigitte nods, understanding.</context>
      <utterance>Made an appointment for you girls at my gynecologist. Next Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>why.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>we're not going to a gynecologist.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I say about that tone of voice? .You are going to the gynecologist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!? She's completely paranoid!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd rather stay out of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's gonna have some fat jerk get his jollies poking his fingers up our ./</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>INTERRUPTING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm actually eating here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, neither one of them has had a period yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Pamela says the next line, Ginger mou t:hs it- word for word 1.a Brigitte.</context>
      <utterance>Ah. Yes. You've said. Repeatedly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briggitte apes Henry's next line back to Ginger.</context>
      <utterance>It's very odd that two perfectly healthy fifteen year olds are not menstruating. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sisters giggle. Pamela is losing her cool.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm. steak's really yummy tonight. This a new sauce?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I started at eleven. The problem must be on your side, Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pamela? This is not my fault. No one's at fault here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>when did your sister start?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've told you, I really have no idea. Oddly enough, we never discussed it. why don't you call her and ask her yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They'll be eating.</context>
      <utterance>I can't call her out of the blue and ask a thing like that. Besides, it's dinner time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A--ha!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I've been checking panties for four years now</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER &amp; BRIGITTE/HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mo-othe-er!!! /For chrissakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look at our underwear? Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From under the table, Henry produces the bloodied, sawed-off picket stained bloody from Ginger's impaling. Brigitte holds her full mouth open so Ginger can see its masticated contents. Ginger cracks up laughing. Henry and Pamela sigh.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey - I don't want to hear that word in my house. You will do as your mother says and I will change the subject. Anybody going to tell me what happened to my fence?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why din't you jus' tell her you're going to get it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte puts a fresh tampon up her nose and lifts a Polaroid camera at arms' length from her face.</context>
      <utterance>Can't take her 'attention'. She grosses me out. Can't believe she's our mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH! The Polaroid spits out the front. Brigitte sticks another tampon in her free nostril, and one in each ear as,</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but now we have to see this doctor. You can jus' say you got it, but I'm screwed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I get you out of Home Ec? Did I get you out of ballet classes? So I'll get you out of this, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH! Brigitte takes a Polaroid of herself with a tampon sticking out of every visible orifice. Ginger slides the grass into a pre-rolled fresh casing and sticks it in her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>You better, gawd the idea</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger cranks the stereo and throws on a coat. She double- takes Brigitte' s tampon face.</context>
      <utterance>I said I will, I will. This jay's fine. Let us smoke, sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WHAT are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look - a walrus.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hardee-har. Har.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'l1 you know when you finally get it any ways?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prob'ly feel like peein' your pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm not too excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're missing Unsolved Mysteries.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte reflects on this heavy thought, nodding - stoned.</context>
      <utterance>Wish I was an unsolved mystery.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. You smell somethin' gross?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte helps her to her feet. Ginger shakes what she slipped on off her shoe. It's a long, ropy intestine. She drags her shoe to get the blood and goo of it.</context>
      <utterance>This is so not my day.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice. Dog shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A line of blood and gore trails across the grass to a back lane. Brigitte follows it. Ginger looks around for something on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>That isn't shit... it's death.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Lost the jay. Great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte takes its picture FLASH! with the Polaroid, which is strung around her neck.</context>
      <utterance>Ack, it's still warm, gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why every dog but the mutt next door to us?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, we could take it home. Try like, an autopsy. Like, crack the case!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah. Let's put ' im in there so he won't. Lraumatize the kiddies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We never do what I wanna do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hoist the dog up and dump it in the dumpster. It's hind end sticks out. Brigitte climbs into the dumpster, dragging it all the way in. Dusting herself off, Ginger notices some blood on her thigh.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, c' mon. Would stink up the whole room!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger wipes at the blood with her hand. More appears. She lifts up the hem of her skirt. Her face falls. She looks around. She slips her fingers up to her crotch. Her hand comes out bloody.</context>
      <utterance>Nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bee. I JUST got the curse. Brigitte stops rooting garbage over the dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger wiggles her wet fingers at her.</context>
      <utterance>Serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte catches her kilt on a nail sticking out of a plank in the trash. Something is crunching through the leaves toward them. Ginger peers out into the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Eeew, 'kay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry upt</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few homes down, a garage's motion-sensitive security lamp trips on. Ginger squints, blinded.</context>
      <utterance>I'm stuck3</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte contorts to deal with the nail. Brigitte tears her hem free and jumps down. The light snaps off.</context>
      <utterance>Bee?:</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte dips a hand back into the dumpster for the plank with the nail. Off Ginger's look, Brigitte shrugs. They start walking down the lane. The greenery behind them starts swelling again. The leaves crunch, faster. Brigitte and Ginger look at one another, and walk faster. The lane empties behind a deserted strip mall.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go this way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger is pissed off now. she turns to confront their stalker.</context>
      <utterance>This is stupid. We're getting farther from home.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's cut cold by a roaring blur of speeding fur and teeth and claws: SOMETHING takes Ginger down hard. We cannot see it as a whole, we can't make out what it is. It's big, heavy, and raging. Immense jaws snap vicious teeth, going for Ginger's jugular. Brigitte drops her plank.</context>
      <utterance>All right you ass-/</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger looks at herself. Ginger starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger, shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fuck was that, Bee?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carefully, Brigitte begins to dab at Ginger's arms with it, wiping off the blood. Ginger flinches. The damage is gradually revealed: massive claw marks, deep scratches, and puncture wounds - BITE MARKS. Brigitte's eyes fill with tears.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger, sshhh, don't, 'kay. Don't cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, this is really bad. You need a doctor, Ginge', I can't stop all the -/</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Not tellin' anybody! Bee?! Nobody. Get in shit for bein' out, smokin' up - don't tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if you get, sick? What if these bites get infected?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bce!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte starts tearing off strips of gauze and taping it on thick. Oblivious, Ginger fumbles for a smoke. She can't get the lighter to work.</context>
      <utterance>Fine! I won't tell!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanted to kill me! I could tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know. I was so scared, I thought you were -/</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte lights her smoke for her. Ginger takes a drag and passes it back to Brigitte.</context>
      <utterance>Me too. Don't say it. I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte resumes her first aid.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck. You okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why!?? Why me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was crazy, it was like rabid or somethin' -- Shit, look at the size of these bites!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte doesn't look convinced. Brigitte snaps the port of an internal vacuum system open and reaches into the tube. She withdraws a sample-size of Jack Daniels.</context>
      <utterance>I'm okay, I'm okay, I'm okay. Right? It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger glugs some down, and passes the last mouthful left to Brigit.t.e. Brigitte waves it. away, -,o Ginger finishes it al.l.</context>
      <utterance>Drink this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen this thing, on bears? Said bears'd come after like, chicks on the rag. 'Cause of the smell.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't my fault!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say that.../</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't a f uckin' bear either. Whatever it was, it wasn't a bear!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I'm not /</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I stink? Can you smell it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A heavy silence falls between them. Brigitte keeps working.</context>
      <utterance>No! Geez, I was jus', whatever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't feel anythin' like peeing your pants, by the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gross though. It's really gross. I better, ya know, deal with that...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger's only half-bandaged up. she staggers to the bathroom and shuts the door. Brigitte eyes the Polaroid camera: a picture sits ready to be dispensed. She pulls it free. We do not see the photo. Brigitte's eyes bug out as she examines it. The toilet flushes in the bathroom and Brigitte pushes the photo under the pillow on her bed. Shaking her head.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/0</mode>
      <context>Ginger emerges pulling uncomfortably at her crotch. she climbs painfully onto her bed, and collapses.</context>
      <utterance>It was blurry. It was really outta focus, so. Ya couldn't TELL it was really anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That booze - straight to my head, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger-es eyes are already fluttering shut.</context>
      <utterance>You really okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte leans in, listening to Ginger breathe.</context>
      <utterance>You saved me. Love you. Bee.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too, Ginge'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Brigitte peers at Ginger: she's snoring. Brigitte pulls out the Polaroid and fires up her lighter to see by. This time we see it too. A streak of fur, fangs and a golden glinting eye.</context>
      <utterance>I woke up later, I thought the thing was in our room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T-V/0</mode>
      <context>Wasn't.</context>
      <utterance>Then I remembered Sam the tree planter killed it with his truck, an' we were okay. .But really, Ginger -? well.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger shakes her head as she picks at her bandages. Brigitte helps herself.</context>
      <utterance>Gonna eat that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm! Sad, but Pamela's egg salad is her best thing. Like that she can do.  Like, when she puts the baby onions in?  And she gobs on it and adds those hard little pieces of</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger pulls at her own crotch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell-o 1?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Pads suck, so ya know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should eat something.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Brigitte's insulted look,</context>
      <utterance>Thanks Pamela, I'm aware.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte stops in mid-chew.</context>
      <utterance>T dunno, I'm all blaaahh, I got this, like I can taste what I want, but nothin's it. Ya know?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A craving?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte chews very slowly as she stares at Ginger. Ginger squints at Jason and his pals across the yard.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I crave. Ya know?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McCardy's a stoner right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah -?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, I wanna feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger heads off toward the boys - without waiting. Brigitte is in mid-,mouthful, and has to scramble to catch up.</context>
      <utterance>You joke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh - hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. So. Nice day, blah blah blah. Got any smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smoke. Grass, weed, dope, green, bud, Nancy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sh-sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna share?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I thought your slide show in art was cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER GUYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah/Unh-huh/Very cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This home-grown?</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. This guy we know? Learned hydrophonics in the pen, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>HydroPONics.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte gapes at Ginger, who does not respond. Brigitte hides beneath her hair and presses even further into a corner. She starts quietly ripping up the corner of the old shag rug. There is a codified knock on the vain door. Brigitte jumps.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The back doors open and Sam (the tree planter) stands in silhouette, backlit by the day. His battered county truck waits behind him. He has a pit bull with him - MORELY.</context>
      <utterance>speak of the devil. Enter!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam and Morely hop in and close the doors. Brigitte is frozen at the sight of Sam up so close.</context>
      <utterance>Sam the Man! Hey Morely!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa dude. What happened to your truck?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morely stomps into Brigitte's lap, sniffing her crotch.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. Had an accident on the 403. It was weird it../</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte's mouth is hanging open. Morely slobbers all over her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry about him, he's an ass hole. Morely! My girlfriend's, she won't leave him at home alone any more. Ya know, dog killers. Morely, no! Sit!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Ginger's perma-smug smile fades as she makes eye contact with Morely. Morel growls at her. Sam is about to resume his accident story when,</context>
      <utterance>I know, I look like an asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam produces several baggies of grass. Morely's hackles rise. Brigitte looks from the dog to Ginger, Ginger squirms.</context>
      <utterance>Watcha got for us?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger sneers at Morely and Morely bares his teeth.</context>
      <utterance>New harvest, see whatcha think.  What's your problem? Never seen a pretty girl before?</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON/TIM/FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morely bursts out barking and charges at Ginger. Mayhem as the guys try to contain the dog in the small space. Jason uses the opportunity to shield Ginger for a free body press. Brigitte gets banged and shoved. Ginger kicks and screams at the dog, her boot connects squarely with his snout. Morely keels back, and Sam snaps him up.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, he's not really like this. I'm really sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jus' get'im out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And in another flash of daylight, Sam and Morely are gone. Brigitte looks longingly at the closed door. The stone has set in, and everyone but Brigitte giggles as they settle. Brigitte takes in the Lesser Mortals like they're lepers.</context>
      <utterance>I'm really - well, see you guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They give one another this corny smile. Brigitte bugs her eyes at Ginger. Ginger rises reluctantly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Just hate dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. Thanks for the smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger places a finger to her lips, then makes a finger gun and shoots him.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we could --/</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger grins ear-to-ear, elbowing Brigitte. Ginger kicks the van doors open and saunters out. Brigitte :Follows, trying not to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I'll letcha know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context>Brigitte doesn't hear her over the roar of the tap in her face. It shuts off automatically over her gaping mouth. Brigitte puts her finger up the spout and almost gets it stuck.</context>
      <utterance>Bee-?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bee!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>STARTLED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte shuffles to the wrong door, opens it and finds it empty. She giggles and moves to the next one.</context>
      <utterance>Com'ere-!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte finds Ginger with her shirt and all, the bandages peeled off. she is dabbing at herself with wads of toilet paper. The scratches and bites are oozing a clear gelatinous goo, under which a fine film of dark hairs have sprouted. Brigitte steps into the stall agape. The door hits her on the way in.</context>
      <utterance>That smoke fucked me _up._ up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez that's not right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1 didn't think.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the sticky stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh. Tickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it on my tits too, look.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weird. Does it hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's itchy. I can't have a hairy chest Bee, that's fucked.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, like forget that tattoo you wanned.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This sucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The idiocy of the looks of awe on the other's face makes them both crack up.</context>
      <utterance>Quito badly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BR I G ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(she counts on her</context>
      <utterance>I know, but okay. what I think?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGERS)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Attacked. On a full moon. Now, yer hairy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode>SNORTING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not Harry, I'm Ginger.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger stops laughing long enough to let the suggestion settle.</context>
      <utterance>Stop, I'm serious. Think about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trina backs away, her hands to her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Eeeew!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gawd: They're lesbos!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte smacks her forehead. Ginger steps out and leers at Trina, licking her lips in a grotesque mock-lust. The Trinas shrink back against the farthest wall.</context>
      <utterance>Feeeewww!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte's jaw drops. Ginger turns to leave and the Trinas, start to relax. Ginger whips around again:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, who's next? I'm still sticky!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rrr-uf, ruf, rr-of-rufrf</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context>Trina stares Brigitte down as she folds up a note and passes it to a classmate. It is read and passed on by every kid in the room during this scene. Brigitte holds her scalpel over the over their piggy - hesitating. Ginger's attention is riveted on the little carcass.</context>
      <utterance>'Course Trina din't waste any time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're all looking at us.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger looks up at Jason, who is reading the note. Jason smiles at Ginger and destroys the note. Trina seethes. Ginger grabs the knife from Brigitte. she makes a deep incision in the pig's belly.</context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger spies two girls giggling at her. Using both hands Ginger cracks the carcass. wide open like a clam. Ginger digs in, gouging out the pig's parts with her bare hands. Ginger breaks into a sweat, her breathing gets heavy. Brigitte cautiously looks around at their classmates. she moves to shield Ginger from prying eyes.</context>
      <utterance>So! You're growing fur an, acting like a nut, is so!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um. Ginger-?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger has begun scraping away at the pig's cranium with her finger nails. A sickening creak, snap, and the brain is exposed. Ginger - unconsciously - licks her fingers as she admires its frontal lobe.</context>
      <utterance>hold on, I'm goi.n' for the brain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>40</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brigitte fights a ralph.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't believe you did that!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Brigitte can answer, Ginger lifts the brain out on her finger tips, gently pushes Brigitte out of her way and... Whap! The brain lands squarely on Trina's head. Trina screams.</context>
      <utterance>Hunh? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha-ha! Bull's eye!</utterance>
   <speaker>BIO TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger Fitzgerald! Hall, NOW!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ginger stomps out with the teacher. Brigitte and Trina gape at one another.</context>
      <utterance>What, it slipped!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GYNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte pokes Ginger in the ribs. Ginger doesn't like this, and pushes Brigitte so hard she almost falls off her chair.</context>
      <utterance>I've never seen anything like it. She's not built like a normal girl. I've sent samples to the lab. But this is very, VERY unusual.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girls, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT GIRLS' BEDROOM - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger is in a tank shirt which reveals her hair growth is spreading. Brigitte is sitting at. the desk with a pile of monster books.</context>
      <utterance>The window is open. Norman the terrier yams.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you, nuts? I got a skin thing, whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you just gotta skin thing why does it get worse everytime yer being a bitch? Why's the gyno say you're a monster inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He din't say that!</utterance>
   <speaker>BR I G ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just listen to these symptoms!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm takin' a shower.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/0 - CON'T</mode>
      <context>Ginger shaves the delicate area around her ankles. She cuts herself and freaks. Ginger snaps the Lady Bic in half and throws the pieces hard against the shower wall.</context>
      <utterance>".. .for eventually the blood- lust over-takes human reason, overtakes oven the instinct for self-preservation, and he will risk all for the excitement of the euphoric high of his murders."</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are two other broken razors in the stall, stuffed with hairs. Blood mixes with the water and swirls around her toes.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck fuck fuck FUCK</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now livid, Ginger takes up a dead tree branch. Up in the tree, Brigitte hides her face in her hands. Ginger (:racks the stick over the dog's head. The yelping stops but Ginger keeps hitting. Blood splatters over her face. And Ginger tastes it. Ginger drops her stick. She drags the body into the hedge next to the fence. Brigitte lowers her hands from her eyes. Ginger is directly below her, concealed from the house by the shrubs. Ginger falls to her knees before the corpse. She lifts a rattling hand to touch him. She lowers her face to the bloody mess. She's sweating, vibrating, physically resisting an irresistible drive. Ginger's tongue slips between her lips. And Ginger licks Morely's body.</context>
      <utterance>Sonnovabitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger begins to eat the dead dog. The feed. quickly becomes a ravenous frenzy. Above her, Brigitte leans over the branch she's barely balancing on, hyperventilating. Vomit sails down from Brigitte's perch.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. No. G-ginger -!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte scrambles down the tree and yanks Ginger off the dog. Ginger's face is smeared in blood. Ginger's stunned, and reels dizzily. They crouch, waiting. Their NEIGHBOR opens the screen door, shaking a box of dog biscuits.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The neighbor steps into the yard. Approaches the hedge. Stops right before them - they can see a pair of slippers twitching in the grass. Then they disappear, the porch light switches off, the screen door shuts.</context>
      <utterance>Dore-maan! Tweat-time! Hunh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode>O/S - SINGING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ho-ow much is that daw-gy in the window... Arf-Arf!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>There is a knock at the door. Brigitte checks the dead bolt is on.</context>
      <utterance>Ever been too sick to be sick? Like the bottom of your stomach is wrapped over the top of your head?</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's showering so late?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte throws up her hands: what an idiotic conversation.</context>
      <utterance>she's dirty?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode>01S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dirty!? How'd she get/</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm tryin' to study, here!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode>01S</mode>
      <context>Brigitte slumps against the door. The showers stops. Ginger appears in a towel, pink and clean and freshly furry in places. She's in a really good mood. She takes one look at Brigitte's face of doom and tries to be serious.</context>
      <utterance>oh, all right then.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger finds and lights a smoke.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't help it. Really. Guess you were right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what's really weird?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weirder than KILLING A DOG AND</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte shakes her head over and over.</context>
      <utterance>I liked it. I liked it a lot. I feel all fucki.n' goofy now. Like, I dunno. Like .happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger leaps to the stereo and blasts on some tunes. She flails around the room wildly. Ginger grabs Brigitte by the arms and makes her dance too. Ginger spins and spins Brigitte, who fights it but laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I feel like I just got off the Planet Smasher ride at WarWorid, okay? It rules!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>There is repeated pounding on their door. Brigitte still entangled in Ginger, hits the music off.</context>
      <utterance>So she'd killed Norman. 1 never seen anyone bliss out like that. I wanted to be so blissed, jus' once.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little late for that, girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER/BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand in each other's arms listening to Pamela mount the stairs OFF SCREEN. Ginger shoves Brigitte backward onto her bed. Ginger piles on top of her, playfully pinning her down.</context>
      <utterance>/Sorry;</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte squirms fitfully.</context>
      <utterance>I want more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's too gross! You'll get caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte looks into her sister's beaming face.</context>
      <utterance>Not if you help. Bee. I'm starving.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte groans.</context>
      <utterance>Jus' keep watch. Look, I'm gonna be somethin' totally else. Tell me you don't so dig it. Tell me you don't wanna see what happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Trust me.</context>
      <utterance>Straight up? Crazy's contagious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte examines the feminine hygiene calendar. In it, a cartoon of a female egg is personified with a heels and sunglasses, strutting across the date.</context>
      <utterance>You love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRTGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger rubs her belly.</context>
      <utterance>trey, look yer ovulating.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still hungry, Bee.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you - you've done every dog we can</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not enough. I want somethin'... I need more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason and his pals all fumble for lighters and five little flames appear before her smoke. She lights her smoke on Jason's, and exhaling looks him up and down. The boys flames go out, all at once.</context>
      <utterance>Got a light, Jace'?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>obediently, they all light up for Brigitte. Brigitte falters before the attention. At Ginger's nod, Brigitte lights up too.</context>
      <utterance>My sister would like one also.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINA</speaker>
      <mode>O1S</mode>
      <context>Ginger turns to see Trina and the Clones sizing her up.</context>
      <utterance>Slut.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger seems to tower over the Trinas today. Trina can't match the menace. Ginger exhales smoke in Trinals face and climbs the steps into the school. Brigitte double-takes Ginger's back. Ginger's spine is protruding sharply through her shirt. Trina leers at Brigitte.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte snorts and follows Ginger in.</context>
      <utterance>Better watch your back, Fitzenstein.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I'm scared.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>we need your cooperation. If you know anything about the so- called Beast of Bailey Downs, call in. You can be anonymous.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha! As if they weren't already.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context>Ginger sighs loudly and Brigitte prods her.</context>
      <utterance>But your pets aren't safe until the perpetrator is caught.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger's rolling the taste of Trina's blood around in her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmnun .</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte and Ginger stare at one another. Ginger first shakes her head., but then nods. Ginger looks around and whispers</context>
      <utterance>You can't do that, That's human blood! .Feel anything?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte makes a sour face.</context>
      <utterance>It's sick but - I'm all like horny.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fitzgerald, bench!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte watches Ginger march to the sidelines, throwing off her gear as she goes.</context>
      <utterance>What, she started it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger gives Sykes the finger without looking back. Brigitte groans.</context>
      <utterance>Pick that stuff up!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yer bitch sister's dead, freak.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason lopes up. He indicates the guidance office door.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte ignores him.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger in there again?</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool. Um. Look, Belinda...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brigitte.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, right. T'd really like to take yer sister out. Think you could ask her for me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>53</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brigitte' s face clouds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte seethes.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. I could fix you up too. I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason takes a post on the opposite Brigitte to wait. Brigitte glares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck. Never mind, I'll ask her myself.  Freak.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you keep getting sent here. We might as well be friendly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't do friendly, Mr. Wayne.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I know where you're coming from. I was a kid once too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger fakes an eye-lash batting smile. She winds the condom over her erect fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Really? So was I. Weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's explore them.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, you aren't a kid. You're a young adult. With some issues.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MR. WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I'm reaching out here. Your plays for attention are a cry for help, aren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it a problem at home? With your parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Wayne sighs.</context>
      <utterance>They think I'm cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I ought to split you and your sister up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GTNGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, c'mon Mr. Wa-ayne. Divide aii' conquer? That's so old.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. You're antisocial, antagonistic, and now violent. The point of high school is you learn to develop a place for yourselves in society.../</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Long as you like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger gives him a cold, dead stare.</context>
      <utterance>As long as you're at this school young lady, I better like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>consider this your final warning. I see you outta line again, and we're talking expulsion. And don't look at me like that, missy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pounds her fist into a locker and makes a dent. Brigitte cringes. Ginger admires the damage.</context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' guidance my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger notices Jason and visibly brightens.</context>
      <utterance>Holy...</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. whatcha doin' now?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothin' special.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna go for a ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason and Brigitte's faces darken simultaneously.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. C'mon Bee.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger, we should get home.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte drags Ginger aside. Ginger notes Brigitte's hand squeezing her arm with a dangerous look.</context>
      <utterance>No we shouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger shakes Brigitte's hand off.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty minutes ago you coulda killed somebody. Is this really a good time to start dating? I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?! Look, grow up a little an' maybe you'll get it</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger takes Jason's hand and pulls him off to the exit. Jason gives Brigitte SUCH a smug look over his shoulder. Brigitte stands alone in the hall, gaping after them.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it, I'm goin'. I'll draw ya a picture later, 'kay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Brigitte wanders over the emptying school. lot. She looks small and alone. She looks disoriented.</context>
      <utterance>When Henry renovated the basement, to build our room? I was like ten an, in the way an, shit. Well, he rammed iue with this beam, right in my stomach. Accidentally.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T-V/0</mode>
      <context>Brigitte consults the hygiene calendar. Ginger's ending the third week of checked-off days. A special note on today's date asks DO YOU HAVE PMS?</context>
      <utterance>But all the air came outta my lungs at once an, I kept tryin' to breathe but I couldn't. I forgot all about that. Till like right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger licks his blood from her own lips and freezes dead cold. Jason dives back at her for more. Ginger looks both aroused and unnerved by her arousal. Ginger's stomach growls. Ginger pushes Jason off of her.</context>
      <utterance>Ouch! whoa. Can't believe you never had a boyfriend...</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go. It's getting late.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason presses himself on her again. Ginger shoves him off, hard.</context>
      <utterance>It's only six o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1-have-to-go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Now you get all moody on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey_ You got no idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context>Ginger stops in her tracks. She shakes her head and continues away.</context>
      <utterance>Chicks, yer all the same!</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cock tease!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger force-feeds Trina something on a spoon. Trina screams with her mouth full, trying to spit it back out. Ginger offers Trina a glass of milk.</context>
      <utterance>Stop screaming or I'll rip your permed head right off you neck. An' ya know what? I can do that. Now open wide</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chaser? No?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger grins and shows Bee a bowl of crushed glass and tacks.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger WHAT are you doing-!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte grabs the bowl away: glass shards and tacks rain around them.</context>
      <utterance>Jus' like you said, Bee! S' perfect!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy?!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the sisters argue, Trina rocks the chair back and forth, trying to free herself.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! I'm Join' this for you!</utterance>
   <speaker>BR I G ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, no way... No!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yer still burnt over Jason!</utterance>
   <speaker>BR I G ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trina lurches back hard and rocks forward. Trina struggles to get her toes to meet the floor. She lurches back for more momentum.</context>
      <utterance>No, Ginger, I'm burnt 'cause you don't see like jail in yer future! You don't get how hugely fucked this is! DO you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sayin' I'm stupid?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trina throws herself forward again and her toes connect firmly with the floor - just as her temple connects with a sickening CRACK on the sharp corner of the desk. The milk glass dumps on top of her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sayin' she? Will tell on you! This is someone who will tell!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger grabs her own right arm (most damaged by the original attack) and shudders with pain.</context>
      <utterance>Ha-ha.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte takes Trina in from head to toe. Brigitte checks Trina for a pulse. Brigitte snaps her hand back as though it were burned. A tremor wracks Brigitte's body and she convulses. Brigitte runs to the bathroom. OFF SCREEN, Brigitte throws up. Meanwhile Ginger raises her afflicted hand. The hand is nowsomething clearly on the way to being a wolfen paw. The nails are black, curling claws. Oblivious, Brigitte climbs back into bed and covers her face with a pillow.</context>
      <utterance>Ow. Ow. Owchee-wow-ow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My life is basically over.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Awestruck, they both watch as Ginger extends and retracts her: new set of claws. There is a knock at the door. The girls look at one another in mute horror. Ginger addresses the door.</context>
      <utterance>Bee. ..BEE!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you two fighting?!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context>Brigitte and Ginger hop up and down in a brief freak fit.</context>
      <utterance>come on then. Dinner's ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pamela grasps Ginger's gnarly arm and squeezes it through her sleeve. Brigitte and Ginger look at Pamela's hand.</context>
      <utterance>The gynecologist called.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wants to do an ultra-sound!</context>
      <utterance>There's something wrong, Ginger.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pamela, don't scare her. How could the cells not be human cells? we'll send you to somebody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure your father's right. I'm just upset... How are you feeling, do you feel. all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um. sure. Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry, Brigitte and Ginger groan.</context>
      <utterance>No unusual discharge or anything like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I worry, all right? I've made another appointment with a new doctor. Early next month was the earliest he could see you. okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rigor mortis. Knew we shoulda skipped dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte hesitates, her anxieties rising.</context>
      <utterance>Can we do it my way now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So is this it? You doin' people now?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She won't fit unless I</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I mean. Just say.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I din't kill her!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a long pause. Ginger tries to laugh it off with,</context>
      <utterance>But were you gonna?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte takes a deep breath, nodding. She acts belief.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm not doing people. No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger drags a section of the body into the playhouse with her. Disgusting gnashing and tearing, bones snapping and other sounds of devouring are heard from within. Brigitte keeps watch. Tears appear in her eyes. The body is dragged another foot into the playhouse. Ginger is eating Trina to make her fit in the grave.</context>
      <utterance>'Kay. .Hurry up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trina was dead. Trina was dinner. This was BAD.An'I kept wonderin' what Sam was doin' right then. I couldn't help it, he jus' kept poppin' into my head, like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O - READING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The Beast was usually finally eliminated with a bullet, the cost of breaking the curse the human life that bore it.,, oh man. "However many believed wolfs bane  had the power not only to protect the innocent, but calmed those afflicted to a restored sense of reason and self- control."</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context>Brigitte nearly jumps into orbit, slamming her book shut as Ginger appears over her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>What:cha Join' ?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thought they were useless.</context>
      <utterance>Hm. Big Book of Monsters, hunh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rrigitte gives Ginger a nervous smile. Ginger smiles back. Her fangs show.</context>
      <utterance>They are. Couldn't sleep. So.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger, don't be pissed...</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open the fuckin' door you feeb.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger pounds on the door with great violence.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>BR I( 'TF.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pounding Sto2s.</context>
      <utterance>Want Pamela dc h, e?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte tears the page with the plant out of her book and leaves by the window.</context>
      <utterance>We have to stop it Ginge'. If we can. I`ll be back before dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Told Pammy Ginger wasn't feeling well. Just to get her checkin' regular on. her, keep the pressure on Ginger to be cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT COUNTY GREENHOUSES - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a police car parked next to the Sam's truck. She looks back to the bus, but the doors swing shut and it pulls away. Brigitte smoothes her hair, takes a deep breath, and over- acts innocent as she walks up.</context>
      <utterance>Brigitte steps off a county bus at the drive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's in your best interests to be cooperative.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context>She ends up backing into a COP behind some palms.</context>
      <utterance>My lawyer's co-operative, I just know my rights. I don't know where she is, I'm very concerned. That's it, unless you got a warrant.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhh-it! I mean, sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can see I got customers, so if that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop gives Sam a final Dirty Harry squint and leaves. Sam collects himself with difficulty. So does Brigitte.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Sure. For now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>if you skipped school lookin' to score, I don't keep nothin' here at work, sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I din't. I mean I skipped, but-/</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. From Mccardy's van, right? You know my girlfriend? Trina Sinclair?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rinda.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seen her today?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not today...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck. She's missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. S-sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam looks Brigitte right in the eye. Brigitte is caught up in him for a second.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well. Cops think I know where she is. I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you need.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, what do you care right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds out the torn page. Sam takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Um. Lookin' for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte yanks her own hair hard. Sam smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Aconitum lycoctonum? Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tryin' to kill somebody?  Well, you know it's poisonous, right? Wolfs bane? Deadly. Be like stocking hemlock an, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I thought it did something else. Doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte turns to leave, hot with frustration, huinilliation. Sam watches her stamp toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Anyways they're perennials - only flowers in spring.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If you're interested.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Ranunculaceae come in about a hundred species. I've gotta cousin, monkshood. Not so toxic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>66</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brigitte stops and considers him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know if it'd help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>S'called monkshood 'cause people used to think it kept 'em pure from dirty thoughts. Seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>EARNESTLY</mode>
      <context>Sam laughs. Surprised by this, Brigitte smiles and hides under her hair.</context>
      <utterance>Make my life easier.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is awful. but the whole time I was with him there? I din't even think how I'd just put pieces of his girlfriend in the deep freeze, like, at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit down, Ginger.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' I said ./</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are expelled. This is not your personal playground, this is a school.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh dear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ever fuck with me like that again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte gapes at all the blood. Ginger is very agitated.</context>
      <utterance>You .got out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Backing away, Brigitte trips over Mr. Wayne's foot sticking out from under the desk.</context>
      <utterance>He asked for it. Was gonna expel me. So.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do, Bee? What do we do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The school bell goes off. Brigitte snaps out of her daze, reaches up and hits the light switch off. They now sit in virtual darkness.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon we need a fuckin' plan here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of the full halls around them seems very loud now.</context>
      <utterance>Last bell. wait till everyone goes. We'll stuff him someplace. Clean this up. I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte hands her a smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Bee, gotta a smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be mad, ' kay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not mad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger nods. Brigitte slips out and creeps down the corridor. Ginger shuts the door. Then Ginger whips it open again.</context>
      <utterance>Stay here. Lock the door. I'll knock once.</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the door, Ginger!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger throws the canister any way, forcing Brigitte to dive out of the way. SMASH! Glass rains down over. Brigitte. Brigitte lifts her head in time to see Ginger burn down the hall looking for more mischief. Brigitte curls into a fetal position, burying her face in her lap and rocks herself. Brigitte sobs. OFF-SCREEN we hear Ginger cont.inuing her ram a e else where in the school. Brigitte wanders up to the janitor's cart, looking like a plane crash survivor - dazed and wretched. Brigitte picks up a bottle of cleaning fluid. She sniffs it. She closes her eyes and tips it back. She washes it around in her mouth and lifts her chin to swallow. She spews it into the air, the taste making her heave instinctively. she dry heaves a couple of times. She throws the bottle at the wall.</context>
      <utterance>STOP IT! Just stop. Enough, Ginger. Please. Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fair sisters Fitzgerald.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. How's it goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell me. Tim cracks the door and takes a look inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guys gawk: they are very impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit - they trashed the place!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who--oooaa. Fuck, unbelievable!</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger, I had no idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I say. I had an urgo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte glares at Ginger.</context>
      <utterance>Cool. But. This is ya know, uh, a bit of a problem. What's gonna happen when they start lookin' for the ah, people responsible?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh I might.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger -?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up. Shut up.  How ' bout a deal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have to be sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte slumps against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>You keep our lil' secret and I do you. All a' you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jason gets the eager nod from his gang.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now - I'm a mess. We're  having a Halloween party at. our place, Friday night. We'll do it then.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right Saturday. You'll ditch.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't ditch. But you guys say a word about this to any one, - and there's no action. So it's up to you. You stay quiet, you score. You don't - phhtt - nice knowin' ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He extends his hand to shake on it. Linger shakes it awkwardly with her good hand. Brigitte thumps her head against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, leave me alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not that big a deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you say that! Two people are dead because of you. Us.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte opens the bathroom door.</context>
      <utterance>They pissed me off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger prods a claw into Brigitte's chest, pinning her in place.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Then they we asking for it? What about Jason an' them? Gonna kill 'em all when yer done, Ginger? 'Cause you have to take yer clothes OFF for that shit, they wanna SEE yer BODY for that shit, you gonna let like five guys live to tell how they fucked the Beast a' Bailey Downs? That could annoy you too!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think yer sooo smart? I think yer sooo jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sure.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm jealous yer turning into a nympho. I'm so jealous yer killing people who did never did nothing to you. Yeah Ginger.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, wow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>79</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brigitte takes a deep breath, swallows hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger's claw pricks Brigitte's skin. Brigitte cringes. Blood appears around the claw.</context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna do this any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte writhes in pain as Ginger's claw slices in deeper.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but...!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger retracts the claw, and Brigitte grabs the wound.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger?! This is me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte is helpless and looks terrified. Ginger's face is contorted with intensity, with madness. Ginger's drooling. A drip of gob drops onto Brigitte's face.</context>
      <utterance>Who needs you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>very small,</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAINTIVE)</speaker>
      <mode> PLAINTIVE)</mode>
      <context>Ginger lifts Brigitte by the shirt-front and searches her eyes. Ginger drops Brigitte to the floor and grabs her coat. Brigitte grabs Ginger's leg.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte struggles to hang on, to rise from the floor; Ginger's really hurt her.</context>
      <utterance>Don't, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger kicks free.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we can stop it! Lemme try!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte struggles to a point between Ginger and the window.</context>
      <utterance>An' spoil my fun? I'll skin you alive first.</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They'll catch you. Wake up!</context>
      <utterance>You're fucked without me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger steps up i.o the window and climbs through. Brigitte rubs her throat, trying hard to keep breathing. Brigitte dashes to her own bed and drags an Adidas gym bag from under it. Brigitte starts grabbing clothes off the floor and jamming them into the bag.</context>
      <utterance>No, you wake up! Nobody'll live to catch me. Yer a two-faced lil' chicken shit? Your problem, Brigitte. I don't need ya. I don't WANTCHA! So stay away from me or I'll kill you I swear I'll have you for breakfast. Brigitte backs out of Ginger's way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Right.</context>
      <utterance>I was like, okay. Fuck you too. She'd be sorry. And I'd be like, I dunno - somewheres' totally else goin' not my problem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Brigitte creeps to the bathroom and snaps the light on. Empty.</context>
      <utterance>I'd get the monkshood from my locker at school the next morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Brigitte locks the window shut. She locks the bedroom door and pushes a bureau of drawers in front of it.</context>
      <utterance>I'd find Ginger, I'd find out if the stuff even worked.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Brigitte turns on the bedside lamp and fishes a baseball bat out of the closet.</context>
      <utterance>I could deal with whatever, as long as I tried. If it was the last thing she ever saw me do, it was gonna be me goin' fer somethin' by myself. The real Ginger woulda dug that large.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FEMALE STUDENTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger Fitzgerald is such a slut./No kidding./The bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>VARIOUS STUDENTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Brigitte gets closer to the building, she finds police cars and cops at the main entrance.</context>
      <utterance>You hear about Trina Sinclair?/Dug her up in somebody's back yard!/oh that's so sad!/ Poor Trina, Ga-awd!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PRINCIPAL FARDOR is speaking with the RCMP constable who has been visiting classes. Fardor holds a hanky over his face.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FARDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte hedges up the steps toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>That stench near the staff offices, what is that you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte slips past the two men.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't say, sir. Now is there anyone you suggest we talk to? Anyone with something against the school?</utterance>
   <speaker>FARDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte stops at the threshold.</context>
      <utterance>For god's sake look around you. I got 350 angry young people bored blind.Helluva day for my goddamn cleaning staff to be late ... . IIEY!</utterance>
   <speaker>FARDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I left something in my locker.</utterance>
   <speaker>FARDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte backs down the steps, looking like she just took a good slap. She turns to confront the mass confusion around her. Brigitte spots Ginger dancing on the roof of a car in the lot now, surrounded by boys. Brigitte spots Sam's truck near-by.</context>
      <utterance>Find your homeroom and wait. School's outta bounds until we call you in. Get!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte doesn't know what to say, so she offers his a smoke. He takes it.</context>
      <utterance>I showed up to see Trina? But she's I'm goin' strange in the head.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte examine his. face for an implication. There isn't one.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Why would ya do a thing like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's unny is I dumped her that night. Feel bad about it now. Truth is, she was a pain in the ass. I sound like a jerk, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam is over-come again. Brigitte raises a hand to touch him, chickens out, and then scores on the second attempt. He rolls right into her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Yeah well, while she was - disappearin', I'm off have a time at the Highway Home with my buddy Georgio. Drinkin', dealin' - an, now she's</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam leans in and kisses her right back. Better. Longer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm really, um.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. Sorry. Kinda freaked. You know? I shouldn't, well.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that was really nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit staring straight ahead a moment. A cop ahead double- takes them, and reaches into his car for the radio mic.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. 'Kay. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna lil' dube or somethin'? Listenin' to me go on like a loser-What's yet- name?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brigitte. Fitzgerald. No, that's okay. I need more monkshood...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte drags her hands over her face with extreme anxiety.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! Dirty thoughts! oh. I been drinkin'. Should not drive. Right, Brr-igitte?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right. OK. Ur.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam grimaces as Brigitte nods.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger's yer sister right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger's most maniacal laugh drifts over to them. Brigitte sees her dancing sexily on the roof of a car with a whole crowd of leering boys.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, rumors - say she's doin' all these guys at some party. Goias' around she's a big time ho', that kinder thing. Hey. Don't worry about it. Nobody mentioned you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Ginger! Take it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wish!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, everybody knows! Can I bring my cousin?</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What -?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like to see ya again. Can I come to yer party too?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte slips out of the truck as they stare at one another with that look you get when you're scared because you just kissed someone you really, really like.</context>
      <utterance>sh-sure. Sorry. I gotta - Ginger, so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Beyond Sam's truck, behind Brigitte, the two new cruisers lurch to a stop. Cops approach Sam's vehicle with extreme caution. Brigitte arrives at the car with Ginger as,</context>
      <utterance>fie was jus' drunk, I'm thinkin'. I mean he prob'ly din't mean it. Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>we'll do it till you drop.</context>
      <utterance>All a' you guys?! My house! Tonight!  I wanna party with everybody.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>A commotion behind them causes everyone to turn. Sam is being dragged from his truck by the cops. He is flung face-first onto the hood and hand-cuffed.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger was gonna kill every one of l em.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte physically fights with herself not to yell out. She runs a few steps toward Sam. Brigitte looks back at Ginger, who drills her with an evil warning glare. The cops shove Sam into the back of a cruiser. They roar off. Brigitte stands alone, apart from the crowd. The cruisers' flashing lights disappear down the street. Brigitte turns to face Ginger, mustering her own first menacing look. Ginger accepts a cigarette offered by one of her boys.</context>
      <utterance>Sam McDonald? You're under arrest for the murder of Trina Sinclair.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They closed the school that day. So I never got to my locker. So I never got the monkshood. I thought, this is it. I fucked up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now just remember, no boys in you bedroom during this party. Your room is off limits. Ginger are you sure that arm's not sprained, or worse?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bruise. Lacrosse.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte and Ginger exchange a look.</context>
      <utterance>Mm Henry when'd you get this new meat from Tinny's? Quite nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't been to Tinny's.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte spits out her food.</context>
      <utterance>Then where's all the packs marked "t" come from -?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I be excused?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>911 OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>911, do you need fire, ambulance or police, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>speaking very</utterance>
   <speaker>QUICKLY)</speaker>
      <mode> QUICKLY)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam McDonald is not the Beast of Bailey Downs. He was at the Highway Home Motel when Trina Sinclair was killed. Sam didn't do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Sinclair girl was found at the Bernstein's, can you believe it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pamela is feverishly creating little straw witches and such party decorations. She has a se]ecl.i.on of dried flowers, wheat etc on the table before her.</context>
      <utterance>What, last night? I didn't hear a thing! Never going to have these done in time. Henry help.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte slides into her regular chair and props her hands on her wrists in an attitude of complete distraction.</context>
      <utterance>Brigitte, honey we're thrilled you two are making friends. But next time you two do something like this give Mummy a little more notice, will you? Hate having to scramble.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte looks at Henry as he works on a little witch.</context>
      <utterance>What's your sister up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry grimaces. He sifts through the dried plants before them. Brigitte double-takes the pile.</context>
      <utterance>She said she had a lot of work to do on her costume. Should we dress up, you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAME-LA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>oh, Henry. You're no fun at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>91</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brigitte sits bolt up right in her seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just weeds, old cuttings from the yard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte plucks out a handful of dried plant with tiny purple flowers.</context>
      <utterance>No, THIS stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I had that around the dahlias. Man at the greenhouse said it'd keep the cats out. Seemed to do the job. It's got a funny name - nun's robe, priest hat, something</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monkshood.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. Do we have a budding botanist in the family?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pamela giggles as does Henry. Brigitte grabs a fistful of monkshood and races for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Pun intended.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Brigitte is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, we need that! Brigitte!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was my accent colour!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bathroom door unlocks but. remains closed.</context>
      <utterance>McCardy's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte casts an uncertain look at Jason.</context>
      <utterance>Git in here an, gimme a hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte's face darkens. She slips into the bathroom and shuts the door.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon ladies, there's six other guys sitting in the shrub waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think some people deserve to die?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger lowers the towel she's wearing enough to show the bump on her butt is now a twitching tail. Brigitte gasps.</context>
      <utterance>Don't say a fuckin' word.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take this gauze and tie it flat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger, you can't</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte grits her teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Now get outta my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta get ready for the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then wait here till I'm done.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, through all fifty a' them?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger takes a deep breath before she opens the bathroom door. Her breath is ragged. She smoothes her hair and chews her lip. She's nervous. Ginger opens the door and closes it behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't tempt me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really dark in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode>01S</mode>
      <context>Brigitte puts the toilet seat down and sits on it. Brigitte lights a smoke. Brigitte withdraws the monkshood from under her shirt and has a good scratch where it was itching her. OFF-SCREEN are the sounds of slurp kisses and Jason's moans. A fly unzips. Clothes fall with soft plunks to the floor. Bed springs creak. Plastic condom wrappers crinkle and then the SNAP-WHAP of one being fitted on pretty roughly. Somewhere above them the door bell starts ringing. From a vanity cupboard she pulls a Zombie face-painting kit and sets it next to the monkshood.</context>
      <utterance>I'm shy. Lay down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In English I heard about this chick who used a man's name to get her books read. She went by George but she was really Mary Ann? Goes, "It's never too late to be what you might have been." I was jus' there thinkin', is that true? Was it too late to be an unsolved Mystery? Alls I had to do was walk away...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context>Brigitte looks up to see a cheap plastic Frankenstein mask looking down at her. Its owner flips it up: it's Sam. Brigitte's eyes snap wide open in shock.</context>
      <utterance>Brigitte F.!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They let me go. No evidence: someone called in this tip.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I decided to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger emerges from the bedroom like a reigning diva, and the room stops dead. Brigitte drops her glass of punch. Ginger has come out as herself, as an almost full-blown werewolf. She wears a Lill Red Riding Hood cape jobbie and a plastic mask. She's the best looking monster you ever laid eyes on. Down her belly she has six perfect nipples showing and everything. The room bursts into a_cheerinq round of applause.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you gotta get outta here -/</utterance>
   <speaker>GUS.' WITH 'AX IN THE HEAD'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That make-up is amazing!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GUY WITH 'EYE MISSING'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger, it looks totally real!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Told you. She's a arts-type, for chrissakes, look at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's very good, isn't she?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, yer sister's gone to town.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>can you do me a favor?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she's gone all right. Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you give somethin' to Ginger for me? Jus' - we're Navin' a fight, but I got this thing for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte shows him what appears to be a joint. Sam takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, what.</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell her I gave it to you. Jus' act like it's from you. She won't take it if it's from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An, don't like, go any wheres with her. Okay? Jus' come right back, 'kay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte smiles, embarrassed and freaking at the exact same time.</context>
      <utterance>Gonna miss me Bee F.?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>one minute young lady, I could use a little help here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BR I G ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go of me, I have to get Ginger!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pamela is already marching Brigitte up the stairs. Brigitte strains to get back. Looking between her mother and her closed bedroom door, desperately.</context>
      <utterance>I have to get two more veggie trays down those stairs. I think your sister' 11 be fine for two minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pamela stands between Brigitte and the bedroom door, her arms folded.</context>
      <utterance>All these boys came to see you two, least you can do is stop hiding in your room. Honestly, you act like someone'd forced this party down your throat. Now go be nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother. You don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes--I do. I was shy too at your age. Mingle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>okay, cut it out now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This dope's fucked. Makin' me blaarrggh. C'mon. I'll do ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks. Told yer sister I'd be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up your ass?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get mean, s'nothin' personal. I happen to think Brigitte's pretty cool. and -/</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave my baby sister alone. Do me, don't hurt her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't hurt her. Now be a good girl and finish up your joint.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger takes a big toke as she paces between Sam and the door. Suddenly she's coughing uncontrollably, rubbing her eyes, wailing in pain.</context>
      <utterance>oh. Well fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam makes a move toward her and Ginger blindly lashes out at him. Ginger hurls Sam into the bed. Sam's flight path knocks the mattress askew: dozens and dozens of dog collars pour out over him. Sam fingers one in particular.</context>
      <utterance>Burning! What is this?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context>Brigitte eyes Pamela, who is slowly being distracted by horny young men who will now dance with anybody, even Pamela.</context>
      <utterance>Something was definitely fucked.</utterance>
   <speaker>COW GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte looks at her watch. Pamela is dragged off into the throng by a band of juveniles singing Do The Hustle. Brigitte makes her move at last.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think this is a faggy costume for a guy? You can just say. I dunno I been gettin' funny looks. What, like we aren't advanced enough that a guy can show up completely in the spirit of the thing with an udder, an' not get treated like a freakin' fruit?</utterance>
   <speaker>COW GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte makes a badly-faked would-be casual bee-line for their bedroom door. Brigitte wiggles the knob. It's locked.</context>
      <utterance>snob.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte discovers Ginger sitting in the tub floor under the running shower, weeping. Her eyes are swollen. Ginger is now covered in coarse hair. The water around her is full of blood. There is a kitchen knife next to her. Ginger's stoned numb on the monkshood dose. She's groggy and weak.</context>
      <utterance>You bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>BR IG ITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger is squeezing her now full tail at its base, where the blood is oozing between her f..inger.s. Ginger has tried - and tailed - to euL her tail off.</context>
      <utterance>oh fuck !</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger doesn't move. Ginger looks so pathetic, it's heart- breaking. Brigitte snatches the knife away and shuts off the water.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no. Oh no. Fuck, fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte takes in the cut, the rest of the monstrosity her sister has become.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody'll want me now any ways. Sc.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte yanks Ginger out of the tub and grabs a towel, frantic.</context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna do this any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Move, c'mon!</context>
      <utterance>Press this on the cut! Ginger!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte searches Ginger's face.</context>
      <utterance>I missed you Bee. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger cracks an uncertain, pained smile. Brigitte does too, an exact replica, in fact.</context>
      <utterance>Ginge'? That you in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte gently turns Ginger around to try and deal with her tail. Ginger is woozy and weak from blood loss.</context>
      <utterance>Ya feeb.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>okay. I can't clean this one up. We have to go. Like Go, go. Can you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte glances out into the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so woozy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um. Ever bite something you din't kill?</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  Wanna be one with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah. No. Sam? Isn't dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>GINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh nooo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>T'll be right back.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. Keep pressing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's no answer. She tries the knob, and is surprised to find it unlocked. She opens the door. She turns on the lights. Pamela takes in the bloody muck everywhere. The room is deserted. No Sam. No sisters Fitzgerald. Just gore. Pamela swoons and drops like a deadweight to the floor. Henry rushes up, looking in over his wife's body. The boys in costume crowd in behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Girls? You in there? You're not being very sociable...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he fingers some</context>
      <utterance>Pamela, honey, it's just a prank, you know how they...</utterance>
   <speaker>GORE)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where are my kids?!!</context>
      <utterance>Holy mother of - it's warm.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY WITH AX IN THE HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ginger went in here with Sam McDonald a while back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam McDonald?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode>V/O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plans, plans arc good. 'Course I hardly had one. Adrenaline though, adrenaline is pretty speedy shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte floors it and the truck blasts down their cul du sac to the main road.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger?! Don't eat the body okay? I got this idea, an' we'll need Sam.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ginger doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>So boom, diversion. Meanwhile you an, me hit the highway. we can hitch, get you cleaned up. By the time the find out we weren't in Sam's clutches at all, we could be any wheres. Yeah? Whatcha think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte puts the brake on but does not cut the engine.</context>
      <utterance>It'll work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte climbs up into the truck, reaching for something on its floor. Brigitte f itids Sam's prone feet. An animal/Ginger launches out at her, knocking her back, out, clear of the truck. Ginger isn't Ginger any more - what we can glimpse in the darkness is an attack by a creature much like the one that bit Ginger. And it's attacking Brigitte. Brigitte flails, kicks and punches at it. She breaks free and clambers at the tool rack on the inside panel of the truck. She grabs a shovel as the creature comes snarling up at her.</context>
      <utterance>Ginger? C'mon, we got move. Shove Sam down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It lunges at her again and Brigitte clocks it. It slides, dazed, off the back of the truck to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Stop. I mean it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tense seconds pass as she searches through the scrub and trees, shovel ready. we can hear panting and growling.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck Ginger. Leave a fuckin' trail much? Could leave everybody a fuckin' map...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigitte spots something ahead and lowers the shovel as she approaches it. It/Ginger cowers in the brush, collapsed. Her head and tail are bleeding. Brigitte drops to her knees nest to her sister, frantic with grief.</context>
      <utterance>I won't hurt you if you don't hurt me. 'Kay? Ginge'? 'Kay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGITTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no. Ginger. I didn't mean</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
