<movie id="248" title="Grand Hotel">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This line is only just above the general clatter of action but it is picked-up sharply first by Senf then by Bell-Captain -- and as the CAMERA SLOWLY TURNS AROUND, we see the boy going towards the door and we hear the voice in the distance, saying:</context>
      <utterance>Madam Grusinskaya will not want her car.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA now backs away from the scene into the BAR. (a section.) It backs to the back of the bar and proceeds -- in profile -- behind the backs of the barmen. A mixed crowd of people drinking before their lunch. We pick up the Doctor, leaning his head upon his hands, looking into space. The woman next to him, a noisy blonde, is laughing. The doctor glances up at her -- she glances at the doctor. She and the audience see the scarred side of his face -- the laugh dies on her lips and she turns suddenly to her companion, who is the Baron. We do not get much of a chance to see him because at that instant he is glancing at his watch, his shoulders are turning away from THE CAMERA and he moves out towards the lobby. BACK UP a few feet and LAP DISSOLVE as you move into the main aisle of busy room in restaurant. Great activity of waiters. The bustle and activity of fashionable lunchtime. A string orchestra is playing. Among other things, we pick up the smiling face of the pompous Maitre d'hotel, he has apparently just shown someone important to a table. THE CAMERA watches his face and follows him. His face just as CAMERA reaches service table. The pompous Maitre d'hotel now becomes a thing of drama as he demands of a waiter:</context>
      <utterance>Cancel Madam Grusinskaya's car.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE D'HOTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter, frightened and perspiring, doesn't bother to argue -- he tears off quickly (CAMERA FOLLOWING HIM) to another service table. The waiter seizes buss-boy's arm:</context>
      <utterance>Where is that gentleman's soup?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boy goes off at great rate of speed, CAMERA FOLLOWS HIM, into service room of kitchen. Boy stops at soup chef's counter. He is not the only waiter wanting soup at that moment. He pushes his way to the front and puts his ticket forward.</context>
      <utterance>Where's that soup?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soup chef, used to impatient waiters, makes no exception of the young man. He looks at him as much as to say: "I'll slap you on the mouth." At the same time he is pulling over a cauldron of soup.</context>
      <utterance>Quick -- come on -- come on...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Preysing...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing rises, struts from restaurant. CAMERA FOLLOWS HIM -- He walks out through the door...</context>
      <utterance>Telephone -- from Fredersdorf --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Preysing from Fredersdorf -- his call.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing begins drumming his fingers on the top of switchboard.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Preysing --</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've gone -- Just a moment, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he waits irritably)</context>
      <utterance>You told me it was on -- you said the call was through.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's in number three?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Girl looks off at...)</context>
      <utterance>Senf -- the hall porter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the conclusion of Senf's speech, CAMERA MOVES TO NEXT BOOTH. Thru the glass door we see Preysing approaching from desk. He enters booth and commences conversation:</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's Senf, the head porter, Grand Hotel... Are you at the Clinic?,... How's my wife?,... Is she in pain?,... Isn't the child coming soon?,... Patience! It's easy for you to talk... Get away?,... No, I can't -- I'd lose my job. It's like being in jail. Oh, I hope the child comes along all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE CAMERA THEN PANS TO Suzette. Suzette is already in the booth and she is waiting for Mr. Meierheim to come on.</context>
      <utterance>Hello! Long Distance?,... Get off the wire... No... I was talking to Fredersdorf... What?,... Oh... Hello!... Is that you dear?... How is everything at home?... What do you hear from the factory?... No... How are the children?... I left my shaving set at home... Yes, is your father there?... Hello, father?... Our stock has gone down twenty-three points. If our merger with the Saxonia doesn't go through -- I don't know what we can do... Hello, hello... yes, papa. Rely on me -- everything depends on Manchester... If they refuse to come in -- well, we will be in bad shape... no... Rely on me, I'll make it go through -- I'll make it go through... Waiting?... Yes, I'm still speaking...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAN TO BARON just entering booth. He is lighting a cigarette. (receiver down - trick)</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Meierheim?... Is that, Mr. Meierheim?... This is Suzette... Suzette, Madam Grusinskaya's maid... No... Madam Grusinskaya will not go to the rehearsal... No... Madam is in a terrible state, she didn't sleep all night -- She's very tired... No, I'm speaking from a booth -- I didn't want to speak in front of her... I gave her a tablet of veronal... She's sleeping now... You had better come to the hotel, I'm afraid...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAN TO KRINGELEIN - booth.</context>
      <utterance>Baron Gaigern speaking. Yes, Baron Gaigern himself. Where are you?,... Good... No -- first, I need money. I need it right now. I have to make a showing... That's my business. I hope to do it tonight... at the theatre or after the show... But money -- for the hotel bill, for tips... I don't need advice, I need money!... Now, listen...</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Near the conclusion of Kringelein's speech, we see the Doctor approaching through Kringelein's booth. He is looking down at something.</context>
      <utterance>Who is that, This is... Hello, hello!... Who is that... Heinrich? This is Kringelein. Hello, Heinrich. This is Otto Kringelein. Hello! Can you hear me?... I've got to speak very quickly. Every minute costs two marks ninety... What?... Otto Kringelein! Yes, I'm in Berlin, staying at the best hotel, the Grand Hotel... No, don't you understand? I want to explain, but I must do so quickly, it costs so much. Please don't interrupt me -- hello? Hello! Listen! You know that will I made before my operation? I gave it to you. I want you to tear it up. Destroy it. Because, listen, I came to Berlin to see a great specialist about that old trouble of mine... It's pretty bad, Heinrich. The specialist says I can't live much longer.  I haven't long to live! That's what's the matter! Hello, hello. Are you on the line? No, it isn't nice to be told a thing like that. All sorts of things run through your head. I am going to stay here in Berlin. I am never coming back to Fredersdorf. Never! I want to get something out of life, too. You plague, and bother, and save -- and all of a sudden you are dead. Heinrich... You don't say anything. I am in the Grand Hotel, do you understand, the most expensive hotel in Berlin? I'm going to get a room here. The very best people stay here. Our big boss, Preysing, too. I saw him -- not five minutes after I was here. Sometime, I'd like to tell him exactly what I think of him. Listen, Heinrich -- I have taken all my savings; my life insurance, too; I cashed in all my policies, the sick benefit fund, the old age pension, the unemployment insurance, the burial fund and everything... What's that, miss?... Hello, Heinrich. I have to hang up now. I have to pay three times overcharge. Just think, Heinrich! There's music here all day long. And in the evening, they go around in full dress... Yes, sometimes I have pain, but I can stand it. Everything is frightfully expensive here. You can imagine, the Grand Hotel... What? Time's up...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doctor passes Baron's booth next.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a sick man -- Heinrich -- Hello - hello -- Operator -- every minute two marks ninety.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doctor passes Suzette's booth.</context>
      <utterance>Dangerous?... That's my business... I'll do it tonight -- ...I'll do it alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam is afraid -- she will never dance again -- there was no applause last night -- Doctor passes Preysing's booth.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- the merger -- Manchester -- it is my business as much as yours -- we've already lost eighty-five thousand -- Doctor passes Senf's booth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on duty -- I can't leave the Grand Hotel -- it's like being in prison -- the baby -- Doctor crosses to telephone operator:</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any calls?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grand Hotel -- people -- coming -- going... Who cares... nothing ever happens.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELECTRIC CONTROL ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>small section -- Engineer pulling down lever.</utterance>
   <speaker>FACADE OF HOTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>sign flashes on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good little girl -- nice ones?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron would stay and flirt but he has a mission; he leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Baron.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="101">
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- Madam Grusinskaya's car is to be brought.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boy leaves. We hear his voice out of scene at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Madam Grusinskaya's car is to be brought.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLBOY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam Grusinskaya's car... to be brought.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening, Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening. Will you send these up to Madam Grusinskaya?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clerk hands box to bellboy.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Baron.  Madam Grusinskaya.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Room one-seventy -- Madam Grusinskaya.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you my tickets for the theatre?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Telephone rings again. Clerk picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, Baron --  Baron von Gaigern's seats for Madam Grusinskaya.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- Madam Grusinskaya's car is not to be brought.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Baron is picking up his tickets he looks around quickly as he hears the voice of Pimenov, who has arrived apparently from his afternoon walk from the rehearsal at the theatre.</context>
      <utterance>Charge them...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening -- my key -- one sixty- eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening, Mr. Pimenov.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- good evening, Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the beautiful lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grusinskaya -- well, to tell the truth, Baron -- tonight we are a little bit nervous. Were you at the theatre last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly -- always when Grusinskaya dances.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- last night was not so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought she was splendid!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment they are interrupted by a vehement little Japanese with his wife. They are arguing with the Clerk. The Japanese speaks in Japanese to his wife.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- but the audience.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The parquot loges are behind the parquet chairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAPANESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Senf is speaking to a lady at the same time.</context>
      <utterance>Then they've put me back and I want to be up in front. How is that, chairs in front of loges?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron and Pimenov exchange glances as the little Japanese speaks volubly to his wife.</context>
      <utterance>The train leaves at seven-thirty, Madam. That is the only through train -- the dining car goes along.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's always so quiet here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you occupied the room next to Madam Grusinskaya, you would appreciate the quiet of a hotel lobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear sir, I would gladly change rooms with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, Zinnowitz pushes past them.</context>
      <utterance>No doubt you would, Baron. But do you know, I'm quite indispensable to her. I'm her ballet master and her nurse. I hardly belong to myself anymore. But, there you are, it's Grusinskaya -- you can't help adoring her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me.  Is Mr. Preysing in -- I am Doctor Zinnowitz.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Preysing -- from Fredersdorf --</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Preysing -- Preysing steps quickly into scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ach! Here you are, Doctor Zinnowitz.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have I kept you waiting?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waiting -- I'm waiting for news from Manchester.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No news yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No word.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything depends on the Manchester merger.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know -- I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they begin to move out of scene, Zinnowitz calls back to Senf.</context>
      <utterance>I saw Gerstenkorn at lunch -- and as your lawyer I made it my business to broach the matter ---</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm expecting a young woman -- a stenographer -- she will ask for Mr. Preysing. Ask her to wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they move out of scene, telephone bell goes.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Doctor Zinnowitz.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- letters to two-eighty.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any letters?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Telegrams?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone asked for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor turns slowly away, taking out a cigarette with his one hand.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The war.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is Doctor Otternschlag -- You know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- He always seems to be waiting for something -- and nothing ever comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The war dropped him here and forgot him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I was in the war.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pan back to desk:</context>
      <utterance>Please -- please pay some attention to me -- I have no time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROHNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you will wait one moment, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't wait -- I can't wait -- I waited three days before I got a room at all and what a room that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROHNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a very nice room and inexpensive, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rohna, sensing a scene with this strange dirty little gentleman, looks furtively around for the manager.</context>
      <utterance>Did I say I wanted a cheap room to live in -- when I came here did I ask for a cheap room? Did I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROHNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just one moment, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein turns his attention directly to this man and proceeds:</context>
      <utterance>No, I won't wait -- I can't -- Every day is precious -- every hour -- Every minute. Second Clerk is looking straight at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he finishes the Doctor draws into the scene -- he is watching. Assistant Manager enters.</context>
      <utterance>I came here because I wanted to live here, two weeks, maybe three -- God only knows -- I've told you I'll pay -- I'll pay anything you ask. I'm tired -- I'm ill -- I can't wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rohna and Kringelein speak together.</context>
      <utterance>Has the gentleman a complaint?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROHNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The gentleman is dissatisfied with room number five fifty-nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He senses an audience and warms up. The Baron and Pimenov enter the scene. The lady and gentleman have turned. The bellboy stands watching curiously and even Senf pauses and looks up.</context>
      <utterance>I certainly have a complaint -- and a fair one.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came here from a long distance to stay at the Grand Hotel. I want a room -- a big room -- like you would give General Director Preysing -- I'm as good as Mr. Preysing -- I can pay like Mr. Preysing -- would you give him a little room, way up in the corner with the hot water pipes going -- bang -- bang -- bang...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This gentleman can have my room.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send his bags up to my room.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- but -- I --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're tired. I can see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- yes -- I am tired. I have been ill...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this scene the manager has been talking with Rohna quietly. The manager how turns.</context>
      <utterance>You are ill.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kringelein will take room number one-seventy-six, one of our most expensive rooms. It is large and on the front with bath.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that mean that the bath is my own? --- Private?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out his wallet and nervously commences to extract money.</context>
      <utterance>Well, now, that's very kind -- thanks. That's what I want -- a large room on the front with a private bath -- Yes, that's what I want. I can pay now if you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The manager is instructing the bellboy to take Kringelein to the new room. Kringelein accidentally drops a bill -- the Baron, who has noticed the money, stoops to pick it up. In bending himself, Kringelein drops his hat. Baron picks up the hat and considerately brushes it with his sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>That will not be necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he beams)</context>
      <utterance>Not at all, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Permit me -- my name is Kringelein -- from Fredersdorf.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Baron von Gaigern.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baron catches the mood of making this gentleman suddenly popular.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, a Baron!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is Doctor Otternschlag.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- Doctor -- you are a Doctor -- I am --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know -- I know -- when a man's collar is an inch too big for him -- I know he is ill.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zinnowitz passes through scene quickly on his way out. At that moment, Pimenov returns from the news-stand, where he has bought the evening papers.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- Oh -- oh -- yes, --</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Baron -- I must go and dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this gentleman a Baron, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Manager comes into scene.</context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will Mr. Kringelein kindly register.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein turns to the desk. The Doctor turns up with him. At that moment the Baron's chauffeur touches his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you a minute now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- I told you not to come in this lobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time's getting short.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chauffeur takes the cigarette out of his mouth -- but still holds it in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I've told you a hundred times not to speak to me with a cigarette in your mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to speak --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>General moving off, towards elevator, of Baron, Pimenov, Kringelein and the Doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. The Baron leaves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Preysing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you wait please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The stenographer is to go up -- Mr. Preysing telephoned.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Preysing -- one sixty-four.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses to elevator.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks --  Heigh! -- Wait!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor Grusinskaya -- how can she receive anyone. She can't -- theatre, trains, hotels -- hotels, trains theatre. We see Flaemmchen being directed by the floor clerk to Mr. Preysing's room.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...! --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the stenographer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flaemmchen, who has seen many large gentlemen in the altogether --</context>
      <utterance>Then you will please wait outside. He is very much affronted.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes out of the room and shuts the door.</context>
      <utterance>Don't hurry -- take your time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>UPPER CORRIDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baron loitering in the hall. (Whistling as outlined). Baron approaches, he is also whistling -- the same tune that Flaemmchen is whistling. She glances at him, as he continues whistling with an amusing dance step, as much as to say: "Are you mad?"</context>
      <utterance>Flaemmchen emerges from Preysing's room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like dancing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baron glances back up the passage; it is apparent that he is going to make conversation here with this girl, in order to keep legitimately in the passage until Grusinskaya comes out.</context>
      <utterance>Not with strangers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a fool!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances down the passage again, his hands in his pockets. She glances impatiently at her watch.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am rather.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He must be very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever is keeping you waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my large and noisy neighbor -- really? That?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- work!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dictation.  You know...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... poor child. If you were free, I'd ask you to come and have some tea -- but --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tea would spoil my dinner.  One meal a day, I'd hate to spoil it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reducing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- why? -- should I?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord no -- charming -- but why one meal a day?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Money -- Ever heard of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- yes indeed -- but you are a...  ...a stenographer. Don't little stenographers earn little pennies?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very little.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever see a stenographer with a decent frock on? -- One that she'd bought herself?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor child --  I wish I were free tonight -- we could --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Free --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately no -- to bad -- tomorrow though.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow? What time tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall we say five o'clock -- downstairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where downstairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yellow Room where they dance --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're very funny --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes? -- Tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flaemmchen laughs at him.</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment we hear Kringelein's voice calling from his doorway at the end of the passage.</context>
      <utterance>All right. We'll dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron turns and looks off at ---</context>
      <utterance>Baron -- Oh, Baron!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waiter, oh waiter! Wait a minute!  We are having caviar -- it's expensive but that makes no difference -- I see the Baroness is laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment Grusinskaya's door opens suddenly and Suzette comes out into the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Have caviar if you like, but it tastes like herring to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ssshh! Please! Madam is asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By this time the others are entering Kringelein's room. The Baron turns back for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzette turns back into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Asleep? -- Ssshhh -- sorry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>SUZETTE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam has slept well.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I have been awake -- thinking -- thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is time for the performance.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The performance?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like a soldier called to attention Grusinskaya sits suddenly upright --</context>
      <utterance>It is time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(laughs a little)</context>
      <utterance>Always the performance -- every day the performance -- time for the performance.  I think, Suzette, I have never been so tired in my life.  Veronal didn't even help me to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't dance tonight --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will pass -- it will pass -- come.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let us cancel the engagement.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Madam. cannot do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans forward against the dressing-table and her hands unconsciously touch the pearls.</context>
      <utterance>Now is the time to cancel to stop entirely. I feel it -- everything tells me -- enough -- enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws the pearls away, down upon the floor.</context>
      <utterance>The peals are cold -- everything is cold -- finished -- it seems so far away -- so threadbare -- the Russians -- St. Petersburg -- the Imperial Court -- the Grand Duke Sergei --  -- Sergei -- dead -- Grusinskaya -- it's all gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mon Dieu -- the pearls -- if they were to break --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzette crosses replacing the pearls.</context>
      <utterance>The pearls won't break -- they hold together and bring me bad luck ---- I hate them!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Orchids come again, Madam -- no card -- I think perhaps they are from the same young man -- he is at the end of the corridor -- tall -- he walks like a soldier -- Madam must have noticed how often he is in the elevator with us. Last night for instance --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grusinskaya's eyes are looking off into space -- she is away in Russia -- she does not look -- Telephone rings -- Suzette crosses to telephone.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Suzette -- Suzette -- Sshh -- quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, oui -- the car is here for Madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a knock at the door -- a certain kind of knock.</context>
      <utterance>Send it away -- I shan't need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up the telephone and as she does so Pimenov enters. Suzette quickly gives Pimenov a signal that there is trouble. As Pimenov is closing the door we hear Grusinskaya speak into telephone.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is time for the performance.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pimenov kneels by Grusinskaya -- he is chafing her hands, he attempts to soothe her. Now Grusinskaya draws her hands suddenly away.</context>
      <utterance>Poor little Lisevata -- she still has her stage frights -- it will pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is not stage fright -- it's something more --</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What -- what is it? Last night...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last night?... There was no applause.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was -- there was.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a sudden knocking at the door.</context>
      <utterance>That theatre -- half empty -- dancing for those few -- I was frantic -- I finished -- the last beat and...  ...I waited -- I listened -- but the applause didn't come -- nothing. A man in the box -- and just the claques behind -- it is passed, Pimenov. We are dead -- it's finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens suddenly. Meierheim bursts into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Meierheim --</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this that you have cancelled your car? Who am I that I should wait like a fool at the door? And here on a whim, you cancel your car. Have you forgotten there is a performance? Do you know the time? Or, are we all mad? Am I your manager?... Have we a contract? Have we obligations? Am I blind?  ...Or is that the time?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm cancelling the engagement.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Business of Pimenov signaling to him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! Madam is cancelling the engagement. Madam has chosen a funny time for such a funny joke. Ha, ha, ha -- hurry, come on. Tonight -- there's a line in front of the theatre since six o'clock. The house is jammed to the roof.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The house is not full -- Is it really full?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Packed to the ceiling. Hurry -- get dressed. And what an audience -- the French Ambassador -- American Millionaires -- Princess Ratzville -- er -- er --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- but it can't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come, Madam -- please come.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Suzette -- quickly -- hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meierheim goes over to telephone, he picks up receiver and says:</context>
      <utterance>You are late. Hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell Madam Grusinskaya's chauffeur to bring the car. Show few feet of Grusinskaya getting dressed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>BY ELEVATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meierheim is pushing the bell.</context>
      <utterance>Pimenov and Meierheim.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is the house?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terrible. After this, no more ballets for me. Jazz --  Just jazz.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the house is empty again, I don't know --</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are walking towards Kringelein's room. They are pacing rather like men who walk the deck on a liner. They turn almost together, but when they turn back past the CAMERA the CAMERA PROCEEDS on into Kringelein's room. The CAMERA ENTERS THE ROOM to a burst of laughter. Champagne bottles open, caviar, smoke, etc. In the room are the Doctor, Kringelein, the Baron, Flaemmchen, and a very fat waiter -- comedian.</context>
      <utterance>When she gets her paint on and hears the music -- she'll be all right. I know these people.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may laugh. Caviar and champagne may mean nothing to you, but to me -- they mean a great deal. You see, I'm ill and all of a sudden I got a fear of missing life. I don't want to miss life -- do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are funny. You speak of life as if it were a train you wanted to catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron offers Flaemmchen a glass of champagne. She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- and for me, it's going to leave at any minute. Let's drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure this beautiful room must appeal to your taste -- distinctive, don't you think? Velvet upholstery -- 'A-number one'. I'm in the textile trade and I know.  And these are real silk drapes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silk -- think of that -- silk -- they are, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment Preysing's voice is heard calling to the Floor Clerk.</context>
      <utterance>Have you seen the bathroom? -- Hot and cold running water -- You see, I can get a bath whenever I like.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flaemmchen, hearing this, turns and looks off, apparently through the door. Her manner changes, she puts down her glass.</context>
      <utterance>The stenographer!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her master's voice!  I must go now -- goodbye -- thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't go.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm engaged for the evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, can anyone engage you for the evening?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein's optimism has left him for a moment, he stands looking out of door undecided, he is drooped suddenly, as though years had returned to him.</context>
      <utterance>To take dictation -- a Mr. Preysing --  Goodbye, you -- tomorrow at five o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, Mr. Kringelein?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General Director Preysing!  Baron, when I was sixteen years old, I started as an office boy in that man's factory --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to leave. Oh, gentlemen, please don't go.</context>
      <utterance>Do I know him -- I know him through and through.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baron leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I must -- I hope to see you again, Mr. Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will stay, Doctor -- if you have nothing better to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move into the room.</context>
      <utterance>I have nothing better to do, Mr. Kringelein.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you could present me now, Mr. Pimenov.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron leans forward quickly and pushes the bell with a glance at her. They look at each other. He fixes his eyes on her characteristically. She glances at him. This is the first time they have met in the picture. She is impatient. As if to break an awkward silence, she turns to Suzette.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Baron -- forgive me -- not now -- here she is. Grusinskaya sweeps into scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzette is carrying the coat over the pearls. As she takes the coat off her arm, Grusinskaya glances down at the jewel case.</context>
      <utterance>My coat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suzette -- I told you not to bring the pearls. I will not wear them tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take them back, Suzette.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzette hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>You haven't time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry, Suzette.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzette toddles off with the pearls. The elevator opens, collects its passengers, all except the Baron and descends.</context>
      <utterance>Such nonsense.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PREYSING'S ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zinnowitz and Preysing are standing by door.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No news from Manchester yet -- Do you think we ought to postpone the conference?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good heavens no. That'd create the very worst impression. You must be optimistic. You must convince them. You know as well as I do that the merger must go through.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- the merger must go through -- But I am used to making my deals on a solid basis. I am not a liar. I am an honest business man -- a good husband and father -- I have a sense of honor -- I have nothing to conceal. I couldn't live happily otherwise.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, don't get excited about it. We agreed that the merger with the Saxonia people must go through.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to dictate my statement for tomorrow. I can't speak without notes. I like to have things down before me in black and white.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see you in the morning then, at the conference. Everything'll be all right, Preysing... Don't worry. Goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zinnowitz leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="49">
   <speaker>PREYSING'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing moves forward showing that we are in Preysing's room. The change of light shows us plainly the time lapse. Flaemmchen is seated at a small table typing. Preying strides forward As he strides he says:</context>
      <utterance>Both parties have fully agreed that this merger can result only in mutual advantages.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moreover --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moreover -- Preysing paces the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this, Flaemmchen, who is tired sits back and rubs her fingers that have been over-worked. She glances at her wrist- watch. Preysing comes and stands behind Flaemmchen.</context>
      <utterance>Moreover --  Is there a telegram for me yet?... Oh -- when it does, send it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he turns, he catches a down shot on her from behind as she stretches back showing her busts. Seeing his face looking down on her she pulls herself together and seats herself at attention.</context>
      <utterance>Now, where was I?  Oh -- sorry.  Where was I?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moreover...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It seems a silly kind of lull.</context>
      <utterance>Moreover...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you work in Justice Zinnowitz' office?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(she yawns suddenly)</context>
      <utterance>No -- only occasional jobs.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tired?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You pay me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a very unusual stenographer --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moreover...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, waits a moment and then begins characteristically to, change the sheet of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Moreover...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see why it's unusual for a stenographer to be pretty -- if she does her work well, -- seems so silly. I don't know why they don't like girls like me in offices. Personally, I hate offices -- I'd much rather be in the movies.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Movies?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tosses magazine -- as if it were nothing at all over to him. He looks down at it without touching it.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I photograph very well. Look --</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>I got ten marks for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he looks at picture -- he lowers his voice two notes.</context>
      <utterance>Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moreover...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only in mutual advantages -- moreover.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What brown hands you have.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's from skiing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he holds her hands)</context>
      <utterance>Skiing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops her hand suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... A man I know took me to Switzerland last month...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man? -- To Switzerland? -- That must have been nice -- for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing paces the room trying to get his thoughts back to the work in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Only in mutual advantages -- moreover...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moreover... He was a lucky man -- that man.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps.  He paces back and forth again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't misunderstand me. I'm a married man -- with grownup daughters. Uh --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moreover -- Do you mind if I smoke?  I went to Florence once, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By this time she is smoking her cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>With the same friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moreover, the possibility of the successful termination of negotiations now pending with the Manchester Cotton Company...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not too quickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a little too fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you understand me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand you perfectly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you got it now?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cotton Company --</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should throw a great weight into the balance...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a sudden knock at the door.</context>
      <utterance>...weight into the balance...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boy enters with telegram.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With almost hysterical speed, Preysing snatches the telegram -- opens it. Flaemmchen powders her nose.</context>
      <utterance>Telegram for Mr. Preysing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flaemmchen, believing the telegram to be something that she must copy, picks it up quite naturally and reads it.</context>
      <utterance>Oh -- oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing turns and snatches the telegram from her.</context>
      <utterance>Deal with Manchester Cotton Company definitely off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing paces the room with the telegram. Flaemmchen rises, stretches. Quite naturally she glances at the pictures on Preysing's dressing-table.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How nice -- your daughters?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daughters -- yes, my daughters.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Mrs. Preysing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Definitely off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- too bad. Did you quarrel?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flaemmchen, delighted and with alacrity, crosses, piles up her papers and is prepared to leave.</context>
      <utterance>That'll be all -- be here tomorrow at nine o'clock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are late -- the dancer's gone to the theatre.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's gone to the theatre -- don't you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pearls are in her room.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now listen to me. The others are getting suspicious of you. I was on the telephone to Amsterdam today, they think you're scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been careful, I've been waiting my chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been waiting your chance. You're too much of a gentleman -- that's the trouble with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you I'll get the pearls tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need any help?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the skeleton key out of his pocket and produces it to the Baron.</context>
      <utterance>Have you got that skeleton key?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The floor clerk is out there in the corridor -- she sees everything ---</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could take care of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chloroform on a handkerchief from behind -- while you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- no -- no -- no...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor girl -- chloroform would give her a rotten headache... I know -- I had it in the war. Besides, she's very pretty -- not young but --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're no good for this business. It's just a joke to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like your tone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baron is suddenly seized with uncontrollable temper -- twists his wrists -- backs him to door, speaks quietly.</context>
      <utterance>No --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out and leave it to me... be ready to leave on the night train for Amsterdam...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the pearls?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment he is gone -- Baron looks the door -- business ad lib. Crosses to window.</context>
      <utterance>With the pearls -- The Chauffeur leaves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHAMBERMAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, the Inspectress, a large stout woman, appears at the open door.</context>
      <utterance>No -- no -- there is no one here.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're late... What have you been doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, out of scene, we hear the voice of Suzette. Suzette is calling out to the night clerk in the passage.</context>
      <utterance>No, Madame Grusinskaya is not here... The Western Theater?... No...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen Madame?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzette comes in and hurries to telephone.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't she at the theatre?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, hello, Mr. Pimenov? Yes... Mr. Pimenov, have they found her?... No, she is not here... Yes, I'm at the hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the Baron watching.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pimenov?... What's happening?... No, I haven't found her. Is Desprez dancing?... How is it?... Oh, all right. Keep the show going.  Wait till I see her, she'll pay for this -- this little trick is going to cost Grusinskaya a suit for breach of contract.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame is ill -- her nerves...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and sees Grusinskaya standing at the door. She is in costume, very pale, very beautiful. Her coat, over one shoulder, is ragging, she lets it drop and moves slowly into the center of the room. Her hair, dressed for the dance, make-up is on her face -- she is breathless.</context>
      <utterance>Her nerves... What about my nerves?... Who is she anyway? Where does she think she is -- Russia? Those days have passed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame --</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other women in the room draw out, leaving Suzette to pick up the robe that has fallen to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>I want to be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I -- Does madame wish...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzette obediently crosses to door and pauses on threshold, waiting for Meierheim. Meierheim approaches Grusinskaya.</context>
      <utterance>Suzette, please go, I want to be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose I can cancel the Vienna engagement.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish to be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzette, with a frightened look through the door, closes it on Meierheim's exit.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be very much alone, my dear madame. This is the end.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="80">
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly she moves quickly across the room. Goes to bathroom. Baron half starts out toward door. He watches -- darts across the room as if towards the door. He hears her coming and darts quickly into the half open door of the closet. She re-enters -- carrying a glass of water. She crosses, places the glass down beside the bed -- her movements are quick and furtive -- then she crosses, picks up the telephone -- asks for the theatre.</context>
      <utterance>The end -- over -- finished --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves receiver down -- crosses quickly to mirror -- stands there and brushes back her hair -- crosses back to telephone speaks:</context>
      <utterance>The Western Theatre --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances up at the clock.</context>
      <utterance>Western Theatre?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again she puts the receiver down -- picking up a pencil she commences hastily to scribble a note. She writes frantically. Her other hand goes up and picks up the receiver.</context>
      <utterance>The stage -- Mr. Pimonov -- the ballet master... Grusinskaya -- hurry -- hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finishes the note -- commences suddenly to speak into the telephone --</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- yes, I'm waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is about to replace the receiver. She sits with it in her hand, unreplaced. The music has stopped. The room is strangely silent. Behind her the Baron peers from the closet. Her head sinks down upon her hands. A funny, singing noise comes from the telephone. She lifts the receiver to her ear. In a very strange voice, the voice of Opehlia, she speaks:</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Pimenov? -- I'm at the hotel. I couldn't go on -- I couldn't... No, no don't --  ...Just alone... Good night, good night, my dear -- goodbye... Pimenov, how is it going, badly?... Uh?... Who's dancing?... Desprez?... Oh -- and how is it?... Oh, -- oh, I see -- they didn't miss me?... They didn't miss me.  They didn't miss me -- good night, Pimenov...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances up at him. She is bewildered. She seems to be coming out of a trance. Again she wants to jump from the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Please, do not be alarmed, Madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she becomes conscious of almost nakedness. She draws her kimono tightly around her, glances across the wide expanse of bed. We see her consider passing over that way, but she is now a woman again -- a woman of the earth -- it would be a silly movement.</context>
      <utterance>Careful -- there's broken glass on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(takes a pillow from the bed throws it upon the floor over the glass, steps back) She gets up quickly and crosses, putting on her robe which was lying across the back of a chair. Her first movement is not one of alarm but of -- shame. She draws her robe more closely around her and looks at the Baron puzzled. She thinks, dreamily, "What is this?" She glances back at the veronal and the bed showing us plainly that this man must have watched her preparation for bed. We get a sense of relief with her. She is trembling. The Baron has controlled his nerves perfectly. He senses his danger. He is caught red-handed with five hundred thousand marks worth of pearls in his pocket. He is wondering if she will ring the bell. For an instant he thinks of escape. He could dash for the balcony. He could strike her dead or silence her with threats. There is in the room an intoxicating sense of romance and danger. (It should be in the scene.)</context>
      <utterance>There.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please do not be frightened, Madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing -- only to be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you hide in my room?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But surely you must know -- because I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him for a few moments and then suddenly she throws herself upon the bed and begins to weep more and more passionately.</context>
      <utterance>Because you love me -- you love me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor little Grusinskaya! Does it do you good to cry? Are you afraid? Shall I go?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was so alone -- always alone -- and suddenly you were there and said that.  No. I am not afraid. It is strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't cry -- it tears my heart to see you sob like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nerves -- just nerves. You must forgive me. I have had a bad evening. I am very tired. Do you know what it is to be tired -- tired of a routine existence?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look in his eyes reminds her of the strangeness of the situation. She rises with returning dignity and pulls her robe around her -- she is becoming the Grusinskaya of Imperial Russia; she is the woman Grand Dukes have fought for. She sweeps across the room.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid not -- I usually do just what I feel like doing at the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you feel like coming into a lady's room -- and you come... What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to smoke a cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets her cigarette box from the writing table and holds it out to him. He takes a cigarette and lights it. She watches him curiously. She smiles, as she watches him greedily inhale the smoke. She crosses and sits before her looking glass. She brushes her hair back and powders her face. She looks into the mirror, we feel that she has regained a desire to live. He crosses and looks at her in the mirror. He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you look at me like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not know you were so beautiful... and --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then --?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No irony. You're so appealing -- so soft -- so tired. I feel like taking you in my arms and not letting anything more happen to you -- ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And -- and --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How tired you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- tired...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alone. All alone.  Oh, you strange -- strange creature.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mustn't talk Russian to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strange man...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I quite strange to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite strange now. It is as if I had been expecting you. You know, once when the Grand Duke was alive, I found a man hiding in my room -- a young officer --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And...?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He disappeared. Later he was found dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he embraces her)</context>
      <utterance>I never knew it was so dangerous to hide in a woman's room when she's alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away. Who are you --?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man who could love -- that is all, who has forgotten everything else for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could love me. It is so long since I have heard that word. Nobody has loved me for a long time. It is so icy-cold to be famous. One is so cruelly alone. How is it that you -- Let me look at you. Your hands. Your eyes. Why could you love me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw you just now -- then I saw you cry -- and now I see you in the mirror -- Grusinskaya...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grusinskaya... Oh -- oh if you knew how I slaved and slaved for Grusinskaya -- for the success of Grusinskaya -- for the triumph of Grusinskaya... and what is she now? Just someone who has found that on the day success ceases life ceases -- Are you listening to me -- Do you understand? -- I want you to understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- I do understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you must go now -- the key is on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going -- You know I'm not going -- Let me stay here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is not so -- you don't want to be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be alone --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- You don't want to be alone at all -- You were in despair before -- If I left you, you'd feel worse than you did before, You must not be alone -- You mustn't cry -- you must forget... Tell me that I can stay with you -- tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Outside the distant noise of Kringelein is heard --</context>
      <utterance>Just for a minute then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whispers.</context>
      <utterance>What? Say it again -- I didn't hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The way she says it, the word goes home. It hurts him. She has looked into his eyes for a moment with a strangely melting and almost happy expression. She gets up suddenly. (NOTE: The other side of the bed -- not where the glass is) She reaches with her feet for her slippers. She puts one on. She can't find the other. Business as he gets other slipper for her. He kisses her ankle and looks up at her. She smiles down.</context>
      <utterance>You -- man...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of her own voice reassures her. She is generating warmth. Her cry has done her good, she speaks quickly, volubly.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you -- you are gallant.  What a sentimental scene. Grusinskaya weeping is a sight worth seeing. It is many years since she did such a thing... You frightened me -- badly. You're responsible for this -- painful scene. He watches her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The stage frays one's nerves... the discipline -- it's so exacting. Discipline means doing what you don't want to do and take no pleasure in doing. Do you know what I mean? Have you ever experienced the weariness that comes from discipline?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grusinskaya turns, she is graceful again.</context>
      <utterance>I? -- Oh, no. I do only what I take pleasure in doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see -- you do only what you take pleasure in doing. You take pleasure in coming into a woman's bedroom and you come. You take pleasure in a dangerous climb onto a balcony, so you do it... And what is your pleasure now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rises. She had expected something else. His reply strikes her as chivalrous and considerate. She crosses to the writing table brings back her little cigarette box which she holds out to him. He takes a cigarette and lights it. She watches him curiously. She smiles, as she watches him greedily inhale the smoke. She crosses and sits before her looking glass. She brushes her hair back and powders her face. She looks into the mirror, we feel that she has regained a desire to live. He crosses and looks at her in the mirror, he smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I should like to smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you smile?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I can see something in the mirror that you cannot. My dear --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are beautiful!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he stoops, takes her shoulder in his hands and kisses it. A long tender and sincere embrace. Her eyes close. A tremor passes through her. Suddenly his whole being is aware of her. She turns, rises and disengages herself.</context>
      <utterance>Beautiful but so sad. I did not know it was so dangerous to look into a woman's bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances back. He speaks suddenly with an air of command.</context>
      <utterance>I think you had better go now. The key is on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going... You know that I'm not going... Do you think I could leave you alone here? After that --?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The veronal -- you. I'm going to stay here with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is not the truth.  You do not want to be alone -- you're afraid of being alone -- I know you're afraid. I know you. You were desperate, just now, if I go away you'll be more desperate than ever. Say I am to stay with you... say it.  Her head falls slowly on his breast.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses quickly to her and holds her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>For just a minute then.  No -- oh, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Outside the distant noise of Kringelein and the doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Just for a minute, Grusinskaya --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRONT ON SHOT OF KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are returning from the bar and are passing Grusinskaya's room. THE CAMERA precedes them. The Doctor is characteristically drunk. He is silent, tense, cynical. A distinct contrast to Kringelein, whose soul is warmed for the first time by alcohol. Kringelein's hat, the same, eccentric one, is twisted upon his head jauntily. The carnation is in his buttonhole. THE CAMERA backs into Kringelein's room and pauses, because the Doctor has paused at the door.</context>
      <utterance>approaching the CAMERA with the Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, but Doctor. Isn't this wonderful. To live -- to live -- in the Grand Hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Grand Hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, but Doctor. The music -- the champagne -- girls when they dance -- all the shining ice in those big silver things -- That's life --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he leaves)</context>
      <utterance>Life! -- Mr. Kringelein, you are drunk -- good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein re-enters his beautiful room. He crosses to the mirror, regards himself. Business ad lib. He looks at himself in the mirror and raises his hat. Imitating the doctor, he repeats:</context>
      <utterance>But Doctor -- But the Doctor has gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his hat on the knob of the bed. He takes off his coat, holds it up and carefully takes the carnation out of his buttonhole. With the coat over his arm and the carnation in his hand he looks around for a glass and some water which he sees standing on the night table by his bed. He puts the carnation in the glass, having filled it with water and then his eyes fall upon his small group of medicine bottles. His demeanor changes. He immediately becomes a thing of pain. He glances at his watch -- it is long past his medicine time -- his spirit droops -- he might almost be in pain. He picks up a small bottle and carefully counts eight drops into the glass. He is about to take it, he smells it, a sudden impulse of well-being surges over him. He flings the medicine away. With a great wave of optimism he commences to sing the song that we have heard during the evening -- the chambermaid song - the Preysing radio song -- the love song. He saunters around the room, undressing.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kringelein -- you are drunk -- good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BARON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never been as happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRU'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never been as happy!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it again -- say it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have never been so happy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GIRL FIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grand Hotel -- good morning... who is calling Madam Grusinskaya?... Oh, Mr. Pimenov. Madam Grusinskaya is not to be disturbed, sir... no, sir... yes, sir -- The word passes down repeated.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Preysing's calls to one sixty two for today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>CONFERENCE ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerstenkorn, an old business man and Doctor Waitz, counsel for the Saxonia organization are sitting at a gree table, smoking and waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Telephone bell ringing. General shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine-thirty, Mr. Preysing keeps us waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHWEIMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He likes to play the great man.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Preysing stock is holding its own today on the market.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHWEIMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask Preysing what it's costing him to keep it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And ask me what it's costing us to hammer it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the Preysing people get the Manchester contract, we shall certainly merge with the Preysing company -- but if they haven't they're ruined -- Preysing will have to declare himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens and Flaemmchen enters. She is agreeably surprised to see the room full of men. She likes men.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh -- here he is now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Door opens suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, gentlemen -- Mr. Preysing will be here in a minute. Business of Schweimann and Flaemmchen. Gerstenkorn, making notes, glances at his watch again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late, I've been waiting for Justice Zinnowitz, my legal advisor.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- ho -- you want legal aid against us? -- The whole thing seems to me to be very simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very simple -- I've always liked the way you dressed, Preysing -- English, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They turn out marvelous material in Manchester.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flaemmchen, who has been busy preparing her little table for work is seen in several CLOSEUPS:</context>
      <utterance>Manchester -- yes. Yes, yes, they do. Yes -- Now gentlemen shall we begin at the beginning? -- Have we cigars -- water and everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHWEIMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manchester is a very interesting city, don't you think so, Preysing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manchester -- yes -- yes. A man in the textile industry naturally has to know Manchester.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a lot of business to be done with the Manchester Cotton Company. They've the whole English market right in their hands. Have you any connections with -- Manchester?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a good many connections in England, naturally.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean with the Manchester people?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are here to discuss our merger. Naturally I can make no statement at this time. We must begin at the beginning.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>interesting, with signals, winks and signs between the other three men.</context>
      <utterance>Since, on the eleventh of June, this year -- when the first negotiations for a merger between our respective firms was entered into -- both parties have fully agreed that this merger can result only in mutual advantages. INTERCUT this speech, which if played by Beery will be</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- yes -- I beg your pardon!</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm laying before you the last general statement of our concern. Active capital, plant and machinery, raw material and finished product -- for instance -- mop rags --</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Business between Preysing and Flaemmchen finding papers on 'Mop Rag' report.</context>
      <utterance>Mop rags --!</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What we want to know about is Manchester.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Preysing -- that's what we want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to wait for Justice Zinnowitz, before I commit myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- Preysing, Preysing --</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No water -- What a place!</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flaemmchen, who is on her toes and busy every minute, rushes to the telephone and gives an order -- her conversation is heard over the conversation of the men in the room -- CAMERA</context>
      <utterance>All you have to do is phone for it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Water -- seltzer, three or four bottles and cigars -- good ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see this session is going to be exhaustive.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now to proceed with the projected merger, the advantages for the Saxonia are so obvious...</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- now let's talk like adults. You want to tell us now a along story of what your factory can do. We know all that you could tell us and if you tell the truth it wouldn't sound so good. When you first approached us...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did not approach you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Letter on file September fourteenth would show that you approached...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't so -- this was a response to a tentative feeler of your own.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tentative my foot -- a month before this your old father-in-law came very privately and scratched at my door.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scratched --  We did not take the initiative.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zinnowitz enters the room.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you took the initiative.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, gentlemen -- I see the conference is already underway.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, here you are, Justice Zinnowitz -- I'm at cross-purposes with these gentlemen -- will you clear up the situation?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the situation is perfectly clear, If you will allow me --</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How clear is Manchester?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Foggy -- frightfully foggy, always, I'm told.  Have you said anything about Manchester, Mr. Preysing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can make no statement about Manchester at this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is dead silence for a moment -- he clears his throat, commences in almost the same tone as Preysing.</context>
      <utterance>Well -- gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since, on the eleventh of June of this year -- when the first negotiations for a merger...</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God we're beginning at the beginning.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you remember it -- when you approached us...</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did not approach you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you did -- I said you did --</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I said we didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During all this commotion Flaemmchen is paying no attention whatsoever. She is calmly spraying herself with a perfume atomizer and smiling at a gentleman. The noise continues over her.</context>
      <utterance>And I know we didn't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="57">
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- I was ambitious then -- ambition was in my blood -- no rest, no stopping. We were drilled like little soldiers -- We danced in the school of the Imperial Ballet, in St. Petersburg. I was little and slim but hard as diamond -- a duty machine -- No rest, no stopping. And then -- I became famous and whoever is famous is alone... But why should I be telling you this? Last night I did not know you at all -- who are you, really? -- I do not even know your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Felix Benvenuto von Gaigern. My mother called me Flix.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flix. -- And how do you live? What kind of a person are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a prodigal son, the black sheep of a white flock -- I shall die on the gallows.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, I haven't a bit of character. None at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was a little boy I was taught to ride and be a gentleman -- at school, it was a monastery, I learned to pray and lie -- and ---</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then, in the war, to kill and hide. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do you do -- now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a gambler -- I'm running at large like a happy pig, devouring anything of life that pleases me, I really belong in jail</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! What a picture -- and what else?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he turns away)</context>
      <utterance>I'm also a criminal and a hotel thief.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a silly joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please look at me. You must believe me -- you must believe that I love you -- that I have never known what love is -- until last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does not answer.</context>
      <utterance>What is the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron takes the pearls out of his pocket and lays them before her.</context>
      <utterance>Flix!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron makes a gesture as if to stroke her hair and then holds back.</context>
      <utterance>Oh --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is suddenly cold.</context>
      <utterance>Did you come here just -- just for that? Oh -- it's horrible. Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may keep the pearls -- I don't want them any more -- I'll make you a present of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want them now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll not denounce you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesterday I was a thief -- but now, --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But now, you must go... I give you the pearls. But now you must go ---</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted money desperately -- Can you understand? -- That's why I wanted the pearls. I was threatened -- I was desperately in need of a certain big sum of money. I've been following you -- I've admired you. But I have forced myself not to think about you -- Last night, at last, I managed to came into your room and -- and now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand touches her hair -- tenderly.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't go through with it.  Remarkable.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a sudden knock at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- yes -- yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a quick gesture Grusinskaya beckons the Baron to the bathroom. He disappears into the bathroom. She opens the door, after finding the key and radiantly addresses Suzette.</context>
      <utterance>Quickly -- here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Suzette.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charming piece of business as Suzette, in putting the coffee down on the table must necessarily push back the heavily crested cigarette case of the Baron.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Madam. She puts the coffee down on the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam has slept well?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, Suzette.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam will dress now, it is late.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five minutes, Suzette, come back in five minutes. I'll ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is a French woman. She is pleased.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, madam Suzette knows all about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Grusinskaya hurries Suzette to the door she says:</context>
      <utterance>Madam is beautiful this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzette goes out. Quickly Grusinskaya crosses and flings open the bathroom door. The Baron comes out.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Suzette.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she speaks the telephone goes. She gives the telephone a dirty look. Telephone rings again. She pulls him across to the telephone.</context>
      <utterance>You must go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a hand in his she lifts the telephone receiver and speaks.</context>
      <utterance>There -- it begins.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this scene the Baron is touching her shoulder. A charming light moment. She continues to speak into telephone. His touch probably tickles her, she laughs -- quickly covers the receiver so that Meierheim will not hear her laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Hello -- hello -- Meierheim? Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this scene she is listening to Meierheim. She frowns suddenly --</context>
      <utterance>No --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to the Baron and their arms go around each other. The telephone rings again.</context>
      <utterance>What?... Cancel Vienna?... Are you mad? We always have great success in Vienna... Certainly not. Come here and see me... yes... good-bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lets the telephone ring.</context>
      <utterance>There -- the day begins... I must go to rehearsal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grusinskaya --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do believe that I really love you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- If I didn't believe that, I'd die after last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be good to you -- madly good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suzette will be back here in a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go -- good-bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall I see you again?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suzette will be back here any minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When are you leaving Berlin?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very early in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For Vienna?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't -- can't you -- Couldn't you come too -- I think it would be better -- for us -- for us both.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- yes but -- later.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why later?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no money now -- I must get some first -- I must get some.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you what you need -- I have money.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no -- that would spoil everything. I'll -- I will manage somehow -- I'll manage myself. I will go with you. When does the train leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six twenty-seven in the morning... But the money?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind -- I'll get it. I have a whole day. I'll be on that train.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Telephone starts ringing.</context>
      <utterance>I shall dance and you'll be with me and then -- listen -- After that you will come with me to Lake Como, I have a villa there. The sun will be shining. I will take a vacation -- six weeks -- eight weeks. We'll be happy and lazy. And then you will go with me to South America -- oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must go now. Be careful on your way to your room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds him back. The telephone is ringing.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go. -- I love you.  I'll be on that train. I'll get the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do anything foolish -- I'm alarmed about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alone with the telephone bell ringing, Grusinskaya breathes deeply, stretches herself. She goes to the glass and looks at herself -- smiling. Happily she takes the pearls, kisses them, drops them into the casket -- picks up the telephone.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'll be on the train.  He leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a knock at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Not that dark dress -- something light -- bright -- it's a sunny morning, Suzette. Suzette happily glances at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come in.  Pimenov enters, before he can speak --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Pimenov.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can start speaking of last night she quickly speaks:</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Gru -- your --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this scene Grusinskaya has not looked at him, she is busy in the glass. Nice photography on hair and face. Side scene between Suzette and Pimenov, as Suzette shows him the cigarette case on the table. As he goes through the door Grusinskaya crosses and almost sweeps Suzette to the door with him.</context>
      <utterance>Pimenov, I have an idea -- a new ballet -- it must have mad music -- I'll explain it to you later. But now, hurry to the theatre -- I want full rehearsal -- properties -- full ballet and some musicians. Hurry -- Quickly. I will be there --</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gru -- you are positively radiant.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grusinskaya shuts the door. She sweeps happily to the telephone.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Pimenov.  One minute, Suzette, I will call you. They leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While she waits, she moves with a sense of dance.</context>
      <utterance>Hello -- will you -- will you get me Baron von Gaigern, please... yes... Baron von Gaigern -- yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you get me Baron von Gaigern, please...  Cherie... yes... it is you... nothing... good morning, good morning, cherie... nothing... no... just to tell you I'm happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chauffeur makes no effort to move. Against the normal busy, happy traffic of the evening he is a sinister figure. He does not move but glares at Senf.</context>
      <utterance>Step back please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've told you three times -- Baron von Gaigern is out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he leave any message for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This whole scene is played in a very low key, almost in a whisper, it is interrupted by the entrance of the Doctor.</context>
      <utterance>No, he did not -- there is no message.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any letters?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this short scene the chauffeur saunters off. Kringelein comes to the doctor.</context>
      <utterance>No, doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein's voice diminishes as the CAMERA MOVES following the chauffeur. The chauffeur saunters unthoughtfully past the florist shop and out of the door. As we pass the florist shop we see the back of the Baron in the shot. CAMERA PANS chauffeur out to door. He has not seen the Baron in the florist shop. THE CAMERA PANS back to florist shop waits for the Baron who emerges carrying his usual box of orchids. CAMERA FOLLOWS BARON back to Senf's desk. Key shot.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Doctor, such a day -- such a day! They move away from the scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam Grusinskaya.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For Madam Grusinskaya.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam Grusinskaya -- at once --</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your chauffeur's been waiting, Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron approaches them.</context>
      <utterance>All right.  Kringelein is speaking to the doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baron, we must have gone a hundred miles an hour, at least...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, quite.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been together all day... and in an aeroplane.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life is changing you, Mr. Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron smiles. He slaps his gauntlets on his dusty coat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, thanks to the Baron. The best shops, the very best. Look, Doctor, silk -- feels so nice on the skin... a London hat, see -- made in England, that's silk, too -- fifty marks... Look, the price is on it. That was half my salary before. The Baron is a very fine gentleman -- no one in my life has been so nice to me as the Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to change and we'll meet for a drink in the Yellow Room.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the Yellow Room, where the music's playing and the ladies are?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Where the music's playing and the ladies are...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No pain, Mr. Kringelein?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Kringelein is talking, they move away from the CAMERA.</context>
      <utterance>Pain? Oh, no, Doctor. I think if I had pain I'd be too happy to notice it... NOTE: Find cut here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and let me say again for the tenth time...  ...you people were quite ready for the merger. You declared yourselves... fully agreed on all the terms -- Why should the signing of these articles be suddenly held up?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing jumps to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>I've admitted that at one time we had reason for desiring ther merger -- What reason have we now? The Preysing Company has fallon upon evil days, very evil days.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evil days -- I've shown you here --  -- my company exports to the Balkans alone, sixty-five thousand marks worth of mop rags a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mop rags -- mop rags -- we're interested in something quite different!</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHWEIMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall I tell them again?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why waste time -- it's getting late.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHWEIMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see -- what we are interested in --</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Due to the long tedious session the men's collars are wilted.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, come on -- we're going home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Preysing has too scrupulous a regard for certainties...</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've talked enough today, you're hoarse now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he gets his hat)</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Preysing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've decided against the merger?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes --</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, it's all over?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes --</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a general movement to go.</context>
      <utterance>Well -- well -- You could call my office.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GENERAL SHOT OF ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gerstenkorn crosses to Preysing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Preysing, I hope you pull through. This is a very bad time to be in such a crisis. We've...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why talk -- it's over -- it's over -- it's finished. You've broken off negotiations. You did it. You're calling them off. You had nothing on your mind all day, but Manchester, -- Manchester -- Manchester.  You don't suppose for one moment that I'm such a fool as not to have something that I could say definitely about Manchester.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no -- no -- the session is over. Let's go, it's off. Thank you, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you actually have news from Manchester then...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, I am now free to announce...  ...that the deal between my firm and the Manchester Cotton Company has been successfully negotiated.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Preysing, you're joking with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHWEIMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a deep one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In that case give us the articles. We'll sign at once. We know all the details...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we'd suspended negotiations, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under these circumstances it's quite a different matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By this time, Waitz and Zinnowitz have the articles out upon the table. Preysing is perspiring. Gerstenkorn puts his arms around Preysing's shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Under these circumstances we might refuse to sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerstenkorn picks up the papers glances at them, looks at Waitz. Flaemmchen is awakening.</context>
      <utterance>Come on -- business is business -- Come on -- Preysing stands, looking ahead of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's my signature -- here Preysing, sign here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Preysing is signing.</context>
      <utterance>What a session this has been.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHWEIMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's twenty-five to six.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should celebrate this with a bottle of wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERSTENKORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you soon, Preysing. Next week we'll meet and discuss further details.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hasty hand-shaking, business of exits. Waitz, Gerstenkorn and Schweimann out. Preysing has not moved. Zinnowitz takes the agreement and waves it in the air to dry the signature.</context>
      <utterance>Next week.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next week.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zinnowitz amiably shrugs his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>You let me talk till I'm hoarse and you had Manchester sewed-up all the time. Why? Preysing does not answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing commences to laugh suddenly with increasing violence.</context>
      <utterance>Well -- the deal has been put through.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this scene, Flaemmchen has risen, piled up her papers, glanced at her watch. During this action Flaemmchen motions to Zinnowitz that she is going down to dance, etc., Preysing is unaware of this action. Flaemmchen leaves the room trying not to attract attention.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it has been put through -- it has been put through.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bluff -- Bluff -- all bluff.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's bluff?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Deal with Manchester definitely off! "Preysing, oh -- I'd never have thought it of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he turns away)</context>
      <utterance>No one would have thought it of me. I've been getting rusty in Fredersdorf. Well, if bluff is what the world wants I guess I can put up as big a bluff as anyone. From now on...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must go to Manchester at once yourself and really see it through.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- I must go to England -- I was desperate -- Now I don't care -- This sort of thing goes to a man's head.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you need is some relaxation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- that's what I want -- I'd like to tear loose -- I'd like a drink. I'd like to go down to that dancing place. I'd like to start something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can understand that -- after your -- uh --</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it -- say it -- my lie -- it's the first time in thirty years that I've ever... Where's that stenographer? Miss Flaemm...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to see her, I want to do some dictating -- report of the conference for my father-in-law.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had an engagement in the Yellow Room at five o'clock -- she was in a hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zinnowitz, would you say she was pretty?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty as a picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go down and find her -- I need a drink -- Come along Zinnowitz.  I don't know anything about women -- been married for twenty-six years.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZINNOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing is very excited, they start to leave -- at that moment the telephone rings.</context>
      <utterance>Bluff does it, Preysing, bluff does it. Goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses to the telephone.</context>
      <utterance>Aeh!</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When he picks the telephone up his hands are shaking --</context>
      <utterance>Hello... Father-in-law?... Is that you?... The agreement is signed -- I did it... yes, father-in-law... but now I must go to Manchester.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barman -- whiskey --  For you, Mr. Kringelein?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For me? -- Oh, please, something sweet and cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Louisiana flip, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the following speech Kringelein keeps reaching for the moustache that is not there. He is thoroughly happy.</context>
      <utterance>A Louisiana flip, that sounds very nice -- sweet, eh? --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment Flaemmchen enters.</context>
      <utterance>What do you do in the Grand Hotel? Eat -- sleep -- loaf around -- do business -- flirt a little -- dance a little. A hundred doors to one hall and nobody knows anything about the person next to him. When you leave another takes your room and lies in your bed -- the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening, Mr. Kringelein -- Where's the Baron?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm waiting for him here. The Baron and I have been together all day. A hundred miles an hour -- in a motor car -- and in an aeroplane -- It was marvelous --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kringelein -- How you have changed, you look so nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you, Miss Flaemm. Oh, please, Miss Flaemm -- Permit me, Miss Flaemm, won't you have something sweet -- a Louisiana flip.  A Louisiana flip.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No - absinthe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein is beating time to the music -- a little carried away. Flaemmchen laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- that --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like music?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- it's stimulating -- a man might --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man might what?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know -- I'd like to do anything --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron enters quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh -- you would!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello -- sorry I'm late.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- here you are, Baron. A drink -- A Louisiana flip?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Kringelein. How do you feel now?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little strange, Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd given you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A drink, Baron -- A Louisiana flip?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks -- keeping my head clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(they exit)</context>
      <utterance>Dance then?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's beautiful -- isn't she?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- there are plenty of women.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you been doing all day?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chasing around.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chasing what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dance a few steps, in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Money.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were very different yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dance into the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Yesterday -- yes -- that was yesterday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Mr. Kringelein, are you getting what you're looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, Doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A masculine paradise -- drink, the ladies, dancing...</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a very good opportunity, a young lady asked me to dance -- I ought to be able to dance, it seems to be very important.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must learn as quickly as your time allows -- Believe me Mr. Kringelein, a man who isn't with a woman is a dead man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't you anyone -- Haven't you anybody -- you -- I mean -- Are you all alone in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm always alone -- I have been everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The music has stopped.</context>
      <utterance>I was sent as a military surgeon to South Africa. Stinking climate. Taken prisoner. Home on parole not to fight. I was a surgeon in the Great War till the end. Grenade in the face. Carried diphtheria bacilli in the wound until 1920. Isolated two years.  I've been everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was lovely.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you do me a big favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do anything for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to make a man happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- I'd love to.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then dance the next number with Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel sorry for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not a bit like you were yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fell in love last night -- the real thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- there's no real thing -- it doesn't exist.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought that, too -- but I found that it does. Come along, dance with Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move off. As they approach the bar, happily Preysing pushes into scene, touches Flaemmchen's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Anything for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Flaemm.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello!</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must speak with you, Miss Flaemm.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Presently, Mr. Preysing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's urgent.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me, the lady has urgent business here with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment Kringelein has descended from the stool and crosses to Preysing.</context>
      <utterance>Insolent -- Berlin manners.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you a very good evening, Mr. Preysing. You are staying here, too, Mr. Preysing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- you must know me -- Kringelein at the plant. Assistant bookkeeper, building C, room twenty-three -- third floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come and dance with me, Mr. Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must speak to you, Miss Flaemm -- business.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They bow stiffly.</context>
      <utterance>Do you gentlemen know each other, Mr. Kringelein -- Mr. Preysing -- Baron von Gaigern.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kringelein will be a good friend and not accept your invitation to dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could not think of not accepting.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein stands watching Preysing, his eyes narrowing.</context>
      <utterance>You say that you are employed by us in Fredersdorf, and here you are in Berlin, indulging in diversions which ill befit your position and which are very much beyond your means -- Quite extraordinary, Mr. Kringelein, I think we will look into your books.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, children, no fighting -- save that for the office. Let's have our dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll remember you, Mr. Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, let the poor devil alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men eye each other; for a moment there might be a fight.</context>
      <utterance>I did not ask your advice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it would be much better if you went away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We shall see who remains here the longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing leans against the bar, orders a cognac. The Baron turns his back to him, watching the dancing.</context>
      <utterance>As you will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must look at my face and not at the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're trembling.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never danced before -- in public.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dance splendidly.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm happy, Miss Flaemm.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flaemmchen watches him quickly.</context>
      <utterance>For the first time in my life, I'm happy. Kringelein shows signs of exhaustion.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is obvious that she has stopped because of Kringelein's distress.</context>
      <utterance>Let's stop -- I'm tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move back to the bar. Preysing catches Flaemmchen's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Miss Flaemm.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well now, Miss Flaemm, we can talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some champagne, Miss Flaemm?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may go, Mr. Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does the world belong to you, Mr. Preysing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this insolence?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think you have free license to be insulting? Believe me you have not. You think you're superior, but you're quite an ordinary man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away -- go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please -- please!</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't like to see me enjoying myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you? -- An embezzler most likely.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An embezzler -- you're going to take that back, right here in the presence of this young lady -- who do you think you're talking to? You think I'm dirt, if I'm dirt, you're a lot dirtier, Mr. Industrial Magnate Preysing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're discharged.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein's hat has fallen from the stool upon the floor. Flaemmchen picks it up, brushes it. Kringelein starts to laugh. The Baron steps into the scene. The Doctor slowly comes from the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Yes you -- shut your mouth -- get out -- you're discharged.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron steps between the two looking straight into Preysing's face.</context>
      <utterance>You can't discharge me -- I'm my own master now -- at last. I'm ill, I'm going to die -- do you understand? I'm going to die very soon. Nothing can happen to me now. Nobody can do anything any more to me. By the time you can have discharged me I shall have been dead already.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come, Mr. Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man's insane -- he acts as if he is glad he is going to die...  I shall see you in the lobby in half an hour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>HOUSE DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better let him stay -- I've sent for the Baron... How's your wife coming along?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was at the hospital all night walking up and down the corridor. They wouldn't let me in to see her. She has the pains, but the child doesn't come and I have to stay here chained to this desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSE DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will be all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment Preysing enters.</context>
      <utterance>I hope so.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you send that page?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing glances off to see Flaemmchen standing looking around. Preysing crosses to Flaemmchen.</context>
      <utterance>The young lady's there, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, Mr. Preysing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit here.  Cognac -- for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment the Baron and Kringelein pass. Preysing glances up at Kringelein as he passes.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to keep an eye on that Kringelein fellow. I'll find out where he gets the money to hang around the Grand Hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- you want me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must go to England -- at once.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, I'd like to take a secretary with me for my correspondence and -- humm -- humm -- for company on the trip -- I'm nervous -- I need somebody -- I don't know if you quite understand me. You said you have travelled with gentlemen -- and I mean --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand perfectly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think your salary would be -- for such a trip?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait -- I must figure it up.  First, I'll need -- clothes -- shoes -- it's cold in England in March, I'll need a suit... You'd want me to look nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he is fidgeting)</context>
      <utterance>Of course -- of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A thousand marks --</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is looking away.</context>
      <utterance>It's agreed -- I will get a room here for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She still looks away.</context>
      <utterance>I can get a room here in the Grand Hotel for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you pay some attention to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Insolent young cub!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean Baron von Gaigern?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baron!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he's a gentleman!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He slumps on the arm of the chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Baron is tired?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Kringelein, not tired, -- just --  Well -- well --</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps this evening, Baron, we could go to the Casino -- the place we passed with the marvelous bright lights?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to Kringelein, but I can't -- I am broke!</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Broke -- A Baron? But, Baron -- The Baron looks off, sees the chauffeur --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BARON AND CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moving into position. They are talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to get those pearls and neither are you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the money?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll pay you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have an idea working in my head...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might find a bullet through that head...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you did that, you'd get nothing except the police after you. If you wait -- I'll give you your six thousand back -- At that moment a voice is heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is passed along.</context>
      <utterance>Madam Grusinskaya's car -- Madam Grusinskaya's car.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSIDE PORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam Grusinskaya's car --</utterance>
   <speaker>MEGAPHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam Grusinskaya's car --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Later.  Baron looks off...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She and the Baron are alone.</context>
      <utterance>Go on please -- go on, Suzette.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless you...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you coming to the theatre? Oh -- I shall dance tonight -- How I shall dance -- I want to feel that you are in the theatre.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I can't explain now. Oh, look -- the pearls. You wear them now...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you think --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've brought me such good luck -- you -- He takes her hand, kisses it quietly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm worried about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the train?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- I will be on the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Till then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this scene Kringelein has been hovering nearby. As Grusinskaya turns away and exits, Kringelein approaches the Baron, who is standing perfectly still, looking off, -- his mind miles away.</context>
      <utterance>Bless you --</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was the Baron joking, or is it really true that the Baron is -- in financial straits.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely true, Kringelein and I have to raise some money immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the Baron -- if you would permit me -- The Baron looks at him suddenly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would be awfully glad to oblige, you've been so decent to me. Three hundred?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I could get into a game I might win some.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gambling! I'd like that. I have over six thousand eight hundred marks with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we could scare up some men to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could come to my room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment Flaemmchen passes.</context>
      <utterance>Good!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flaemmchen hesitates as though she wanted to say something that is on her mind. A curious little scene. She doesn't speak, she just turns suddenly through the door. The Baron glances after her a little puzzled, turns back to Kringelein.</context>
      <utterance>Yes --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready, Kringelein?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move off and are last in the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Ready, Baron.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="80">
   <speaker>BARON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I play -- I play -- Here -- Up -- Playing --</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several men glance at Kringelein and the size of his stake.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that too much, Baron?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is tension in the room. The Baron deals two cards. Kringelein takes cards.</context>
      <utterance>All right then.</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein turns it down. He is like a little boy learning a new game. The Baron deals himself a card.</context>
      <utterance>Don't show them.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron is serious. There is enough money on the table to take him to Vienna.</context>
      <utterance>What do I do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn 'em up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes -- that's right -- look! I win, don't I --  The Baron rises.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you are gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you take the bank, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein kisses the Baron -- he looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- I'll take everything gentlemen -- please, let us drink -- champagne --- champagne is expensive and good. I'm winning more than I used to earn in a year -- double what I used to earn.  They hand him the cards.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the side table the Baron is standing -- he is drinking -- his face is white -- he has lost.</context>
      <utterance>Where is the Baron -- where are you, Baron?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein has come to the Baron.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take the bank -- All right, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was my last.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've lost everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've no luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baron pours out a glass of champagne -- he has been drinking plenty -- he hands glass to Kringelein.</context>
      <utterance>Pardon me, Baron. Permit me again...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drink to me, Kringelein -- it's my last chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I take five hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron picks cards, shows them to Kringelein who doesn't understand.</context>
      <utterance>All of that at once, Baron?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he is triumphant.)</context>
      <utterance>Eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron throws the cards into the middle of the table and turns to Kringelein:</context>
      <utterance>Nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he walks away.)</context>
      <utterance>That's it. The luck's with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come along, Mr. Kringelein. Sit here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm having luck for the first time in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein seats himself, puts his glass of champagne down on the table. Doctor leaves table, crosses to Baron who is pouring another drink.</context>
      <utterance>Your bank, Mr. Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out, Baron?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a while -- I'll recover -- in ten or twenty years.  Look at that. He has pointed and turned off because we hear Kringelein's voice:</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baron moves out of scene followed by Doctor. As Baron approaches table.</context>
      <utterance>I've won again, Baron -- I've won again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the foregoing scene, one of the men at the table has answered the ringing of the telephone bell, he comes back now.</context>
      <utterance>Baron, I drink and win -- I drink and win -- I win and drink!</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are complaints in the hotel about the noise.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Business ad lib. General business of slow normal exit. Kringelein looks up from counting his money. He has been like a little boy with a Christmas stocking. He looks up suddenly, sees men are leaving --</context>
      <utterance>What time is it? Getting late? Let's break it up!  You've been very lucky... Where's my coat? Let's go. He's drunk anyway!... Goodnight, Baron. Let's wind up the game, I'm broke and tired; you can't play against him. I put my hat down here, somewhere. I think I'll have a drink before I go. By the way, I've got to see you tomorrow morning. How've you been, Doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't go, gentlemen! -- Stay a while.  Be my guests! By this time the men are pausing by the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I oughtn't to presume, but I --  I'm so grateful to you -- it's been so marvelous. The first time in my life I have gambled -- I've danced! Oh, you can laugh, gentlemen, but it's the first time in my life I've ever tasted life!</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a general feeling in the room that although this man is drunk he is terribly sincere, and that there is no wish to embarrass themselves or him. In fact, there is a nervous impatient movement among the men. But Kringelein has reached an emotional pitch.</context>
      <utterance>Splendid!</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life, gentlemen, is wonderful, but very dangerous. You must have courage for it, then it's wonderful. You gentlemen don't know that because you are all healthy and happy, but I -- believe me -- a man must know death and not until then does a man know anything about life.</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a short life and a gay one...</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor is there quickly. The Baron next.</context>
      <utterance>Every glass high to life -- the splendid, dangerous, mighty, brief -- brief life -- and the courage to live it.  Baron, you know -- I've only lived since last night -- but that little while seems longer than all the time before -- all the --  Business ad lib.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>General normal business ad lib between the men. Perhaps three of them help him up, including the Baron. They carry Kringelein to the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Poor fellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drunk? No, he's ill. Looks ill.  He's a doctor -- The doctor's here -- He's just drunk!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, this man is ill -- very ill -- if you will leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly, Doctor. Goodnight! Goodnight, Baron! Bad luck!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNKEN MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT FOR RELIEF -- Kringelein's face -- white, drawn, tragic. One man, perhaps, remains.</context>
      <utterance>He's not used to champagne -- why does he drink it? Little comedy on exit. Ad lib.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help, doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, the Baron will stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man leaves. During this scene the Baron has been carefully making Kringelein comfortable on the bed, bolstering pillows behind his head. Kringelein's eyes are shut tightly, his hands are limp. By the business of the Baron, although we do not of course know it, this is the time that he takes the wallet from Kringelein and puts it in his own pocket. We might perhaps remember a sudden turn away in which we see his back and his right hand raised as though reaching in his inside pocket -- He stands looking down at Kringelein.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein's eyes flutter. His voice sounds hoarsely:</context>
      <utterance>It will be over in a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over -- over so soon -- it has just begun.  Oh, the pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try and sleep, Kringelein, don't be afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to live a little longer but -- I'm not afraid to die -- I'm not...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be all right, Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My pocketbook... my money in it...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We watch Baron's face, he looks back over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>What do you say -- what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You what -- Oh, isn't it there?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baron turns in this scene. He walks forward toward them. The Doctor's hands are on Kringelein's coat.</context>
      <utterance>No -- But no I -- Baron, I've lost my pocketbook.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(He glances down)</context>
      <utterance>There is no pocketbook here... On the floor probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than fourteen thousand marks... were in that pocketbook.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fourteen thousand marks... One can travel -- one's happiness might depend on fourteen thousand marks -- don't you think so, Baron?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, Kringelein, who has been staring up at the ceiling, his hands clenching and reclenching, starts up.</context>
      <utterance>Quite possibly.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I've got to find it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- I must find it --  Fourteen thousand two hundred marks.  The doctor goes to restrain him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is suddenly on his hands and knees, crawling along the floor, looking for it, like a little boy; his drunkenness, his condition, makes the situation tragic. He actually gets under the card table. The Doctor looks at the Baron. The Baron only watches Kringelein. He follows him, fascinated.</context>
      <utterance>I'm all right, Doctor. There's no pain now -- only you don't know what that money means to a man like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now, Kringelein lies upon the floor, a troubled little sack of pain, his head down. The Baron turns away. He bends down as though he were looking for the pocketbook. We see him take it from his pocket and turn. There is a very light, almost triumphant ring in his voice as he says:</context>
      <utterance>He must find his money, Baron.  Mr. Kringelein should find his pocketbook, Baron, shouldn't he? These are two interjections.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here -- here it is. Here's your pocketbook, Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- yes -- that's it -- you found it -- you found it for me, Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- no please -- oh, don't go -- don't go -- don't leave me alone, Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've nothing to fear, Kringelein</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NOTE: If he is a strong actor he can pick Kringelein up -- If not, he and Doctor lift Kringelein to bed.</context>
      <utterance>Come, get up -- come let me help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all right now -- it's very late -- goodnight, Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baron bites his lip. It is the first and only time in the play that we see a tear near -- the strong man almost breaks.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, stay here, Baron -- stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flaemmchen, what are you doing here in the middle of the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking for my room -- one sixty- six.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You live here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- such is life, Flaemmchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both go into their respective rooms. Here are our two gay young characters. The gay, fresh Flaemmchen and the debonair Baron, crucified for lack of funds. Both trying to smile, both trying to be light about themselves. Yet, each about to involve themselves tragically for the want of a little money.</context>
      <utterance>And Baron, thanks so much for everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes to his arms passively. He rubs his face in her hair. She is passive -- cold.</context>
      <utterance>Flaemmchen!</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are late. I've been waiting for you -- waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to arrange about the trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds her again, trying to kiss her. She deliberately avoids his kiss.</context>
      <utterance>You think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing rises while she pulls her night dress from under him. He draws her to him.</context>
      <utterance>Here, hold up!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- careful, Mr. Preysing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me -- do you know -- would you -- would you like to call me by my first name?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't do that, you're a stranger to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a funny little creature, Flaemmchen. I can't make you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing laughs. She laughs.</context>
      <utterance>It's not funny at all. One can't get intimate just off hand. I could go to England with you and everything like that -- supposing I met you next year and I said: 'How do you do, Mr. Preysing! And you said:  'That was the young lady who was my secretary in Manchester'.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a pause for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>That's all quite proper.  But supposing I met you when you were with your wife and I called out: "Hello you big baby -- remember Manchester?' And you with your wife, how would you like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flaemmchen yawns straight in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Flaemmchen -- we'll leave my wife out of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves towards the windows which are open. She pushes his fat body out, almost playfully, through the doors and onto the balcony. Preysing stands out on the balcony. He looks down in the street below, then off. He starts suddenly because he sees a shadow over the railing of his own balcony. He is puzzled. Shadow crosses again. "Who can be in his room?" He moves forward and peeps through the window. One side of the French window is closed. From his angle we see the Baron furtively searching the room. He is now wearing an overcoat, the collar is turned up. Business ad lib. He finds Preysing's wallet. He stuffs this in his overcoat pocket. Preysing's face watching him. As Baron turns to exit, Preysing surges forward, pulling the window after him. The two men face each other.</context>
      <utterance>All right. I'll get undressed -- get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aha! -- The Baron. What do you want here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must have made a mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron hands him the pocketbook without a word.</context>
      <utterance>Made a mistake -- remarkable. We shall soon see if you made a mistake.   Stay here... Give me that money.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's how we stand, Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look here, sir -- I'm completely at your mercy -- I'm desperate -- it's a matter of life or death -- I had to get some money -- tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed you must, Baron -- you must. Humm -- humm, but you must go to jail, Baron, you're a thief.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron makes for the door on the other side of the room, pulls at the knob.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to call the police. I'm going to watch you play the great Baron with the police. Aristocrat! Aristocrat!</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron makes one dive across the room. Preysing grasps at his coat and tears it. With one hand holding the telephone, (the receiver dropping on its cord towards the ground) and one hand holding the Baron.</context>
      <utterance>The door is locked, Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello! Hello! --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing wrenches the telephone suddenly away from the Baron. The action excites him.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a terrific lunge, Preysing brings the telephone down upon the Baron's head. The Baron sways, stunned. (as in book). In his mad rage, Preysing, hits again with the telephone.</context>
      <utterance>Strike me, would you? Attack me would you? Attack me --</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By this time the Baron is a heap on the floor. We see Preysing come out of his blind trance. He even repeats again.</context>
      <utterance>I'll strike you -- I'll strike you -- I'll strike you -- Strike me!</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I strike you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOWNSTAIRS TELEPHONE ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dozing night girl plugs in, lazily.</context>
      <utterance>Sharp sound of buzzing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHT GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With nonchalance she flicks plug out again, as she does so:</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- yes -- Operator -- Operator --  They are having a nice little game up there with the telephone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sweeps to bed. She shakes him. Kringelein starts up.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kringelein -- Mr. Kringelein -- where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quick -- Mr. Kringelein.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls on the light by the bed, it flames up on their faces.</context>
      <utterance>Oh -- what -- what --</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- oh, Miss Flaemmchen. It's you --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quick -- something awful -- awful has happened. Go -- go at once, -- Mr. Preysing --</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It occurs to him that this girl with her torn clothes must have been roughly treated by Preysing. He suddenly assumes a strength.</context>
      <utterance>Preysing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slides down to the floor, by the side of the bed. Kringelein climbs out of bed, tries to help her up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't wait -- go -- it's awful -- it's awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waves him away.</context>
      <utterance>Stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein assumes suddenly a strength. He is a man for a crisis -- he forgets that he was ever ill -- he leaves. WE GO WITH HIM. CUT HIM DOWN CORRIDOR QUICKLY. He pauses outside Preysing's door, uncertain of the rooms, then he knocks.</context>
      <utterance>Don't wait now -- go -- Preysing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- the Baron -- the Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He tried to rob me -- he is dead --</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My best friend -- poor, Baron -- dead -- just like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- We must do something...</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, the police must be called.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- no -- wait -- the man was a burglar -- he was going to steal my money.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no -- no -- not the Baron.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is that girl -- she was working with him -- she enticed me into her room.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her room -- oh -- I see, Mr. Preysing -- I understand, Mr. General Director Preysing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can answer for this, it was self- defense -- I can answer for this -- but that girl -- the scandal -- my wife -- my daughters, you know them?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know them --</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The scandal -- we are men -- you -- you could take that affair of the young lady upon yourself -- take her and hold your tongue. Then you can travel -- I'll give you anything -- anything -- she was with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Preysing takes him by the shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>We must call the police, your excellency.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREYSING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much -- how much do you want -- you need money -- you have nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about me, Mr. General Director Pryesing -- worry about yourself.  There has been a murder -- this is room one sixty-four.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TELEPHONE ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Telephone girl plugs in.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello -- hurry up... hurry up... someone in one sixty-four says there has been a murder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam should sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've done my hair differently -- do you like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When a lady falls in love she does her hair differently.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the middle of the night -- those flowers make me think of a funeral. Laurels and tube-roses.  Oh, think, Suzette -- the Villa and the sun at Tremezzo -- quiet -- simple -- happy -- we'll have a guest, Suzette.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Madam. And now Madam will sleep. It is not long 'till the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzette leaves -- turning out a light. Alone, Grusinskaya goes to the telephone. She raises the receiver.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Suzette.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT IN HERE at discretion the:</context>
      <utterance>Hello -- can you tell me if Baron von Gaigern is in his room -- ring him.  Cherie, I must wake you or you'll miss the train.  ...yes... are you ringing, he may be asleep.  Cherie, you must get up and fetch me from my room -- I'm longing for you, Cherie -- I have not been to sleep -- I kept thinking you would come to me.  ...Oh, but he must answer. Ring -- ring -- ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARON'S EMPTY ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Telephone is ringing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The night clerk has already gone -- you are late.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man -- I was at the clinic the whole night -- there are no words to describe what my wife suffered.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the child isn't coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- no -- not yet. Well, I mustn't let it interfere with my duty. Any news here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>News? Yes -- killing in number one- sixty-four.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? -- Who? -- Whom?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The big manufacturer killed Baron von Gaigern.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good heavens. What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man -- that's terrible. He was a nice fellow -- I am sorry about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems that he was a thief and an imposter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it -- he was a real gentleman. I know people... I'm so tired I can hardly see out of my eyes. No sleep for two nights and so many duties and now this killing in the hotel -- that means a lot of work. But it's too bad about the Baron, you always felt better when he came along -- always friendly -- such an agreeable fellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A number of bellboys march up and form a line. Senf comes from behind the desk and inspects them.</context>
      <utterance>Most imposters are --</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They show their hands.</context>
      <utterance>Show your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys sit down on the bench.</context>
      <utterance>You have dirty nails -- you little pig -- you're no good... Caps off! -- Let's see your hair.  Good -- caps on!  Where is number seven?... Not here?  Take his name -- if he comes late again today, he's fired. Dismissed!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein exits.</context>
      <utterance>That will be sufficient for the present, sir, you may travel in peace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they've taken him away.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOOR CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- it's terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam must not know -- you understand -- Madam must not know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOOR CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzette hurries down corridor. By this time Kringelein has arrived at his door, he opens it.</context>
      <utterance>I will tell the maids. I cannot answer for downstairs --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- I was thinking -- Poor Baron -- Lying there, his eyes so open.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You loved the Baron, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes --</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So did I. He was friendly to me as no man ever was.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps he really was a burglar -- But they don't kill a man for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was in desperate straits. He'd been trying to raise money all day. He laughed -- Poor devil! And then a man like Preysing kills him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't like Preysing right off.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why did you have anything to do with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Money!</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course, -- money!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't understand that do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I do -- I never knew what money really meant till I started spending it. Do you know --  I can hardly believe that anything so beautiful should come to me from Preysing -- I'll take care of you. Will -- will you let me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have a good time with me. Want to? I've got enough money. Ten thousand two hundred in my pocketbook. Three thousand four hundred that I won. It will last a long time. I can win more -- we'll travel.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- to Paris? I wanted to go there always.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wherever you like. Here I'll give you the money I won, three thousand four hundred. Later you can have more.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Later?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I -- I'm ill, Flaemmchen -- It will not be long -- I'll not last long. Will you stay with me until...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense! We'll find a great doctor, he'll cure you. They can cure anything these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe that you will have a better time with me than you would with Preysing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like me better?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein straightens, happy, inspired, a smile on his face. He assumes in his gestures. Takes the telephone.</context>
      <utterance>You're a good man, Mr. Kringelein -- a very good man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When is the next train leaving for Paris? -- Yes... Get two tickets for me... and my bill please... and the lady's -- Miss Flaemm's.   We have to hurry let's pack -- we'll have breakfast on the train.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madam, it is Mr. Meierheim -- he is waiting downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(she looks off.)</context>
      <utterance>Where is Pimenov? Where is Pimenov?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH OF PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grusinskaya hurries down to Pimenov -- they meet.</context>
      <utterance>coming out of the elevator.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will be on the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses and looks in the Baron's room. A maid is there changing the bedding. The room is unoccupied otherwise.</context>
      <utterance>But when did he go? How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The maid nods.</context>
      <utterance>Baron von Gaigern has left?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maid shrugs her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>When? How long ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE OF FLOOR CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Baron left about half an hour ago, Madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While they are waiting for the elevator Grusinskaya is like a live electric wire. The elevator arrives. They are stepping in.</context>
      <utterance>Oh -- Gru -- come, come -- we'll lose the train.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General activity. We hear the cry go up:</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grusinskaya comes out of the elevator followed by Suzette and Pimenov. Meierheim meets her.</context>
      <utterance>Madam Grusinskaya's car...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come along, oh, Madam, come along. The train will be going.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. I've got to ask myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the use of asking, Gru -- he is at the train -- He will be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grusinskaya crosses to the desk. She speaks to Senf.</context>
      <utterance>The troupe, the scenery, everything -- all on board, waiting. You have a rehearsal in Vienna tomorrow morning. Come, Madam, are you mad?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen Baron von Gaigern?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROHNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Baron is not here, Madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROHNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four minutes past. Please come.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMENOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come, Lisaveta, he will be there -- he will be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grusinskaya, followed by the others, sweeps out towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>Madam Grusinskaya's car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, the sun -- it will be sunny in Tremezzo --</utterance>
   <speaker>MEIERHEIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every seat for the opening has been sold at Vienna. Sold out for three days.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUSINSKAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know -- I know -- but it will be sunny in Tremezzo. We'll have a guest then.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grusinskaya moves forward.</context>
      <utterance>Madam Grusinskaya's car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing the word 'Excellency' Kringelein goes through a transformation. He stands and with a flourish hands the suitcase over to the boy. He is a big man now.</context>
      <utterance>Your bag, your Excellency --</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cab please!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cab, for his Excellency, Mr. Kringelein!</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now we travel, Flaemmchen... Glad?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I!</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the bill ready -- the lady's too?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At once. Any forwarding address, Mr. Kringelein?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Paris -- Grand Hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAEMMCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know there is a Grand Hotel?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRINGELEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, there must be one in Paris... They have everything in Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kringelein pays and taking Flaemmchen's arm starts to move away from the desk, General business ad lib of tipping. Boys line up, making a deep bow. There is almost a triumphant march as Kringelein and Flaemmchen move towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>Your bill, Your Excellency.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that Mr. Kringelein leaving?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
